>>
>> Why
>> Why did
>> Why did I
>> Why did I want
>> Why did I want to
>> Why did I want to direct
>> Why did I want to direct a
WWDC
WWDC opening
>> Why did I want to direct a
WWDC opening number
WWDC opening number?
>> Why did I want to direct a
WWDC opening number? Good
qu
question
WWDC opening number? Good
question.
question. You
WWDC opening number? Good
question. You know
question. You know,
WWDC opening number? Good
question. You know, I
question. You know, I think
I've
I've always
question. You know, I think
I've always been
I've always been attract
question. You know, I think
I've always been attracted
I've always been attracted to
question. You know, I think
risk.
I've always been attracted to
risk. You
risk. You know
I've always been attracted to
risk. You know?
risk. You know? When
I've always been attracted to
risk. You know? When I
risk. You know? When I shared
my
my vision
risk. You know? When I shared
my vision for
my vision for the
risk. You know? When I shared
my vision for the number
my vision for the number,
risk. You know? When I shared
my vision for the number, I
my vision for the number, I --
you
you know,
my vision for the number, I --
you know, they
you know, they said
my vision for the number, I --
you know, they said this
you know, they said this is
just
just a
you know, they said this is
just a developers
just a developers conference
you know, they said this is
just a developers conference.
You
You know?
just a developers conference.
You know? You
You know? You don't
just a developers conference.
You know? You don't n
You know? You don't need
just a developers conference.
You know? You don't need to
overthink
overthink it.
You know? You don't need to
overthink it. But
overthink it. But I
You know? You don't need to
overthink it. But I always
feel
feel that
overthink it. But I always
feel that my
feel that my j
overthink it. But I always
feel that my job
feel that my job as
overthink it. But I always
feel that my job as a
feel that my job as a director
is
is to
feel that my job as a director
is to push
is to push an
feel that my job as a director
is to push an idea.
is to push an idea. What's
that?
that? Am
is to push an idea. What's
that? Am I
that? Am I a
is to push an idea. What's
that? Am I a genius
that? Am I a genius?
is to push an idea. What's
that? Am I a genius? I
that? Am I a genius? I don't
know.
know. What
that? Am I a genius? I don't
know. What!
>>
>> Hey,
know. What!
>> Hey, David.
>> Hey, David. Are
know. What!
>> Hey, David. Are you
>> Hey, David. Are you ready
for
for the
>> Hey, David. Are you ready
for the walk-through
for the walk-through?
>>
>> Y
for the walk-through?
>> Yeah.
>>
>> Who
>> Yeah.
>> Who are
>> Who are you
>> Yeah.
>> Who are you talking
>> Who are you talking to
>> Yeah.
>> Who are you talking to in
here?
>>
>> No
here?
>> No one
>> No one.
>>
>> You
>> No one.
>> You were
>> You were talking
>> No one.
>> You were talking to
somebody.
somebody. Unless
>> You were talking to
somebody. Unless you
somebody. Unless you were
talking
talking to
somebody. Unless you were
talking to yourself.
>>
>> I
talking to yourself.
>> I have
>> I have been
talking to yourself.
>> I have been working
>> I have been working on
talking to yourself.
>> I have been working on this
new
new app
>> I have been working on this
new app called
new app called Work
>> I have been working on this
new app called Work Crush.
It's
It's for
new app called Work Crush.
It's for people
It's for people who
new app called Work Crush.
It's for people who have
crushes
crushes on
It's for people who have
crushes on their
crushes on their w
It's for people who have
crushes on their work
crushes on their work mates
It's for people who have
crushes on their work mates and
want
want to
crushes on their work mates and
want to know
want to know when
crushes on their work mates and
want to know when they
want to know when they are
crushes on their work mates and
nearby.
want to know when they are
nearby. It's
nearby. It's n
want to know when they are
nearby. It's not
nearby. It's not for
want to know when they are
nearby. It's not for me
nearby. It's not for me,
want to know when they are
nearby. It's not for me, but
--
-- o
nearby. It's not for me, but
-- oh,
-- oh, oh
nearby. It's not for me, but
-- oh, oh,
-- oh, oh, hi,
nearby. It's not for me, but
-- oh, oh, hi, David.
>>
>> Yeah,
-- oh, oh, hi, David.
>> Yeah, I
>> Yeah, I thought
-- oh, oh, hi, David.
>> Yeah, I thought you
>> Yeah, I thought you were
supposed
supposed to
>> Yeah, I thought you were
supposed to be
supposed to be guarding
>> Yeah, I thought you were
supposed to be guarding my
supposed to be guarding my door
>> Yeah, I thought you were
supposed to be guarding my d
door.
>>
>> Which
door.
>> Which one
>> Which one is
door.
>> Which one is your
>> Which one is your d
door.
>> Which one is your door?
>>
>> This
>> Which one is your door?
>> This is
>> This is Rick
>> Which one is your door?
>> This is Rick.
>> This is Rick. Rick,
>> Which one is your door?
>> This is Rick. Rick, look
at
at me
>> This is Rick. Rick, look
at me.
at me. I
>> This is Rick. Rick, look
at me. I need
at me. I need you
>> This is Rick. Rick, look
at me. I need you angry
at me. I need you angry in
there,
there, Rick
at me. I need you angry in
there, Rick.
there, Rick. I
at me. I need you angry in
there, Rick. I need
there, Rick. I need you
at me. I need you angry in
there, Rick. I need you angry,
angry
angry,
there, Rick. I need you angry,
angry, angry!
angry, angry! Y
there, Rick. I need you angry,
angry, angry! Yeah!
Did
Did you
angry, angry! Yeah!
Did you get
Did you get that
angry, angry! Yeah!
Did you get that email
Did you get that email about
my
my email
Did you get that email about
my email not
my email not working
Did you get that email about
my email not working?
>>
>> No
my email not working?
>> No.
>>
>> What
>> No.
>> What?
>> What? No,
>> No.
>> What? No, no,
>> What? No, no, no.
>> No.
>> What? No, no, no. It
needs
needs to
>> What? No, no, no. It
needs to be
needs to be more
>> What? No, no, no. It
needs to be more like,
needs to be more like, you
>> What? No, no, no. It
needs to be more like, you know
needs to be more like, you k
know,
know, Pshhhh!
>>
>> Yeah,
know, Pshhhh!
>> Yeah, he
>> Yeah, he means
know, Pshhhh!
>> Yeah, he means bigger.
>>
>> Bigger,
>> Yeah, he means bigger.
>> Bigger, yeah,
>> Bigger, yeah, like
developers
developers are
>> Bigger, yeah, like
developers are on
developers are on fire.
>>
>> Which
developers are on fire.
>> Which one
>> Which one do
developers are on fire.
>> Which one do you
>> Which one do you need
developers are on fire.
>> Which one do you need for
the
the new
>> Which one do you need for
the new one
the new one,
>> Which one do you need for
the new one, silver
the new one, silver or
>> Which one do you need for
the new one, silver or G
the new one, silver or Gold
>> Which one do you need for
the new one, silver or Gold?
the new one, silver or Gold? I
can't
can't tell
the new one, silver or Gold? I
can't tell because
can't tell because the
reflection
reflection of
can't tell because the
reflection of the
reflection of the flame
can't tell because the
reflection of the flame is
reflection of the flame is on
it.
>>
>> With
it.
>> With you
>> With you decide
it.
>> With you decide this
>> With you decide this later
it.
>> With you decide this later?
>>
>> Yeah
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, he
>> Yeah, he is
>> Yeah, he is right.
>> Yeah, he is right. Let's
decide
decide it
>> Yeah, he is right. Let's
decide it late
decide it later.
>>
>> We'll
decide it later.
>> We'll take
>> We'll take the
decide it later.
>> We'll take the gold.
Got
Got to
>> We'll take the gold.
Got to choose
Got to choose a
>> We'll take the gold.
Got to choose a talent
Got to choose a talent for
>> We'll take the gold.
Got to choose a talent for the
dating
dating app
Got to choose a talent for the
dating app n
dating app number.
>>
>> Yes.
dating app number.
>> Yes. No.
>> Yes. No. Yes.
dating app number.
>> Yes. No. Yes. No.
>> Yes. No. Yes. No. Yeah.
The
The pretty
>> Yes. No. Yes. No. Yeah.
The pretty one
The pretty one.
>>
>> That's
The pretty one.
>> That's you
>> That's you.
>>
>> Whoa!
>> That's you.
>> Whoa! Did
>> Whoa! Did you
>> That's you.
>> Whoa! Did you do
>> Whoa! Did you do that?
>>
>> Yes.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, my
>> Yes.
>> Oh, my gosh!
>> Oh, my gosh! That's
>> Yes.
>> Oh, my gosh! That's my
coffee.
>>
>> Yeah.
>> Ahhh!
>> Ahhh! Oh,
>> Yeah.
>> Ahhh! Oh, cool.
>> Ahhh! Oh, cool. Oh,
that's
that's awesome.
>> Ahhh! Oh, cool. Oh,
that's awesome. Did
that's awesome. Did you
>> Ahhh! Oh, cool. Oh,
that's awesome. Did you bring
my
my s
that's awesome. Did you bring
my sugar?
my sugar? Ahhh!
Who
Who are
my sugar? Ahhh!
Who are these
Who are these guys?
>>
>> The
Who are these guys?
>> The Tim
>> The Tim Cook-alikes
Who are these guys?
>> The Tim Cook-alikes you
asked
asked f
>> The Tim Cook-alikes you
asked for.
>>
>> Oh,
asked for.
>> Oh, right.
>> Oh, right. You
asked for.
>> Oh, right. You guys
>> Oh, right. You guys are
good
good to
>> Oh, right. You guys are
good to get
good to get wet;
>> Oh, right. You guys are
good to get wet; right
good to get wet; right?
>>
>> Hey.
>> Hey,
>> Hey, you
>> Hey.
>> Hey, you guys
>> Hey, you guys are
>> Hey.
>> Hey, you guys are the
>> Hey, you guys are the faces
of
of WWDC.
>> Hey, you guys are the faces
of WWDC. Let's
of WWDC. Let's go
>> Hey, you guys are the faces
of WWDC. Let's go.
of WWDC. Let's go. Not
>> Hey, you guys are the faces
of WWDC. Let's go. Not the
real
real faces
of WWDC. Let's go. Not the
real faces.
real faces. You
of WWDC. Let's go. Not the
real faces. You are
real faces. You are the
of WWDC. Let's go. Not the
real faces. You are the masks
that
that they
real faces. You are the masks
that they give
that they give you.
real faces. You are the masks
that they give you. What's
this
this?
>>
>> Goat
this?
>> Goat Simulator
>> Goat Simulator.
>>
>> Goat
>> Goat Simulator.
>> Goat Simulator
>> Goat Simulator. I
>> Goat Simulator.
>> Goat Simulator. I am
>> Goat Simulator. I am not
feeling
feeling it.
>> Goat Simulator. I am not
feeling it. Kill
feeling it. Kill it.
>> Goat Simulator. I am not
feeling it. Kill it. Oh,
that's
that's an
feeling it. Kill it. Oh,
that's an ax.
that's an ax. No,
feeling it. Kill it. Oh,
that's an ax. No, no,
that's an ax. No, no, don't
actually
actually kill
that's an ax. No, no, don't
actually kill it.
actually kill it. Okay
that's an ax. No, no, don't
actually kill it. Okay?
There
There he
actually kill it. Okay?
There he is.
There he is. Hey.
>>
>> David,
There he is. Hey.
>> David, what
>> David, what have
There he is. Hey.
>> David, what have you
>> David, what have you got
There he is. Hey.
>> David, what have you got me
into
into here?
>> David, what have you got me
into here? Am
into here? Am I
>> David, what have you got me
into here? Am I like
into here? Am I like a
Victoria
Victoria secrets
into here? Am I like a
Victoria secrets guy
Victoria secrets guy?
>>
>> You
Victoria secrets guy?
>> You are
>> You are an
Victoria secrets guy?
>> You are an angel
>> You are an angel investor.
You
You make
>> You are an angel investor.
You make millions
You make millions off
>> You are an angel investor.
You make millions off kids'
dreams
dreams.
>>
>> So
dreams.
>> So I
>> So I am
dreams.
>> So I am just
>> So I am just a
dreams.
>> So I am just a rich
>> So I am just a rich guy?
>>
>> You
>> So I am just a rich guy?
>> You are
>> You are a
>> So I am just a rich guy?
>> You are a rich
>> You are a rich guy
>> So I am just a rich guy?
>> You are a rich guy.
>> You are a rich guy. Bring
him
him up.
>>
>> Ooh,
him up.
>> Ooh, t
>> Ooh, this
him up.
>> Ooh, this harness
>> Ooh, this harness cuts
him up.
>> Ooh, this harness cuts the
circulation
circulation off
>> Ooh, this harness cuts the
circulation off in
circulation off in my
>> Ooh, this harness cuts the
circulation off in my legs.
>>
>> That's
circulation off in my legs.
>> That's all
>> That's all right,
circulation off in my legs.
>> That's all right, buddy.
No
No worries
>> That's all right, buddy.
No worries.
>>
>> Let's
>> Let's run
>> Let's run it.
>>
>> No,
>> Let's run it.
>> No, I
>> No, I say
>> Let's run it.
>> No, I say when
>> No, I say when we
>> Let's run it.
>> No, I say when we run
>> No, I say when we run it.
Who
Who is
>> No, I say when we run it.
Who is it?
Who is it? Why
>> No, I say when we run it.
Who is it? Why is
Who is it? Why is he
>> No, I say when we run it.
Who is it? Why is he saying
Who is it? Why is he saying my
words
words?
>>
>> Run
words?
>> Run it.
>>
>> Thank
>> Run it.
>> Thank you
>> Thank you.
>>
>> So
>> Thank you.
>> So many
>> So many days
>> Thank you.
>> So many days of
>> So many days of dev
>> Thank you.
>> So many days of dev time,
haven't
haven't seen
>> So many days of dev time,
haven't seen a
haven't seen a ray
>> So many days of dev time,
haven't seen a ray of
haven't seen a ray of sunshine.
Locked
Locked in
haven't seen a ray of sunshine.
Locked in my
Locked in my coding
haven't seen a ray of sunshine.
Locked in my coding lair.
It's
It's been
Locked in my coding lair.
It's been day
It's been days
Locked in my coding lair.
It's been days since
It's been days since I
Locked in my coding lair.
It's been days since I changed
my
my underwear
It's been days since I changed
my underwear.
My
My app
my underwear.
My app is
My app is in
my underwear.
My app is in the
My app is in the store
my underwear.
My app is in the store?
>>
>> Your
My app is in the store?
>> Your app
>> Your app is
My app is in the store?
>> Your app is in
>> Your app is in the
My app is in the store?
>> Your app is in the store.
>>
>> From
>> Your app is in the store.
>> From the
>> From the whiteboard
>> Your app is in the store.
>> From the whiteboard to
>> From the whiteboard to the
app
app s
>> From the whiteboard to the
app store
app store because
>> From the whiteboard to the
app store because when
app store because when I
>> From the whiteboard to the
app store because when I c
app store because when I code,
I'm
I'm swift,
app store because when I code,
I'm swift, boy
I'm swift, boy.
app store because when I code,
I'm swift, boy. Yeah,
I'm swift, boy. Yeah, I
app store because when I code,
I'm swift, boy. Yeah, I rule
objective
objective C,
I'm swift, boy. Yeah, I rule
objective C, objective
objective C, objective one,
objective
objective m
objective C, objective one,
objective me.
objective me. See
objective C, objective one,
objective me. See the
objective me. See the app,
objective C, objective one,
objective me. See the app, I
made
made that.
objective me. See the app, I
made that. Download
made that. Download m
objective me. See the app, I
made that. Download my
made that. Download my game,
you
you play
made that. Download my game,
you play that.
you play that. App
made that. Download my game,
you play that. App of
you play that. App of the
made that. Download my game,
you play that. App of the day,
now
now I'm
you play that. App of the day,
now I'm worldwi
now I'm worldwide.
you play that. App of the day,
now I'm worldwide. Five
now I'm worldwide. Five stars,
now
now watch
now I'm worldwide. Five stars,
now watch me
now watch me shine.
You
You made
now watch me shine.
You made the
You made the cut.
now watch me shine.
You made the cut. The
You made the cut. The world
is
is yours
You made the cut. The world
is yours.
is yours. Now
You made the cut. The world
is yours. Now that
is yours. Now that your
You made the cut. The world
is yours. Now that your app
is yours. Now that your app is
in
in the
is yours. Now that your app is
in the store.
This
This is
in the store.
This is your
This is your break,
in the store.
This is your break, your
This is your break, your time
to
to fly.
This is your break, your time
to fly. S
to fly. So
This is your break, your time
to fly. So raise
to fly. So raise your
This is your break, your time
to fly. So raise your ha
to fly. So raise your hands
This is your break, your time
to fly. So raise your hands up
and
and touch
to fly. So raise your hands up
and touch the
and touch the sky
to fly. So raise your hands up
and touch the sky.
>>
>> What
>> What happened?
>>
>> T
>> What happened?
>> The
>> The generator's
>> What happened?
>> The generator's blown.
>>
>> Dammit!
>> The generator's blown.
>> Dammit! Can
>> Dammit! Can I
>> The generator's blown.
>> Dammit! Can I at
>> Dammit! Can I at least
>> The generator's blown.
>> Dammit! Can I at least get
a
a work
>> Dammit! Can I at least get
a work light
a work light?
>>
>> Rebooting.
>> How
>> How long
>> Rebooting.
>> How long until
>> How long until we're
>> Rebooting.
>> How long until we're up
>> How long until we're up and
running?
>>
>> I
running?
>> I don't
>> I don't know.
running?
>> I don't know. Maybe
>> I don't know. Maybe 24
hours.
>>
>> Well,
hours.
>> Well, what
>> Well, what am
hours.
>> Well, what am I
>> Well, what am I supposed
hours.
>> Well, what am I supposed to
do
do with
>> Well, what am I supposed to
do with this?
do with this? Guys,
>> Well, what am I supposed to
do with this? Guys, we
do with this? Guys, we go
>> Well, what am I supposed to
do with this? Guys, we go live
tomorrow.
tomorrow. That's
do with this? Guys, we go live
tomorrow. That's just
tomorrow. That's just a
do with this? Guys, we go live
tomorrow. That's just a bottle
of
of water
tomorrow. That's just a bottle
of water and
of water and a
tomorrow. That's just a bottle
of water and a laptop.
>>
>> I
of water and a laptop.
>> I don't
>> I don't know.
of water and a laptop.
>> I don't know. I
>> I don't know. I think
of water and a laptop.
>> I don't know. I think it's
kind
kind of
>> I don't know. I think it's
kind of pretty
kind of pretty.
>>
>> All
>> All right.
>> All right. We'll
>> All right. We'll work
>> All right. We'll work with
it.
(Laughter)
I
I tell
(Laughter)
I tell you
I tell you what,
(Laughter)
I tell you what, though,
whoever
whoever walks
I tell you what, though,
whoever walks out
whoever walks out there
I tell you what, though,
whoever walks out there better
have
have something
whoever walks out there better
have something pretty
incredible
incredible to
have something pretty
incredible to say.
>>
>> Yeah
incredible to say.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, let's
incredible to say.
>> Yeah, let's just
>> Yeah, let's just hope
incredible to say.
>> Yeah, let's just hope he
doesn't
doesn't get
>> Yeah, let's just hope he
doesn't get booed.
>>
>> Either
doesn't get booed.
>> Either way
>> Either way,
doesn't get booed.
>> Either way, we
>> Either way, we are
doesn't get booed.
>> Either way, we are getting
free
free wat
>> Either way, we are getting
free watches
free watches out
>> Either way, we are getting
free watches out o
free watches out of
>> Either way, we are getting
free watches out of it.
(Laughter)
(Laughter) (Cheers
free watches out of it.
(Laughter) (Cheers and
applause)
appl
(Cheers
(Cheers and
appl
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> TIM
>> TIM COOK:
>> TIM COOK: Good
>> TIM COOK: Good morning
>> TIM COOK: Good morning!
Good
Good morning!
Good morning
Good morning.
Good morning!
Good morning. Good
Good morning. Good morning
Good morning!
Good morning. Good morning.
Good
Good morning
Good morning. Good morning.
Good morning!
Good morning! Thanks
Good morning. Good morning.
Good morning! Thanks for
joining
joining us
Good morning! Thanks for
joining us.
joining us. And
Good morning! Thanks for
joining us. And welcome
joining us. And welcome to
Good morning! Thanks for
joining us. And welcome to San
Francisco
Francisco.
joining us. And welcome to San
Francisco. Welcome
Francisco. Welcome to
joining us. And welcome to San
Francisco. Welcome to WWDC
2015.
2015. Although
Francisco. Welcome to WWDC
2015. Although we
2015. Although we may
Francisco. Welcome to WWDC
2015. Although we may not
2015. Although we may not have
any
any --
2015. Although we may not have
any -- thank
any -- thank you
2015. Although we may not have
any -- thank you --
any -- thank you -- high
2015. Although we may not have
any -- thank you -- high-flying
trapeze
trapeze acts,
any -- thank you -- high-flying
trapeze acts, we
trapeze acts, we do
any -- thank you -- high-flying
trapeze acts, we do have
trapeze acts, we do have a
any -- thank you -- high-flying
trapeze acts, we do have a lot
of
of great
trapeze acts, we do have a lot
of great things
of great things to
trapeze acts, we do have a lot
of great things to talk
of great things to talk about
this
this morning.
of great things to talk about
This
this morning.
This developer
This developer conference
continues
continues to
This developer conference
continues to be
continues to be The
This developer conference
continues to be The Epicenter
of
of Change
continues to be The Epicenter
of Change for
of Change for not
continues to be The Epicenter
of Change for not only
of Change for not only Apple,
but
but the
of Change for not only Apple,
but the industry
but the industry.
of Change for not only Apple,
but the industry. This
but the industry. This is
of Change for not only Apple,
but the industry. This is our
26th
26th WWDC.
but the industry. This is our
26th WWDC. We
26th WWDC. We have
but the industry. This is our
26th WWDC. We have attendees
today
today from
26th WWDC. We have attendees
today from over
today from over 70
26th WWDC. We have attendees
today from over 70 countries,
and
and 80
today from over 70 countries,
and 80%
and 80% are
today from over 70 countries,
and 80% are here
and 80% are here for
today from over 70 countries,
and 80% are here for the
and 80% are here for the very
first
first time
and 80% are here for the very
first time.
(Applause)
This
This is
(Applause)
This is o
This is our
(Applause)
This is our most
This is our most global
conference
conference ever.
This is our most global
conference ever. And
conference ever. And a
This is our most global
conference ever. And a special
shout
shout-out
conference ever. And a special
shout-out for
shout-out for our
conference ever. And a special
shout-out for our 350
scholarship
scholarship winners
shout-out for our 350
scholarship winners.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
scholarship winners.
(Cheers and applause)
(Cheers and applause) these
guys
guys are
(Cheers and applause) these
guys are unbelievable.
guys are unbelievable. I
(Cheers and applause) these
guys are unbelievable. I spent
some
some time
guys are unbelievable. I spent
some time with
some time with them
guys are unbelievable. I spent
some time with them yesterday
some time with them yesterday.
Our
Our young
some time with them yesterday.
Our youngest
Our youngest s
some time with them yesterday.
Our youngest scholarship
Our youngest scholarship winner
is
is a
Our youngest scholarship winner
is a 12-year-old
is a 12-year-old g
Our youngest scholarship winner
is a 12-year-old girl
is a 12-year-old girl from
Our youngest scholarship winner
is a 12-year-old girl from New
York
York.
is a 12-year-old girl from New
York. She
York. She is
is a 12-year-old girl from New
York. She is going
York. She is going to
is a 12-year-old girl from New
York. She is going to have
York. She is going to have a
fantastic
fantastic future
York. She is going to have a
fantastic future ahead
fantastic future ahead.
We've
We've got
fantastic future ahead.
We've got over
We've got over a
fantastic future ahead.
We've got over a hundred
sessions
sessions planned
We've got over a hundred
sessions planned for
sessions planned for you
We've got over a hundred
sessions planned for you and
over
over 150
sessions planned for you and
over 150 labs
over 150 labs so
sessions planned for you and
over 150 labs so that
over 150 labs so that you
sessions planned for you and
over 150 labs so that you can
get
get your
over 150 labs so that you can
get your hands
get your hands on
over 150 labs so that you can
get your hands on our
get your hands on our latest
over 150 labs so that you can
technologies
get your hands on our latest
technologies.
technologies. And
get your hands on our latest
technologies. And we've
technologies. And we've got
over
over a
technologies. And we've got
over a t
over a thousand
technologies. And we've got
over a thousand Apple
over a thousand Apple engineers
to
to a
over a thousand Apple engineers
to answer
to answer jus
over a thousand Apple engineers
to answer just
to answer just about
over a thousand Apple engineers
to answer just about any
question
question that
to answer just about any
question that y
question that you
to answer just about any
question that you might
question that you might have.
Now,
Now, we
question that you might have.
Now, we had
Now, we had a
question that you might have.
Now, we had a lot
Now, we had a lot more
question that you might have.
Now, we had a lot more people
that
that would
Now, we had a lot more people
that would have
that would have liked
Now, we had a lot more people
that would have liked to
that would have liked to have
been
been here
that would have liked to have
been here this
been here this m
that would have liked to have
been here this morning,
been here this morning, b
that would have liked to have
been here this morning, but
unfortunately,
unfortunately, we
been here this morning, but
unfortunately, we just
unfortunately, we just can't
fit
fit any
unfortunately, we just can't
fit any m
fit any more
unfortunately, we just can't
fit any more in,
fit any more in, as
unfortunately, we just can't
fit any more in, as you
fit any more in, as you can
tell.
tell. And
fit any more in, as you can
tell. And so
tell. And so for
fit any more in, as you can
tell. And so for the
tell. And so for the first
time
time,
tell. And so for the first
time, we
time, we are
tell. And so for the first
time, we are not
time, we are not only
tell. And so for the first
time, we are not only live
streaming
streaming the
time, we are not only live
streaming the Keynote,
streaming the Keynote, but
time, we are not only live
streaming the Keynote, but we
are
are live
streaming the Keynote, but we
are live streaming
are live streaming 30
streaming the Keynote, but we
are live streaming 30 session
are live streaming 30 sessions
of
of the
are live streaming 30 sessions
of the conference
of the conference as
are live streaming 30 sessions
of the conference as well.
(Applause)
Now
Now,
(Applause)
Now, before
Now, before we
(Applause)
Now, before we get
Now, before we get right
(Applause)
Now, before we get right to
the
the show
Now, before we get right to
the show,
the show, I'd
Now, before we get right to
the show, I'd like
the show, I'd like to
Now, before we get right to
the show, I'd like to bring
the show, I'd like to bring up
Now, before we get right to
something
the show, I'd like to bring up
something that
something that I
the show, I'd like to bring up
something that I saw
something that I saw o
the show, I'd like to bring up
something that I saw on
something that I saw on the
news
news j
something that I saw on the
news just
news just a
something that I saw on the
news just a few
news just a few d
something that I saw on the
news just a few days
news just a few days ago
something that I saw on the
news just a few days ago.
news just a few days ago. This
is
is Brandon
news just a few days ago. This
is Brandon Moss
is Brandon Moss of
news just a few days ago. This
is Brandon Moss of the
Cleveland
Cleveland Indians,
is Brandon Moss of the
Cleveland Indians, a
Cleveland Indians, and
is Brandon Moss of the
Cleveland Indians, and he
Cleveland Indians, and he hit
his
his 1
Cleveland Indians, and he hit
his 100th
his 100th career
Cleveland Indians, and he hit
his 100th career home
his 100th career home run
Cleveland Indians, and he hit
his 100th career home run last
Tuesday
Tuesday.
his 100th career home run last
Tuesday. Obviously,
Tuesday. Obviously, it's
his 100th career home run last
Tuesday. Obviously, it's a
huge
huge m
Tuesday. Obviously, it's a
huge milestone
huge milestone if
Tuesday. Obviously, it's a
huge milestone if you
huge milestone if you are
Tuesday. Obviously, it's a
huge milestone if you are a
basketball
basketball player.
huge milestone if you are a
basketball player. Not
basketball player. Not a
huge milestone if you are a
basketball player. Not a lot
of
of people
basketball player. Not a lot
of people do
of people do --
basketball player. Not a lot
of people do -- baseball
player.
player. Not
of people do -- baseball
player. Not a
player. Not a lot
of people do -- baseball
player. Not a lot of
player. Not a lot of p
of people do -- baseball
player. Not a lot of people
player. Not a lot of people do
this
this.
player. Not a lot of people do
this. You
this. You can
player. Not a lot of people do
this. You can imagine
this. You can imagine how
player. Not a lot of people do
this. You can imagine how much
that
that ball
this. You can imagine how much
that ball would
that ball would mean
this. You can imagine how much
that ball would mean to
that ball would mean to him
this. You can imagine how much
that ball would mean to him to
have
have it.
that ball would mean to him to
have it. It
have it. It turns
that ball would mean to him to
have it. It turns out
have it. It turns out the
that ball would mean to him to
have it. It turns out the ball
was
was hit
have it. It turns out the ball
was hit i
was hit into
have it. It turns out the ball
was hit into t
was hit into the
have it. It turns out the ball
was hit into the Indians
was hit into the Indians b
have it. It turns out the ball
was hit into the Indians bull
pen,
pen, and
was hit into the Indians bull
pen, and h
pen, and his
was hit into the Indians bull
pen, and his team
pen, and his teammates
was hit into the Indians bull
pen, and his teammates decide
pen, and his teammates decided
to
to play
pen, and his teammates decided
to play a
to play a bit
pen, and his teammates decided
to play a bit of
to play a bit of a
pen, and his teammates decided
to play a bit of a prank
to play a bit of a prank on
him.
him. They
to play a bit of a prank on
him. They decided
him. They decided to
to play a bit of a prank on
him. They decided to hold
him. They decided to hold it
for
for ransom
him. They decided to hold it
for ransom.
for ransom. And
him. They decided to hold it
for ransom. And this
for ransom. And this is
him. They decided to hold it
for ransom. And this is the
list
list o
for ransom. And this is the
list of
list of things
for ransom. And this is the
list of things they
list of things they asked
for ransom. And this is the
list of things they asked for
list of things they asked for.
for ransom. And this is the
Apple
list of things they asked for.
Apple Watches
Apple Watches,
list of things they asked for.
Apple Watches, iPad
Apple Watches, iPad s
list of things they asked for.
Apple Watches, iPad s,
Apple Watches, iPad s, MacBook
Air
Airs,
Apple Watches, iPad s, MacBook
Airs, iPhones.
Airs, iPhones. I
Apple Watches, iPad s, MacBook
Airs, iPhones. It's
unbelievable.
unbelievable. It's
Airs, iPhones. It's
unbelievable. It's a
unbelievable. It's a shopping
list
list for
unbelievable. It's a shopping
list for the
list for the Apple
unbelievable. It's a shopping
list for the Apple Store
list for the Apple Store.
(Applause)
No
Now,
(Applause)
Now, Brandon
Now, Brandon would
(Applause)
Now, Brandon would have
Now, Brandon would have had
(Applause)
Now, Brandon would have had to
raid
raid an
Now, Brandon would have had to
raid an Apple
raid an Apple Store
Now, Brandon would have had to
raid an Apple Store to
raid an Apple Store to g
Now, Brandon would have had to
raid an Apple Store to get
raid an Apple Store to get that
ball
ball back
raid an Apple Store to get that
ball back.
ball back. That
raid an Apple Store to get that
ball back. That didn't
ball back. That didn't seem
quite
quite right
ball back. That didn't seem
quite right to
quite right to us,
ball back. That didn't seem
quite right to us, and
quite right to us, and so
ball back. That didn't seem
quite right to us, and so what
we're
we're going
quite right to us, and so what
we're going to
we're going to do
quite right to us, and so what
we're going to do is
we're going to do is we're
going
going to
we're going to do is we're
going to pay
going to pay the
we're going to do is we're
going to pay the ransom
going to pay the ransom.
we're going to do is we're
going to pay the ransom. And
going to pay the ransom. And I
have
have the
going to pay the ransom. And I
have the ball
have the ball right
going to pay the ransom. And I
have the ball right here
have the ball right here.
(Applause)
We
We are
(Applause)
We are giving
We are giving the
(Applause)
We are giving the ball
We are giving the ball to
Brandon,
Brandon, and
We are giving the ball to
Brandon, and we
Brandon, and we are
We are giving the ball to
Brandon, and we are going
Brandon, and we are going to
give
give everything
Brandon, and we are going to
give everything his
give everything his team
Brandon, and we are going to
give everything his teammates
asked
asked for
give everything his teammates
asked for to
asked for to them
give everything his teammates
asked for to them so
asked for to them so everybody
is
is happy.
asked for to them so everybody
is happy. So
is happy. So congratulations
asked for to them so everybody
is happy. So congratulations,
Brandon,
Brandon, on
is happy. So congratulations,
Brandon, on a
Brandon, on a hundred
is happy. So congratulations,
Brandon, on a hundred home
Brandon, on a hundred home r
runs,
runs, and
Brandon, on a hundred home r
runs, and good
runs, and good luck
Brandon, on a hundred home r
runs, and good luck on
runs, and good luck on the
Brandon, on a hundred home r
runs, and good luck on the next
hundred
hundred.
(Applause)
Now,
Now, we've
(Applause)
Now, we've got
Now, we've got a
(Applause)
Now, we've got a jam
Now, we've got a jam-packed
morning
morning for
Now, we've got a jam-packed
morning for you.
morning for you. We
Now, we've got a jam-packed
morning for you. We are
morning for you. We are going
to
to get
morning for you. We are going
to get started
to get started with
morning for you. We are going
to get started with OS
to get started with OS X
morning for you. We are going
to get started with OS X.
to get started with OS X. We
are
are bringing
to get started with OS X. We
are bringing a
are bringing a whole
to get started with OS X. We
are bringing a whole bunch
are bringing a whole bunch of
new
new great
are bringing a whole bunch of
new great capabilities
new great capabilities to
are bringing a whole bunch of
new great capabilities to the
Macintosh.
And
And next
Macintosh.
And next we've
And next we've got
Macintosh.
And next we've got a
And next we've got a great
update
update for
And next we've got a great
update for iOS,
update for iOS, the
And next we've got a great
update for iOS, the world's
most
most advance
update for iOS, the world's
most advanced
most advanced mobile
update for iOS, the world's
most advanced mobile operating
system.
And
And t
system.
And today
And today we're
system.
And today we're bringing
native
native apps
And today we're bringing
native apps to
native apps to t
And today we're bringing
native apps to the
native apps to the Watch
And today we're bringing
native apps to the Watch with
native apps to the Watch with a
new
new version.
(Applause)
With
With a
(Applause)
With a new
With a new version
(Applause)
With a new version o
With a new version of
(Applause)
With a new version of the
watch
watchOS,
With a new version of the
watchOS, which
watchOS, which gives
With a new version of the
watchOS, which gives the
develop
developers
watchOS, which gives the
developers even
developers even more
watchOS, which gives the
developers even more time
developers even more time to
create
create even
developers even more time to
create even great
create even greater
developers even more time to
create even greater apps
create even greater apps for
the
the Watch
create even greater apps for
the Watch that
the Watch that will
create even greater apps for
the Watch that will change
the Watch that will change the
world.
Now,
Now, all
world.
Now, all three
Now, all three of
world.
Now, all three of these
ecosystems
ecosystems together
Now, all three of these
ecosystems together provide
incredible
incredible o
ecosystems together provide
incredible opportunities
incredible opportunities for
ecosystems together provide
develop
incredible opportunities for
developer
developers
incredible opportunities for
developers and
developers and u
incredible opportunities for
developers and unbelievable
possibilities
possibilities for
developers and unbelievable
possibilities for users.
possibilities for users. So
developers and unbelievable
possibilities for users. So we
are
are very
possibilities for users. So we
are very excited
are very excited about
possibilities for users. So we
are very excited about this.
There
There's
are very excited about this.
There's a
There's a l
are very excited about this.
There's a lot
There's a lot here
are very excited about this.
There's a lot here,
There's a lot here, and
are very excited about this.
There's a lot here, and so
There's a lot here, and so I
are very excited about this.
There's a lot here, and so I am
going
going to
There's a lot here, and so I am
going to dispense
going to dispense with
There's a lot here, and so I am
going to dispense with m
going to dispense with my
There's a lot here, and so I am
going to dispense with my n
normal
normal updates
going to dispense with my n
normal updates other
normal updates other than
going to dispense with my n
normal updates other than to
tell
tell you
normal updates other than to
tell you everything's
tell you everything's going
great.
(Laughter)
(Applause)
(Applause) and
(Laughter)
(Applause) and I'd
(Applause) and
And
And I'd
(Applause) and
And I'd like
And I'd like to
(Applause) and
And I'd like to bring
And I'd like to bring out
(Applause) and
And I'd like to bring out my
friend
friend and
And I'd like to bring out my
friend and colleague
friend and colleague Craig
Federighi
Federighi to
friend and colleague Craig
Federighi to take
Federighi to take you
friend and colleague Craig
Federighi to take you through
OS
OS X
Federighi to take you through
OS X and
OS X and iOS
Federighi to take you through
OS X and iOS.
OS X and iOS. Craig.
(Applause)
>>
>> CRAIG
(Applause)
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI:
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: Good
morning
morning!
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: Good
It's
morning!
It's fantastic
It's fantastic to
morning!
It's fantastic to be
It's fantastic to be with
morning!
It's fantastic to be with you
here
here at
It's fantastic to be with you
here at WWDC.
here at WWDC. The
It's fantastic to be with you
here at WWDC. The team
here at WWDC. The team has
been
been doing
here at WWDC. The team has
been doing some
been doing some amazing
here at WWDC. The team has
been doing some amazing work
this
this year,
been doing some amazing work
this year, and
this year, and I
been doing some amazing work
this year, and I am
this year, and I am thrilled
been doing some amazing work
this year, and I am thrilled to
be
be able
this year, and I am thrilled to
be able to
be able to share
this year, and I am thrilled to
be able to share it
be able to share it with
this year, and I am thrilled to
be able to share it with you
today.
We
We are
today.
We are going
We are going to
today.
We are going to start
We are going to start with
today.
We are going to start with OS
X.
X. Now,
We are going to start with OS
X. Now, our
X. Now, our current
We are going to start with OS
X. Now, our current release,
Yosemite,
Yosemite, is
X. Now, our current release,
Yosemite, is a
Yosemite, is a big,
X. Now, our current release,
Yosemite, is a big, b
Yosemite, is a big, bold,
beautiful
beautiful release
Yosemite, is a big, bold,
beautiful release with
beautiful release with a
gorgeous
gorgeous new
beautiful release with a
gorgeous new UI
gorgeous new UI and
breakthrough
breakthrough features
gorgeous new UI and
breakthrough features l
breakthrough features like
Continuity
Continuity that
breakthrough features like
Continuity that let
Continuity that let you
breakthrough features like
Continuity that let you work
across
across your
Continuity that let you work
across your devices
across your devices l
Continuity that let you work
across your devices like
across your devices like n
Continuity that let you work
across your devices like never
before
before.
Now,
Now, the
before.
Now, the adoption
Now, the adoption rate
before.
Now, the adoption rate for
Yosemite
Yosemite is
Now, the adoption rate for
Yosemite is just
Yosemite is just incredible.
In
In fact
Yosemite is just incredible.
In fact,
In fact, over
Yosemite is just incredible.
In fact, over 55
In fact, over 55%
Yosemite is just incredible.
In fact, over 55% o
In fact, over 55% of
Yosemite is just incredible.
In fact, over 55% of active
In fact, over 55% of active Mac
users
users are
In fact, over 55% of active Mac
users are running
users are running our
In fact, over 55% of active Mac
users are running our latest
update,
update, and
users are running our latest
update, and this
update, and this is
users are running our latest
update, and this is just
unprecedent
unprecedented
update, and this is just
unprecedented in
unprecedented in the
update, and this is just
unprecedented in the h
unprecedented in the history
update, and this is just
unprecedented in the history of
our
our industry.
(Laughter)
In
In fact
(Laughter)
In fact,
In fact, Yosemite
(Laughter)
In fact, Yosemite has
In fact, Yosemite has the
(Laughter)
In fact, Yosemite has the f
fastest
fastest adoption
In fact, Yosemite has the f
fastest adoption rate
fastest adoption rate for
In fact, Yosemite has the f
fastest adoption rate for any
PC
PC operating
fastest adoption rate for any
PC operating system
PC operating system e
fastest adoption rate for any
PC operating system ever
PC operating system ever.
fastest adoption rate for any
PC operating system ever. So
thank
thank you
PC operating system ever. So
thank you.
(Applause)
So
So for
(Applause)
So for our
So for our next
(Applause)
So for our next big
So for our next big release
(Applause)
So for our next big release of
OS
OS X
So for our next big release of
OS X,
OS X, we
So for our next big release of
OS X, we knew
OS X, we knew we
So for our next big release of
OS X, we knew we wanted
OS X, we knew we wanted to
build
build on
OS X, we knew we wanted to
build on those
build on those strengths
OS X, we knew we wanted to
build on those strengths of
Yosemite
Yosemite w
build on those strengths of
Yosemite with
Yosemite with some
build on those strengths of
Yosemite with some really
Yosemite with some really great
refinements
refinements and
Yosemite with some really great
refinements and advances
refinements and advances.
Yosemite with some really great
refinements and advances. The
only
only r
refinements and advances. The
only real
only re
refinements and advances. The
only real
only real question,
refinements and advances. The
only real question, o
only real question, of
refinements and advances. The
only real question, of course,
was
was what
only real question, of course,
was what to
was what to call
only real question, of course,
was what to call it.
was what to call it. So
only real question, of course,
was what to call it. So we
was what to call it. So we h
only real question, of course,
was what to call it. So we had
to
to once
was what to call it. So we had
to once again
to once again turn
was what to call it. So we had
to once again turn to
to once again turn to o
was what to call it. So we had
to once again turn to our
to once again turn to our crack
Apple
Apple M
to once again turn to our crack
Apple Marketing
Apple Marketing Team
to once again turn to our crack
Apple Marketing Team.
Apple Marketing Team. Now
to once again turn to our crack
Apple Marketing Team. Now,
Apple Marketing Team. Now, in
typical
typical California
Apple Marketing Team. Now, in
typical California fashion,
they
they start
typical California fashion,
they started
they started with
typical California fashion,
they started with a
they started with a project
kickoff
kickoff meeting.
(Laughter)
And
And then
(Laughter)
And then headed
And then headed immediately
into
into a
And then headed immediately
into a team
into a team-building
And then headed immediately
into a team-building off-site.
(Laughter)
No
Now
(Laughter)
Now,
Now, of
(Laughter)
Now, of course
Now, of course t
(Laughter)
Now, of course they
Now, of course they are
(Laughter)
Now, of course they are in
their
their tradition
Now, of course they are in
their traditional
their traditional Apple
marketing
marketing free
their traditional Apple
marketing free-bottom
marketing free-bottom Fridays
attire
attire.
marketing free-bottom Fridays
attire. They
attire. They s
marketing free-bottom Fridays
attire. They say
attire. They say it's
marketing free-bottom Fridays
attire. They say it's all
attire. They say it's all part
of
of their
attire. They say it's all part
of their process.
of their process. I
attire. They say it's all part
of their process. I am
of their process. I am not
sure
sure I
of their process. I am not
sure I get
sure I get it
of their process. I am not
sure I get it.
sure I get it. Ultimately
of their process. I am not
sure I get it. Ultimately,
this
this did
sure I get it. Ultimately,
this didn't
this didn't yield
sure I get it. Ultimately,
this didn't yield any
this didn't yield any names
sure I get it. Ultimately,
this didn't yield any names,
this didn't yield any names, so
they
they c
this didn't yield any names, so
they called
they called i
this didn't yield any names, so
they called in
they called in a
this didn't yield any names, so
they called in a c
they called in a consultant
this didn't yield any names, so
they called in a consultant.
(Laughter)
He
He told
(Laughter)
He told them
He told them the
(Laughter)
He told them the answer
He told them the answer was
(Laughter)
He told them the answer was t
He told them the answer was to
be
be found
He told them the answer was to
be found within.
be found within. Not
He told them the answer was to
be found within. Not within
themselves,
themselves, but
be found within. Not within
themselves, but within
themselves, but within Yos
Yosemite.
Yosemite. And
themselves, but within Yos
Yosemite. And so
Yosemite. And so the
themselves, but within Yos
Yosemite. And so the new
Yosemite. And so the new name
for
for O
Yosemite. And so the new name
for OS
for OS X
Yosemite. And so the new name
for OS X is
for OS X is OS
Yosemite. And so the new name
for OS X is OS X
for OS X is OS X E
Yosemite. And so the new name
for OS X is OS X El
for OS X is OS X El Capitan
Yosemite. And so the new name
for OS X is OS X El Capitan.
(Applause)
For
For El
(Applause)
For El Capitan
For El Capitan,
(Applause)
For El Capitan, we
For El Capitan, we focused
(Applause)
For El Capitan, we focused i
For El Capitan, we focused in
two
two major
For El Capitan, we focused in
two major areas
two major areas --
For El Capitan, we focused in
two major areas -- experience
and
and performance
two major areas -- experience
and performance.
and performance. For
experience,
experience, w
and performance. For
experience, we've
experience, we've m
and performance. For
experience, we've made
Spotlight
Spotlight m
experience, we've made
Spotlight more
Spotlight more expressive
experience, we've made
Spotlight more expressive,
Spotlight more expressive, more
powerful
powerful,
Spotlight more expressive, more
powerful, and
powerful, and more
knowledgeable
knowledgeable than
powerful, and more
knowledgeable than ever
knowledgeable than ever.
powerful, and more
knowledgeable than ever. We've
made
made big
knowledgeable than ever. We've
made big enhancements
made big enhancements to
knowledgeable than ever. We've
made big enhancements to the
apps
apps you
made big enhancements to the
apps you use
apps you use most
made big enhancements to the
apps you use most,
apps you use most, and
made big enhancements to the
apps you use most, and we
apps you use most, and we made
some
some real
apps you use most, and we made
some real great
some real great advance
apps you use most, and we made
some real great advancements
some real great advancements in
the
the area
some real great advancements in
the area of
the area of how
some real great advancements in
the area of how you
the area of how you m
some real great advancements in
the area of how you manage
Windows
Windows on
the area of how you manage
Windows on the
Windows on the s
the area of how you manage
Windows on the system.
But
But rather
Windows on the system.
But rather than
But rather than just
Windows on the system.
But rather than just talk
about
about it,
But rather than just talk
about it, I'd
about it, I'd like
But rather than just talk
about it, I'd like to
about it, I'd like to show
But rather than just talk
about it, I'd like to show it
to
to you
about it, I'd like to show it
to you,
to you, so
about it, I'd like to show it
to you, so let's
to you, so let's start
about it, I'd like to show it
to you, so let's start with
to you, so let's start with a
demo
demo right
to you, so let's start with a
demo right now.
(Applause)
Now
Now,
(Applause)
Now, your
Now, your first
(Applause)
Now, your first task,
Now, your first task, of
course
course,
Now, your first task, of
course, in
course, in a
Now, your first task, of
course, in a demonstration
course, in a demonstration or
whenever
whenever you
course, in a demonstration or
whenever you wake
whenever you wake your
course, in a demonstration or
whenever you wake your Mac,
whenever you wake your Mac, is
find
finding
whenever you wake your Mac, is
finding the
finding the cursor
whenever you wake your Mac, is
finding the cursor,
finding the cursor, and
whenever you wake your Mac, is
finding the cursor, and El
Capitan
Capitan makes
finding the cursor, and El
Capitan makes this
Capitan makes this easier
finding the cursor, and El
Capitan makes this easier than
ever.
ever. I
Capitan makes this easier than
ever. I just
ever. I just do
Capitan makes this easier than
ever. I just do that
ever. I just do that little
shake
shake we
ever. I just do that little
shake we all
shake we all normally
ever. I just do that little
shake we all normally do,
shake we all normally do, and
there
there it
shake we all normally do, and
there it is.
there it is. It
shake we all normally do, and
there it is. It comes
there it is. It comes right
out
out to
there it is. It comes right
out to greet
out to greet you.
there it is. It comes right
out to greet you. It's
out to greet you. It's really
hand
handy.
(Applause)
No
Now
(Applause)
Now,
Now, we
(Applause)
Now, we brought
Now, we brought other
(Applause)
Now, we brought other great
gestures
gestures to
Now, we brought other great
gestures to the
gestures to the system.
Now, we brought other great
gestures to the system. I
gestures to the system. I am
just
just g
gestures to the system. I am
just going
just going to
gestures to the system. I am
just going to go
just going to go here
gestures to the system. I am
just going to go here in
just going to go here in Mail.
I
I have
just going to go here in Mail.
I have a
I have a message
just going to go here in Mail.
I have a message here
I have a message here from
just going to go here in Mail.
I have a message here from Eddy
I have a message here from E
Eddy.
Eddy. Looks
I have a message here from E
Eddy. Looks like
Eddy. Looks like --
I have a message here from E
Eddy. Looks like -- well
Eddy. Looks like -- well,
I have a message here from E
Eddy. Looks like -- well, now
--
-- (Laughter)
Eddy. Looks like -- well, now
-- (Laughter) --
-- (Laughter) -- that's
Eddy. Looks like -- well, now
-- (Laughter) -- that's a
-- (Laughter) -- that's a keep
Eddy. Looks like -- well, now
-- (Laughter) -- that's a k
keeper.
keeper. So
-- (Laughter) -- that's a k
keeper. So I
keeper. So I can
-- (Laughter) -- that's a k
keeper. So I can actual
keeper. So I can actually
-- (Laughter) -- that's a k
keeper. So I can actually mark
it
it unread
keeper. So I can actually mark
it unread to
it unread to keep
keeper. So I can actually mark
it unread to keep it
it unread to keep it just
keeper. So I can actually mark
it unread to keep it just by
swiping
swiping two
it unread to keep it just by
swiping two fingers
swiping two fingers acros
it unread to keep it just by
swiping two fingers across
swiping two fingers across the
Trackpad
Trackpad just
swiping two fingers across the
Trackpad just like
Trackpad just like that
swiping two fingers across the
Trackpad just like that.
Trackpad just like that. And
this
this one
Trackpad just like that. And
this one I'd
this one I'd kind
Trackpad just like that. And
this one I'd kind of
this one I'd kind of like
Trackpad just like that. And
this one I'd kind of like to
delete,
delete, so
this one I'd kind of like to
delete, so I
delete, so I am
this one I'd kind of like to
delete, so I am just
delete, so I am just going
this one I'd kind of like to
delete, so I am just going to
swipe
swipe it
delete, so I am just going to
swipe it away
swipe it away just
delete, so I am just going to
swipe it away just like
swipe it away just like that.
So
So some
swipe it away just like that.
So some real
So some real nice
swipe it away just like that.
So some real nice little
gestures.
Let's
Let's m
gestures.
Let's move
Let's move on
gestures.
Let's move on now
Let's move on now to
gestures.
Let's move on now to Safari
Let's move on now to Safari.
Now,
Now, in
Let's move on now to Safari.
Now, in Safari
Now, in Safari,
Let's move on now to Safari.
Now, in Safari, I
Now, in Safari, I have
Let's move on now to Safari.
Now, in Safari, I have some
sites
sites that
Now, in Safari, I have some
sites that I
sites that I like
Now, in Safari, I have some
sites that I like to
sites that I like to keep
around
around because
sites that I like to keep
around because I
around because I refer
sites that I like to keep
around because I refer t
around because I refer to
sites that I like to keep
around because I refer to them
on
on and
around because I refer to them
on and off
on and off throughout
around because I refer to them
on and off throughout the
on and off throughout the day,
and
and now
on and off throughout the day,
and now in
and now in Safari
on and off throughout the day,
and now in Safari,
and now in Safari, I
on and off throughout the day,
and now in Safari, I can
and now in Safari, I can pin
those
those sites
and now in Safari, I can pin
those sites just
those sites just like
and now in Safari, I can pin
those sites just like this.
those sites just like this. So
there's
there's --
those sites just like this. So
there's -- I
there's -- I am
those sites just like this. So
there's -- I am going
there's -- I am going t
those sites just like this. So
there's -- I am going to
there's -- I am going to pin
those sites just like this. So
there's -- I am going to pin my
twitter
twitter s
there's -- I am going to pin my
twitter site
twitter site h
there's -- I am going to pin my
twitter site here.
twitter site here. And
there's -- I am going to pin my
twitter site here. And of
course
course I
twitter site here. And of
course I have
course I have been
twitter site here. And of
course I have been following
the
the Warriors
course I have been following
the Warriors.
the Warriors. G
course I have been following
the Warriors. Go
the Warriors. Go Warriors
course I have been following
the Warriors. Go Warriors,
the Warriors. Go Warriors, w
course I have been following
the Warriors. Go Warriors, we
are
are going
the Warriors. Go Warriors, we
are going to
are going to g
the Warriors. Go Warriors, we
are going to get
are going to get it
the Warriors. Go Warriors, we
are going to get it done
are going to get it done.
(Applause)
Ju
Just
(Applause)
Just like
Just like that
(Applause)
Just like that.
Just like that. Now,
(Applause)
Just like that. Now, Pinned
Sites
Sites have
Just like that. Now, Pinned
Sites have a
Sites have a lot
Just like that. Now, Pinned
Sites have a lot of
Sites have a lot of special
properties
properties.
Sites have a lot of special
properties. For
properties. For one
Sites have a lot of special
properties. For one,
properties. For one, if
Sites have a lot of special
properties. For one, if I
close
close this
properties. For one, if I
close this window
close this window and
properties. For one, if I
close this window and reopen
it,
it, you
close this window and reopen
it, you see
it, you see that
close this window and reopen
it, you see that my
it, you see that my Pinned
Sites
Sites are
it, you see that my Pinned
Sites are all
Sites are all right
it, you see that my Pinned
Sites are all right there,
Sites are all right there, and
they
they load
Sites are all right there, and
they load instant
they load instantly
Sites are all right there, and
they load instantly.
they load instantly. Now
Sites are all right there, and
they load instantly. Now,
Pinned
Pinned Sites
they load instantly. Now,
Pinned Sites also
Pinned Sites also b
they load instantly. Now,
Pinned Sites also behave
differently
differently when
Pinned Sites also behave
differently when I
differently when I follow
links,
links, so
differently when I follow
links, so I
links, so I am
differently when I follow
links, so I am j
links, so I am just
differently when I follow
links, so I am just going
links, so I am just going to
click
click on
links, so I am just going to
click on one
click on one here,
links, so I am just going to
click on one here, and
click on one here, and you
notice
notice it
click on one here, and you
notice it opens
notice it opens in
click on one here, and you
notice it opens in a
notice it opens in a n
click on one here, and you
notice it opens in a new
notice it opens in a new tab
click on one here, and you
notice it opens in a new tab,
but
but my
notice it opens in a new tab,
but my pinned
but my pinned site
notice it opens in a new tab,
but my pinned site remains.
Now
Now I
but my pinned site remains.
Now I am
Now I am g
but my pinned site remains.
Now I am going
Now I am going to
but my pinned site remains.
Now I am going to open
Now I am going to open up
but my pinned site remains.
Now I am going to open up a
couple
couple more
Now I am going to open up a
couple more links
couple more links.
Now I am going to open up a
couple more links. This
couple more links. This one,
Now I am going to open up a
let's
couple more links. This one,
let's see
let's see,
couple more links. This one,
let's see, this
let's see, this one
couple more links. This one,
let's see, this one.
let's see, this one. I
couple more links. This one,
let's see, this one. I will
take
take a
let's see, this one. I will
take a quick
take a quick look.
let's see, this one. I will
take a quick look. This
take a quick look. This one
looks
looks like
take a quick look. This one
looks like a
looks like a presentation
take a quick look. This one
looks like a presentation video
looks like a presentation vi
video.
video. This
looks like a presentation vi
video. This one
video. This one is
looks like a presentation vi
video. This one is about
video. This one is about the
Giants
Giants.
video. This one is about the
Giants. Have
Giants. Have you
video. This one is about the
Giants. Have you ever
Giants. Have you ever had
video. This one is about the
Giants. Have you ever had this
happen
happen to
Giants. Have you ever had this
happen to you?
happen to you? You
Giants. Have you ever had this
happen to you? You are
happen to you? You are like
where
where is
happen to you? You are like
where is this
where is this a
happen to you? You are like
where is this audio
where is this audio coming
from?
from? N
where is this audio coming
from? Now
from? Now with
where is this audio coming
from? Now with just
from? Now with just a
where is this audio coming
from? Now with just a tap
from? Now with just a tap,
where is this audio coming
from? Now with just a tap, you
can
can mute
from? Now with just a tap, you
can mute it
can mute it or
from? Now with just a tap, you
can mute it or f
can mute it or find
from? Now with just a tap, you
can mute it or find out
can mute it or find out where
it
it came
can mute it or find out where
it came from
it came from and
can mute it or find out where
it came from and shut
it came from and shut i
can mute it or find out where
it came from and shut it
it came from and shut it down
just
just like
it came from and shut it down
just like that.
(Applause)
So
So I
(Applause)
So I am
So I am interested
(Applause)
So I am interested in
So I am interested in seeing
this
this Giants
So I am interested in seeing
this Giants game
this Giants game,
So I am interested in seeing
this Giants game, and
this Giants game, and now
Spotlight
Spotlight can
this Giants game, and now
Spotlight can actually
Spotlight can actually h
this Giants game, and now
Spotlight can actually help
Spotlight can actually help me
out
out there
Spotlight can actually help me
out there.
out there. So
Spotlight can actually help me
out there. So I
out there. So I am
Spotlight can actually help me
out there. So I am j
out there. So I am just
Spotlight can actually help me
out there. So I am just going
to
to do
out there. So I am just going
to do a
to do a search
out there. So I am just going
to do a search for
to do a search for the
out there. So I am just going
to do a search for the S
to do a search for the SF
Giants
Giants,
to do a search for the SF
Giants, and
Giants, and we
to do a search for the SF
Giants, and we s
Giants, and we see
to do a search for the SF
Giants, and we see right
Giants, and we see right now
to do a search for the SF
Giants, and we see right now I
get
get current
Giants, and we see right now I
get current g
get current game
Giants, and we see right now I
get current game scores
get current game scores,
upcoming
upcoming games
get current game scores,
upcoming games.
upcoming games. Looks
get current game scores,
upcoming games. Looks like
upcoming games. Looks like the
game
game I
upcoming games. Looks like the
game I want
game I want to
upcoming games. Looks like the
game I want to go
game I want to go to
upcoming games. Looks like the
game I want to go to is
game I want to go to is on
Friday
Friday,
game I want to go to is on
Friday, so
Friday, so I
game I want to go to is on
Friday, so I can
Friday, so I can just
game I want to go to is on
Friday, so I can just search
for
for weather
Friday, so I can just search
for weather on
for weather on Friday.
Friday, so I can just search
for weather on Friday. See
for weather on Friday. See we
get
get the
for weather on Friday. See we
get the weather.
get the weather. We
for weather on Friday. See we
get the weather. We can
get the weather. We can e
for weather on Friday. See we
get the weather. We can even
resize
resize the
get the weather. We can even
resize the Spotlight
resize the Spotlight p
get the weather. We can even
resize the Spotlight panel
resize the Spotlight panel and
move
move i
resize the Spotlight panel and
move it
move it around.
resize the Spotlight panel and
move it around. I
move it around. I mean,
resize the Spotlight panel and
move it around. I mean, th
there's
there's innovation;
move it around. I mean, th
there's innovation; huh?
(Laughter)
But
But I
(Laughter)
But I can
But I can also
(Laughter)
But I can also express
But I can also express myself
in
in my
But I can also express myself
in my own
in my own words
But I can also express myself
in my own words in
in my own words in Spotlight
Searches
Searches now
in my own words in Spotlight
Searches now,
Searches now, so
in my own words in Spotlight
Searches now, so I
Searches now, so I can
in my own words in Spotlight
Searches now, so I can do
things
things l
Searches now, so I can do
things like
things like slides
Searches now, so I can do
things like slides from
things like slides from Brian
Searches now, so I can do
things like slides from Brian,
and
and you
things like slides from Brian,
and you see
and you see I
things like slides from Brian,
and you see I find
and you see I find those
things like slides from Brian,
and you see I find those there.
But
But how
and you see I find those there.
But how about
But how about slides
and you see I find those there.
But how about slides from
Brian
Brian about
But how about slides from
Brian about El
Brian about El Capitan
But how about slides from
Brian about El Capitan?
Brian about El Capitan? You
see,
see, I
Brian about El Capitan? You
see, I f
see, I find
Brian about El Capitan? You
see, I find exact
see, I find exactly
Brian about El Capitan? You
see, I find exactly what
see, I find exactly what I
Brian about El Capitan? You
see, I find exactly what I am
looking
looking for
see, I find exactly what I am
looking for in
looking for in my
see, I find exactly what I am
looking for in my own
looking for in my own words.
Now
Now,
looking for in my own words.
Now, this
Now, this works
looking for in my own words.
Now, this works great
Now, this works great in
looking for in my own words.
Now, this works great in other
apps
apps as
Now, this works great in other
apps as well.
apps as well. Let's
Now, this works great in other
apps as well. Let's try
apps as well. Let's try it
Now, this works great in other
apps as well. Let's try it out
in
in Mail.
apps as well. Let's try it out
in Mail. So
in Mail. So I've
apps as well. Let's try it out
in Mail. So I've b
in Mail. So I've been
apps as well. Let's try it out
in Mail. So I've been really
busy,
busy, of
in Mail. So I've been really
busy, of course,
busy, of course, the
in Mail. So I've been really
busy, of course, the last
couple
couple of
busy, of course, the last
couple of days,
couple of days, so
busy, of course, the last
couple of days, so I
couple of days, so I have
busy, of course, the last
couple of days, so I have been
getting
getting a
couple of days, so I have been
getting a little
getting a little behind
couple of days, so I have been
getting a little behind on
getting a little behind on my
Mail.
Mail. I
getting a little behind on my
Mail. I want
Mail. I want to
getting a little behind on my
Mail. I want to see
Mail. I want to see the
messages
messages t
Mail. I want to see the
messages that
messages that I've
Mail. I want to see the
messages that I've received
from
from Phil
messages that I've received
from Phil but
from Phil but that
messages that I've received
from Phil but that I
from Phil but that I h
messages that I've received
from Phil but that I haven't
respond
responded
from Phil but that I haven't
responded to
responded to yet
from Phil but that I haven't
responded to yet.
responded to yet. So
from Phil but that I haven't
responded to yet. So I
responded to yet. So I am
from Phil but that I haven't
responded to yet. So I am just
going
going to
responded to yet. So I am just
going to say
going to say "mail
responded to yet. So I am just
going to say "mail I
going to say "mail I ignored
from
from Phil."
(L
(Laughter)
There
There are
(Laughter)
There are a
There are a few,
(Laughter)
There are a few, b
There are a few, but
(Laughter)
There are a few, but I
There are a few, but I will
(Laughter)
There are a few, but I will be
getting
getting back
There are a few, but I will be
getting back t
getting back to
There are a few, but I will be
getting back to him
getting back to him right
There are a few, but I will be
getting back to him right after
the
the show.
(Laughter)
So
So n
(Laughter)
So next,
So next, of
(Laughter)
So next, of c
So next, of course,
(Laughter)
So next, of course, it's
So next, of course, it's great
in
in the
So next, of course, it's great
in the F
in the Finder
So next, of course, it's great
in the Finder a
in the Finder as
So next, of course, it's great
in the Finder as well,
in the Finder as well, so
So next, of course, it's great
in the Finder as well, so if
in the Finder as well, so if I
want
wanted
in the Finder as well, so if I
wanted to
wanted to look
in the Finder as well, so if I
wanted to look at
wanted to look at documents
that
that I
wanted to look at documents
that I was
that I was working
wanted to look at documents
that I was working on
that I was working on last
wanted to look at documents
that I was working on last year
at
at this
that I was working on last year
at this time
at this time,
that I was working on last year
at this time, I
at this time, I might
that I was working on last year
at this time, I might s
at this time, I might say
something
something like
at this time, I might say
something like "documents
something like "documents I
work
worked
something like "documents I
worked on
worked on l
something like "documents I
worked on last
worked on last June."
something like "documents I
worked on last June." And
worked on last June." And I
find
find e
worked on last June." And I
find exactly
find exactly what
worked on last June." And I
find exactly what I
find exactly what I am
worked on last June." And I
find exactly what I am looking
for.
for. So
find exactly what I am looking
for. So this
for. So this is
find exactly what I am looking
for. So this is rea
for. So this is really
find exactly what I am looking
for. So this is really a
for. So this is really a great
way
way to
for. So this is really a great
way to search.
Ne
Next
way to search.
Next I
Next I want
way to search.
Next I want to
Next I want to turn
way to search.
Next I want to turn to
Next I want to turn to window
management
management,
Next I want to turn to window
management, so
management, so I
Next I want to turn to window
management, so I am
management, so I am j
Next I want to turn to window
management, so I am just
management, so I am just going
to
to run
management, so I am just going
to run a
to run a script
management, so I am just going
to run a script here
to run a script here that's
going
going to
to run a script here that's
going to open
going to open up
to run a script here that's
going to open up a
going to open up a whole
to run a script here that's
going to open up a whole bunch
of
of windows
going to open up a whole bunch
of windows to
of windows to s
going to open up a whole bunch
of windows to simulate
of windows to simulate k
going to open up a whole bunch
of windows to simulate kind
of windows to simulate kind of
what
what m
of windows to simulate kind of
what my
what my desktop
of windows to simulate kind of
what my desktop looks
what my desktop looks like
after
after a
what my desktop looks like
after a day
after a day working
what my desktop looks like
after a day working on
after a day working on OS
what my desktop looks like
after a day working on OS X
after a day working on OS
what my desktop looks like
after a day working on OS X
because
because it's
after a day working on OS X
because it's a
because it's a pouvrful
after a day working on OS X
because it's a pouvrf
because it's a po f
after a day working on OS X
because it's a powerful
because it's a powerful system
and
and we
because it's a powerful system
and we t
and we tend
because it's a powerful system
and we tend to
and we tend to have
because it's a powerful system
and we tend to have a
and we tend to have a lot
because it's a powerful system
and we tend to have a lot of
things
things open.
and we tend to have a lot of
OS
things open.
OS X
OS X has
things open.
OS X has great
OS X has great ways
things open.
OS X has great ways t
OS X has great ways to
things open.
OS X has great ways to manage
Windows
Windows,
OS X has great ways to manage
Windows, and
Windows, and one
OS X has great ways to manage
Windows, and one o
Windows, and one of
OS X has great ways to manage
Windows, and one of those
Windows, and one of those is
Mission
Mission Control.
Windows, and one of those is
Mission Control. In
Mission Control. In El
Windows, and one of those is
Mission Control. In El Capitan
Mission Control. In El Cap
Capitan,
Capitan, we
Mission Control. In El Cap
Capitan, we made
Capitan, we made Mission
Control
Control s
Capitan, we made Mission
Control smooth
Control smoother
Capitan, we made Mission
Control smoother and
Control smoother and faster
than
than ever.
Control smoother and faster
than ever. I
than ever. I am
Control smoother and faster
than ever. I am going
than ever. I am going to
Control smoother and faster
than ever. I am going to take
a
a finger
than ever. I am going to take
a finger and
a finger and swipe
than ever. I am going to take
a finger and swipe on
a finger and swipe on the
than ever. I am going to take
a finger and swipe on the pad.
We
We get
a finger and swipe on the pad.
We get this
We get this gorgeous
a finger and swipe on the pad.
We get this gorgeous view
We get this gorgeous view of
Mission
Mission Control
We get this gorgeous view of
Mission Control.
Mission Control. Let's
We get this gorgeous view of
Mission Control. Let's d
Mission Control. Let's do
We get this gorgeous view of
Mission Control. Let's do that
again
again a
Mission Control. Let's do that
again and
again and bring
Mission Control. Let's do that
again and bring up
again and bring up Mail.
Mission Control. Let's do that
again and bring up Mail. Just
like
like that.
again and bring up Mail. Just
like that. Works
like that. Works really
again and bring up Mail. Just
like that. Works really great.
Of
Of course
like that. Works really great.
Of course,
Of course, OS
like that. Works really great.
Of course, OS X
Of course, OS X p
like that. Works really great.
Of course, OS X provides
Of course, OS X provides great
tools
tools also
Of course, OS X provides great
tools also to
tools also to organize
Of course, OS X provides great
tools also to organize y
tools also to organize your
Windows
Windows,
tools also to organize your
Windows, and
Windows, and one
tools also to organize your
Windows, and one of
Windows, and one of those
tools also to organize your
Windows, and one of those is
Full
Full S
Windows, and one of those is
Full Screen.
Full Screen. I
Windows, and one of those is
Full Screen. I am
Full Screen. I am going
Windows, and one of those is
Full Screen. I am going to
take
take this
Full Screen. I am going to
take this window
take this window here
Full Screen. I am going to
take this window here full
screen,
screen, and
take this window here full
screen, and I
screen, and I am
take this window here full
screen, and I am going
screen, and I am going to
take this window here full
screen, and I am going to r
screen, and I am going to reply
take this window here full
screen, and I am going to re
reply.
reply. Looks
screen, and I am going to re
reply. Looks like
reply. Looks like there's
screen, and I am going to re
reply. Looks like there's a
message
message here
reply. Looks like there's a
message here from
message here from E
reply. Looks like there's a
message here from Eddy.
message here from Eddy. He
says
says sorry
message here from Eddy. He
says sorry a
says sorry about
message here from Eddy. He
says sorry about bailing
says sorry about bailing o
message here from Eddy. He
says sorry about bailing on
says sorry about bailing on the
team
team d
says sorry about bailing on the
team dinner
team dinner last
says sorry about bailing on the
team dinner last night
team dinner last night.
says sorry about bailing on the
team dinner last night. H
team dinner last night. He
says sorry about bailing on the
team dinner last night. He was
apparent
apparently
team dinner last night. He was
apparently prepping
apparently prepping for
team dinner last night. He was
apparently prepping for t
apparently prepping for the
Keynote.
Keynote. So
apparently prepping for the
Keynote. So that's
understandable
understandable.
Keynote. So that's
understandable. But
understandable. But it
Keynote. So that's
understandable. But it looks
like,
like, actual
understandable. But it looks
like, actually,
like, actually, I
understandable. But it looks
like, actually, I just
like, actually, I just got
understandable. But it looks
like, actually, I just got a
new
new mail
like, actually, I just got a
new mail from
new mail from Jeff
like, actually, I just got a
new mail from Jeff here,
new mail from Jeff here, a
like, actually, I just got a
new mail from Jeff here, and
now
now I
new mail from Jeff here, and
now I can
now I can just
new mail from Jeff here, and
now I can just click
now I can just click a
new mail from Jeff here, and
now I can just click away,
now I can just click away, and
it
it hides
now I can just click away, and
it hides,
it hides, and
now I can just click away, and
it hides, and t
it hides, and then
now I can just click away, and
it hides, and then --
it hides, and then -- oh
now I can just click away, and
it hides, and then -- oh,
it hides, and then -- oh, hold
on
on.
it hides, and then -- oh, hold
on. Bust
on. Busted,
it hides, and then -- oh, hold
on. Busted, Eddy.
on. Busted, Eddy. So
it hides, and then -- oh, hold
on. Busted, Eddy. So I
on. Busted, Eddy. So I think
I'll
I'll j
on. Busted, Eddy. So I think
I'll just
I'll just drag
on. Busted, Eddy. So I think
I'll just drag t
I'll just drag this,
on. Busted, Eddy. So I think
I'll just drag this, actual
I'll just drag this, actually,
right
right i
I'll just drag this, actually,
right into
right into my
I'll just drag this, actually,
right into my Compose
right into my Compose w
I'll just drag this, actually,
right into my Compose window,
it
it hops
right into my Compose window,
it hops up
it hops up automatically,
right into my Compose window,
it hops up automatically, and
it hops up automatically, and I
can
can do
it hops up automatically, and I
can do it
can do it just
it hops up automatically, and I
can do it just like
can do it just like that.
it hops up automatically, and I
can do it just like that. It's
really
really great
can do it just like that. It's
really great.
really great. And
can do it just like that. It's
really great. And I
really great. And I can
can do it just like that. It's
really great. And I can even
open
open up
really great. And I can even
open up tabs
open up tabs in
really great. And I can even
open up tabs in Compose
open up tabs in Compose a
really great. And I can even
open up tabs in Compose as
well.
well. It's
open up tabs in Compose as
well. It's really
well. It's really han
open up tabs in Compose as
well. It's really hand
well. It's really handy.
open up tabs in Compose as
well. It's really handy. So
this
this is
well. It's really handy. So
this is a
this is a great
well. It's really handy. So
this is a great w
this is a great way
well. It's really handy. So
this is a great way now
this is a great way now t
well. It's really handy. So
this is a great way now to
this is a great way now to work
in
in full
this is a great way now to work
in full screen
in full screen in
this is a great way now to work
in full screen in Mail
in full screen in Mail.
(Applause)
Thank
Thank you
(Applause)
Thank you.
Now,
Now, we've
Thank you.
Now, we've done
Now, we've done something
totally
totally new
Now, we've done something
totally new to
totally new to El
Now, we've done something
totally new to El Capitan
totally new to El Capitan,
Now, we've done something
totally new to El Capitan, and
it's
it's the
totally new to El Capitan, and
it's the ability
it's the ability to
totally new to El Capitan, and
it's the ability to work
it's the ability to work really
easily
easily on
it's the ability to work really
easily on two
easily on two windows
it's the ability to work really
easily on two windows side
easily on two windows side by
side
side.
easily on two windows side by
side. So
side. So I
easily on two windows side by
side. So I am
side. So I am just
easily on two windows side by
side. So I am just going
side. So I am just going to
click
click and
side. So I am just going to
click and hold
click and hold here
side. So I am just going to
click and hold here on
click and hold here on the
green
green but
click and hold here on the
green button
green button.
click and hold here on the
green button. And
green button. And you
click and hold here on the
green button. And you see
green button. And you see it's
prompting
prompting me
green button. And you see it's
prompting me to
prompting me to pick
green button. And you see it's
prompting me to pick a
prompting me to pick a side.
green button. And you see it's
prompting me to pick a side. I
will
will just
prompting me to pick a side. I
will just d
will just drop
prompting me to pick a side. I
will just drop it
will just drop it in
prompting me to pick a side. I
will just drop it in.
will just drop it in. And
prompting me to pick a side. I
will just drop it in. And you
notice
notice I
will just drop it in. And you
notice I g
notice I get
will just drop it in. And you
notice I get an
notice I get an e
will just drop it in. And you
notice I get an expose
notice I get an expose of
will just drop it in. And you
notice I get an expose of all
my
my other
notice I get an expose of all
my other windows.
my other windows. Let
notice I get an expose of all
my other windows. Let me
my other windows. Let me pick
the
the new
my other windows. Let me pick
the new News
the new News app,
my other windows. Let me pick
the new News app, just
the new News app, just like
that.
(Applause)
Of
Of course,
(Applause)
Of course, I
Of course, I can
(Applause)
Of course, I can r
Of course, I can resize
(Applause)
Of course, I can resize this
window
window to
Of course, I can resize this
window to style
window to style it
Of course, I can resize this
window to style it just
window to style it just the
Of course, I can resize this
window to style it just the way
I
I want.
window to style it just the way
I want. H
I want. How
window to style it just the way
I want. How about
I want. How about that
window to style it just the way
I want. How about that blur?
Again,
Again, innovation.
(Laughter)
So
So g
(Laughter)
So great
So great way
(Laughter)
So great way to
So great way to w
(Laughter)
So great way to work.
So great way to work. Here
(Laughter)
So great way to work. Here I
can
can d
So great way to work. Here I
can drag
can drag links,
So great way to work. Here I
can drag links, f
can drag links, for
So great way to work. Here I
can drag links, for instance,
from
from Safari
can drag links, for instance,
from Safari right
from Safari right in
can drag links, for instance,
from Safari right in here.
from Safari right in here. You
notice
notice in
from Safari right in here. You
notice in the
notice in the n
from Safari right in here. You
notice in the new
notice in the new Notes
from Safari right in here. You
notice in the new Notes app,
notice in the new Notes app, I
get
get a
notice in the new Notes app, I
get a b
get a beautiful
notice in the new Notes app, I
get a beautiful graphical
get a beautiful graphical link
that
that gives
get a beautiful graphical link
that gives me
that gives me a
get a beautiful graphical link
that gives me a nice
that gives me a nice thumbnail
that
that helps
that gives me a nice thumbnail
that helps m
that helps me
that gives me a nice thumbnail
that helps me identify
that helps me identify w
that gives me a nice thumbnail
that helps me identify what
that helps me identify what I
dragged
dragged in
that helps me identify what I
dragged in there
dragged in there.
that helps me identify what I
dragged in there. I
dragged in there. I am
that helps me identify what I
dragged in there. I am going
to
to drag
dragged in there. I am going
to drag in
to drag in some
dragged in there. I am going
to drag in some yurts.
to drag in some yurts. I
dragged in there. I am going
to drag in some yurts. I think
yurts,
yurts, first
to drag in some yurts. I think
yurts, first time
yurts, first time mention
to drag in some yurts. I think
yurts, first time mentioned
yurts, first time mentioned on
the
the WWDC
yurts, first time mentioned on
the WWDC Keynote
the WWDC Keynote stage
yurts, first time mentioned on
the WWDC Keynote stage.
the WWDC Keynote stage. There
you
you g
the WWDC Keynote stage. There
you go.
you go. Got
the WWDC Keynote stage. There
you go. Got some
you go. Got some y
the WWDC Keynote stage. There
you go. Got some yurts
you go. Got some yu
the WWDC Keynote stage. There
you go. Got some yurts
you go. Got some yurts there
the WWDC Keynote stage. There
you go. Got some yurts there.
Great
Great way
you go. Got some yurts there.
Great way to
Great way to work
you go. Got some yurts there.
Great way to work s
Great way to work split
you go. Got some yurts there.
Great way to work split screen
Great way to work split screen.
We've
We've also
We've also provide
We've also provided
We've also provided a
We've also provided a really
easy
easy way
We've also provided a really
easy way to
easy way to move
We've also provided a really
easy way to move w
easy way to move window
We've also provided a really
easy way to move windows
easy way to move windows in
We've also provided a really
easy way to move windows in a
their
their own
easy way to move windows in a
their own desktops
their own desktops.
easy way to move windows in a
their own desktops. I
their own desktops. I am
easy way to move windows in a
their own desktops. I am going
to
to take
their own desktops. I am going
to take that
to take that there
their own desktops. I am going
to take that there,
to take that there, drop
their own desktops. I am going
to take that there, drop it
to take that there, drop it up
past
past the
to take that there, drop it up
past the top
past the top of
to take that there, drop it up
past the top of the
past the top of the screen,
to take that there, drop it up
past the top of the screen, and
drop
drop it
past the top of the screen, and
drop it there
drop it there just
past the top of the screen, and
drop it there just like
drop it there just like that.
So
So easy.
I
I can
So easy.
I can also
I can also do
So easy.
I can also do this
I can also do this to
So easy.
I can also do this to look
I can also do this to look at
a
a window
I can also do this to look at
a window full
a window full s
I can also do this to look at
a window full screen.
a window full screen. Take
photos
photos,
a window full screen. Take
photos, drop
photos, drop it
a window full screen. Take
photos, drop it h
photos, drop it here
a window full screen. Take
photos, drop it here,
photos, drop it here, I
a window full screen. Take
photos, drop it here, I put
photos, drop it here, I put it
full
full screen
photos, drop it here, I put it
full screen.
Check
Check this
full screen.
Check this out.
Check this out. I
full screen.
Check this out. I am
Check this out. I am going
full screen.
Check this out. I am going to
take
take messages,
Check this out. I am going to
take messages, drop
take messages, drop i
Check this out. I am going to
take messages, drop it
take messages, drop it on
Check this out. I am going to
take messages, drop it on ph
photos,
photos, and
take messages, drop it on ph
photos, and create
photos, and create a
take messages, drop it on ph
photos, and create a split
photos, and create a split view
just
just like
photos, and create a split view
just like that.
just like that. Totally
awesome
awesome.
(Applause)
And
And t
(Applause)
And that
And that is
(Applause)
And that is a
And that is a quick
(Applause)
And that is a quick look
And that is a quick look at
(Applause)
And that is a quick look at am
so
so improvements
And that is a quick look at am
so improvements to
so improvements to the
experience
experience in
so improvements to the
experience in El
experience in El Capitan
so improvements to the
experience in El Capitan.
(Applause)
So
So we
(Applause)
So we saw
So we saw in
(Applause)
So we saw in El
So we saw in El Capitan
(Applause)
So we saw in El Capitan a
powerful
powerful t
So we saw in El Capitan a
powerful tool
powerful tool i
So we saw in El Capitan a
powerful tool in
powerful tool in Spotlight
So we saw in El Capitan a
powerful tool in Spotlight that
lets
lets you
powerful tool in Spotlight that
lets you compose
lets you compose your
powerful tool in Spotlight that
lets you compose your searches
in
in your
lets you compose your searches
in your own
in your own words.
lets you compose your searches
in your own words. It
in your own words. It knows
more
more than
in your own words. It knows
more than ever,
more than ever, can
in your own words. It knows
more than ever, can look
more than ever, can look up
weather
weather,
more than ever, can look up
weather, stocks
weather, stocks,
more than ever, can look up
weather, stocks, game
weather, stocks, game scores.
We
We s
weather, stocks, game scores.
We saw
We saw gestures
weather, stocks, game scores.
We saw gestures,
We saw gestures, for
weather, stocks, game scores.
We saw gestures, for instance,
just
just swiping
We saw gestures, for instance,
just swiping to
just swiping to delete
We saw gestures, for instance,
just swiping to delete in
just swiping to delete in Mail
We saw gestures, for instance,
just swiping to delete in Mail.
And,
And, of
just swiping to delete in Mail.
And, of course,
And, of course, p
just swiping to delete in Mail.
And, of course, pin
And, of course, pin sites
just swiping to delete in Mail.
And, of course, pin sites in
Safari
Safari a
And, of course, pin sites in
Safari and
Safari and the
And, of course, pin sites in
Safari and the ability
Safari and the ability to
easily
easily m
Safari and the ability to
easily mute
easily mute tabs.
Safari and the ability to
easily mute tabs. A
easily mute tabs. A great
Safari and the ability to
easily mute tabs. A great n
easily mute tabs. A great new
Notes
Notes app
easily mute tabs. A great new
Notes app that
Notes app that s
easily mute tabs. A great new
Notes app that supports
Notes app that supports text
styling
styling,
Notes app that supports text
styling, checklists
styling, checklists,
Notes app that supports text
styling, checklists, and
graphical
graphical l
styling, checklists, and
graphical links
graphical links.
styling, checklists, and
graphical links. And
graphical links. And better
window
window management
graphical links. And better
window management than
window management than ever
with
with a
window management than ever
with a beautiful
with a beautiful n
window management than ever
with a beautiful new
with a beautiful new Mission
Control
Control i
with a beautiful new Mission
Control interface
Control interface,
with a beautiful new Mission
Control interface, easy
Control interface, easy a
with a beautiful new Mission
Control interface, easy access
to
to y
Control interface, easy access
to your
to your s
Control interface, easy access
to your spaces
to your spaces bar
Control interface, easy access
to your spaces bar,
to your spaces bar, and
Control interface, easy access
to your spaces bar, and of
course
course,
to your spaces bar, and of
course, the
course, the ability
to your spaces bar, and of
course, the ability to
course, the ability to do
to your spaces bar, and of
course, the ability to do s
course, the ability to do split
view
view and
course, the ability to do split
view and a
view and adjust
course, the ability to do split
view and adjust it
view and adjust it to
course, the ability to do split
view and adjust it to see
exactly
exactly what
view and adjust it to see
exactly what you
exactly what you are
view and adjust it to see
exactly what you are looking
for
for,
exactly what you are looking
for, every
for, every pixel
exactly what you are looking
for, every pixel of
for, every pixel of your
display
display devote
for, every pixel of your
display devoted
display devoted to
for, every pixel of your
display devoted to your
content.
Of
Of course,
content.
Of course, there's
Of course, there's much
content.
Of course, there's much more
to
to experience
Of course, there's much more
to experience in
to experience in E
Of course, there's much more
to experience in El
to experience in El Capitan
Of course, there's much more
to experience in El Capitan,
but
but now
to experience in El Capitan,
but now I
but now I want
to experience in El Capitan,
but now I want to
but now I want to turn
to experience in El Capitan,
but now I want to turn to
performance
performance.
but now I want to turn to
performance. S
performance. So
but now I want to turn to
performance. So we've
performance. So we've optimize
but now I want to turn to
performance. So we've opt
optimized
optimized performance
throughout
throughout the
optimized performance
throughout the system.
throughout the system. In
fact,
fact, we
throughout the system. In
fact, we are
fact, we are seeing
throughout the system. In
fact, we are seeing about
fact, we are seeing about a
throughout the system. In
fact, we are seeing about a 1
fact, we are seeing about a 1.4
times
times acceleration
fact, we are seeing about a 1.4
times acceleration in
times acceleration in app
launching,
launching, a
times acceleration in app
launching, a 2
launching, a 2X
times acceleration in app
launching, a 2X improvement
launching, a 2X improvement in
the
the snap
launching, a 2X improvement in
the snapiness
the snapiness of
launching, a 2X improvement in
the snapiness of switching
the snapiness of switching apps
launching, a 2X improvement in
the snapiness of switching a
apps.
apps. Opening
the snapiness of switching a
apps. Opening up
apps. Opening up a
the snapiness of switching a
apps. Opening up a P
apps. Opening up a PDF
the snapiness of switching a
apps. Opening up a PDF in
preview
preview four
apps. Opening up a PDF in
preview four times
preview four times as
apps. Opening up a PDF in
preview four times as fast.
But
But w
preview four times as fast.
But we've
But we've also
preview four times as fast.
But we've also m
But we've also made
preview four times as fast.
But we've also made deep
architectural
architectural improvements,
But we've also made deep
architectural improvements, and
that
that brings
architectural improvements, and
that brings us
that brings us to
architectural improvements, and
that brings us to Metal
that brings us to Metal.
(Applause)
Thank
Thank you
(Applause)
Thank you.
Thank you. Last
(Applause)
Thank you. Last year
Thank you. Last year we
introduced
introduced M
Thank you. Last year we
introduced Metal
introduced Metal at
Thank you. Last year we
introduced Metal at W
introduced Metal at WWDC
Thank you. Last year we
introduced Metal at WWDC as
introduced Metal at WWDC as a
way
way t
introduced Metal at WWDC as a
way to
way to accelerate
introduced Metal at WWDC as a
way to accelerate graphics
way to accelerate graphics in
high
high-performance
way to accelerate graphics in
high-performance g
high-performance games.
way to accelerate graphics in
high-performance games. I
high-performance games. It
takes
takes the
high-performance games. It
takes the overhead
takes the overhead out
high-performance games. It
takes the overhead out of
OpenGL
OpenGL,
takes the overhead out of
OpenGL, providing
OpenGL, providing a
takes the overhead out of
OpenGL, providing a h
high-performance
high-performance API
OpenGL, providing a h
high-performance API that
high-performance API that gives
the
the game
high-performance API that gives
the game direct
the game direct access
high-performance API that gives
the game direct access to
the game direct access to t
high-performance API that gives
the game direct access to the
power
power o
the game direct access to the
power of
power of the
the game direct access to the
power of the underlying
graphics
graphics hardware
power of the underlying
graphics hardware.
graphics hardware. Well
power of the underlying
graphics hardware. Well,
graphics hardware. Well, this
year
year we
graphics hardware. Well, this
year we are
year we are bringing
graphics hardware. Well, this
year we are bringing Metal
year we are bringing Metal t
graphics hardware. Well, this
year we are bringing Metal to
the
the M
year we are bringing Metal to
the Mac.
the Mac. And
year we are bringing Metal to
the Mac. And we
the Mac. And we are
year we are bringing Metal to
the Mac. And we are doing
the Mac. And we are doing more
than
than that.
the Mac. And we are doing more
than that. Because
than that. Because we
the Mac. And we are doing more
than that. Because we are
taking
taking the
than that. Because we are
taking the g
taking the graphic
than that. Because we are
taking the graphic stacks
taking the graphic stacks o
than that. Because we are
taking the graphic stacks on
which
which apps
taking the graphic stacks on
which apps on
which apps on OS
taking the graphic stacks on
which apps on OS X
which apps on OS X a
taking the graphic stacks on
which apps on OS X are
which apps on OS X are b
taking the graphic stacks on
which apps on OS X are built,
Core
Core Animation
which apps on OS X are built,
Core Animation and
Core Animation and Core
Graphics
Graphics a
Core Animation and Core
Graphics and
Graphics and moving
Core Animation and Core
Graphics and moving them
Graphics and moving them from
OpenGL
OpenGL to
Graphics and moving them from
OpenGL to move
OpenGL to move native
Graphics and moving them from
OpenGL to move natively
OpenGL to move natively on
Graphics and moving them from
OpenGL to move natively on top
of
of Metal,
OpenGL to move natively on top
of Metal, making
of Metal, making e
OpenGL to move natively on top
of Metal, making everything
of Metal, making everything you
do
do faster
of Metal, making everything you
do faster.
do faster. We
of Metal, making everything you
do faster. We are
do faster. We are seeing
of Metal, making everything you
do faster. We are seeing 5
do faster. We are seeing 50%
improvements
improvements in
do faster. We are seeing 50%
improvements in rendering
performance
performance and
improvements in rendering
performance and a
performance and a 40
improvements in rendering
performance and a 40%
performance and a 40% reduction
in
in the
performance and a 40% reduction
in the amount
in the amount of
performance and a 40% reduction
in the amount of CPU
in the amount of CPU necessary
to
to do
in the amount of CPU necessary
to do graphics.
to do graphics. That
in the amount of CPU necessary
to do graphics. That means
improved
improved performance
to do graphics. That means
improved performance for
improved performance for your
applications
applications a
improved performance for your
applications and
applications and better
improved performance for your
applications and better battery
life.
But
But the
life.
But the benefits
But the benefits of
life.
But the benefits of Metal
don't
don't stop
But the benefits of Metal
don't stop there
don't stop there.
But the benefits of Metal
don't stop there. Metal's
don't stop there. Metal's also
great
great f
don't stop there. Metal's also
great for
great for high
don't stop there. Metal's also
great for high-performance
great for high-performance a
apps.
apps. In
great for high-performance a
apps. In fact,
apps. In fact, Metal
great for high-performance a
apps. In fact, Metal combines
the
the compute
apps. In fact, Metal combines
the compute pow
the compute power
apps. In fact, Metal combines
the compute power of
the compute power of OpenCL
apps. In fact, Metal combines
the compute power of OpenCL and
the
the graphics
the compute power of OpenCL and
the graphics power
the graphics power of
the compute power of OpenCL and
the graphics power of OpenGL
the graphics power of OpenGL in
the compute power of OpenCL and
a
the graphics power of OpenGL in
a higher
a higher performance
the graphics power of OpenGL in
a higher performance API
a higher performance API that
does
does both
a higher performance API that
does both.
does both. And
a higher performance API that
does both. And what
does both. And what w
a higher performance API that
does both. And what we've
does both. And what we've seen
from
from working
does both. And what we've seen
from working with
from working with early
does both. And what we've seen
from working with early p
from working with early pro
developers
developers i
from working with early pro
developers is
developers is really
from working with early pro
developers is really phenomenal
developers is really phen
phenomenal.
phenomenal. Adobe
developers is really phen
phenomenal. Adobe came
phenomenal. Adobe came i
developers is really phen
phenomenal. Adobe came in
phenomenal. Adobe came in and,
in
in s
phenomenal. Adobe came in and,
in short
in short order,
phenomenal. Adobe came in and,
in short order, was
in short order, was able
phenomenal. Adobe came in and,
in short order, was able to
deliver
deliver an
in short order, was able to
deliver an eight
deliver an eight times
improvement
improvement in
deliver an eight times
improvement in their
improvement in their rendering
effects
effects inside
improvement in their rendering
effects inside of
effects inside of Aftereffects,
and
and t
effects inside of Aftereffects,
and they
and they have
effects inside of Aftereffects,
and they have been
and they have been able
effects inside of Aftereffects,
and they have been able to
and they have been able to take
the
the drawing
and they have been able to take
the drawing engine
the drawing engine i
and they have been able to take
the drawing engine in
Illustrator
Illustrator,
the drawing engine in
Illustrator, move
Illustrator, move it
the drawing engine in
Illustrator, move it on
Illustrator, move it on top
the drawing engine in
Illustrator, move it on top of
Metal
Metal,
Illustrator, move it on top of
Metal, and
Metal, and t
Illustrator, move it on top of
Metal, and take
Metal, and take kinds
Illustrator, move it on top of
Metal, and take kinds o
Metal, and take kinds of
Illustrator, move it on top of
Metal, and take kinds of UI
that
that pre
Metal, and take kinds of UI
that previously
that previously was
non-interactive,
non-interactive, like
that previously was
non-interactive, like zoom
non-interactive, like zoom of
extreme
extremely
non-interactive, like zoom of
extremely detailed
extremely detailed drawings,
and
and make
extremely detailed drawings,
and make it
and make it completely
extremely detailed drawings,
and make it completely flawle
and make it completely flawless
and
and interactive,
and make it completely flawless
and interactive, thanks
and interactive, thanks to
Metal.
Ad
Adobe
Metal.
Adobe i
Adobe is
Metal.
Adobe is so
Adobe is so pleased
Metal.
Adobe is so pleased with
Adobe is so pleased with this
they
they said
Adobe is so pleased with this
they said they
they said they are
Adobe is so pleased with this
they said they are committed
they said they are committed to
adopting
adopting Metal
they said they are committed to
adopting Metal on
adopting Metal on their
they said they are committed to
adopting Metal on their OS
adopting Metal on their OS X
apps
apps,
adopting Metal on their OS X
apps, seeing
apps, seeing performance
increase
increases
apps, seeing performance
increases up
increases up to
apps, seeing performance
increases up to 8x
increases up to 8x.
apps, seeing performance
increases up to 8x. T
increases up to 8x. They
apps, seeing performance
increases up to 8x. They are
excited
excited what
increases up to 8x. They are
excited what it
excited what it can
increases up to 8x. They are
excited what it can do
excited what it can do for
their
their creative
excited what it can do for
their creative cloud
their creative cloud users.
Of
Of course,
their creative cloud users.
Of course, Metal
Of course, Metal is
their creative cloud users.
Of course, Metal is also
fantastic
fantastic for
Of course, Metal is also
fantastic for games
fantastic for games with
Of course, Metal is also
fantastic for games with a
fantastic for games with a 10x
improvement
improvement.
fantastic for games with a 10x
improvement. That's
improvement. That's ten
fantastic for games with a 10x
improvement. That's ten times
improvement
improvement in
improvement. That's ten times
improvement in drawing
performance
performance.
improvement in drawing
performance. So
performance. So we
improvement in drawing
performance. So we brought
performance. So we brought in
Epic
Epic to
performance. So we brought in
Epic to see
Epic to see w
performance. So we brought in
Epic to see what
Epic to see what they
performance. So we brought in
Epic to see what they could
Epic to see what they could do
in
in short
Epic to see what they could do
in short order
in short order,
Epic to see what they could do
in short order, and
in short order, and t
Epic to see what they could do
in short order, and the
in short order, and the results
are
are really
in short order, and the results
are really phenomenal
are really phenomenal.
in short order, and the results
are really phenomenal. I'd
like
like t
are really phenomenal. I'd
like to
like to welcome
are really phenomenal. I'd
like to welcome to
like to welcome to the
are really phenomenal. I'd
like to welcome to the stage
Josh
Josh Adams
like to welcome to the stage
Josh Adams a
Josh Adams and
like to welcome to the stage
Josh Adams and Billy
Josh Adams and Billy Bramer
like to welcome to the stage
Josh Adams and Billy Bramer for
a
a quick
Josh Adams and Billy Bramer for
a quick demo.
(Applause)
>>
>> Thank
(Applause)
>> Thank you,
>> Thank you, Craig.
(Applause)
>> Thank you, Craig. Thank
you
you very
>> Thank you, Craig. Thank
you very much
you very much for
>> Thank you, Craig. Thank
you very much for having
you very much for having us
here
here today
you very much for having us
here today.
here today. So
you very much for having us
here today. So last
here today. So last year
you very much for having us
here today. So last year Metal
revolution
revolutionized
here today. So last year Metal
revolutionized graphics
revolutionized graphics on
here today. So last year Metal
revolutionized graphics on iOS,
and
and now
revolutionized graphics on iOS,
and now Apple's
and now Apple's amazed
revolutionized graphics on iOS,
and now Apple's amazed us
and now Apple's amazed us again
by
by bringing
and now Apple's amazed us again
by bringing Metal
by bringing Metal to
and now Apple's amazed us again
by bringing Metal to the
by bringing Metal to the Mac.
and now Apple's amazed us again
Of
by bringing Metal to the Mac.
Of course,
Of course, this
by bringing Metal to the Mac.
Of course, this is
Of course, this is great
by bringing Metal to the Mac.
Of course, this is great news
for
for games,
Of course, this is great news
for games, but
for games, but also
Of course, this is great news
for games, but also for
for games, but also for the
tools
tools that
for games, but also for the
tools that we
tools that we use
for games, but also for the
tools that we use to
tools that we use to make
for games, but also for the
tools that we use to make those
games.
Here
Here you
games.
Here you are
Here you are seeing
games.
Here you are seeing Epic
Here you are seeing Epic's
upcoming
upcoming multiplay
Here you are seeing Epic's
upcoming multiplayer
upcoming multiplayer title
Fortnite
Fortnite,
upcoming multiplayer title
Fortnite, running
Fortnite, running entirely
upcoming multiplayer title
Fortnite, running entirely on
Metal
Metal.
Fortnite, running entirely on
Metal. We
Metal. We are
Fortnite, running entirely on
Metal. We are modify
Metal. We are modifying
Fortnite, running entirely on
Metal. We are modifying it
direct
directly
Metal. We are modifying it
directly within
directly within the
Metal. We are modifying it
directly within the Unreal
Engine
Engine,
directly within the Unreal
Engine, a
Engine, a development
directly within the Unreal
Engine, a development tool
Engine, a development tool that
powers
powers many
Engine, a development tool that
powers many of
powers many of today's
Engine, a development tool that
powers many of today's best
games.
games. It's
powers many of today's best
games. It's quite
games. It's quite a
powers many of today's best
games. It's quite a bit
games. It's quite a bit going
on
on in
games. It's quite a bit going
on in this
on in this scene,
games. It's quite a bit going
on in this scene, though,
on in this scene, though, so
let's
let's break
on in this scene, though, so
let's break it
let's break it down.
First,
First, there
let's break it down.
First, there are
First, there are 6
let's break it down.
First, there are 64
First, there are 64 different
layers
layers of
First, there are 64 different
layers of rendering
layers of rendering e
First, there are 64 different
layers of rendering effects,
and
and that's
layers of rendering effects,
and that's a
and that's a lot
layers of rendering effects,
and that's a lot.
and that's a lot. All
combining
combining together,
and that's a lot. All
combining together, though
combining together, though,
and that's a lot. All
combining together, though, to
produce
produce what
combining together, though, to
produce what you
produce what you see
combining together, though, to
produce what you see on
produce what you see on the
scene
scene today.
produce what you see on the
scene today. If
scene today. If we
produce what you see on the
scene today. If we go
scene today. If we go into
produce what you see on the
scene today. If we go into a
simple
simple wireframe
scene today. If we go into a
simple wireframe m
simple wireframe mode,
scene today. If we go into a
simple wireframe mode, you
simple wireframe mode, you can
see
see the
simple wireframe mode, you can
see the thousands
see the thousands of
simple wireframe mode, you can
see the thousands of building
blocks
blocks that
see the thousands of building
blocks that make
blocks that make up
see the thousands of building
blocks that make up this
blocks that make up this world.
We
We can
blocks that make up this world.
We can start
We can start to
blocks that make up this world.
We can start to add
We can start to add in
blocks that make up this world.
We can start to add in layers
We can start to add in layers,
flat
flat shading,
We can start to add in layers,
flat shading, detailed
lighting,
lighting, runtime
flat shading, detailed
lighting, runtime shadows
lighting, runtime shadows,
flat shading, detailed
lighting, runtime shadows, and
final
finally
lighting, runtime shadows, and
finally we
finally we combine
lighting, runtime shadows, and
finally we combine them
finally we combine them all
together
together to
finally we combine them all
together to bring
together to bring Fortnite's
fun
fun and
together to bring Fortnite's
fun and lig
fun and lighthearted
together to bring Fortnite's
fun and lighthearted aesthetic
to
to life.
The
The interesting
to life.
The interesting thing
The interesting thing here,
though,
though, is
The interesting thing here,
though, is that
though, is that all
The interesting thing here,
though, is that all of
though, is that all of the
effects
effects you
though, is that all of the
effects you are
effects you are seeing
though, is that all of the
effects you are seeing are
being
being done
effects you are seeing are
being done completely
being done completely in
effects you are seeing are
being done completely in real
being done completely in r
real-time.
real-time. Notice
being done completely in r
real-time. Notice how
real-time. Notice how t
being done completely in r
real-time. Notice how the
shadow
shadows
real-time. Notice how the
shadows and
shadows and objects
real-time. Notice how the
shadows and objects interact
nicely
nicely a
shadows and objects interact
nicely as
nicely as Josh
shadows and objects interact
nicely as Josh moves
nicely as Josh moves the
shadows and objects interact
nicely as Josh moves the car
around
around.
Final
Finally
around.
Finally,
Finally, we
around.
Finally, we can
Finally, we can change
around.
Finally, we can change the
time
time of
Finally, we can change the
time of day
time of day on
Finally, we can change the
time of day on the
time of day on the fly,
dramatically
dramatically a
time of day on the fly,
dramatically alter
dramatically alter the
time of day on the fly,
dramatically alter the scene.
All
All of
dramatically alter the scene.
All of this
All of this is
dramatically alter the scene.
All of this is thanks
All of this is thanks to
dramatically alter the scene.
All of this is thanks to the
efficiency
efficiency o
All of this is thanks to the
efficiency of
efficiency of Metal.
All of this is thanks to the
efficiency of Metal. I
efficiency of Metal. In
All of this is thanks to the
efficiency of Metal. In fact,
we
we are
efficiency of Metal. In fact,
we are seeing
we are seeing a
efficiency of Metal. In fact,
we are seeing a 70
we are seeing a 70%
efficiency of Metal. In fact,
we are seeing a 70% reduction
in
in CPUs
we are seeing a 70% reduction
in CPUs compared
in CPUs compared t
we are seeing a 70% reduction
in CPUs compared to
in CPUs compared to OpenGL
we are seeing a 70% reduction
in CPUs compared to OpenGL,
enabling
enabling d
in CPUs compared to OpenGL,
enabling develops
enabling develops like
in CPUs compared to OpenGL,
enabling develops like us
enabling develops like us to
create
create richer
enabling develops like us to
create richer 3D
create richer 3D worlds.
Speaking
Speaking o
create richer 3D worlds.
Speaking of
Speaking of those
create richer 3D worlds.
Speaking of those worlds,
let's
let's hop
Speaking of those worlds,
let's hop into
let's hop into the
Speaking of those worlds,
let's hop into the g
let's hop into the game,
Fortnite
Fortnite.
let's hop into the game,
Fortnite. N
Fortnite. Now,
let's hop into the game,
Fortnite. Now, if
Fortnite. Now, if you've
let's hop into the game,
Fortnite. Now, if you've ever
built
built a
Fortnite. Now, if you've ever
built a p
built a pillow
Fortnite. Now, if you've ever
built a pillow f
built a pillow fort
Fortnite. Now, if you've ever
built a pillow fort and
built a pillow fort and b
Fortnite. Now, if you've ever
built a pillow fort and battled
imaginary
imaginary monsters
built a pillow fort and battled
imaginary monsters with
imaginary monsters with your
friends,
friends, you
imaginary monsters with your
friends, you already
friends, you already know
imaginary monsters with your
friends, you already know how
to
to play
friends, you already know how
to play Fortnite
to play Fortnite.
friends, you already know how
to play Fortnite. This
to play Fortnite. This is
friends, you already know how
to play Fortnite. This is the
end
end-of-the-world
to play Fortnite. This is the
end-of-the-world scenario
end-of-the-world scenario you
have
have been
end-of-the-world scenario you
have been training
have been training for
end-of-the-world scenario you
have been training for since
you
you were
have been training for since
you were a
you were a kid.
have been training for since
you were a kid. It's
you were a kid. It's beau
beautifully
beautifully stylized
you were a kid. It's beau
beautifully stylized universe.
You
You can
beautifully stylized universe.
You can destroy
You can destroy anything
beautifully stylized universe.
You can destroy anything you
want.
want. G
You can destroy anything you
want. Gather
want. Gather resources
You can destroy anything you
want. Gather resources and
build
build a
want. Gather resources and
build a fort
build a fort.
want. Gather resources and
build a fort. So
build a fort. So let's
want. Gather resources and
build a fort. So let's go
ahead
ahead and
build a fort. So let's go
ahead and wreck
ahead and wreck this
build a fort. So let's go
ahead and wreck this car
ahead and wreck this car.
Gather
Gather i
ahead and wreck this car.
Gather its
Gather its metal
ahead and wreck this car.
Gather its metal.
Gather its metal. And
ahead and wreck this car.
Gather its metal. And continue
our
our wanton
Gather its metal. And continue
our wanton destruction
our wanton destruction b
Gather its metal. And continue
our wanton destruction by
chopping
chopping down
our wanton destruction by
chopping down this
chopping down this tree
our wanton destruction by
chopping down this tree to
chopping down this tree to get
some
some wood
chopping down this tree to get
some wood for
some wood for later.
Did
Did we
some wood for later.
Did we mention
Did we mention there
some wood for later.
Did we mention there are
purple
purple death
Did we mention there are
purple death storms,
purple death storms, like
Did we mention there are
purple death storms, like this
one,
one, for
purple death storms, like this
one, for instance?
one, for instance? We
purple death storms, like this
one, for instance? We should
go.
go. Luckily
one, for instance? We should
go. Luckily,
go. Luckily, while
one, for instance? We should
go. Luckily, while we
go. Luckily, while we were
one, for instance? We should
go. Luckily, while we were out
exploring
exploring,
go. Luckily, while we were out
exploring, we
exploring, we found
go. Luckily, while we were out
exploring, we found a
exploring, we found a m
go. Luckily, while we were out
exploring, we found a multitude
of
of weapons,
exploring, we found a multitude
of weapons, a
of weapons, and
exploring, we found a multitude
of weapons, and t
of weapons, and this
exploring, we found a multitude
of weapons, and this broom
of weapons, and this broom.
exploring, we found a multitude
of weapons, and this broom. I
of weapons, and this broom. If
we
we can
of weapons, and this broom. If
we can j
we can just
of weapons, and this broom. If
we can just get
we can just get across
of weapons, and this broom. If
we can just get across the
field,
field, our
we can just get across the
field, our friend
field, our friend has
we can just get across the
field, our friend has been
field, our friend has been busy
building
building a
field, our friend has been busy
building a f
building a fort
field, our friend has been busy
building a fort across
building a fort across the
field, our friend has been busy
building a fort across the --
did
did we
building a fort across the --
did we men
did we mention
building a fort across the --
did we mention the
did we mention the s
building a fort across the --
did we mention the storms
did we mention the storms are
made
made of
did we mention the storms are
made of monsters
made of monsters?
did we mention the storms are
made of monsters? We
made of monsters? We are
did we mention the storms are
made of monsters? We are going
to
to need
made of monsters? We are going
to need s
to need something
made of monsters? We are going
to need something a
to need something a bit
made of monsters? We are going
to need something a bit better
than
than this
to need something a bit better
than this bro
than this broom.
to need something a bit better
than this broom. Nice!
There's
There's our
than this broom. Nice!
There's our fri
There's our friend
than this broom. Nice!
There's our friend laying
There's our friend laying down
some
some covering
There's our friend laying down
some covering.
>>
>> H
some covering.
>> Hey,
>> Hey, look
some covering.
>> Hey, look out
>> Hey, look out!
>>
>> We
>> Hey, look out!
>> We call
>> We call that
>> Hey, look out!
>> We call that move
>> We call that move t
>> Hey, look out!
>> We call that move the
>> We call that move the pow
>> Hey, look out!
>> We call that move the power
cord.
cord. I've
>> We call that move the power
cord. I've g
cord. I've got
>> We call that move the power
cord. I've got a
cord. I've got a bad
>> We call that move the power
cord. I've got a bad feeling
about
about this
cord. I've got a bad feeling
about this.
about this. You
cord. I've got a bad feeling
about this. You are
about this. You are going
cord. I've got a bad feeling
about this. You are going to
need
need a
about this. You are going to
need a bigger
need a bigger fort
about this. You are going to
need a bigger fort.
need a bigger fort. Place
about this. You are going to
need a bigger fort. Place a
trap,
trap, head
need a bigger fort. Place a
trap, head inside
trap, head inside.
need a bigger fort. Place a
trap, head inside. Looks
trap, head inside. Looks like
an
an enemy
trap, head inside. Looks like
an enemy has
an enemy has broken
trap, head inside. Looks like
an enemy has broken into
an enemy has broken into our
fort
fort.
All
All right
fort.
All right.
All right. Let's
fort.
All right. Let's use
All right. Let's use that
wood
wood we
All right. Let's use that
wood we gathered
wood we gathered earlier
All right. Let's use that
wood we gathered earlier t
wood we gathered earlier to
All right. Let's use that
wood we gathered earlier to fix
this
this wall,
wood we gathered earlier to fix
this wall, build
this wall, build some
wood we gathered earlier to fix
this wall, build some s
this wall, build some stairs,
meet
meet up
this wall, build some stairs,
meet up w
meet up with
this wall, build some stairs,
meet up with our
meet up with our friend
this wall, build some stairs,
meet up with our friend t
meet up with our friend topside
this wall, build some stairs,
meet up with our friend top
topside.
>>
>> Glad
>> Glad you
>> Glad you could
>> Glad you could make
>> Glad you could make i
>> Glad you could make it
>> Glad you could make it.
(Monster
(Monster screaming)
>>
>> Whether
(Monster screaming)
>> Whether you
>> Whether you are
(Monster screaming)
>> Whether you are a
>> Whether you are a gaming
(Monster screaming)
>> Whether you are a gaming or
a
a g
>> Whether you are a gaming or
a game
a game developer
>> Whether you are a gaming or
a game developer,
a game developer, Metal
>> Whether you are a gaming or
a game developer, Metal opens
new
new p
a game developer, Metal opens
new possibilities
new possibilities for
a game developer, Metal opens
new possibilities for rich
new possibilities for rich and
engaging
engaging worlds.
new possibilities for rich and
engaging worlds. Y
engaging worlds. You
new possibilities for rich and
engaging worlds. You can
download
downlo
engaging worlds. You can
down o
down Unreal
engaging worlds. You can
down Unreal Engine
down Unreal Engine right
engaging worlds. You can
down Unreal Engine right now,
and
and the
down Unreal Engine right now,
and the Fortnite
and the Fortnite bet
down Unreal Engine right now,
and the Fortnite beta
and the Fortnite beta for
down Unreal Engine right now,
and the Fortnite beta for Mac
starts
starts this
and the Fortnite beta for Mac
starts this fall.
Thank
Thank you
starts this fall.
Thank you very
Thank you very much.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
Thank you very much.
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> CRAIG
(Cheers and applause)
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI:
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: Thank
(Cheers and applause)
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: Thank you
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: Thank you,
guys
guys.
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: Thank you,
guys. That
guys. That was
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: Thank you,
guys. That was great.
guys. That was great. We
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: Thank you,
guys. That was great. We have
been
been totally
guys. That was great. We have
been totally impressed
been totally impressed with
what
what Epic
been totally impressed with
what Epic has
what Epic has been
been totally impressed with
what Epic has been able
what Epic has been able to
accomplish
accomplish in
what Epic has been able to
accomplish in such
accomplish in such a
what Epic has been able to
accomplish in such a short
accomplish in such a short t
time.
time. And
accomplish in such a short t
time. And this
time. And this is
accomplish in such a short t
time. And this is in
time. And this is in part
because
because the
time. And this is in part
because the work
because the work t
time. And this is in part
because the work they
because the work they did
time. And this is in part
because the work they did to
adopt
adopt Metal
because the work they did to
adopt Metal in
adopt Metal in their
because the work they did to
adopt Metal in their rendering
engines
engines f
adopt Metal in their rendering
engines for
engines for iOS
adopt Metal in their rendering
engines for iOS immediately
pays
pays dividends
engines for iOS immediately
pays dividends on
pays dividends on OS
engines for iOS immediately
pays dividends on OS X
pays dividends on OS X,
engines for iOS immediately
pays dividends on OS X, and
pays dividends on OS X, and we
are
are seeing
pays dividends on OS X, and we
are seeing this
are seeing this w
pays dividends on OS X, and we
are seeing this with
are seeing this with many
pays dividends on OS X, and we
are seeing this with many o
are seeing this with many other
developers
developers as
are seeing this with many other
developers as well
developers as well who
are seeing this with many other
developers as well who are
bringing
bringing t
developers as well who are
bringing their
bringing their gaming
developers as well who are
bringing their gaming engines
immediate
immediately
bringing their gaming engines
immediately to
immediately to the
bringing their gaming engines
immediately to the Mac
immediately to the Mac.
bringing their gaming engines
immediately to the Mac. And
pro
pro app
immediately to the Mac. And
pro app makers
pro app makers are
immediately to the Mac. And
pro app makers are seeing
pro app makers are seeing the
benefits
benefits of
pro app makers are seeing the
benefits of Metal
benefits of Metal as
pro app makers are seeing the
benefits of Metal as well
benefits of Metal as well,
people
people like
benefits of Metal as well,
people like The
people like The Foundry
benefits of Metal as well,
people like The Foundry and
Auto
Autode
people like The Foundry and
Autodesk
Autodesk.
people like The Foundry and
Autodesk. I
Autodesk. I think
people like The Foundry and
Autodesk. I think we
Autodesk. I think we are
people like The Foundry and
Autodesk. I think we are going
to
to see
Autodesk. I think we are going
to see pro
to see pro users,
Autodesk. I think we are going
to see pro users, game
to see pro users, gamers,
Autodesk. I think we are going
to see pro users, gamers, and
all
all of
to see pro users, gamers, and
all of us
all of us benefiting
to see pro users, gamers, and
all of us benefiting from
all of us benefiting from the
advantages
advantages of
all of us benefiting from the
advantages of Metal
advantages of Metal.
So
So that
advantages of Metal.
So that is
So that is El
advantages of Metal.
So that is El Capitan
So that is El Capitan,
improvements
improvements to
So that is El Capitan,
improvements to experience
improvements to experience and
performance
performance.
improvements to experience and
performance. Now,
performance. Now, El
improvements to experience and
performance. Now, El Capitan
is
is available
performance. Now, El Capitan
is available to
is available to all
performance. Now, El Capitan
is available to all of
is available to all of you
developers
developers today
is available to all of you
developers today.
(Applause)
We
We will
(Applause)
We will be
We will be d
(Applause)
We will be doing
We will be doing a
(Applause)
We will be doing a p
We will be doing a public
(Applause)
We will be doing a public beta
once
once again
We will be doing a public beta
once again in
once again in July,
We will be doing a public beta
once again in July, and
once again in July, and we
We will be doing a public beta
once again in July, and we will
be
be rolling
once again in July, and we will
be rolling out
be rolling out to
once again in July, and we will
be rolling out to everyone
be rolling out to everyone with
a
a free
be rolling out to everyone with
a free upgrade
a free upgrade this
be rolling out to everyone with
a free upgrade this f
a free upgrade this fall.
be rolling out to everyone with
a free upgrade this fall. And
that's
that's our
a free upgrade this fall. And
that's our u
that's our update
a free upgrade this fall. And
that's our update on
that's our update on OS
a free upgrade this fall. And
that's our update on OS X
that's our update on OS X.
(Applause)
Next
Next --
(Applause)
Next -- you
Next -- you guessed
(Applause)
Next -- you guessed it
Next -- you guessed it --
(Applause)
Next -- you guessed it -- i
Next -- you guessed it -- iOS.
Now
Now,
Next -- you guessed it -- iOS.
Now, our
Now, our current
Next -- you guessed it -- iOS.
Now, our current b
Now, our current big
Next -- you guessed it -- iOS.
Now, our current big release
of
of iOS
Now, our current big release
of iOS is
of iOS is iOS
Now, our current big release
of iOS is iOS 8
of iOS is iOS 8,
Now, our current big release
of iOS is iOS 8, and
of iOS is iOS 8, and iOS
Now, our current big release
of iOS is iOS 8, and iOS 8
of iOS is iOS 8, and iOS 8 was
a
a huge
of iOS is iOS 8, and iOS 8 was
a huge release
a huge release with
of iOS is iOS 8, and iOS 8 was
a huge release with t
a huge release with tons
of iOS is iOS 8, and iOS 8 was
a huge release with tons of
a huge release with tons of new
features
features f
a huge release with tons of new
features for
features for users
a huge release with tons of new
features for users and
features for users and a
phenomenal
phenomenal s
features for users and a
phenomenal set
phenomenal set of
features for users and a
phenomenal set of technologies
that
that you
phenomenal set of technologies
that you d
that you developers
phenomenal set of technologies
that you developers have
that you developers have been
phenomenal set of technologies
able
that you developers have been
able to
able to use
that you developers have been
able to use to
able to use to d
that you developers have been
able to use to deliver
able to use to deliver all
that you developers have been
able to use to deliver all new
experience
experiences
able to use to deliver all new
experiences to
experiences to the
able to use to deliver all new
experiences to the platform
experiences to the platform.
The
The upgrade
experiences to the platform.
The upgrade r
The upgrade rate
experiences to the platform.
The upgrade rate for
The upgrade rate for iOS
experiences to the platform.
The upgrade rate for iOS h
The upgrade rate for iOS has
been
been f
The upgrade rate for iOS has
been fantastic.
been fantastic. We
The upgrade rate for iOS has
been fantastic. We have
been fantastic. We have 8
The upgrade rate for iOS has
been fantastic. We have 83%
been fantastic. We have 83% of
active
active iPhone
been fantastic. We have 83% of
active iPhone u
active iPhone users
been fantastic. We have 83% of
active iPhone users currently
running
running the
active iPhone users currently
running the latest
running the latest OS.
active iPhone users currently
running the latest OS. And
this
this is
running the latest OS. And
this is really
this is really i
running the latest OS. And
this is really important
because
because it
this is really important
because it means
because it means not
this is really important
because it means not only
because it means not only are
they
they getting
because it means not only are
they getting the
they getting the most
because it means not only are
they getting the most recent
features
features,
they getting the most recent
features, but
features, but they're
they getting the most recent
features, but they're a
features, but they're also
up-to-date
up-to-date on
features, but they're also
up-to-date on all
up-to-date on all the
features, but they're also
up-to-date on all the security
fixes
fixes,
up-to-date on all the security
fixes, and
fixes, and y
up-to-date on all the security
fixes, and you're
fixes, and you're able
up-to-date on all the security
fixes, and you're able to
fixes, and you're able to know
as
as a
fixes, and you're able to know
as a developer
as a developer that
fixes, and you're able to know
as a developer that you
as a developer that you can
target
target all
as a developer that you can
target all the
target all the users
as a developer that you can
target all the users with
target all the users with the
latest
latest a
target all the users with the
latest and
latest and greatest
target all the users with the
latest and greatest A
latest and greatest APIs
target all the users with the
latest and greatest APIs.
latest and greatest APIs. And
this
this is
latest and greatest APIs. And
this is a
this is a b
latest and greatest APIs. And
this is a benefit
this is a benefit t
latest and greatest APIs. And
this is a benefit that
this is a benefit that actually
remains
remains r
this is a benefit that actually
remains really
remains really u
this is a benefit that actually
remains really unique
remains really unique t
this is a benefit that actually
remains really unique to
remains really unique to iOS
this is a benefit that actually
remains really unique to iOS.
(Applause)
So
So we
(Applause)
So we are
So we are now
(Applause)
So we are now looking
So we are now looking forward
to
to iOS
So we are now looking forward
to iOS 9,
to iOS 9, and
So we are now looking forward
to iOS 9, and as
to iOS 9, and as we
So we are now looking forward
to iOS 9, and as we conceived
of
of what
to iOS 9, and as we conceived
of what we
of what we want
to iOS 9, and as we conceived
of what we wanted
of what we wanted to
accomplish,
accomplish, first
of what we wanted to
accomplish, first and
accomplish, first and foremost,
we
we wanted
accomplish, first and foremost,
we wanted to
we wanted to elevate
accomplish, first and foremost,
we wanted to elevate the
foundations
foundations of
we wanted to elevate the
foundations of the
foundations of the platform
we wanted to elevate the
foundations of the platform,
things
things like
foundations of the platform,
things like extending
things like extending your
battery
battery life,
things like extending your
battery life, improving
performance
performance,
battery life, improving
performance, and
performance, and enhancing
security
security t
performance, and enhancing
security to
security to protect
performance, and enhancing
security to protect customer
data.
But
But t
data.
But there
But there was
data.
But there was more
But there was more we
data.
But there was more we wanted
to
to do.
But there was more we wanted
to do. Adding
to do. Adding i
But there was more we wanted
to do. Adding intelligence
throughout
throughout the
to do. Adding intelligence
throughout the user
throughout the user experience
in
in a
throughout the user experience
in a way
in a way that
throughout the user experience
in a way that enhance
in a way that enhances
throughout the user experience
in a way that enhances how
in a way that enhances how y
throughout the user experience
in a way that enhances how you
use
use your
in a way that enhances how you
use your d
use your device
in a way that enhances how you
use your device but
use your device but w
in a way that enhances how you
use your device but without
compromising
compromising your
use your device but without
compromising your privacy.
Things
Things like
compromising your privacy.
Things like improving
Things like improving the
compromising your privacy.
Things like improving the apps
that
that you
Things like improving the apps
that you u
that you use
Things like improving the apps
that you use m
that you use most
Things like improving the apps
that you use most and
that you use most and taking
the
the experience
that you use most and taking
the exper
the experience
that you use most and taking
the experience of
the experience of the
that you use most and taking
the experience of the iPad
the experience of the iPad to
the
the next
the experience of the iPad to
the next level.
I
I want
the next level.
I want to
I want to start
the next level.
I want to start t
I want to start today
the next level.
I want to start today with
intelligence
intelligence and
I want to start today with
intelligence and Siri.
intelligence and Siri. N
I want to start today with
intelligence and Siri. Now,
Siri
Siri has
intelligence and Siri. Now,
Siri has q
Siri has quiet
intelligence and Siri. Now,
Siri has quietly
Siri has quietly become
incredibly
incredibly popular.
Siri has quietly become
incredibly popular. I
incredibly popular. It
Siri has quietly become
incredibly popular. It serves
over
over a
incredibly popular. It serves
over a b
over a billion
incredibly popular. It serves
over a billion requests
over a billion requests p
incredibly popular. It serves
over a billion requests per
week
week.
over a billion requests per
week. And
week. And this
over a billion requests per
week. And this is
week. And this is i
over a billion requests per
week. And this is in
week. And this is in part
because
because Siri
week. And this is in part
because Siri has
because Siri has gotten
week. And this is in part
because Siri has gotten so
great
great at
because Siri has gotten so
great at understanding
great at understanding what
because Siri has gotten so
great at understanding what we
are
are saying
great at understanding what we
are saying.
are saying. In
great at understanding what we
are saying. In just
are saying. In just the
great at understanding what we
are saying. In just the last
year,
year, we've
are saying. In just the last
year, we've seen
year, we've seen a
are saying. In just the last
year, we've seen a 40
year, we've seen a 40%
reduction
reduction in
year, we've seen a 40%
reduction in wrait
reduction in wr
year, we've seen a 40%
reduction in word
reduction in word e
year, we've seen a 40%
reduction in word error
reduction in word error rate
down
down t
reduction in word error rate
down to
down to 5
reduction in word error rate
down to 5%.
down to 5%. That's
reduction in word error rate
down to 5%. That's an
down to 5%. That's an industry
leading
leading number
down to 5%. That's an industry
leading number.
leading number. And
down to 5%. That's an industry
leading number. And Siri
leading number. And Siri is
down to 5%. That's an industry
leading number. And Siri is 4
leading number. And Siri is
40%
40% fast
leading number. And Siri is
40% faster
40% faster than
leading number. And Siri is
40% faster than ever
40% faster than ever at
leading number. And Siri is
40% faster than ever at res
responding
responding to
40% faster than ever at res
responding to what
responding to what we
40% faster than ever at res
responding to what we say.
Now
Now,
responding to what we say.
Now, for
Now, for iOS
responding to what we say.
Now, for iOS 9
Now, for iOS 9,
responding to what we say.
Now, for iOS 9, Siri
Now, for iOS 9, Siri has
responding to what we say.
Now, for iOS 9, Siri has a
beautiful
beautiful new
Now, for iOS 9, Siri has a
beautiful new UI
beautiful new UI and
Now, for iOS 9, Siri has a
beautiful new UI and is
beautiful new UI and is capable
of
of doing
beautiful new UI and is capable
of doing so
of doing so much
beautiful new UI and is capable
of doing so much more
of doing so much more.
beautiful new UI and is capable
of doing so much more. Things
like
like "
of doing so much more. Things
like "show
like "show me
of doing so much more. Things
like "show me photos
like "show me photos f
of doing so much more. Things
like "show me photos from
like "show me photos from Utah
last
last August"
like "show me photos from Utah
last August" ca
last August" can
like "show me photos from Utah
last August" can instant
last August" can instantly
like "show me photos from Utah
last August" can instantly show
you
you the
last August" can instantly show
you the right
you the right p
last August" can instantly show
you the right photos
you the right photos from
last August" can instantly show
you the right photos from your
photo
photo library.
And
And Siri's
photo library.
And Siri's really
And Siri's really great
photo library.
And Siri's really great at
taking
taking reminders.
And Siri's really great at
taking reminders. Now
taking reminders. Now you
And Siri's really great at
taking reminders. Now you can
ask
ask Siri
taking reminders. Now you can
ask Siri things
ask Siri things like
taking reminders. Now you can
ask Siri things like "remind
ask Siri things like "remind me
to
to grab
ask Siri things like "remind me
to grab my
to grab my coffee
ask Siri things like "remind me
to grab my coffee off
to grab my coffee off the
ask Siri things like "remind me
to grab my coffee off the roof
of
of my
to grab my coffee off the roof
of my car
of my car when
to grab my coffee off the roof
of my car when I
of my car when I get
to grab my coffee off the roof
of my car when I get in."
Because
Because Siri
of my car when I get in."
Because Siri knows
Because Siri knows now
of my car when I get in."
Because Siri knows now when
you've
you've gotten
Because Siri knows now when
you've gotten i
you've gotten in
Because Siri knows now when
you've gotten in the
you've gotten in the c
Because Siri knows now when
you've gotten in the car.
And
And o
you've gotten in the car.
And of
And of course,
you've gotten in the car.
And of course, we
And of course, we often
you've gotten in the car.
And of course, we often want
to
to take
And of course, we often want
to take reminders
to take reminders about
And of course, we often want
to take reminders about things
that
that we
to take reminders about things
that we are
that we are looking
to take reminders about things
that we are looking at
that we are looking at on
to take reminders about things
that we are looking at on our
device,
device, some
that we are looking at on our
device, some content
device, some content inside
that we are looking at on our
device, some content inside of
our
our app,
device, some content inside of
our app, maybe
our app, maybe a
device, some content inside of
our app, maybe a Safari
our app, maybe a Safari.
device, some content inside of
our app, maybe a Safari. Now
you
you can
our app, maybe a Safari. Now
you can say
you can say things
our app, maybe a Safari. Now
you can say things like
you can say things like "remind
me
me about
you can say things like "remind
me about this
me about this when
you can say things like "remind
me about this when I
me about this when I get
you can say things like "remind
me about this when I get home,"
and
and that
me about this when I get home,"
and that r
and that remind
me about this when I get home,"
and that reminder
and that reminder refers
me about this when I get home,"
and that reminder refers r
and that reminder refers right
back
back with
and that reminder refers right
back with a
back with a link
and that reminder refers right
back with a link specifically
to
to what
back with a link specifically
to what you
to what you were
back with a link specifically
to what you were looking
to what you were looking at
when
when you
to what you were looking at
when you took
when you took that
to what you were looking at
when you took that reminder.
So
So Siri
when you took that reminder.
So Siri is
So Siri is a
when you took that reminder.
So Siri is a great
So Siri is a great assistant.
But
But the
So Siri is a great assistant.
But the best
But the best assistants
So Siri is a great assistant.
But the best assistants a
But the best assistants are
proactive.
proactive. And
But the best assistants are
proactive. And so
proactive. And so on
But the best assistants are
proactive. And so on iOS
proactive. And so on iOS 9,
But the best assistants are
proactive. And so on iOS 9, we
are
are bringing
proactive. And so on iOS 9, we
are bringing proactivity
throughout
throughout the
are bringing proactivity
throughout the system.
So
So say
throughout the system.
So say you
So say you like
throughout the system.
So say you like to
So say you like to run
throughout the system.
So say you like to run in
So say you like to run in the
morning
morning,
So say you like to run in the
morning, and
morning, and when
So say you like to run in the
morning, and when you
morning, and when you do,
So say you like to run in the
morning, and when you do, you
like
like to
morning, and when you do, you
like to list
like to listen
morning, and when you do, you
like to listen to
like to listen to music
morning, and when you do, you
like to listen to music.
like to listen to music. Well,
now
now your
like to listen to music. Well,
now your phone
now your phone can
like to listen to music. Well,
now your phone can learn
now your phone can learn that
about
about you,
now your phone can learn that
about you, and
about you, and when
now your phone can learn that
about you, and when you
about you, and when you plug
now your phone can learn that
about you, and when you plug in
your
your headphones
about you, and when you plug in
your headphones,
your headphones, can
about you, and when you plug in
your headphones, can offer
your headphones, can offer up
Now
Now Playing
your headphones, can offer up
Now Playing automat
Now Playing automatically
your headphones, can offer up
Now Playing automatically right
on
on the
Now Playing automatically right
on the lock
on the lock screen.
Now Playing automatically right
(Applause)
And
And this
(Applause)
And this is
And this is all
(Applause)
And this is all context
sensitive
sensitive t
And this is all context
sensitive to
sensitive to the
And this is all context
sensitive to the time
sensitive to the time,
And this is all context
sensitive to the time, the
place,
place, a
sensitive to the time, the
place, and
place, and even
sensitive to the time, the
place, and even the
place, and even the devices
sensitive to the time, the
place, and even the devices you
are
are connected
place, and even the devices you
are connected to
are connected to so
place, and even the devices you
are connected to so you
are connected to so you do
place, and even the devices you
are connected to so you do the
same
same t
are connected to so you do the
same thing
same thing in
are connected to so you do the
same thing in the
same thing in the car
are connected to so you do the
same thing in the car late
same thing in the car later
are connected to so you do the
same thing in the car later on,
and
and i
same thing in the car later on,
and it
and it might
same thing in the car later on,
and it might offer
and it might offer up
same thing in the car later on,
and it might offer up the
and it might offer up the audio
book
book that
and it might offer up the audio
book that you
book that you h
and it might offer up the audio
book that you have
book that you have been
and it might offer up the audio
book that you have been l
listening
listening to
book that you have been l
listening to.
Now,
Now, a
listening to.
Now, as
Now, as a
listening to.
Now, as a great
Now, as a great assistant,
your
your iPhone
Now, as a great assistant,
your iPhone can
your iPhone can n
Now, as a great assistant,
your iPhone can now
your iPhone can now take
invitations
invitations y
your iPhone can now take
invitations you
invitations you receive
your iPhone can now take
invitations you receive in
invitations you receive in your
email
email and
invitations you receive in your
email and without
email and without you
invitations you receive in your
email and without you even
touching
touching them
email and without you even
touching them automatically
touching them automatically put
them
them on
touching them automatically put
them on your
them on your calendar
touching them automatically put
them on your calendar and
them on your calendar and even
give
give you
them on your calendar and even
give you a
give you a t
them on your calendar and even
give you a time
give you a time to
them on your calendar and even
give you a time to leave
reminder,
reminder, taking
give you a time to leave
reminder, taking into
reminder, taking into account
current
current traffic
reminder, taking into account
current traffic conditions,
current traffic conditions, and
of
of course,
current traffic conditions, and
of course, with
of course, with just
current traffic conditions, and
of course, with just a
of course, with just a swipe
current traffic conditions, and
of course, with just a swipe,
give
give y
of course, with just a swipe,
give you
give you access
of course, with just a swipe,
give you access to
give you access to driving
direction
directions
give you access to driving
directions.
No
Now
directions.
Now,
Now, have
directions.
Now, have you
Now, have you ever
directions.
Now, have you ever had
Now, have you ever had this
happen
happen to
Now, have you ever had this
happen to you,
happen to you, you
Now, have you ever had this
happen to you, you get
happen to you, you get a
Now, have you ever had this
happen to you, you get a call,
the
the number
happen to you, you get a call,
the number looks
the number looks kind
happen to you, you get a call,
the number looks kind of
familiar,
familiar, but
the number looks kind of
familiar, but you
familiar, but you are
the number looks kind of
familiar, but you are really
not
not s
familiar, but you are really
not sure
not sure who
familiar, but you are really
not sure who it
not sure who it is
familiar, but you are really
not sure who it is?
not sure who it is? As
familiar, but you are really
not sure who it is? As a
not sure who it is? As a g
familiar, but you are really
not sure who it is? As a great
assistant
assistant,
not sure who it is? As a great
assistant, yo
assistant, your
not sure who it is? As a great
assistant, your phone
assistant, your phone can
not sure who it is? As a great
assistant, your phone can now
look
look in
assistant, your phone can now
look in your
look in your email
assistant, your phone can now
look in your email and
look in your email and find
assistant, your phone can now
look in your email and find o
look in your email and find out
who
who that
look in your email and find out
who that person
who that person might
look in your email and find out
who that person might be
who that person might be and
suggest
suggest it
who that person might be and
suggest it to
suggest it to you
who that person might be and
suggest it to you right
suggest it to you right on
who that person might be and
suggest it to you right on the
incoming
incoming call
suggest it to you right on the
incoming call s
incoming call screen.
suggest it to you right on the
incoming call screen. It's
super
super handy
incoming call screen. It's
super handy.
(Applause)
Now,
Now, this
(Applause)
Now, this k
Now, this kind
(Applause)
Now, this kind of
Now, this kind of proactivity
is
is also
Now, this kind of proactivity
is also g
is also great
Now, this kind of proactivity
is also great when
is also great when it
Now, this kind of proactivity
is also great when it comes
is also great when it comes to
Search.
Search. So
is also great when it comes to
Search. So now
Search. So now when
is also great when it comes to
Search. So now when you
Search. So now when you swipe
to
to the
Search. So now when you swipe
to the left
to the left of
Search. So now when you swipe
to the left of the
to the left of the H
Search. So now when you swipe
to the left of the Home
to the left of the Home screen
to
to get
to the left of the Home screen
to get to
to get to Search
to the left of the Home screen
to get to Search,
to get to Search, you
to the left of the Home screen
to get to Search, you see
to get to Search, you see that
Siri
Siri offers
to get to Search, you see that
Siri offers great
Siri offers great suggestions
to get to Search, you see that
Siri offers great suggestions,
things
things like
Siri offers great suggestions,
things like the
things like the p
Siri offers great suggestions,
things like the people
things like the people that
Siri offers great suggestions,
things like the people that you
might
might want
things like the people that you
might want to
might want to contact
things like the people that you
might want to contact now
might want to contact now base
things like the people that you
might want to contact now based
on
on your
might want to contact now based
on your upcoming
on your upcoming meetings
might want to contact now based
on your upcoming meetings a
on your upcoming meetings and
your
your communication
on your upcoming meetings and
your communication patterns
your communication patterns t
on your upcoming meetings and
your communication patterns the
apps
apps that
your communication patterns the
apps that you
apps that you m
your communication patterns the
apps that you might
apps that you might want
your communication patterns the
apps that you might want to
launch
launch base
apps that you might want to
launch based,
launch based, for
apps that you might want to
launch based, for instance,
launch based, for instance, on
what
what you
launch based, for instance, on
what you j
what you just
launch based, for instance, on
what you just download
what you just downloaded
launch based, for instance, on
what you just downloaded from
the
the App
what you just downloaded from
the App Store
the App Store and
what you just downloaded from
the App Store and haven't
the App Store and haven't tried
out
out or
the App Store and haven't tried
out or a
out or apps
the App Store and haven't tried
out or apps you
out or apps you tend
the App Store and haven't tried
out or apps you tend to
out or apps you tend to use
this
this time
out or apps you tend to use
this time of
this time of day
out or apps you tend to use
this time of day,
this time of day, o
out or apps you tend to use
this time of day, or
this time of day, or eas
out or apps you tend to use
this time of day, or easy
this time of day, or easy o
one-tap
one-tap access
this time of day, or easy o
one-tap access t
one-tap access to
this time of day, or easy o
one-tap access to links.
When
When it
one-tap access to links.
When it comes
When it comes to
one-tap access to links.
When it comes to search,
When it comes to search, we
also
also know
When it comes to search, we
also know more
also know more than
When it comes to search, we
also know more than e
also know more than ever
When it comes to search, we
also know more than ever be
before.
before. So
also know more than ever be
before. So for
before. So for instance
also know more than ever be
before. So for instance,
before. So for instance, y
also know more than ever be
before. So for instance, you
can
can search
before. So for instance, you
can search f
can search for
before. So for instance, you
can search for sports
can search for sports scores.
And
And we
can search for sports scores.
And we n
And we now
can search for sports scores.
And we now support
And we now support video
can search for sports scores.
And we now support video se
search,
search, o
And we now support video se
search, of
search, of popular
And we now support video se
search, of popular video
search, of popular video s
And we now support video se
search, of popular video sites
like
like Vivi,
search, of popular video sites
like Vivi, Vimeo,
like Vivi, Vimeo, YouTube,
search, of popular video sites
like Vivi, Vimeo, YouTube, and
the
the iTunes
like Vivi, Vimeo, YouTube, and
the iTunes Video
the iTunes Video Store.
like Vivi, Vimeo, YouTube, and
the iTunes Video Store. And
the iTunes Video Store. And we
have
have these
the iTunes Video Store. And we
have these cards
have these cards so
the iTunes Video Store. And we
have these cards so y
have these cards so you
the iTunes Video Store. And we
have these cards so you can
play
play directly
have these cards so you can
play directly f
play directly from
have these cards so you can
play directly from y
play directly from your
have these cards so you can
play directly from your search
result.
result. Most
play directly from your search
result. Most importantly
result. Most importantly,
play directly from your search
result. Most importantly, we
now
now h
result. Most importantly, we
now have
now have an
result. Most importantly, we
now have an API
now have an API for
result. Most importantly, we
now have an API for Search
now have an API for Search.
(Applause)
So
So now
(Applause)
So now when
So now when a
(Applause)
So now when a use
So now when a user
(Applause)
So now when a user performs
So now when a user performs a
search,
search, we
So now when a user performs a
search, we can
search, we can find
So now when a user performs a
search, we can find content
behind
behind the
search, we can find content
behind the apps
behind the apps they
search, we can find content
behind the apps they have
installed
installed on
behind the apps they have
installed on the
installed on the device
behind the apps they have
installed on the device and
pull
pull t
installed on the device and
pull those
pull those up
installed on the device and
pull those up i
pull those up in
installed on the device and
pull those up in R
pull those up in Results,
installed on the device and
pull those up in Results, a
pull those up in Results, and
when
when t
pull those up in Results, and
when they
when they tap
pull those up in Results, and
when they tap,
when they tap, they
pull those up in Results, and
when they tap, they are
when they tap, they are deep
linked
linked directly
when they tap, they are deep
linked directly into
linked directly into the
application
application.
linked directly into the
application. You
application. You see
linked directly into the
application. You see for
instance
instance here
application. You see for
instance here Air
instance here Air B
application. You see for
instance here Air BNB.
instance here Air BNB. They
can
can get
instance here Air BNB. They
can get their
can get their result.
instance here Air BNB. They
can get their result. Of
course
course,
can get their result. Of
course, we
course, we even
can get their result. Of
course, we even p
course, we even provide
can get their result. Of
course, we even provide a
convenient
convenient b
course, we even provide a
convenient backlink
convenient backlink so
course, we even provide a
convenient backlink so they
convenient backlink so they can
get
get right
convenient backlink so they can
get right back
get right back t
convenient backlink so they can
get right back to
get right back to their
convenient backlink so they can
get right back to their search
results.
So
So we
results.
So we think
So we think these
results.
So we think these kinds
So we think these kinds of
intelligence
intelligence features
So we think these kinds of
intelligence features really
make
make a
intelligence features really
make a huge
make a huge difference
intelligence features really
make a huge difference in
make a huge difference in your
experience
experience in
make a huge difference in your
experience in iOS
experience in iOS.
make a huge difference in your
experience in iOS. And
experience in iOS. And to
make a huge difference in your
experience in iOS. And to show
you
you how,
experience in iOS. And to show
you how, I
you how, I would
experience in iOS. And to show
you how, I would like
you how, I would like to
experience in iOS. And to show
you how, I would like to give
you
you a
you how, I would like to give
you a quick
you a quick demo
you how, I would like to give
you a quick demo now
you a quick demo now.
So
So I
So I want
So I want to
So I want to take
So I want to take you
So I want to take you through
a
a day
So I want to take you through
a day in
a day in the
So I want to take you through
a day in the life
a day in the life with
So I want to take you through
a day in the life with iOS
a day in the life with iOS 9
So I want to take you through
a day in the life with iOS 9,
and
and we
a day in the life with iOS 9,
and we are
and we are going
a day in the life with iOS 9,
and we are going to
and we are going to start
a day in the life with iOS 9,
and we are going to start with
a
a typical
and we are going to start with
a typical day
a typical day for
and we are going to start with
a typical day for me
a typical day for me today.
and we are going to start with
a typical day for me today. We
are
are g
a typical day for me today. We
are going
are going to
a typical day for me today. We
are going to start
are going to start in
a typical day for me today. We
are going to start in my
bedroom
bedroom when
are going to start in my
bedroom when I
bedroom when I woke
are going to start in my
bedroom when I woke up
bedroom when I woke up in
are going to start in my
bedroom when I woke up in the
morning.
morning. You
bedroom when I woke up in the
morning. You will
morning. You will notice
because
because my
morning. You will notice
because my phone
because my phone knows
morning. You will notice
because my phone knows in
because my phone knows in the
morning
morning I
because my phone knows in the
morning I like
morning I like to
because my phone knows in the
morning I like to meditate
morning I like to meditate that
it's
it's offered
morning I like to meditate that
it's offered me
it's offered me a
morning I like to meditate that
it's offered me a meditation
app
app right
it's offered me a meditation
app right here
app right here in
it's offered me a meditation
app right here in the
app right here in the bottom
left
left of
app right here in the bottom
left of the
left of the s
app right here in the bottom
left of the screen.
left of the screen. So
app right here in the bottom
left of the screen. So I
left of the screen. So I can
just
just swipe
left of the screen. So I can
just swipe up
just swipe up from
left of the screen. So I can
just swipe up from the
just swipe up from the bottom
left,
left, and
just swipe up from the bottom
left, and I
left, and I am
just swipe up from the bottom
left, and I am taken
left, and I am taken right
just swipe up from the bottom
left, and I am taken right in
to
to meditate.
left, and I am taken right in
to meditate. Ah,
to meditate. Ah, t
left, and I am taken right in
to meditate. Ah, this
to meditate. Ah, this is
left, and I am taken right in
to meditate. Ah, this is so
serene
serene.
to meditate. Ah, this is so
serene. Well,
serene. Well, it
to meditate. Ah, this is so
serene. Well, it looks
serene. Well, it looks l
to meditate. Ah, this is so
serene. Well, it looks like
serene. Well, it looks like I
got
got a
serene. Well, it looks like I
got a message
got a message here
serene. Well, it looks like I
got a message here from
got a message here from Phil.
So
So Phil
got a message here from Phil.
So Phil says
So Phil says that
got a message here from Phil.
So Phil says that he
So Phil says that he is
got a message here from Phil.
So Phil says that he is putting
together
together t
So Phil says that he is putting
together the
together the invite
So Phil says that he is putting
together the invite for
tonight's
tonight's b
together the invite for
tonight's big
tonight's big karaoke
together the invite for
tonight's big karaoke pot
tonight's big karaoke potluck,
and
and c
tonight's big karaoke potluck,
and can
and can I
tonight's big karaoke potluck,
and can I still
and can I still p
tonight's big karaoke potluck,
and can I still pick
and can I still pick up
tonight's big karaoke potluck,
and can I still pick up this
super
super awesome
and can I still pick up this
super awesome karaoke
super awesome karaoke machine
and can I still pick up this
super awesome karaoke machine?
Well,
Well, you
super awesome karaoke machine?
Well, you know
Well, you know,
super awesome karaoke machine?
Well, you know, Siri
Well, you know, Siri actually,
when
when I
Well, you know, Siri actually,
when I take
when I take remind
Well, you know, Siri actually,
when I take reminders,
when I take reminders, is
Well, you know, Siri actually,
when I take reminders, is a
when I take reminders, is able
to
to link
when I take reminders, is able
to link me
to link me right
when I take reminders, is able
to link me right back
to link me right back to
when I take reminders, is able
to link me right back to what
to link me right back to what I
am
am looking
to link me right back to what I
am looking for
am looking for,
to link me right back to what I
am looking for, so
am looking for, so if
to link me right back to what I
am looking for, so if I
am looking for, so if I want
to link me right back to what I
am looking for, so if I want to
remember
remember t
am looking for, so if I want to
remember to
remember to pick
am looking for, so if I want to
remember to pick this
remember to pick this up,
am looking for, so if I want to
remember to pick this up, I
remember to pick this up, I can
just
just say
remember to pick this up, I can
just say this
just say this t
remember to pick this up, I can
just say this to
just say this to Siri
remember to pick this up, I can
just say this to Siri:
just say this to Siri: "Remind
me
me about
just say this to Siri: "Remind
me about this
me about this l
just say this to Siri: "Remind
me about this later
me about this later today
just say this to Siri: "Remind
me about this later today."
And
And so
me about this later today."
And so Siri
And so Siri will
me about this later today."
And so Siri will put
And so Siri will put together
a
a reminde
And so Siri will put together
a reminder,
a reminder, and
And so Siri will put together
a reminder, and y
a reminder, and you
And so Siri will put together
a reminder, and you see
a reminder, and you see the
link
link right
a reminder, and you see the
link right back
link right back to
a reminder, and you see the
link right back to what
link right back to what I
a reminder, and you see the
link right back to what I am
looking
looking f
link right back to what I am
looking for.
Well
Well,
looking for.
Well, I
Well, I think
looking for.
Well, I think after
Well, I think after all,
meditation
meditation isn't
Well, I think after all,
meditation isn't probably
meditation isn't probably for
me,
me, so
meditation isn't probably for
me, so maybe
me, so maybe I'll
meditation isn't probably for
me, so maybe I'll m
me, so maybe I'll move
meditation isn't probably for
me, so maybe I'll move on
me, so maybe I'll move on to
exercise.
exercise. So
me, so maybe I'll move on to
exercise. So I
exercise. So I head
me, so maybe I'll move on to
exercise. So I head i
exercise. So I head into
me, so maybe I'll move on to
exercise. So I head into the
home
home g
exercise. So I head into the
home gym
home gym here,
exercise. So I head into the
home gym here, and
home gym here, and because
exercise. So I head into the
home gym here, and because my
phone
phone know
home gym here, and because my
phone knows
phone knows that
home gym here, and because my
phone knows that w
phone knows that when
home gym here, and because my
phone knows that when I
phone knows that when I am
home gym here, and because my
phone knows that when I am in
the
the home
phone knows that when I am in
the home gym
the home gym and
phone knows that when I am in
the home gym and I
the home gym and I hook
phone knows that when I am in
the home gym and I hook u
the home gym and I hook up
phone knows that when I am in
the home gym and I hook up h
headphones
headphones and
the home gym and I hook up h
headphones and I
headphones and I like
the home gym and I hook up h
headphones and I like to
headphones and I like to l
the home gym and I hook up h
headphones and I like to listen
to
to music,
headphones and I like to listen
to music, watch
to music, watch what
headphones and I like to listen
to music, watch what happens
when
when I
to music, watch what happens
when I plug
when I plug in
to music, watch what happens
when I plug in t
when I plug in the
to music, watch what happens
when I plug in the cord
when I plug in the cord of
to music, watch what happens
when I plug in the cord of my
head
headphones
when I plug in the cord of my
headphones.
headphones. Jumps
when I plug in the cord of my
headphones. Jumps right
headphones. Jumps right in
when I plug in the cord of my
headphones. Jumps right in and
offers
offers me
headphones. Jumps right in and
offers me some
offers me some e
headphones. Jumps right in and
offers me some energetic
offers me some energetic music.
So
So let's
So let's all
So let's all B
So let's all Bust
So let's all Bust a
So let's all Bust a Move
So let's all Bust a Move.
So let's all Bust a Move. I
don't
don't know
So let's all Bust a Move. I
don't know what
don't know what kind
So let's all Bust a Move. I
don't know what kind of
exercise
exercise we
don't know what kind of
exercise we are
exercise we are all
don't know what kind of
exercise we are all doing
exercise we are all doing here
don't know what kind of
exercise we are all doing here,
but
but pretty
exercise we are all doing here,
but pretty good.
Looks
Looks like
but pretty good.
Looks like actually
Looks like actually I've
but pretty good.
Looks like actually I've got
that
that invitation
Looks like actually I've got
that invitation that
that invitation that Phil
Looks like actually I've got
that invitation that Phil was
going
going to
that invitation that Phil was
going to send
going to send me
that invitation that Phil was
going to send me.
going to send me. Now
that invitation that Phil was
going to send me. Now,
going to send me. Now, n
normally
normally I
going to send me. Now, n
normally I would
normally I would have
going to send me. Now, n
normally I would have to
normally I would have to ac
actually
actually go
normally I would have to ac
actually go into
actually go into Mail,
normally I would have to ac
actually go into Mail, look
actually go into Mail, look at
the
the time
actually go into Mail, look at
the time,
the time, put
actually go into Mail, look at
the time, put this
the time, put this on
actually go into Mail, look at
the time, put this on my
Calendar
Calendar,
the time, put this on my
Calendar, but
Calendar, but in
the time, put this on my
Calendar, but in fact
Calendar, but in fact,
the time, put this on my
Calendar, but in fact, my
Calendar, but in fact, my phone
has
has a
Calendar, but in fact, my phone
has automatically
has automatically done
Calendar, but in fact, my phone
has automatically done that
has automatically done that for
me.
me. Let
has automatically done that for
me. Let me
me. Let me just
has automatically done that for
me. Let me just swipe
me. Let me just swipe down
here
here i
me. Let me just swipe down
here into
here into notifications
me. Let me just swipe down
here into notifications Center,
and
and we
here into notifications Center,
and we will
and we will look
here into notifications Center,
and we will look at
and we will look at my
here into notifications Center,
and we will look at my calendar
for
for the
and we will look at my calendar
for the day.
for the day. You
and we will look at my calendar
for the day. You notice
for the day. You notice it
automatically
automatically has
for the day. You notice it
automatically has alr
automatically has already
for the day. You notice it
automatically has already been
add
added
automatically has already been
added right
added right there.
automatically has already been
Now
added right there.
Now,
Now, if
added right there.
Now, if we
Now, if we look
added right there.
Now, if we look at
Now, if we look at the
added right there.
Now, if we look at the rest
Now, if we look at the rest of
the
the day
Now, if we look at the rest of
the day,
the day, a
Now, if we look at the rest of
the day, ahead
the day, ahead I
Now, if we look at the rest of
the day, ahead I have
the day, ahead I have my
Now, if we look at the rest of
the day, ahead I have my vocal
warm-ups
warm-ups for
the day, ahead I have my vocal
warm-ups for the
warm-ups for the karaoke
performance
performance,
warm-ups for the karaoke
performance, then
performance, then WWDC
warm-ups for the karaoke
performance, then WWDC.
It
It looks
performance, then WWDC.
It looks like
It looks like I
performance, then WWDC.
It looks like I have
It looks like I have a
performance, then WWDC.
It looks like I have a little
bit
bit of
It looks like I have a little
bit of time
bit of time to
It looks like I have a little
bit of time to prepare
bit of time to prepare my
It looks like I have a little
bit of time to prepare my dish
for
for the
bit of time to prepare my dish
for the b
for the big
bit of time to prepare my dish
for the big pot
for the big potlu
bit of time to prepare my dish
for the big potluck.
for the big potluck. So
bit of time to prepare my dish
for the big potluck. So I
for the big potluck. So I am
going
going to
for the big potluck. So I am
going to head
going to head into
for the big potluck. So I am
going to head into the
going to head into the Cechen
now,
now, and
going to head into the Cechen
now, and let's
now, and let's just
going to head into the Cechen
now, and let's just s
now, and let's just swipe
going to head into the Cechen
now, and let's just swipe in.
When
When I
now, and let's just swipe in.
When I am
When I am looking
now, and let's just swipe in.
When I am looking for
When I am looking for recipes
now, and let's just swipe in.
When I am looking for recipes,
for
for instance
When I am looking for recipes,
for instance,
for instance, I
When I am looking for recipes,
for instance, I like
for instance, I like to
When I am looking for recipes,
for instance, I like to go
for instance, I like to go into
search.
search. Let's
for instance, I like to go into
search. Let's j
search. Let's just
for instance, I like to go into
search. Let's just swipe
search. Let's just swipe o
for instance, I like to go into
search. Let's just swipe over
into
into S
search. Let's just swipe over
into Search
into Search.
search. Let's just swipe over
into Search. We
into Search. We see
search. Let's just swipe over
into Search. We see Siri
into Search. We see Siri h
search. Let's just swipe over
into Search. We see Siri has
actually
actually a
into Search. We see Siri has
actually already
actually already --
into Search. We see Siri has
actually already -- before
actually already -- before I
typed
typed a
actually already -- before I
typed a character
typed a character --
actually already -- before I
typed a character -- made
suggestions
suggestions f
typed a character -- made
suggestions for
suggestions for me
typed a character -- made
suggestions for me for
suggestions for me for people
typed a character -- made
suggestions for me for people I
could
could contact
suggestions for me for people I
could contact,
could contact, for
suggestions for me for people I
could contact, for instance,
like
like Trent
could contact, for instance,
like Trent Reznor
like Trent Reznor,
could contact, for instance,
like Trent Reznor, my
like Trent Reznor, my vocal
coach.
(Laughter)
So
So I
(Laughter)
So I can
So I can just
(Laughter)
So I can just tap.
So I can just tap. Here
(Laughter)
So I can just tap. Here I
So I can just tap. Here I can
call
call Trent
So I can just tap. Here I can
call Trent up
call Trent up,
So I can just tap. Here I can
call Trent up, and
call Trent up, and he
So I can just tap. Here I can
call Trent up, and he can
call Trent up, and he can help
me
me tap
call Trent up, and he can help
me tap into
me tap into my
call Trent up, and he can help
me tap into my inner
me tap into my inner pain
call Trent up, and he can help
me tap into my inner pain and
rage
rage that
me tap into my inner pain and
rage that allows
rage that allows me
me tap into my inner pain and
rage that allows me to
rage that allows me to f
me tap into my inner pain and
rage that allows me to fuel
rage that allows me to fuel my
vocal
vocal performances
rage that allows me to fuel my
vocal performances.
vocal performances. I
rage that allows me to fuel my
vocal performances. I actually
haven't
haven't been
vocal performances. I actually
haven't been able
haven't been able to
vocal performances. I actually
haven't been able to find
haven't been able to find the
pain
pain and
haven't been able to find the
pain and rage
pain and rage,
haven't been able to find the
pain and rage, truth
pain and rage, truth be
haven't been able to find the
pain and rage, truth be told.
Also
Also,
pain and rage, truth be told.
Also, we
Also, we have
pain and rage, truth be told.
Also, we have a
Also, we have all
pain and rage, truth be told.
Also, we have all these
Also, we have all these great
apps
apps I
Also, we have all these great
apps I can
apps I can run
Also, we have all these great
apps I can run a
apps I can run and
Also, we have all these great
apps I can run and locations
nearby
nearby --
apps I can run and locations
nearby -- for
nearby -- for instance,
apps I can run and locations
nearby -- for instance, because
it's
it's morning
nearby -- for instance, because
it's morning,
it's morning, you
nearby -- for instance, because
it's morning, you see
it's morning, you see coffee
and
and t
it's morning, you see coffee
and tea
and tea and
it's morning, you see coffee
and tea and breakfast
and tea and breakfast places
are
are suggested.
and tea and breakfast places
are suggested. As
are suggested. As well
and tea and breakfast places
are suggested. As well as
news.
news. But
are suggested. As well as
news. But in
news. But in this
are suggested. As well as
news. But in this c
news. But in this case,
are suggested. As well as
news. But in this case, I
actually
actually want
news. But in this case, I
actually want t
actually want to
news. But in this case, I
actually want to do
actually want to do a
news. But in this case, I
actually want to do a search
actually want to do a search.
So
So I
actually want to do a search.
So I have
So I have some
actually want to do a search.
So I have some potatoes
So I have some potatoes I
actually want to do a search.
So I have some potatoes I think
I
I could
So I have some potatoes I think
I could make
I could make use
So I have some potatoes I think
I could make use of
I could make use of in
So I have some potatoes I think
I could make use of in t
I could make use of in this
recipe
recipe.
I could make use of in this
recipe. So
recipe. So let's
I could make use of in this
recipe. So let's j
recipe. So let's just
I could make use of in this
recipe. So let's just search
for
for potato
recipe. So let's just search
for potato.
for potato. Here
recipe. So let's just search
for potato. Here y
for potato. Here you
recipe. So let's just search
for potato. Here you notice
for potato. Here you notice I
am
am getting
for potato. Here you notice I
am getting search
am getting search results
for potato. Here you notice I
am getting search results r
am getting search results right
from
from Y
am getting search results right
from Yummly.
from Yummly. Let
am getting search results right
from Yummly. Let me
from Yummly. Let me tap
am getting search results right
from Yummly. Let me tap into
Yummly,
Yummly, a
from Yummly. Let me tap into
Yummly, and
Yummly, and you
from Yummly. Let me tap into
Yummly, and you see
Yummly, and you see I
from Yummly. Let me tap into
Yummly, and you see I am
Yummly, and you see I am deep
linked
linked direct
Yummly, and you see I am deep
linked directly
linked directly in,
Yummly, and you see I am deep
linked directly in, so
linked directly in, so I
Yummly, and you see I am deep
linked directly in, so I get
the
the g
linked directly in, so I get
the great
the great view
linked directly in, so I get
the great view provided
the great view provided by
linked directly in, so I get
the great view provided by that
application.
Now,
Now, potato
application.
Now, potato chips
Now, potato chips aren't
exactly
exactly what
Now, potato chips aren't
exactly what I
exactly what I am
Now, potato chips aren't
exactly what I am looking
exactly what I am looking f
Now, potato chips aren't
exactly what I am looking for
exactly what I am looking for,
so
so I
exactly what I am looking for,
so I am
so I am going
exactly what I am looking for,
so I am going to
so I am going to hit
exactly what I am looking for,
so I am going to hit the
so I am going to hit the B
exactly what I am looking for,
so I am going to hit the Back
link
link here
so I am going to hit the Back
link here,
link here, and
so I am going to hit the Back
link here, and I
link here, and I can
so I am going to hit the Back
link here, and I can browse
right
right in
link here, and I can browse
right in to
right in to another
link here, and I can browse
right in to another result,
Canadian
Canadian P
right in to another result,
Canadian Poutine.
Canadian Poutine. That
right in to another result,
Canadian Poutine. That looks
exactly
exactly like
Canadian Poutine. That looks
exactly like what
exactly like what the
Canadian Poutine. That looks
exactly like what the doctor
ordered
ordered.
exactly like what the doctor
ordered. Yes
ordered. Yes.
Let's
Let's look
ordered. Yes.
Let's look at
Let's look at the
ordered. Yes.
Let's look at the ingredients.
Looks
Looks like
Let's look at the ingredients.
Looks like 6
Looks like 6 table
Let's look at the ingredients.
Looks like 6 tablespoons
Looks like 6 tablespoons o
Let's look at the ingredients.
Looks like 6 tablespoons of
unsalt
unsalted
Looks like 6 tablespoons of
unsalted butter.
unsalted butter. I
Looks like 6 tablespoons of
unsalted butter. I am
unsalted butter. I am down
with
with that
unsalted butter. I am down
with that.
with that. I
unsalted butter. I am down
with that. I am
with that. I am going
unsalted butter. I am down
with that. I am going to
with that. I am going to make
at
at least
with that. I am going to make
at least a
at least a double
with that. I am going to make
at least a double b
at least a double batch.
with that. I am going to make
at least a double batch. So
at least a double batch. So I
with that. I am going to make
can
at least a double batch. So I
can j
can just
at least a double batch. So I
can just u
can just use
at least a double batch. So I
can just use Search
can just use Search to
at least a double batch. So I
can just use Search to do
can just use Search to do a
conversion
conversion of
can just use Search to do a
conversion of t
conversion of tablespoons
can just use Search to do a
conversion of tablespoons,
figure
figure out
conversion of tablespoons,
figure out how
figure out how much
conversion of tablespoons,
figure out how much that
figure out how much that is.
So
So that
figure out how much that is.
So that actual
So that actually
figure out how much that is.
So that actually is
So that actually is 3
figure out how much that is.
So that actually is 3/4
So that actually is 3/4 of
figure out how much that is.
So that actually is 3/4 of a
cup
cup.
So that actually is 3/4 of a
cup. I
cup. I am
So that actually is 3/4 of a
cup. I am going
cup. I am going to
So that actually is 3/4 of a
cup. I am going to round
cup. I am going to round up
So that actually is 3/4 of a
cup. I am going to round up to
an
an even
cup. I am going to round up to
an even quart
an even quart and
cup. I am going to round up to
an even quart and make
an even quart and make myself
some
some fine
an even quart and make myself
some fine poutine.
(Laughter)
So
So search
(Laughter)
So search is
So search is really
(Laughter)
So search is really handy,
So search is really handy, but
Siri
Siri is
So search is really handy, but
Siri is also
Siri is also g
So search is really handy, but
Siri is also great
Siri is also great at
So search is really handy, but
Siri is also great at search.
So
So I
Siri is also great at search.
So I want
So I want to
Siri is also great at search.
So I want to jump
So I want to jump forward
Siri is also great at search.
So I want to jump forward to
later
later today.
So I want to jump forward to
later today. When
later today. When I
So I want to jump forward to
later today. When I think
later today. When I think I
will
will be
later today. When I think I
will be reminiscing
will be reminiscing about
WWDC's
WWDC's past
will be reminiscing about
WWDC's past.
WWDC's past. I
will be reminiscing about
WWDC's past. I can
WWDC's past. I can a
will be reminiscing about
WWDC's past. I can ask
WWDC's past. I can ask Siri
will be reminiscing about
WWDC's past. I can ask Siri to
help
help me
WWDC's past. I can ask Siri to
help me with
help me with that
WWDC's past. I can ask Siri to
help me with that.
help me with that. Show
WWDC's past. I can ask Siri to
help me with that. Show m
help me with that. Show my
photo
photos
help me with that. Show my
photos from
photos from last
help me with that. Show my
photos from last June
photos from last June in
help me with that. Show my
photos from last June in San
Francisco.
Francisco. O
photos from last June in San
Francisco. Oh
Francisco. Oh,
photos from last June in San
Francisco. Oh, yeah
Francisco. Oh, yeah,
photos from last June in San
Francisco. Oh, yeah, this
Francisco. Oh, yeah, this is
great
great,
Francisco. Oh, yeah, this is
great, all
great, all these
Francisco. Oh, yeah, this is
great, all these photos
great, all these photos f
Francisco. Oh, yeah, this is
great, all these photos from
WWDC
WWDC.
great, all these photos from
WWDC. You
WWDC. You n
great, all these photos from
WWDC. You notice
WWDC. You notice now
great, all these photos from
WWDC. You notice now Photos
WWDC. You notice now Photos in
iOS
iOS 9
WWDC. You notice now Photos in
iOS 9 has
iOS 9 has this
WWDC. You notice now Photos in
iOS 9 has this great
iOS 9 has this great s
WWDC. You notice now Photos in
iOS 9 has this great scrubber
bar
bar a
iOS 9 has this great scrubber
bar at
bar at the
iOS 9 has this great scrubber
bar at the b
bar at the bottom,
iOS 9 has this great scrubber
bar at the bottom, so
bar at the bottom, so I
iOS 9 has this great scrubber
bar at the bottom, so I can
easily
easily s
bar at the bottom, so I can
easily slide
easily slide through
bar at the bottom, so I can
easily slide through photos
easily
easily like
easily slide through photos
easily like this
easily like this.
easily slide through photos
easily like this. Oh,
easily like this. Oh, b
easily slide through photos
easily like this. Oh, boy,
easily like this. Oh, boy, now
we
we are
easily like this. Oh, boy, now
we are into
we are into the
easily like this. Oh, boy, now
we are into the karaoke
we are into the karaoke night
easily like this. Oh, boy, now
we are into the karaoke night.
This
This is
we are into the karaoke night.
This is s
This is some
we are into the karaoke night.
This is some fine
This is some fine stuff.
we are into the karaoke night.
This is some fine stuff. P
This is some fine stuff. Phil
really
really does
This is some fine stuff. Phil
really does an
really does an awesome
This is some fine stuff. Phil
really does an awesome V
really does an awesome Viking
croon
crooner
really does an awesome Viking
crooner.
crooner. This
really does an awesome Viking
crooner. This is
crooner. This is good
really does an awesome Viking
crooner. This is good s
crooner. This is good stuff.
But
But of
crooner. This is good stuff.
But of course
But of course,
crooner. This is good stuff.
But of course, the
But of course, the king
crooner. This is good stuff.
But of course, the king of
karaoke
karaoke --
But of course, the king of
karaoke -- (Laughter)
karaoke -- (Laughter) --
But of course, the king of
karaoke -- (Laughter) -- Eddy
Cue.
Cue. In
karaoke -- (Laughter) -- Eddy
Cue. In fact,
Cue. In fact, when
karaoke -- (Laughter) -- Eddy
Cue. In fact, when I
Cue. In fact, when I want
karaoke -- (Laughter) -- Eddy
Cue. In fact, when I want to
get
get real
Cue. In fact, when I want to
get really
get really pumped
Cue. In fact, when I want to
get really pumped up
get really pumped up and
inspired
inspired for
get really pumped up and
inspired for karaoke
inspired for karaoke n
get really pumped up and
inspired for karaoke night
inspired for karaoke night,
get really pumped up and
inspired for karaoke night, I
like
like to
inspired for karaoke night, I
like to turn
like to turn to
inspired for karaoke night, I
like to turn to my
like to turn to my Eddy
inspired for karaoke night, I
like to turn to my Eddy karaoke
album
album,
like to turn to my Eddy karaoke
album, so
album, so let's
like to turn to my Eddy karaoke
album, so let's do
album, so let's do that
like to turn to my Eddy karaoke
album, so let's do that now
album, so let's do that now.
Show
Show my
album, so let's do that now.
Show my karaoke
Show my karaoke photo
album, so let's do that now.
Show my karaoke photos
Show my karaoke photos o
album, so let's do that now.
Show my karaoke photos of
Show my karaoke photos of Eddy
album, so let's do that now.
Show my karaoke photos of E
Eddy.
Oh
Oh,
Eddy.
Oh, that
Oh, that is
Eddy.
Oh, that is the
Oh, that is the mast
Eddy.
Oh, that is the master
Oh, that is the master at
work.
work. Hitting
Oh, that is the master at
work. Hitting --
work. Hitting -- I
Oh, that is the master at
work. Hitting -- I love
work. Hitting -- I love t
Oh, that is the master at
work. Hitting -- I love this
hat.
(Laughter)
This
This is
(Laughter)
This is totally
This is totally d
(Laughter)
This is totally dope
This is totally dope.
(Laughter)
This is totally dope. G
This is totally dope. Great
stuff.
stuff. Well
This is totally dope. Great
stuff. Well,
stuff. Well, I
This is totally dope. Great
stuff. Well, I could
stuff. Well, I could r
This is totally dope. Great
stuff. Well, I could really
look
look a
stuff. Well, I could really
look at
look at these
stuff. Well, I could really
look at these just
look at these just all
stuff. Well, I could really
look at these just all day,
look at these just all day, but
you
you know,
look at these just all day, but
you know, actual
you know, actually,
look at these just all day, but
you know, actually, my
assistant
assistant has
you know, actually, my
assistant has given
assistant has given me
you know, actually, my
assistant has given me a
reminder
reminder based
assistant has given me a
reminder based on
reminder based on traffic
conditions
conditions that
reminder based on traffic
conditions that it's
conditions that it's time
reminder based on traffic
conditions that it's time t
conditions that it's time to
leave,
leave, s
conditions that it's time to
leave, so
leave, so I
conditions that it's time to
leave, so I am
leave, so I am going
conditions that it's time to
leave, so I am going to
leave, so I am going to w
conditions that it's time to
leave, so I am going to wrap
leave, so I am going to wrap up
this
this demo
leave, so I am going to wrap up
this demo of
this demo of intelligence
leave, so I am going to wrap up
this demo of intelligence on
iOS
iOS 9
this demo of intelligence on
iOS 9.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
iOS 9.
(Cheers and applause)
So
So you've
(Cheers and applause)
So you've seen
So you've seen how
(Cheers and applause)
So you've seen how we've
So you've seen how we've been
able
able to
So you've seen how we've been
able to bring
able to bring intelligence
throughout
throughout t
able to bring intelligence
throughout the
throughout the e
able to bring intelligence
throughout the experience
throughout the experience in
iOS
iOS 9,
throughout the experience in
iOS 9, but
iOS 9, but we
throughout the experience in
iOS 9, but we d
iOS 9, but we do
throughout the experience in
iOS 9, but we do it
iOS 9, but we do it in
throughout the experience in
iOS 9, but we do it in a
iOS 9, but we do it in a w
throughout the experience in
iOS 9, but we do it in a way
that
that does
iOS 9, but we do it in a way
that does not
that does not compromise
iOS 9, but we do it in a way
that does not compromise your
privacy
privacy.
that does not compromise your
privacy. W
privacy. We
that does not compromise your
privacy. We don't
privacy. We don't mine
that does not compromise your
privacy. We don't mine y
privacy. We don't mine your
email,
email, your
privacy. We don't mine your
email, your photo
email, your photos
privacy. We don't mine your
email, your photos,
email, your photos, or
privacy. We don't mine your
email, your photos, or your
contacts
contacts in
email, your photos, or your
contacts in the
contacts in the cloud
email, your photos, or your
contacts in the cloud to
contacts in the cloud to learn
things
things about
contacts in the cloud to learn
things about you
things about you.
contacts in the cloud to learn
things about you. We
things about you. We h
contacts in the cloud to learn
things about you. We honestly
just
just don't
things about you. We honestly
just don't want
just don't want t
things about you. We honestly
just don't want to
just don't want to know
things about you. We honestly
just don't want to know.
just don't want to know. All
of
of t
just don't want to know. All
of this
of this i
just don't want to know. All
of this is
of this is done
just don't want to know. All
of this is done on
of this is done on device,
just don't want to know. All
of this is done on device, a
of this is done on device, and
it
it stays
of this is done on device, and
it stays on
it stays on device,
of this is done on device, and
it stays on device, under
it stays on device, under your
control.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
control.
(Cheers and applause)
And
And if
(Cheers and applause)
And if we
And if we do
(Cheers and applause)
And if we do have
And if we do have to
(Cheers and applause)
And if we do have to p
And if we do have to perform
(Cheers and applause)
And if we do have to perform a
lookup
lookup for
And if we do have to perform a
lookup for you,
lookup for you, for
And if we do have to perform a
lookup for you, for example
lookup for you, for example,
traffic
traffic d
lookup for you, for example,
traffic directions,
traffic directions, it's
anonymous
anonymous,
traffic directions, it's
anonymous, n
anonymous, not
traffic directions, it's
anonymous, not associated
anonymous, not associated with
Apple
Apple ID,
anonymous, not associated with
Apple ID, not
Apple ID, not link
anonymous, not associated with
Apple ID, not linked
Apple ID, not linked w
anonymous, not associated with
Apple ID, not linked with
Apple ID, not linked with other
Apple
Apple services,
Apple ID, not linked with other
Apple services, and
Apple services, and it's
Apple ID, not linked with other
Apple services, and it's not
shared
shared with
Apple services, and it's not
shared with other
shared with other parties.
Apple services, and it's not
shared with other parties. Why
would
would do
shared with other parties. Why
would do you
would do you that
shared with other parties. Why
would do you that?
would do you that? It
shared with other parties. Why
would do you that? It is
would do you that? It is in
your
your control
would do you that? It is in
your control.
your control. That
would do you that? It is in
your control. That is
intelligence
intelligence in
your control. That is
intelligence in iOS
intelligence in iOS 9
your control. That is
intelligence in iOS 9.
(Applause)
Next,
Next, let's
(Applause)
Next, let's turn
Next, let's turn to
(Applause)
Next, let's turn to Apple
Next, let's turn to Apple Pay.
And
And to
Next, let's turn to Apple Pay.
And to take
And to take y
Next, let's turn to Apple Pay.
And to take you
And to take you through
Next, let's turn to Apple Pay.
And to take you through it,
I'd
I'd like
And to take you through it,
I'd like to
I'd like to bring
And to take you through it,
I'd like to bring to
I'd like to bring to the
And to take you through it,
I'd like to bring to the stage
our
our Vice
I'd like to bring to the stage
our Vice President
our Vice President of
I'd like to bring to the stage
our Vice President of o
our Vice President of our
I'd like to bring to the stage
our Vice President of our Apple
Pay
Pay business,
our Vice President of our Apple
Pay business, J
Pay business, Jennifer
our Vice President of our Apple
Pay business, Jennifer Bailey
Pay business, Jennifer Bailey.
our Vice President of our Apple
Jennifer.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
Jennifer.
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> JENNIFER
(Cheers and applause)
>> JENNIFER BAILEY:
>> JENNIFER BAILEY: Thanks
(Cheers and applause)
>> JENNIFER BAILEY: Thanks,
Craig
Craig.
>> JENNIFER BAILEY: Thanks,
Craig. It's
Craig. It's great
>> JENNIFER BAILEY: Thanks,
Craig. It's great to
Craig. It's great to be
>> JENNIFER BAILEY: Thanks,
Craig. It's great to be here
Craig. It's great to be here.
We
We have
We have been
We have been hard
We have been hard at
We have been hard at work
We have been hard at work on
our
our goal
We have been hard at work on
our goal of
our goal of replacing
We have been hard at work on
our goal of replacing the
wallet,
wallet, and
our goal of replacing the
wallet, and we've
wallet, and we've g
our goal of replacing the
wallet, and we've got
wallet, and we've got some
exciting
exciting u
wallet, and we've got some
exciting updates
exciting updates for
wallet, and we've got some
exciting updates for you
exciting updates for you today.
I
I hope
exciting updates for you today.
I hope you've
I hope you've all
exciting updates for you today.
I hope you've all tried
I hope you've all tried Apple
Pay
Pay w
I hope you've all tried Apple
Pay with
Pay with our
I hope you've all tried Apple
Pay with our super
Pay with our super eas
I hope you've all tried Apple
Pay with our super easy,
secure,
secure, and
Pay with our super easy,
secure, and private
secure, and private way
Pay with our super easy,
secure, and private way t
secure, and private way to
Pay with our super easy,
secure, and private way to pay
secure, and private way to pay.
Last
Last year
Last year we
Last year we started
Last year we started with
credit
credit and
Last year we started with
credit and debit
credit and debit cards,
Last year we started with
credit and debit cards, and
credit and debit cards, and we
now
now h
credit and debit cards, and we
now have
now have over
credit and debit cards, and we
now have over 25
now have over 2500
credit and debit cards, and we
now have over 2500 banks
supporting
supporting A
now have over 2500 banks
supporting Apple
supporting Apple P
now have over 2500 banks
supporting Apple Pay.
supporting Apple Pay. And
now have over 2500 banks
supporting Apple Pay. And this
fall,
fall, Discover
supporting Apple Pay. And this
fall, Discover will
fall, Discover will bring
supporting Apple Pay. And this
fall, Discover will bring Apple
Pay
Pay t
fall, Discover will bring Apple
Pay to
Pay to the
fall, Discover will bring Apple
Pay to the more
Pay to the more than
fall, Discover will bring Apple
Pay to the more than 50
Pay to the more than 50 million
card
card members
Pay to the more than 50 million
card members.
(Applause)
Popular
Popular merchants
(Applause)
Popular merchants are
Popular merchants are also
expanding
expanding their
Popular merchants are also
expanding their acceptance
expanding their acceptance for
Apple
Apple Pay,
expanding their acceptance for
Apple Pay, including
Apple Pay, including great
retail
retailer
Apple Pay, including great
retailers
retailers who
Apple Pay, including great
retailers who w
retailers who will
Apple Pay, including great
retailers who will be
retailers who will be sup
Apple Pay, including great
supporting
retailers who will be sup
supporting Apple
supporting Apple Pay
retailers who will be sup
supporting Apple Pay this
supporting Apple Pay this year,
including
including T
supporting Apple Pay this year,
including Trader
including Trader Joe's
supporting Apple Pay this year,
including Trader Joe's,
Baskin-Robbins,
Baskin-Robbins, and
including Trader Joe's,
Baskin-Robbins, and JC
Baskin-Robbins, and JC penny's
these
these incredible
Baskin-Robbins, and JC penny's
these incredible brands
these incredible brands join
Baskin-Robbins, and JC penny's
these incredible brands join a
great
great list
these incredible brands join a
great list of
great list of the
these incredible brands join a
great list of the biggest
great list of the biggest and
best
best merchants
great list of the biggest and
best merchants supporting
best merchants supporting A
great list of the biggest and
best merchants supporting Apple
Pay
Pay since
best merchants supporting Apple
Pay since o
Pay since our
best merchants supporting Apple
Pay since our launch
Pay since our launch in
best merchants supporting Apple
Pay since our launch in Oct
October.
And
And for
October.
And for you
And for you are
October.
And for you are basketball
fans,
fans, if
And for you are basketball
fans, if you
fans, if you are
And for you are basketball
fans, if you are luck
fans, if you are lucky
And for you are basketball
fans, if you are lucky enough
to
to h
fans, if you are lucky enough
to have
to have Finals
fans, if you are lucky enough
to have Finals tickets,
to have Finals tickets, you
will
will be
to have Finals tickets, you
will be able
will be able to
to have Finals tickets, you
will be able to pay
will be able to pay for
to have Finals tickets, you
will be able to pay for all
your
your team
will be able to pay for all
your team logo
your team logo wear
will be able to pay for all
your team logo wear at
your team logo wear at both
arena
arenas
your team logo wear at both
arenas using
arenas using Apple
your team logo wear at both
arenas using Apple Pay
arenas using Apple Pay.
(Applause)
Small
Small b
(Applause)
Small businesses
Small businesses are
(Applause)
Small businesses are also
important
important for
Small businesses are also
important for us,
important for us, so
Small businesses are also
important for us, so w
important for us, so we
Small businesses are also
important for us, so we are
working
working w
important for us, so we are
working with
working with innovative
companies
companies l
working with innovative
companies like
companies like Square
working with innovative
companies like Square t
companies like Square to
working with innovative
companies like Square to enable
millions
millions of
companies like Square to enable
millions of small
millions of small businesses
companies like Square to enable
millions of small businesses to
accept
accept Apple
millions of small businesses to
accept Apple Pay.
accept Apple Pay. This
millions of small businesses to
accept Apple Pay. This fall,
Square
Square will
accept Apple Pay. This fall,
Square will launch
Square will launch a
accept Apple Pay. This fall,
Square will launch a gorgeous
new
new r
Square will launch a gorgeous
new read
new reader.
Square will launch a gorgeous
new reader. Preorders
new reader. Preorders are
start
starting
new reader. Preorders are
starting t
starting today
new reader. Preorders are
starting today on
starting today on square
new reader. Preorders are
starting today on square.com,
and
and these
starting today on square.com,
and these will
and these will be
starting today on square.com,
and these will be a
and these will be available
starting today on square.com,
and these will be available in
our
our Apple
and these will be available in
our Apple Retail
our Apple Retail S
and these will be available in
our Apple Retail Stores
starting
starting this
our Apple Retail Stores
starting this fall.
Wi
With
starting this fall.
With fantastic
With fantastic support
starting this fall.
With fantastic support of
merchants,
merchants, b
With fantastic support of
merchants, both
merchants, both large
With fantastic support of
merchants, both large and
small,
small, we
merchants, both large and
small, we will
small, we will surpass
merchants, both large and
small, we will surpass 1
million
million location
small, we will surpass 1
million locations
million locations accepting
Apple
Apple Pay
million locations accepting
Apple Pay next
Apple Pay next month.
(Applause)
And
And thanks
(Applause)
And thanks t
And thanks to
(Applause)
And thanks to our
And thanks to our amazing
developers,
developers, we
And thanks to our amazing
developers, we have
developers, we have great
momentum
momentum w
developers, we have great
momentum within
momentum within apps
developers, we have great
momentum within apps as
momentum within apps as well
developers, we have great
momentum within apps as well.
Apple
Apple P
momentum within apps as well.
Apple Pay
Apple Pay is
momentum within apps as well.
Apple Pay is so
Apple Pay is so easy
momentum within apps as well.
Apple Pay is so easy to
Apple Pay is so easy to use
momentum within apps as well.
Apple Pay is so easy to use i
Apple Pay is so easy to use in
app
app,
Apple Pay is so easy to use in
app, our
app, our developers
Apple Pay is so easy to use in
app, our developers are
app, our developers are telling
us
us they
app, our developers are telling
us they are
us they are seeing
app, our developers are telling
us they are seeing more
us they are seeing more t
app, our developers are telling
us they are seeing more than
two
two times
us they are seeing more than
two times increase
two times increase in
us they are seeing more than
two times increase in checkout
rates.
rates. And
two times increase in checkout
rates. And we
rates. And we are
two times increase in checkout
rates. And we are adding
rates. And we are adding n
two times increase in checkout
rates. And we are adding new
apps
apps w
rates. And we are adding new
apps with
apps with Apple
rates. And we are adding new
apps with Apple P
apps with Apple Pay
rates. And we are adding new
apps with Apple Pay to
apps with Apple Pay to the
rates. And we are adding new
apps with Apple Pay to the App
Store
Store every
apps with Apple Pay to the App
Store every d
Store every day.
apps with Apple Pay to the App
Store every day. Here
Store every day. Here are
apps with Apple Pay to the App
Store every day. Here are some
of
of the
Store every day. Here are some
of the latest
of the latest,
Store every day. Here are some
of the latest, represent
of the latest, representing
Store every day. Here are some
of the latest, representing a
great
great range
of the latest, representing a
great range of
great range of categories
of the latest, representing a
great range of categories,
great range of categories, from
Delta
Delta in
great range of categories, from
Delta in t
Delta in travel
great range of categories, from
Delta in travel to
Delta in travel to Etsy
great range of categories, from
Delta in travel to Etsy,
Delta in travel to Etsy, the
leading
leading c
Delta in travel to Etsy, the
leading crafts
leading crafts marketplace
Delta in travel to Etsy, the
leading crafts marketplace.
These
These apps
leading crafts marketplace.
These apps join
These apps join an
leading crafts marketplace.
These apps join an incredible
group
group that
These apps join an incredible
group that are
group that are redefining
These apps join an incredible
group that are redefining new
and
and simpler
group that are redefining new
and simpler ways
and simpler ways to
group that are redefining new
and simpler ways to p
and simpler ways to pay
group that are redefining new
and simpler ways to pay.
We're
We're also
and simpler ways to pay.
We're also excited
We're also excited t
and simpler ways to pay.
We're also excited to
We're also excited to be
working
working w
We're also excited to be
working with
working with Pinterest
We're also excited to be
working with Pinterest.
working with Pinterest. L
We're also excited to be
working with Pinterest. Late
working with Pinterest. Later
this
this month,
working with Pinterest. Later
this month, Pinterest
this month, Pinterest will
launch
launch Buyable
this month, Pinterest will
launch Buyable Pins,
launch Buyable Pins, where
this month, Pinterest will
launch Buyable Pins, where you
will
will be
launch Buyable Pins, where you
will be able
will be able to
launch Buyable Pins, where you
will be able to buy
will be able to buy items
launch Buyable Pins, where you
will be able to buy items from
thousands
thousands of
will be able to buy items from
thousands of s
thousands of stores,
will be able to buy items from
thousands of stores, including
Niemann
Niemann Marcus
thousands of stores, including
Niemann Marcus and
Niemann Marcus and Macy
thousands of stores, including
Niemann Marcus and Macy's
Niemann Marcus and Macy's,
right
right from
Niemann Marcus and Macy's,
right from within
right from within the
Niemann Marcus and Macy's,
right from within the Pinterest
app
app using
right from within the Pinterest
app using A
app using Apple
right from within the Pinterest
app using Apple Pay,
app using Apple Pay, and
right from within the Pinterest
app using Apple Pay, and o
app using Apple Pay, and only
on
on iOS
app using Apple Pay, and only
on iOS.
(Applause)
Wi
With
(Applause)
With the
With the great
(Applause)
With the great momentum
With the great momentum of
Apple
Apple P
With the great momentum of
Apple Pay
Apple Pay in
With the great momentum of
Apple Pay in the
Apple Pay in the U.S.,
With the great momentum of
Apple Pay in the U.S., we
Apple Pay in the U.S., we are
now
now excited
Apple Pay in the U.S., we are
now excited to
now excited to announce
Apple Pay in the U.S., we are
now excited to announce that
now excited to announce that we
are
are bringing
now excited to announce that we
are bringing Apple
are bringing Apple Pay
now excited to announce that we
are bringing Apple Pay to
are bringing Apple Pay to the
UK.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
UK.
(Cheers and applause)
And
And it's
(Cheers and applause)
And it's coming
And it's coming next
(Cheers and applause)
And it's coming next month
And it's coming next month!
(Applause)
We
We will
(Applause)
We will launch
We will launch with
(Applause)
We will launch with eight
We will launch with eight of
the
the most
We will launch with eight of
the most popular
the most popular b
We will launch with eight of
the most popular banks
the most popular banks,
We will launch with eight of
the most popular banks, with
more
more c
the most popular banks, with
more coming
more coming t
the most popular banks, with
more coming this
more coming this fall.
the most popular banks, with
more coming this fall. With
this
this great
more coming this fall. With
this great line
this great lineup
more coming this fall. With
this great lineup of
this great lineup of banks,
more coming this fall. With
this great lineup of banks, we
will
will support
this great lineup of banks, we
will support more
will support more than
this great lineup of banks, we
will support more than 70
will support more than 70%
this great lineup of banks, we
will support more than 70% of
the
the credit
will support more than 70% of
the credit and
the credit and debit
will support more than 70% of
the credit and debit cards
the credit and debit cards in
the
the UK.
Great
Great merchants
the UK.
Great merchants are
Great merchants are also
lining
lining up
Great merchants are also
lining up to
lining up to support
Great merchants are also
lining up to support Apple
lining up to support Apple P
Great merchants are also
lining up to support Apple Pay,
like
like Boots
lining up to support Apple Pay,
like Boots,
like Boots, Costa
lining up to support Apple Pay,
like Boots, Costa coffee
like Boots, Costa coffee,
lining up to support Apple Pay,
like Boots, Costa coffee, and
icon
iconic
like Boots, Costa coffee, and
iconic British
iconic British b
like Boots, Costa coffee, and
iconic British brands
iconic British brands,
like Boots, Costa coffee, and
iconic British brands, like
Mark
Marks
iconic British brands, like
Marks a
Marks and
iconic British brands, like
Marks and Spencer
Marks and Spencer,
iconic British brands, like
Marks and Spencer, and
Waitrose.
Waitrose. We
Marks and Spencer, and
Waitrose. We will
Waitrose. We will have
Marks and Spencer, and
Waitrose. We will have over
250,000
250,000 location
Waitrose. We will have over
250,000 locations
250,000 locations supporting
Apple
Apple Pay
250,000 locations supporting
Apple Pay in
Apple Pay in the
250,000 locations supporting
Apple Pay in the U
Apple Pay in the UK.
250,000 locations supporting
Apple Pay in the UK. That's
more
more than
Apple Pay in the UK. That's
more than we
more than we s
Apple Pay in the UK. That's
more than we started
more than we started with
Apple Pay in the UK. That's
more than we started with i
more than we started with in
the
the U.S.
more than we started with in
the U.S. w
the U.S. with
more than we started with in
the U.S. with our
the U.S. with our initial
launch.
launch. We
the U.S. with our initial
launch. We are
launch. We are also
the U.S. with our initial
launch. We are also thrilled
that
that our
launch. We are also thrilled
that our c
that our customers
launch. We are also thrilled
that our customers will
that our customers will be
launch. We are also thrilled
that our customers will be able
to
to commute
that our customers will be able
to commute and
to commute and pay
that our customers will be able
to commute and pay for
to commute and pay for their
fares
fares o
to commute and pay for their
fares on
fares on the
to commute and pay for their
fares on the L
fares on the London
transportation
transportation system
fares on the London
transportation system with
Apple
Apple Pay.
(Applause)
So
So that's
(Applause)
So that's A
So that's Apple
(Applause)
So that's Apple Pay
So that's Apple Pay coming
(Applause)
So that's Apple Pay coming to
the
the UK.
No
Now
the UK.
Now let's
Now let's talk
the UK.
Now let's talk about
Now let's talk about some
the UK.
Now let's talk about some of
the
the new
Now let's talk about some of
the new features
the new features that
Now let's talk about some of
the new features that we
the new features that we are
adding
adding in
the new features that we are
adding in iOS
adding in iOS 9.
the new features that we are
adding in iOS 9. First,
adding in iOS 9. First, you
will
will be
adding in iOS 9. First, you
will be able
will be able to
adding in iOS 9. First, you
will be able to add
will be able to add your
adding in iOS 9. First, you
will be able to add your store
will be able to add your store,
credit
credit,
will be able to add your store,
credit, and
credit, and debit
will be able to add your store,
credit, and debit cards.
credit, and debit cards. Store
cards
cards offer
credit, and debit cards. Store
cards offer unique
cards offer unique membership
benefits
benefits,
cards offer unique membership
benefits, and
benefits, and leading
cards offer unique membership
benefits, and leading retail
benefits, and leading retailers
like
like Kohl's,
benefits, and leading retailers
like Kohl's, JCPenney
like Kohl's, JCPenney,
benefits, and leading retailers
like Kohl's, JCPenney, and
like Kohl's, JCPenney, and B
benefits, and leading retailers
like Kohl's, JCPenney, and BJs
will
will be
like Kohl's, JCPenney, and BJs
will be the
will be the first
like Kohl's, JCPenney, and BJs
will be the first to
will be the first to offer
their
their cards
will be the first to offer
their cards on
their cards on Apple
will be the first to offer
their cards on Apple Pay
their cards on Apple Pay.
will be the first to offer
their cards on Apple Pay. We
will
will also
their cards on Apple Pay. We
will also add
will also add loyalty
their cards on Apple Pay. We
will also add loyalty and
rewards
rewards cards,
will also add loyalty and
rewards cards, also
rewards cards, also with
will also add loyalty and
rewards cards, also with a
great
great line
rewards cards, also with a
great lineup
great lineup of
rewards cards, also with a
great lineup of merchants
great lineup of merchants.
Kohl's
Kohl's will
great lineup of merchants.
Kohl's will bring
Kohl's will bring Yes2You
programs
programs,
Kohl's will bring Yes2You
programs, Walgreens
programs, Walgreens their
Balance
Balance Rewards
programs, Walgreens their
Balance Rewards c
Balance Rewards card,
programs, Walgreens their
Balance Rewards card, and
Balance Rewards card, and f
programs, Walgreens their
Balance Rewards card, and for
your
your coffee
Balance Rewards card, and for
your coffee and
your coffee and d
Balance Rewards card, and for
your coffee and doughnut
your coffee and doughnut lovers
Balance Rewards card, and for
your coffee and doughnut lo
lovers,
lovers, Dunkin'
your coffee and doughnut lo
lovers, Dunkin' Donuts
lovers, Dunkin' Donuts will
bring
bring Apple
lovers, Dunkin' Donuts will
bring Apple Pay
bring Apple Pay t
lovers, Dunkin' Donuts will
bring Apple Pay to
bring Apple Pay to their
DDPerks
DDPerks beginning
bring Apple Pay to their
DDPerks beginning this
DDPerks beginning this f
bring Apple Pay to their
DDPerks beginning this fall.
(Applause)
(Applause) and
DDPerks beginning this fall.
(Applause) and Apple
(Applause) and Apple Pay
automatically
automatically p
(Applause) and Apple Pay
automatically presents
automatically presents the
right
right card,
automatically presents the
right card, so
right card, so you
automatically presents the
right card, so you will
right card, so you will never
miss
miss a
right card, so you will never
miss a reward
miss a reward.
Wi
With
miss a reward.
With the
With the expansion
miss a reward.
With the expansion of
With the expansion of A
miss a reward.
With the expansion of Apple
Pay
Pay and
With the expansion of Apple
Pay and the
Pay and the new
With the expansion of Apple
Pay and the new types
Pay and the new types of
With the expansion of Apple
Pay and the new types of cards,
we
we decided
Pay and the new types of cards,
we decided i
we decided it's
Pay and the new types of cards,
we decided it's time
we decided it's time t
Pay and the new types of cards,
we decided it's time to
we decided it's time to rename
Passbook
Passbook to
we decided it's time to rename
Passbook to Wallet
Passbook to Wallet.
(Applause)
On
One
(Applause)
One place
One place for
(Applause)
One place for all
One place for all your
(Applause)
One place for all your c
One place for all your credit
and
and d
One place for all your credit
and debit
and debit cards
One place for all your credit
and debit cards,
and debit cards, loyalty
One place for all your credit
and debit cards, loyalty cards
and debit cards, loyalty cards,
boarding
boarding passes
and debit cards, loyalty cards,
boarding passes,
boarding passes, and
and debit cards, loyalty cards,
boarding passes, and m
boarding passes, and more.
and debit cards, loyalty cards,
boarding passes, and more. W
boarding passes, and more. We
told
told you
boarding passes, and more. We
told you last
told you last year
boarding passes, and more. We
told you last year that
told you last year that our
ultimate
ultimate goal
told you last year that our
ultimate goal was
ultimate goal was to
told you last year that our
ultimate goal was to r
ultimate goal was to replace
the
the wallet
ultimate goal was to replace
the wallet,
the wallet, and
ultimate goal was to replace
the wallet, and we
the wallet, and we are
ultimate goal was to replace
the wallet, and we are well
the wallet, and we are well on
the
the way
the wallet, and we are well on
the way to
the way to doing
the wallet, and we are well on
the way to doing just
the way to doing just that
the wallet, and we are well on
the way to doing just that.
the way to doing just that. We
couldn't
couldn't b
the way to doing just that. We
couldn't be
couldn't be h
the way to doing just that. We
couldn't be happy
couldn't be happier
the way to doing just that. We
couldn't be happier with
couldn't be happier with the
progress
progress t
couldn't be happier with the
progress towards
progress towards our
couldn't be happier with the
progress towards our v
progress towards our vision
couldn't be happier with the
progress towards our vision and
with
with the
progress towards our vision and
with the momentum
with the momentum of
progress towards our vision and
with the momentum of Apple
with the momentum of Apple P
progress towards our vision and
with the momentum of Apple Pay.
Tha
Thank
with the momentum of Apple Pay.
Thank you.
(Applause)
>>
>> CRAIG
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI:
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: So
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: So that's
Apple
Apple Pay.
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: So that's
Apple Pay. Let's
Apple Pay. Let's turn
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: So that's
Apple Pay. Let's turn now
Apple Pay. Let's turn now to
our
our enhancements
Apple Pay. Let's turn now to
our enhancements to
our enhancements to the
Apple Pay. Let's turn now to
our enhancements to the apps
you
you u
our enhancements to the apps
you use
you use most,
our enhancements to the apps
you use most, and
you use most, and we
our enhancements to the apps
you use most, and we are
you use most, and we are going
to
to start
you use most, and we are going
to start with
to start with N
you use most, and we are going
to start with Notes.
to start with Notes. Notes
you use most, and we are going
to start with Notes. Notes is
used
used regular
to start with Notes. Notes is
used regularly
used regularly by
to start with Notes. Notes is
used regularly by about
used regularly by about half
to start with Notes. Notes is
used regularly by about half of
our
our use
used regularly by about half of
our users
our users on
used regularly by about half of
our users on iPhone
our users on iPhone,
used regularly by about half of
our users on iPhone, and
our users on iPhone, and for
iOS
iOS 9
our users on iPhone, and for
iOS 9,
iOS 9, we
our users on iPhone, and for
iOS 9, we have
iOS 9, we have some
our users on iPhone, and for
iOS 9, we have some really
great
great enhancements
iOS 9, we have some really
great enhancements.
great enhancements. It
iOS 9, we have some really
great enhancements. It starts
with
with how
great enhancements. It starts
with how you
with how you work
great enhancements. It starts
with how you work with
with how you work with simple
text.
text. So
with how you work with simple
text. So n
text. So now
with how you work with simple
text. So now Notes
text. So now Notes provides
with how you work with simple
text. So now Notes provides a
really
really h
text. So now Notes provides a
really hand
really handy
text. So now Notes provides a
really handy tool
really handy toolba
text. So now Notes provides a
really handy toolbar
really handy toolbar with
formatting
formatting options
really handy toolbar with
formatting options,
formatting options, so
really handy toolbar with
formatting options, so it's
easy
easy,
formatting options, so it's
easy, f
easy, for
formatting options, so it's
easy, for instance,
easy, for instance, t
formatting options, so it's
easy, for instance, to
easy, for instance, to create
titles
titles,
easy, for instance, to create
titles, heading
titles, heading s
easy, for instance, to create
titles, heading styles
titles, heading styles,
easy, for instance, to create
titles, heading styles, numbe
titles, heading styles, nu
numbered
numbered lists.
titles, heading styles, nu
numbered lists. But
numbered lists. But of
titles, heading styles, nu
numbered lists. But of c
numbered lists. But of course,
we
we all
numbered lists. But of course,
we all like
we all like to
numbered lists. But of course,
we all like to create
checklists
checklists in
we all like to create
checklists in our
checklists in our notes,
we all like to create
checklists in our notes, a
checklists in our notes, and
we all like to create
checklists in our notes, and so
Notes
Notes makes
checklists in our notes, and so
Notes makes that
Notes makes that really
checklists in our notes, and so
Notes makes that really easy
Notes makes that really easy.
And
And o
Notes makes that really easy.
And of
And of course,
Notes makes that really easy.
And of course, you
And of course, you can
Notes makes that really easy.
And of course, you can just
check
check off
And of course, you can just
check off your
check off your items
And of course, you can just
check off your items with
check off your items with just
a
a tap.
Now,
Now, because
a tap.
Now, because a
Now, because a picture
a tap.
Now, because a picture is
worth
worth a
Now, because a picture is
worth a thousand
worth a thousand words,
Now, because a picture is
worth a thousand words, w
worth a thousand words, we
Now, because a picture is
worth a thousand words, we make
it
it easy
worth a thousand words, we make
it easy to
it easy to get
worth a thousand words, we make
it easy to get at
it easy to get at y
worth a thousand words, we make
it easy to get at your
it easy to get at your camera
and
and your
it easy to get at your camera
and your camera
and your camera roll
it easy to get at your camera
and your camera roll and
and your camera roll and p
it easy to get at your camera
and your camera roll and put
photo
photos
and your camera roll and put
photos directly
photos directly in
and your camera roll and put
photos directly in your
photos directly in your Notes
and your camera roll and put
photos directly in your Notes.
We
We are
We are also
We are also providing
We are also providing a
We are also providing a great
new
new way
We are also providing a great
new way to
new way to capture
We are also providing a great
new way to capture your
new way to capture your ideas
by
by just
new way to capture your ideas
by just drawing
by just drawing with
new way to capture your ideas
by just drawing with your
finger.
finger. We
by just drawing with your
finger. We provide
finger. We provide some
by just drawing with your
finger. We provide some great
drawing
drawing tools
finger. We provide some great
drawing tools.
drawing tools. You
finger. We provide some great
drawing tools. You can
drawing tools. You can make
sketches
sketches w
drawing tools. You can make
sketches with
sketches with these
drawing tools. You can make
sketches with these tools
sketches with these tools and
drop
drop them
sketches with these tools and
drop them right
drop them right inside
sketches with these tools and
drop them right inside your
note.
(Applause)
Now,
Now, I
(Applause)
Now, I don't
Now, I don't know
(Applause)
Now, I don't know if
Now, I don't know if you
(Applause)
Now, I don't know if you are
like
like me
Now, I don't know if you are
like me,
like me, but
Now, I don't know if you are
like me, but a
like me, but a lot
Now, I don't know if you are
like me, but a lot of
like me, but a lot of times
Now, I don't know if you are
like me, but a lot of times the
things
things I
like me, but a lot of times the
things I want
things I want to
like me, but a lot of times the
things I want to put
things I want to put o
like me, but a lot of times the
things I want to put on
things I want to put on my
notes
notes are
things I want to put on my
notes are things
notes are things I
things I want to put on my
notes are things I am
notes are things I am looking
at
at that
notes are things I am looking
at that I
at that I find
notes are things I am looking
at that I find in
at that I find in o
notes are things I am looking
at that I find in other
at that I find in other apps
notes are things I am looking
at that I find in other apps --
for
for instance,
at that I find in other apps --
for instance, a
for instance, a webpage
at that I find in other apps --
for instance, a webpage i
for instance, a webpage in
Safari
Safari.
for instance, a webpage in
Safari. S
Safari. So
for instance, a webpage in
Safari. So now
Safari. So now from
for instance, a webpage in
Safari. So now from the
Safari. So now from the Share
sheet,
sheet, you
Safari. So now from the Share
sheet, you can
sheet, you can just
Safari. So now from the Share
sheet, you can just with
sheet, you can just with a
Safari. So now from the Share
sheet, you can just with a tap
add
add a
sheet, you can just with a tap
add a link
add a link right
sheet, you can just with a tap
add a link right back
add a link right back into
sheet, you can just with a tap
add a link right back into your
notes.
notes. And
add a link right back into your
notes. And we
notes. And we make
add a link right back into your
notes. And we make i
notes. And we make it
add a link right back into your
notes. And we make it really
easy
easy to
notes. And we make it really
easy to find
easy to find your
notes. And we make it really
easy to find your notes.
easy to find your notes. So
notes. And we make it really
easy to find your notes. So w
easy to find your notes. So we
organize
organize t
easy to find your notes. So we
organize them
organize them by
easy to find your notes. So we
organize them by time,
organize them by time, of
course,
course, a
organize them by time, of
course, and
course, and now
organize them by time, of
course, and now we
course, and now we have
organize them by time, of
course, and now we have these
great
great thumb
course, and now we have these
great thumbnails
great thumbnails to
course, and now we have these
great thumbnails to let
great thumbnails to let you
course, and now we have these
great thumbnails to let you see
your
your embedded
great thumbnails to let you see
your embedded images
your embedded images at
great thumbnails to let you see
your embedded images at a
glance,
glance, b
your embedded images at a
glance, but
glance, but we
your embedded images at a
glance, but we also
glance, but we also p
your embedded images at a
glance, but we also provide
this
this cool
glance, but we also provide
this cool new
this cool new Attach
glance, but we also provide
this cool new Attachments
this cool new Attachments view
that
that shows
this cool new Attachments view
that shows you
that shows you all
this cool new Attachments view
that shows you all of
that shows you all of your
photos,
photos, your
that shows you all of your
photos, your maps
photos, your maps links
that shows you all of your
photos, your maps links,
photos, your maps links, your
website
website links
photos, your maps links, your
website links,
website links, and
photos, your maps links, your
website links, and w
website links, and when
photos, your maps links, your
website links, and when you
tap,
tap, you
website links, and when you
tap, you can
tap, you can get
website links, and when you
tap, you can get right
tap, you can get right back
website links, and when you
tap, you can get right back to
the
the note
tap, you can get right back to
the note w
the note where
tap, you can get right back to
the note where they
the note where they came
tap, you can get right back to
the note where they came from.
Now
Now,
Now, Notes
Now, Notes is
Now, Notes is great
Now, Notes is great on
Now, Notes is great on iPhone,
on
on i
Now, Notes is great on iPhone,
on iPad,
on iPad, a
Now, Notes is great on iPhone,
on iPad, and
on iPad, and of
Now, Notes is great on iPhone,
on iPad, and of course
on iPad, and of course,
Now, Notes is great on iPhone,
on iPad, and of course, on
on iPad, and of course, on the
Mac
Mac as
on iPad, and of course, on the
Mac as well.
Mac as well. And
on iPad, and of course, on the
Mac as well. And all
Mac as well. And all of
on iPad, and of course, on the
Mac as well. And all of y
Mac as well. And all of your
content
content i
Mac as well. And all of your
content is
content is kept
Mac as well. And all of your
content is kept up-to-date
across
across all
content is kept up-to-date
across all of
across all of your
content is kept up-to-date
across all of your device
across all of your devices
content is kept up-to-date
across all of your devices v
across all of your devices via
iCloud.
That's
That's a
iCloud.
That's a quick
That's a quick update
iCloud.
That's a quick update to
That's a quick update to No
Notes.
(Applause)
Next,
Next, let's
(Applause)
Next, let's turn
Next, let's turn to
(Applause)
Next, let's turn to Maps.
We've
We've continued
Next, let's turn to Maps.
We've continued to
We've continued to invest
heavily
heavily in
We've continued to invest
heavily in Maps,
heavily in Maps, a
We've continued to invest
heavily in Maps, and
heavily in Maps, and the
improvements
improvements are
heavily in Maps, and the
improvements are really
improvements are really awe
awesome.
awesome. We
improvements are really awe
awesome. We are
awesome. We are seeing
improvements are really awe
awesome. We are seeing 5
billion
billion use
awesome. We are seeing 5
billion user
billion user requests
awesome. We are seeing 5
billion user requests per
billion user requests per week.
Usage
Usage on
billion user requests per week.
Usage on iOS
Usage on iOS is
billion user requests per week.
Usage on iOS is 3
Usage on iOS is 3.5
billion user requests per week.
Usage on iOS is 3.5 times
higher
higher than
Usage on iOS is 3.5 times
higher than for
higher than for the
Usage on iOS is 3.5 times
higher than for the next
leading
leading mapping
higher than for the next
leading mapping a
leading mapping app.
Now,
Now, Maps,
leading mapping app.
Now, Maps, of
Now, Maps, of course,
historically
historically have
Now, Maps, of course,
historically have been
historically have been f
Now, Maps, of course,
historically have been focused
on
on drivers.
historically have been focused
on drivers. They
on drivers. They emphasize
things
things like
on drivers. They emphasize
things like freeways
things like freeways a
on drivers. They emphasize
things like freeways and
things like freeways and roads
on drivers. They emphasize
things like freeways and roads.
But
But we
things like freeways and roads.
But we know
But we know for
things like freeways and roads.
But we know for a
But we know for a lot
things like freeways and roads.
But we know for a lot of
But we know for a lot of our
iOS
iOS use
But we know for a lot of our
iOS users
iOS users,
But we know for a lot of our
iOS users, they
iOS users, they are
But we know for a lot of our
iOS users, they are mostly
focused
focused on
iOS users, they are mostly
focused on public
focused on public transit,
iOS users, they are mostly
focused on public transit, and
so
so now
focused on public transit, and
so now we've
so now we've created
focused on public transit, and
so now we've created a
so now we've created a great
map
map just
so now we've created a great
map just for
map just for them.
(Applause)
Yes,
Yes, it's
(Applause)
Yes, it's Transit.
With
(Applause)
With Transit,
With Transit, we
(Applause)
With Transit, we provide
With Transit, we provide a
(Applause)
With Transit, we provide a map
that
that emphasizes
With Transit, we provide a map
that emphasizes all
that emphasizes all of
With Transit, we provide a map
that emphasizes all of the
different
different transit
that emphasizes all of the
different transit lines
different transit lines,
that emphasizes all of the
different transit lines, buses
and
and t
different transit lines, buses
and trains,
and trains, subway
different transit lines, buses
and trains, subway stations
and trains, subway stations and
so
so forth
and trains, subway stations and
so forth,
so forth, and
and trains, subway stations and
so forth, and when
so forth, and when you
and trains, subway stations and
so forth, and when you t
so forth, and when you tap
and trains, subway stations and
so forth, and when you tap on
so forth, and when you tap on a
station,
station, y
so forth, and when you tap on a
station, you
station, you can
so forth, and when you tap on a
station, you can see
station, you can see all
so forth, and when you tap on a
station, you can see all the
lines
lines that
station, you can see all the
lines that r
lines that run
station, you can see all the
lines that run through
lines that run through i
station, you can see all the
lines that run through it
lines that run through it with
their
their d
lines that run through it with
their depapture
their depapture times
lines that run through it with
their depapture times.
their depapture times. And
lines that run through it with
their depapture times. And we
do
do multimodal
their depapture times. And we
do multimodal r
do multimodal routing
their depapture times. And we
do multimodal routing,
do multimodal routing, w
their depapture times. And we
do multimodal routing, whether
you
you are
do multimodal routing, whether
you are taking
you are taking a
do multimodal routing, whether
you are taking a train
you are taking a train,
do multimodal routing, whether
you are taking a train, a
subway,
subway, a
you are taking a train, a
subway, a bus,
subway, a bus, or
you are taking a train, a
subway, a bus, or a
subway, a bus, or a ferry
you are taking a train, a
subway, a bus, or a ferry.
subway, a bus, or a ferry. And
we
we p
subway, a bus, or a ferry. And
we provide
we provide step-by-step
directions
directions,
we provide step-by-step
directions, i
directions, including
we provide step-by-step
directions, including time
directions, including time for
walking
walking directions
directions, including time for
walking directions.
But
But we've
walking directions.
But we've taken
But we've taken special
walking directions.
But we've taken special care
to
to get
But we've taken special care
to get t
to get the
But we've taken special care
to get the details
to get the details right,
But we've taken special care
to get the details right, the
ones
ones that
to get the details right, the
ones that matter
ones that matter,
to get the details right, the
ones that matter, with
ones that matter, with Transit
to get the details right, the
ones that matter, with Transit.
For
For instance,
ones that matter, with Transit.
For instance, i
For instance, if
ones that matter, with Transit.
For instance, if you
For instance, if you take
ones that matter, with Transit.
For instance, if you take a
subway
subway station
For instance, if you take a
subway station like
subway station like this
For instance, if you take a
subway station like this one
subway station like this one in
Columbus
Columbus Circle
subway station like this one in
Columbus Circle in
Columbus Circle in New
subway station like this one in
Columbus Circle in New York
Columbus Circle in New York,
it's
it's not
Columbus Circle in New York,
it's not just
it's not just a
Columbus Circle in New York,
it's not just a point
it's not just a point on
Columbus Circle in New York,
it's not just a point on a
it's not just a point on a map.
If
If you
it's not just a point on a map.
If you look
If you look close
it's not just a point on a map.
If you look closer,
If you look closer, it's
actually
actually an
If you look closer, it's
actually an enormous
underground
underground structure
actually an enormous
underground structure spanning
many
many c
underground structure spanning
many city
many city blocks,
underground structure spanning
many city blocks, and
many city blocks, and so
underground structure spanning
many city blocks, and so we
carefully
carefully s
many city blocks, and so we
carefully surveyed
carefully surveyed all
many city blocks, and so we
carefully surveyed all of
carefully surveyed all of the
entrances
entrances and
carefully surveyed all of the
entrances and exits
entrances and exits so
carefully surveyed all of the
entrances and exits so that
entrances and exits so that we
could
could g
entrances and exits so that we
could give
could give you
entrances and exits so that we
could give you walking
direction
directions
could give you walking
directions base
directions based
could give you walking
directions based on
directions based on t
could give you walking
directions based on the
directions based on the time
could give you walking
directions based on the time to
travel
travel from
directions based on the time to
travel from w
travel from where
directions based on the time to
travel from where you
travel from where you a
directions based on the time to
travel from where you actually
are.
are. Now
travel from where you actually
are. Now,
are. Now, this
travel from where you actually
are. Now, this not
are. Now, this not only
travel from where you actually
are. Now, this not only saves
you
you a
are. Now, this not only saves
you a ton
you a ton of
are. Now, this not only saves
you a ton of w
you a ton of walking,
are. Now, this not only saves
you a ton of walking, but
you a ton of walking, but it
also
also probably
you a ton of walking, but it
also probably is
also probably is the
you a ton of walking, but it
also probably is the difference
between
between catching
also probably is the difference
between catching your
between catching your t
also probably is the difference
between catching your train
between catching your train on
time
time and
between catching your train on
time and being
time and being stuck.
(Applause)
It's
It's really
(Applause)
It's really great.
We've
(Applause)
We've taught
We've taught Siri
(Applause)
We've taught Siri all
We've taught Siri all about
transit
transit,
We've taught Siri all about
transit, so
transit, so it's
We've taught Siri all about
transit, so it's effortless
transit, so it's effortless to
ask
ask Siri
transit, so it's effortless to
ask Siri f
ask Siri for
transit, so it's effortless to
ask Siri for directions
ask Siri for directions.
transit, so it's effortless to
ask Siri for directions. And
we
we are
ask Siri for directions. And
we are g
we are going
ask Siri for directions. And
we are going to
we are going to be
ask Siri for directions. And
we are going to be r
we are going to be rolling
ask Siri for directions. And
we are going to be rolling Maps
out
out,
we are going to be rolling Maps
out, Transit
out, Transit,
we are going to be rolling Maps
out, Transit, starting
out, Transit, starting w
we are going to be rolling Maps
out, Transit, starting with
these
these cities
out, Transit, starting with
these cities across
these cities across t
out, Transit, starting with
these cities across the
these cities across the world
out, Transit, starting with
these cities across the world,
and
and --
these cities across the world,
and -- [Applause]
and -- [Applause] --
these cities across the world,
and -- [Applause] -- with
and -- [Applause] -- with these
and
and 300
and -- [Applause] -- with these
and 300 more
and 300 more in
and -- [Applause] -- with these
and 300 more in China
and 300 more in China.
(Applause)
Now,
Now, when
(Applause)
Now, when it
Now, when it comes
(Applause)
Now, when it comes to
searching
searching i
Now, when it comes to
searching in
searching in Maps,
Now, when it comes to
searching in Maps, w
searching in Maps, we
Now, when it comes to
searching in Maps, we are
searching in Maps, we are now
letting
letting you
searching in Maps, we are now
letting you f
letting you find
searching in Maps, we are now
letting you find locations
letting you find locations by
type
type n
letting you find locations by
type nearby
type nearby with
letting you find locations by
type nearby with just
type nearby with just a
letting you find locations by
type nearby with just a tap.
And
And when
type nearby with just a tap.
And when y
And when you
type nearby with just a tap.
And when you find
And when you find the
type nearby with just a tap.
And when you find the location
you
you are
And when you find the location
you are interested
you are interested in
And when you find the location
you are interested in,
you are interested in, the
And when you find the location
you are interested in, the card
will
will tell
you are interested in, the card
will tell you
will tell you right
you are interested in, the card
will tell you right a
will tell you right away
you are interested in, the card
will tell you right away right
there
there in
will tell you right away right
there in the
there in the bottom
will tell you right away right
there in the bottom whether
they
they support
there in the bottom whether
they support Apple
they support Apple Pay.
Support
Support those
they support Apple Pay.
Support those Apple
Support those Apple Pay
merchants.
(Applause)
Ma
Maps
(Applause)
Maps i
Maps is
(Applause)
Maps is great
Maps is great on
(Applause)
Maps is great on i
Maps is great on iPhone
(Applause)
Maps is great on iPhone a
Maps is great on iPhone and
iPad,
iPad, and
Maps is great on iPhone and
iPad, and of
iPad, and of course
Maps is great on iPhone and
iPad, and of course,
iPad, and of course, the
Maps is great on iPhone and
iPad, and of course, the Mac
iPad, and of course, the Mac as
well
well.
And
And that
well.
And that is
And that is Maps.
(Applause)
The
The apps
(Applause)
The apps that
The apps that we've
(Applause)
The apps that we've chosen
The apps that we've chosen to
build
build in
The apps that we've chosen to
build in to
build in to iOS
The apps that we've chosen to
build in to iOS are
build in to iOS are t
The apps that we've chosen to
build in to iOS are there
because
because they
build in to iOS are there
because they represent
fundamental
fundamental e
because they represent
fundamental experience
fundamental experiences
because they represent
fundamental experiences to
living
living on
fundamental experiences to
living on a
living on a mobile
fundamental experiences to
living on a mobile device.
living on a mobile device. And
there's
there's been
living on a mobile device. And
there's been one
there's been one that
living on a mobile device. And
there's been one that we've
been
been wanting
there's been one that we've
been wanting t
been wanting to
there's been one that we've
been wanting to do
been wanting to do for
there's been one that we've
been wanting to do for years,
something
something that
been wanting to do for years,
something that so
something that so many
been wanting to do for years,
something that so many of
something that so many of us
find
find ourselves
something that so many of us
find ourselves wanting
find ourselves wanting t
something that so many of us
find ourselves wanting to
find ourselves wanting to do
everyday
everyd
find ourselves wanting to do
every
every day
find ourselves wanting to do
every day on
every day on our
find ourselves wanting to do
every day on our device,
every day on our device, and
find ourselves wanting to do
every day on our device, and so
today
today I'm
every day on our device, and so
today I'm pleased
today I'm pleased to
every day on our device, and so
today I'm pleased to announce
that
that we
today I'm pleased to announce
that we are
that we are introducing
today I'm pleased to announce
that we are introducing a
that we are introducing a new
application,
application, and
that we are introducing a new
application, and it's
application, and it's called
News
News.
application, and it's called
News. News
News. News i
application, and it's called
News. News is
News. News is beautiful
application, and it's called
content
News. News is beautiful
content f
content from
News. News is beautiful
content from the
content from the world's
greatest
greatest sources
content from the world's
greatest sources personalized
for
for you
greatest sources personalized
for you.
Now,
Now, here's
for you.
Now, here's an
Now, here's an article
for you.
Now, here's an article in
Now, here's an article in News
for you.
Now, here's an article in N
News.
News. It's
Now, here's an article in N
News. It's absolutely
News. It's absolutely stunning
Now, here's an article in N
News. It's absolutely stu
stunning.
stunning. Now,
News. It's absolutely stu
stunning. Now, publishers
stunning. Now, publishers can
easily
easily create
stunning. Now, publishers can
easily create beautiful
easily create beautiful content
using
using gorgeous
easily create beautiful content
using gorgeous imagery
using gorgeous imagery,
easily create beautiful content
using gorgeous imagery, custom
layout
layout,
using gorgeous imagery, custom
layout, and
layout, and rich
using gorgeous imagery, custom
layout, and rich typography
layout, and rich typography.
But
But News
layout, and rich typography.
But News is
But News is also
layout, and rich typography.
But News is also interactive
But News is also interactive,
and
and so
But News is also interactive,
and so to
and so to give
But News is also interactive,
and so to give you
and so to give you a
But News is also interactive,
and so to give you a look
and so to give you a look at
News
News in
and so to give you a look at
News in action,
News in action, I'd
and so to give you a look at
News in action, I'd l
News in action, I'd like
and so to give you a look at
News in action, I'd like to
invite
invite to
News in action, I'd like to
invite to the
invite to the stage
News in action, I'd like to
invite to the stage our
invite to the stage our Vice
President
President of
invite to the stage our Vice
President of plaix
President of plaix Product
Application
Application,
President of plaix Product
Application, Product
Management
Management,
Application, Product
Management, Susan
Management, Susan Prescott
Application, Product
Management, Susan Prescott.
Susan.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
Susan.
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> SUSAN
>> SUSAN PRESCOTT:
>> SUSAN PRESCOTT: Thanks,
Craig.
Craig. Thank
>> SUSAN PRESCOTT: Thanks,
Craig. Thank you.
Craig. Thank you. I
>> SUSAN PRESCOTT: Thanks,
Craig. Thank you. I am
Craig. Thank you. I am really
excited
excited to
Craig. Thank you. I am really
excited to be
excited to be the
Craig. Thank you. I am really
excited to be the first
excited to be the first person
to
to show
excited to be the first person
to show you
to show you our
excited to be the first person
to show you our new
to show you our new News
excited to be the first person
to show you our new News app.
It's
It's right
to show you our new News app.
It's right here
It's right here on
to show you our new News app.
It's right here on the
It's right here on the Home
to show you our new News app.
screen.
It's right here on the Home
screen. The
screen. The first
It's right here on the Home
screen. The first thing
screen. The first thing News
wants
wants to
screen. The first thing News
wants to do
wants to do is
screen. The first thing News
wants to do is get
wants to do is get a
screen. The first thing News
wants to do is get a sense
wants to do is get a sense of
what
what I
wants to do is get a sense of
what I like,
what I like, so
wants to do is get a sense of
what I like, so it's
what I like, so it's going
wants to do is get a sense of
what I like, so it's going to
give
give me
what I like, so it's going to
give me a
give me a short
what I like, so it's going to
give me a short list
give me a short list of
what I like, so it's going to
give me a short list of really
great
great c
give me a short list of really
great choices
great choices to
give me a short list of really
great choices to choose
great choices to choose from.
And
And you'll
great choices to choose from.
And you'll see
And you'll see a
great choices to choose from.
And you'll see as
And you'll see as I
great choices to choose from.
And you'll see as I t
And you'll see as I tap,
additional
additional recommendation
And you'll see as I tap,
additional recommendations
additional recommendations come
in
in on
additional recommendations come
in on the
in on the bottom
additional recommendations come
in on the bottom to
in on the bottom to give
additional recommendations come
in on the bottom to give y
in on the bottom to give you
even
even more
in on the bottom to give you
even more choices
even more choices.
in on the bottom to give you
even more choices. So
even more choices. So I
in on the bottom to give you
even more choices. So I read
Atlantic,
Atlantic, Wired
even more choices. So I read
Atlantic, Wired,
Atlantic, Wired, N
even more choices. So I read
Atlantic, Wired, New
Atlantic, Wired, New York
Times,
Times, and
Atlantic, Wired, New York
Times, and ESPN.
Times, and ESPN. I
Atlantic, Wired, New York
Times, and ESPN. I am
Times, and ESPN. I am still
with
with you,
Times, and ESPN. I am still
with you, Warriors
with you, Warriors!
Times, and ESPN. I am still
with you, Warriors! And
with you, Warriors! And daring
fire
fireball,
with you, Warriors! And daring
fireball, topics
fireball, topics,
with you, Warriors! And daring
fireball, topics, too,
fireball, topics, too, like
science,
science, baking
fireball, topics, too, like
science, baking,
science, baking, and
fireball, topics, too, like
science, baking, and travel.
science, baking, and travel. I
could
could keep
science, baking, and travel. I
could keep going,
could keep going, but
science, baking, and travel. I
could keep going, but I
could keep going, but I think
that's
that's a
could keep going, but I think
that's a great
that's a great start,
could keep going, but I think
that's a great start, so
that's a great start, so I
could keep going, but I think
that's a great start, so I will
tap
tap "
that's a great start, so I will
tap "done."
News
News c
tap "done."
News creates
News creates a
tap "done."
News creates a personalized
feed
feed called
News creates a personalized
feed called for
feed called for y
News creates a personalized
feed called for you
feed called for y
News creates a personalized
feed called fo y
feed called For y
News creates a personalized
feed called For You
feed called For You.
News creates a personalized
feed called For You. It's
based
based on
feed called For You. It's
based on t
based on the
feed called For You. It's
based on the choices
based on the choices I
feed called For You. It's
based on the choices I just
made
made,
based on the choices I just
made, and
made, and it's
based on the choices I just
made, and it's on
made, and it's on my
based on the choices I just
made, and it's on my News
made, and it's on my News in
one
one place.
made, and it's on my News in
one place. You
one place. You can
made, and it's on my News in
one place. You can see
one place. You can see it
looks
looks great
one place. You can see it
looks great.
looks great. It's
one place. You can see it
looks great. It's e
looks great. It's easy
one place. You can see it
looks great. It's easy to
scan,
scan, and
looks great. It's easy to
scan, and it
scan, and it updates
looks great. It's easy to
scan, and it updates every
scan, and it updates every time
looks great. It's easy to
I
scan, and it updates every time
I c
I check
scan, and it updates every time
I check News
I check News.
The
The articles
I check News.
The articles can
The articles can come
I check News.
The articles can come from
The articles can come from any
I check News.
The articles can come from a
anywhere,
anywhere, but
The articles can come from a
anywhere, but the
anywhere, but the best
The articles can come from a
anywhere, but the best ones
anywhere, but the best ones are
built
built in
anywhere, but the best ones are
built in our
built in our n
anywhere, but the best ones are
built in our new
built in our new A
anywhere, but the best ones are
built in our new Apple
built in our new Apple News
format
format,
built in our new Apple News
format, like
format, like this
built in our new Apple News
format, like this Wired
format, like this Wired article
featuring
featuring Rashida
format, like this Wired article
featuring Rashida Jon
featuring Rashida Jones
format, like this Wired article
featuring Rashida Jones,
awesome
awesome in
featuring Rashida Jones,
awesome in Parks
awesome in Parks &
featuring Rashida Jones,
awesome in Parks & Rec
awesome in Parks & Rec and
featuring Rashida Jones,
awesome in Parks & Rec and The
Office.
Office. Look
awesome in Parks & Rec and The
Office. Look a
Office. Look at
awesome in Parks & Rec and The
Office. Look at the
Office. Look at the r
awesome in Parks & Rec and The
Office. Look at the rich
typography,
typography, beautiful
Office. Look at the rich
typography, beautiful image
typography, beautiful images,
and
and my
typography, beautiful images,
and my favorite
and my favorite part
typography, beautiful images,
and my favorite part are
and my favorite part are the
really
really fun
and my favorite part are the
really fun animations.
really fun animations. It's
fast
fast and
really fun animations. It's
fast and fluid
fast and fluid.
really fun animations. It's
fast and fluid. We
fast and fluid. We think
really fun animations. It's
fast and fluid. We think this
offers
offers t
fast and fluid. We think this
offers the
offers the best
fast and fluid. We think this
offers the best mobile
offers the best mobile reading
experience
experience ever.
To
To get
experience ever.
To get t
To get to
experience ever.
To get to the
To get to the next
experience ever.
To get to the next article,
To get to the next article, I
just
just s
To get to the next article, I
just swipe.
just swipe. It's
To get to the next article, I
just swipe. It's not
just swipe. It's not just
great
great for
just swipe. It's not just
great for m
great for magazines;
just swipe. It's not just
great for magazines; it's
great for magazines; it's great
for
for newspapers
great for magazines; it's great
for newspapers too.
for newspapers too. This
great for magazines; it's great
for newspapers too. This is
for newspapers too. This is a
New
New York
for newspapers too. This is a
New York Times
New York Times a
for newspapers too. This is a
New York Times article,
New York Times article, and
for newspapers too. This is a
New York Times article, and it
looks
looks like
New York Times article, and it
looks like a
looks like a N
New York Times article, and it
looks like a New
looks like a New York
New York Times article, and it
looks like a New York Times
article.
Swipe
Swipe down,
article.
Swipe down, there's
Swipe down, there's a
article.
Swipe down, there's a photo
gallery
gallery r
Swipe down, there's a photo
gallery right
gallery right in
Swipe down, there's a photo
gallery right in line
gallery right in line,
Swipe down, there's a photo
gallery right in line, f
gallery right in line, fast,
fluid
fluid to
gallery right in line, fast,
fluid to s
fluid to swipe
gallery right in line, fast,
fluid to swipe through.
Go
Go to
fluid to swipe through.
Go to the
Go to the next
fluid to swipe through.
Go to the next article,
Go to the next article, this
one
one's
Go to the next article, this
one's from
one's from Quarts
Go to the next article, this
one's from Quarts,
one's from Quarts, but
Go to the next article, this
one's from Quarts, but I
one's from Quarts, but I am
seeing
seeing it
one's from Quarts, but I am
seeing it because
seeing it because --
one's from Quarts, but I am
seeing it because -- Quartz,
but
but I
seeing it because -- Quartz,
but I am
but I am seeing
seeing it because -- Quartz,
but I am seeing it
but I am seeing it because
seeing it because -- Quartz,
but I am seeing it because I
said
said I
but I am seeing it because I
said I am
said I am interested
but I am seeing it because I
said I am interested in
science.
science. It's
said I am interested in
science. It's a
science. It's a pretty
said I am interested in
science. It's a pretty cool
article
article about
science. It's a pretty cool
article about a
article about a font
science. It's a pretty cool
article about a font based
article about a font based on
Albert
Albert Einstein's
article about a font based on
Albert Einstein's h
Albert Einstein's hand
article about a font based on
Albert Einstein's handwriting
Albert Einstein's handwriting.
Frankly,
Frankly, who
Albert Einstein's handwriting.
Frankly, who knew
Frankly, who knew h
Albert Einstein's handwriting.
Frankly, who knew he
Frankly, who knew he had
Albert Einstein's handwriting.
Frankly, who knew he had such
neat
neat handwriting
Frankly, who knew he had such
neat handwriting?
neat handwriting? It's
Frankly, who knew he had such
neat handwriting? It's kinds
of
of interesting
neat handwriting? It's kinds
of interesting.
Sw
Swipe
Swipe again,
Swipe again, and
Swipe again, and I
Swipe again, and I get
Swipe again, and I get an
article
article from
Swipe again, and I get an
article from bon
article from bon appetit
Swipe again, and I get an
article from bon appetit.
Great
Great s
article from bon appetit.
Great summer
Great summer recipes
article from bon appetit.
Great summer recipes,
Great summer recipes, a
article from bon appetit.
Great summer recipes, and
Great summer recipes, and a
crazy
crazy l
Great summer recipes, and a
crazy little
crazy little jigly
Great summer recipes, and a
crazy little jigly thing
crazy little jigly thing,
Great summer recipes, and a
crazy little jigly thing, which
is
is kind
crazy little jigly thing, which
is kind of
is kind of fun.
(Laughter)
So
So I
(Laughter)
So I am
So I am a
(Laughter)
So I am a little
So I am a little busy
(Laughter)
So I am a little busy right
now,
now, so
So I am a little busy right
now, so I
now, so I am
So I am a little busy right
now, so I am g
now, so I am going
So I am a little busy right
now, so I am going to
now, so I am going to go
So I am a little busy right
now, so I am going to go ahead
and
a
now, so I am going to go ahead
and
and book
now, so I am going to go ahead
and bookmark
and bookmark this
now, so I am going to go ahead
and bookmark this to
and bookmark this to read
now, so I am going to go ahead
and bookmark this to read la
later.
Now
Now,
later.
Now, ESPN
Now, ESPN,
later.
Now, ESPN, I
Now, ESPN, I love
later.
Now, ESPN, I love y
Now, ESPN, I love you,
later.
Now, ESPN, I love you, Steph.
(Applause)
No
Now
(Applause)
Now,
Now, I
(Applause)
Now, I read
Now, I read ESPN
(Applause)
Now, I read ESPN for
Now, I read ESPN for the
articles
articles,
Now, I read ESPN for the
articles, but
articles, but there's
Now, I read ESPN for the
articles, but there's also
articles, but there's also some
beautiful
beautiful --
articles, but there's also some
beautiful -- (Laughter)
beautiful -- (Laughter) --
photos
photos and
beautiful -- (Laughter) --
photos and videos
photos and videos.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
photos and videos.
(Cheers and applause)
Some
Some photos
(Cheers and applause)
Some photos and
Some photos and videos
(Cheers and applause)
Some photos and videos.
Some photos and videos. L
(Cheers and applause)
Some photos and videos. Let's
see
see if
Some photos and videos. Let's
see if Steph
see if Steph can
Some photos and videos. Let's
see if Steph can make
see if Steph can make this
Some photos and videos. Let's
see if Steph can make this one.
Swish.
Swish. All
see if Steph can make this one.
Swish. All right
Swish. All right.
see if Steph can make this one.
Swish. All right. He
Swish. All right. He is
going
going to
Swish. All right. He is
going to be
going to be there
Swish. All right. He is
going to be there for
going to be there for u
Swish. All right. He is
going to be there for us
going to be there for us next
game
game.
In
In addition
game.
In addition,
In addition, data
game.
In addition, data and
In addition, data and stats
are
are part
In addition, data and stats
are part of
are part of what's
In addition, data and stats
are part of what's fun
are part of what's fun about
sports,
sports, so
are part of what's fun about
sports, so of
sports, so of course
are part of what's fun about
sports, so of course,
sports, so of course, rich
are part of what's fun about
sports, so of course, rich info
graphics
graphics can
sports, so of course, rich info
graphics can be
graphics can be part
sports, so of course, rich info
graphics can be part of
graphics can be part of i
sports, so of course, rich info
graphics can be part of it.
graphics can be part of it. I
am
am g
graphics can be part of it. I
am going
am going to
graphics can be part of it. I
am going to swipe
am going to swipe back
graphics can be part of it. I
am going to swipe back to
am going to swipe back to For
You.
You. Now
am going to swipe back to For
You. Now,
You. Now, News
am going to swipe back to For
You. Now, News is
You. Now, News is smart,
am going to swipe back to For
You. Now, News is smart, so
the
the more
You. Now, News is smart, so
the more I
the more I read,
You. Now, News is smart, so
the more I read, the
the more I read, the better
You. Now, News is smart, so
the more I read, the better it
gets
gets at
the more I read, the better it
gets at showing
gets at showing m
the more I read, the better it
gets at showing me
gets at showing me story
the more I read, the better it
gets at showing me stories
gets at showing me stories I
the more I read, the better it
gets at showing me stories I am
interested
interested in.
gets at showing me stories I am
interested in. But
interested in. But what
gets at showing me stories I am
interested in. But what if
interested in. But what if I
want
want to
interested in. But what if I
want to d
want to discover
interested in. But what if I
want to discover something
want to discover something new?
I
I can
want to discover something new?
I can tap
I can tap h
want to discover something new?
I can tap here
I can tap here in
want to discover something new?
I can tap here in the
I can tap here in the about
the
the tomorrow
I can tap here in the about
the tomorrow on
the tomorrow on Explore,
I can tap here in the about
the tomorrow on Explore, and
Explore,
Explore, base
the tomorrow on Explore, and
Explore, based
Explore, based on
the tomorrow on Explore, and
Explore, based on what
Explore, based on what I've
read
read,
Explore, based on what I've
read, will
read, will show
Explore, based on what I've
read, will show me
read, will show me n
Explore, based on what I've
read, will show me new
publisher
publisher c
read, will show me new
publisher channels
publisher channels I
read, will show me new
publisher channels I m
publisher channels I might
read, will show me new
publisher channels I might be
interested
interested in
publisher channels I might be
interested in and
interested in and suggest
publisher channels I might be
interested in and suggested
topics
topics.
Well
Well,
topics.
Well, I
Well, I love
topics.
Well, I love technology.
Well, I love technology. I
topics.
Well, I love technology. I am
going
going to
Well, I love technology. I am
going to go
going to go a
Well, I love technology. I am
going to go ahead
going to go ahead and
Well, I love technology. I am
going to go ahead and follow
that.
that. B
going to go ahead and follow
that. But
that. But News
going to go ahead and follow
that. But News keeps
that. But News keeps track
going to go ahead and follow
that. But News keeps track of
more
more than
that. But News keeps track of
more than a
more than a million
that. But News keeps track of
more than a million top
more than a million topics.
that. But News keeps track of
more than a million topics. So
I
I can
more than a million topics. So
I can be
I can be much
more than a million topics. So
I can be much m
I can be much more
more than a million topics. So
I can be much more specific
about
about my
I can be much more specific
about my interests.
about my interests. To
I can be much more specific
about my interests. To d
about my interests. To do
that,
that, I
about my interests. To do
that, I can
that, I can tap
about my interests. To do
that, I can tap on
that, I can tap on Search
about my interests. To do
that, I can tap on Search a
that, I can tap on Search and
type.
type. I
that, I can tap on Search and
type. I am
type. I am going
that, I can tap on Search and
type. I am going t
type. I am going to
that, I can tap on Search and
type. I am going to type
type. I am going to type Swift
that, I can tap on Search and
type. I am going to type Sw
Swift.
Swift. And
type. I am going to type Sw
Swift. And I
Swift. And I get
type. I am going to type Sw
Swift. And I get a
Swift. And I get a number
type. I am going to type Sw
Swift. And I get a number of
hits
hits,
Swift. And I get a number of
hits, everything
hits, everything from
Swift. And I get a number of
hits, everything from Taylor
Swift,
Swift, to
hits, everything from Taylor
Swift, to what
Swift, to what I
hits, everything from Taylor
Swift, to what I was
Swift, to what I was looking
for,
for, Apple's
Swift, to what I was looking
for, Apple's new
for, Apple's new programming
language
language.
So
So it's
language.
So it's a
So it's a beautiful
language.
So it's a beautiful feed,
So it's a beautiful feed, and
what's
what's really
So it's a beautiful feed, and
what's really cool
what's really cool about
So it's a beautiful feed, and
what's really cool about this
is
is t
what's really cool about this
is there
is there are
what's really cool about this
is there are powerful
is there are powerful m
what's really cool about this
is there are powerful machine
learning
learning algorithms
is there are powerful machine
learning algorithms that
analyze
analyze the
learning algorithms that
analyze the contents
analyze the contents of
learning algorithms that
analyze the contents of the
articles
articles to
analyze the contents of the
articles to figure
articles to figure out
analyze the contents of the
articles to figure out which
stories
stories belong
articles to figure out which
stories belong in
stories belong in which
articles to figure out which
stories belong in which art
article.
article. This
stories belong in which art
article. This looks
article. This looks like
stories belong in which art
article. This looks like just
what
what I
article. This looks like just
what I was
what I was hoping
article. This looks like just
what I was hoping for.
what I was hoping for. I
article. This looks like just
what I was hoping for. I am
going
going to
what I was hoping for. I am
going to go
going to go ahe
what I was hoping for. I am
going to go ahead
going to go ahead and
what I was hoping for. I am
going to go ahead and add
going to go ahead and add Swift
to
to my
going to go ahead and add Swift
to my favorites.
So
So let's
to my favorites.
So let's take
So let's take a
to my favorites.
So let's take a look
So let's take a look at
Favorites.
Favorites. I
So let's take a look at
Favorites. I will
Favorites. I will tap
So let's take a look at
Favorites. I will tap down
here
here.
Favorites. I will tap down
here:
here: F
Favorites. I will tap down
here: Favorites
here: Favorites is
Favorites. I will tap down
here: Favorites is w
here: Favorites is where
Favorites. I will tap down
here: Favorites is where I
here: Favorites is where I can
see
see everything
here: Favorites is where I can
see everything I
see everything I am
here: Favorites is where I can
see everything I am following,
including
including Swift
see everything I am following,
including Swift,
including Swift, which
see everything I am following,
including Swift, which I
including Swift, which I just
add
added.
including Swift, which I just
added. It's
added. It's a
including Swift, which I just
added. It's a great
added. It's a great place
including Swift, which I just
added. It's a great place to
go
go if
added. It's a great place to
go if I
go if I want
added. It's a great place to
go if I want t
go if I want to
added. It's a great place to
go if I want to dig
go if I want to dig into
added. It's a great place to
go if I want to dig into a
particular
particular top
go if I want to dig into a
particular topic
particular topic or
go if I want to dig into a
particular topic or if
particular topic or if I
go if I want to dig into a
particular topic or if I want
to
to read
particular topic or if I want
to read a
to read a newspaper
particular topic or if I want
to read a newspaper or
to read a newspaper or a
magazine
magazine.
to read a newspaper or a
magazine. Let's
magazine. Let's say
to read a newspaper or a
magazine. Let's say today
magazine. Let's say today I
want
want to
magazine. Let's say today I
want to read
want to read Wired
magazine. Let's say today I
want to read Wired.
want to read Wired. You
magazine. Let's say today I
want to read Wired. You can
tell
tell I
want to read Wired. You can
tell I am
tell I am in
want to read Wired. You can
tell I am in the
tell I am in the W
want to read Wired. You can
tell I am in the Wired
tell I am in the Wired channel
want to read Wired. You can
tell I am in the Wired channel.
You
You see
tell I am in the Wired channel.
You see the
You see the Wired
tell I am in the Wired channel.
You see the Wired l
You see the Wired logo
tell I am in the Wired channel.
You see the Wired logo at
You see the Wired logo at the
top
top and
You see the Wired logo at the
top and the
top and the Wired
You see the Wired logo at the
top and the Wired channel
starting
starting with
top and the Wired channel
starting with Top
starting with Top S
top and the Wired channel
starting with Top Story
starting with Top Stories.
I
I can
starting with Top Stories.
I can swipe
I can swipe through
starting with Top Stories.
I can swipe through and
I can swipe through and see
starting with Top Stories.
I can swipe through and see a
collection
collection of
I can swipe through and see a
collection of the
collection of the all
I can swipe through and see a
collection of the all the
collection of the all the print
and
and Web
collection of the all the print
and Web story
and Web stories
collection of the all the print
and Web stories built
and Web stories built in
collection of the all the print
and Web stories built in Apple
News
News format
and Web stories built in Apple
News format,
News format, and
and Web stories built in Apple
News format, and it
News format, and it looks
traffic.
I
I am
traffic.
I am going
I am going to
traffic.
I am going to look
I am going to look at
traffic.
I am going to look at one
I am going to look at one more
story.
story. This
I am going to look at one more
story. This is
story. This is about
I am going to look at one more
story. This is about the
story. This is about the first
civilian
civilian art
story. This is about the first
civilian artist
civilian artist in
story. This is about the first
civilian artist in space.
civilian artist in space. Cool
concept
concept and
civilian artist in space. Cool
concept and really
concept and really cool.
I
I want
concept and really cool.
I want t
I want to
concept and really cool.
I want to show
I want to show you
concept and really cool.
I want to show you this.
We've
We've taken
I want to show you this.
We've taken p
We've taken photo
I want to show you this.
We've taken photo galleries
We've taken photo galleries to
the
the next
We've taken photo galleries to
the next level
the next level with
We've taken photo galleries to
the next level with s
the next level with something
we
we call
the next level with something
we call Photo
we call Photo Mosaic
the next level with something
we call Photo Mosaics
we call Photo Mosaics.
the next level with something
we call Photo Mosaics. Look
how
how beautiful
we call Photo Mosaics. Look
how beautiful it
how beautiful it looks
we call Photo Mosaics. Look
how beautiful it looks on
how beautiful it looks on the
page
page.
how beautiful it looks on the
page. Stunning
page. Stunning.
how beautiful it looks on the
page. Stunning. And
page. Stunning. And,
how beautiful it looks on the
page. Stunning. And, as
page. Stunning. And, as y
how beautiful it looks on the
page. Stunning. And, as you'd
expect,
expect, I
page. Stunning. And, as you'd
expect, I j
expect, I just
page. Stunning. And, as you'd
expect, I just tap
expect, I just tap to
page. Stunning. And, as you'd
expect, I just tap to zoom
expect, I just tap to zoom in
on
on the
expect, I just tap to zoom in
on the p
on the photos
expect, I just tap to zoom in
on the photos.
on the photos. It
expect, I just tap to zoom in
on the photos. It looks
on the photos. It looks great.
We
We think
We think there's
We think there's never
We think there's never been
We think there's never been a
more
more beautiful
We think there's never been a
more beautiful m
more beautiful magazine
We think there's never been a
more beautiful magazine reading
experience
experience,
more beautiful magazine reading
experience, a
experience, a mobile
more beautiful magazine reading
experience, a mobile r
experience, a mobile reading
experience
experience in
experience, a mobile reading
experience in general,
experience in general, and
experience, a mobile reading
experience in general, and this
is
is just
experience in general, and this
is just one
is just one of
experience in general, and this
is just one of many
is just one of many channels
with
with beautiful
is just one of many channels
with beautiful story
with beautiful stories
is just one of many channels
with beautiful stories built
with beautiful stories built in
Apple
Apple News
with beautiful stories built in
Apple News format.
That
That is
Apple News format.
That is a
That is a really
Apple News format.
That is a really quick
That is a really quick look
Apple News format.
That is a really quick look at
News.
News. We
That is a really quick look at
News. We can't
News. We can't wait
That is a really quick look at
News. We can't wait to
News. We can't wait to get
That is a really quick look at
News. We can't wait to get it
in
in your
News. We can't wait to get it
in your hands.
in your hands. Thank
News. We can't wait to get it
in your hands. Thank you
in your hands. Thank you very
much.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
much.
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> CRAIG
(Cheers and applause)
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI:
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: So
(Cheers and applause)
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: So that's
News
News.
>> CRAIG FEDERIGHI: So that's
News. Stunning
News. Stunning content.
Personal
Personaliz
News. Stunning content.
Personalized
Personalized for
News. Stunning content.
Personalized for you
Personalized for you.
Fantastic
Fantastic on
Personalized for you.
Fantastic on iPad
Fantastic on iPad a
Personalized for you.
Fantastic on iPad and
Fantastic on iPad and on
Personalized for you.
Fantastic on iPad and on iPhone
as
as well
Fantastic on iPad and on iPhone
as well.
as well. And
Fantastic on iPad and on iPhone
as well. And of
as well. And of c
Fantastic on iPad and on iPhone
as well. And of course
as well. And of course,
Fantastic on iPad and on iPhone
as well. And of course, u
as well. And of course, unlike
just
just about
as well. And of course, unlike
just about any
just about any other
as well. And of course, unlike
just about any other news
aggregation
aggregation service
just about any other news
aggregation service we
aggregation service we are
aware
aware of
aggregation service we are
aware of on
aware of on the
aggregation service we are
aware of on the planet,
aware of on the planet, news
aggregation service we are
aware of on the planet, ne
aware of on the planet, News
aggregation service we are
aware of on the planet, News is
designed
designed from
aware of on the planet, News is
designed from the
designed from the gound
aware of on the planet, News is
designed from the gound up
designed from the gound up with
your
your privacy
designed from the gound up with
your privacy in
your privacy in --
designed from the gound up with
your privacy in -- ground
your privacy in -- ground up
with
with your
your privacy in -- ground up
with your p
with your privacy
your privacy in -- ground up
with your privacy in
with your privacy in mind.
We
We worked
with your privacy in mind.
We worked with
We worked with leading
publishers
publishers,
We worked with leading
publishers, like
publishers, like The
We worked with leading
publishers, like The New
publishers, like The New York
Times,
Times, w
publishers, like The New York
Times, who
Times, who will
publishers, like The New York
Times, who will be
Times, who will be delivering
articles
articles daily
Times, who will be delivering
articles daily to
articles daily to readers,
Times, who will be delivering
articles daily to readers, and
ESPN
ESPN who
articles daily to readers, and
ESPN who will
ESPN who will be
articles daily to readers, and
ESPN who will be bringing
ESPN who will be bringing the
depth
depth a
ESPN who will be bringing the
depth and
depth and range
ESPN who will be bringing the
depth and range of
depth and range of their
phenomenal
phenomenal s
depth and range of their
phenomenal sports
phenomenal sports reporting
depth and range of their
phenomenal sports reporting.
And
And Conde
phenomenal sports reporting.
And Conde Nast,
And Conde Nast, w
phenomenal sports reporting.
And Conde Nast, who
And Conde Nast, who are
bringing
bringing content
And Conde Nast, who are
bringing content from
bringing content from 17
And Conde Nast, who are
bringing content from 17 of
their
their magazines
bringing content from 17 of
their magazines,
their magazines, like
bringing content from 17 of
their magazines, like vanity
Fare,
Fare, V
their magazines, like vanity
Fare, Vogue,
Fare, Vogue, GQ,
their magazines, like vanity
Fare, Vogue, GQ, Wired
Fare, Vogue, GQ, Wired,
their magazines, like vanity
Fare, Vogue, GQ, Wired, and
Bone
Bone appetite.
Fare, Vogue, GQ, Wired, and
Bone appetite. And
Bone appetite. And they
Fare, Vogue, GQ, Wired, and
Bone appetite. And they will
be
be join
Bone appetite. And they will
be joined
be joined by
Bone appetite. And they will
be joined by many,
be joined by many, many
Bone appetite. And they will
be joined by many, many others
read
read by
be joined by many, many others
read by millions
read by millions of
be joined by many, many others
read by millions of users
read by millions of users da
daily.
News
News isn't
daily.
News isn't just
News isn't just for
daily.
News isn't just for the
News isn't just for the media
titans.
titans. Great
News isn't just for the media
titans. Great content
titans. Great content comes
from
from all
titans. Great content comes
from all kinds
from all kinds of
titans. Great content comes
from all kinds of sources,
from all kinds of sources, a
titans. Great content comes
from all kinds of sources, and
we
we want
from all kinds of sources, and
we want them
we want them all
from all kinds of sources, and
we want them all in
we want them all in news,
from all kinds of sources, and
we want them all in news, so
whether
whether it's
we want them all in news, so
whether it's a
whether it's a local
we want them all in news, so
whether it's a local newspaper
whether it's a local newspaper,
a
a blog
whether it's a local newspaper,
a blog,
a blog, or
whether it's a local newspaper,
a blog, or a
a blog, or a special
whether it's a local newspaper,
a blog, or a special interest
publication
publication,
a blog, or a special interest
publication, they
publication, they will
a blog, or a special interest
publication, they will all
publication, they will all be
here.
We
We will
here.
We will be
We will be rolling
here.
We will be rolling out
We will be rolling out News
starting
starting in
We will be rolling out News
starting in the
starting in the United
We will be rolling out News
starting in the United States,
the
the UK,
starting in the United States,
the UK, and
the UK, and Australia
starting in the United States,
the UK, and Australia.
the UK, and Australia. W
starting in the United States,
the UK, and Australia. We
think
think you
the UK, and Australia. We
think you are
think you are really
the UK, and Australia. We
think you are really going
think you are really going to
like
like it
think you are really going to
like it.
(Applause)
Next
Next,
(Applause)
Next, let's
Next, let's turn
(Applause)
Next, let's turn to
Next, let's turn to i
(Applause)
Next, let's turn to iPad.
Next, let's turn to iPad. N
Now,
Now, iPad
Next, let's turn to iPad. N
Now, iPad is
Now, iPad is a
Next, let's turn to iPad. N
Now, iPad is a transform
Now, iPad is a transformational
device
device.
Now, iPad is a transformational
device. For
device. For our
Now, iPad is a transformational
device. For our users
device. For our users i
Now, iPad is a transformational
device. For our users in
education,
education, b
device. For our users in
education, business,
education, business, and
device. For our users in
education, business, and at
home,
home, for
education, business, and at
home, for m
home, for many
education, business, and at
home, for many of
home, for many of them
education, business, and at
home, for many of them,
home, for many of them, their
iPad
iPad is
home, for many of them, their
iPad is their
iPad is their primary
home, for many of them, their
iPad is their primary c
iPad is their primary computer
home, for many of them, their
iPad is their primary computer.
And
And i
iPad is their primary computer.
And iPads
And iPads is
iPad is their primary computer.
And iPads is just
And iPads is just tremendously
powerful
powerful,
And iPads is just tremendously
powerful, so
powerful, so in
And iPads is just tremendously
powerful, so in iOS
powerful, so in iOS,
And iPads is just tremendously
powerful, so in iOS, we
powerful, so in iOS, we are
elevating
elevating t
powerful, so in iOS, we are
elevating the
elevating the iPad
powerful, so in iOS, we are
elevating the iPad experience
to
to a
elevating the iPad experience
to a whole
to a whole new
elevating the iPad experience
to a whole new level
to a whole new level.
elevating the iPad experience
to a whole new level. Now,
to a whole new level. Now, it
starts
starts with
to a whole new level. Now, it
starts with something
starts with something really
simple,
simple, which
starts with something really
simple, which is
simple, which is how
starts with something really
simple, which is how you
simple, which is how you work
with
with text.
simple, which is how you work
with text. That
with text. That brings
simple, which is how you work
with text. That brings us
with text. That brings us to
the
the QuickType
with text. That brings us to
the QuickType keyboard
the QuickType keyboard.
with text. That brings us to
the QuickType keyboard. N
the QuickType keyboard. Now
with text. That brings us to
the QuickType keyboard. Now,
in
in iOS
the QuickType keyboard. Now,
in iOS 8
in iOS 8,
the QuickType keyboard. Now,
in iOS 8, we
in iOS 8, we introduced
the QuickType keyboard. Now,
in iOS 8, we introduced the
Suggestion
Suggestion b
in iOS 8, we introduced the
Suggestion bar
Suggestion bar that
in iOS 8, we introduced the
Suggestion bar that makes
Suggestion bar that makes it
quick
quicker
Suggestion bar that makes it
quicker than
quicker than ever
Suggestion bar that makes it
quicker than ever to
quicker than ever to type
Suggestion bar that makes it
quicker than ever to type and
enter
enter what
quicker than ever to type and
enter what y
enter what you
quicker than ever to type and
enter what you are
enter what you are trying
quicker than ever to type and
enter what you are trying to
get
get in
enter what you are trying to
get in.
get in. But
enter what you are trying to
get in. But n
get in. But now,
enter what you are trying to
get in. But now, in
get in. But now, in iOS
enter what you are trying to
get in. But now, in iOS 9
get in. But now, in iOS 9,
we've
we've add
get in. But now, in iOS 9,
we've added
we've added shortcuts
get in. But now, in iOS 9,
we've added shortcuts to
we've added shortcuts to that
bar,
bar, so
we've added shortcuts to that
bar, so with
bar, so with just
we've added shortcuts to that
bar, so with just a
bar, so with just a tap,
we've added shortcuts to that
bar, so with just a tap, you
can
can cut
bar, so with just a tap, you
can cut,
can cut, copy
bar, so with just a tap, you
can cut, copy,
can cut, copy, paste,
bar, so with just a tap, you
can cut, copy, paste, format
your
your text,
can cut, copy, paste, format
your text, access
your text, access your
attachments.
attachments. It's
your text, access your
attachments. It's really
handy.
But
But you
handy.
But you know,
But you know, what
handy.
But you know, what makes
But you know, what makes a
Multi-Touch
Multi-Touch keyboard
But you know, what makes a
Multi-Touch keyboard so
Multi-Touch keyboard so special
is
is that
Multi-Touch keyboard so special
is that it
is that it can
Multi-Touch keyboard so special
is that it can be
is that it can be a
Multi-Touch keyboard so special
is that it can be anything
is that it can be anything you
want.
want. I
is that it can be anything you
want. It
want. It can
is that it can be anything you
want. It can transform.
want. It can transform. S
is that it can be anything you
want. It can transform. So
now
now w
want. It can transform. So
now when
now when you
want. It can transform. So
now when you want
now when you want to
want. It can transform. So
now when you want to move
now when you want to move the
cursor
cursor or
now when you want to move the
cursor or make
cursor or make a
now when you want to move the
cursor or make a selection
cursor or make a selection,
now when you want to move the
cursor or make a selection, you
can
can n
cursor or make a selection, you
can now
can now just
cursor or make a selection, you
can now just put
can now just put two
cursor or make a selection, you
can now just put two fingers
down
down on
can now just put two fingers
down on the
down on the keyboard
can now just put two fingers
down on the keyboard,
down on the keyboard, and
can now just put two fingers
down on the keyboard, and it
becomes
becomes a
down on the keyboard, and it
becomes a T
becomes a Trackpad
down on the keyboard, and it
becomes a Trackpad instant
becomes a Trackpad instantly
down on the keyboard, and it
becomes a Trackpad instantly.
(Applause)
You
You can
(Applause)
You can m
You can move
(Applause)
You can move the
You can move the c
(Applause)
You can move the cursor
You can move the cursor,
(Applause)
You can move the cursor, you
can
can m
You can move the cursor, you
can make
can make selections
You can move the cursor, you
can make selections.
can make selections. Of
You can move the cursor, you
course,
can make selections. Of
course, you
course, you can
can make selections. Of
course, you can use
course, you can use the
can make selections. Of
course, you can use the s
course, you can use the sh
shortcut
shortcut bar
course, you can use the sh
shortcut bar to
shortcut bar to cut,
course, you can use the sh
shortcut bar to cut, drag
shortcut bar to cut, drag t
course, you can use the sh
shortcut bar to cut, drag to
shortcut bar to cut, drag to a
new
new p
shortcut bar to cut, drag to a
new place,
new place, and
shortcut bar to cut, drag to a
new place, and paste
new place, and paste,
shortcut bar to cut, drag to a
new place, and paste, editing
more
more quickly
new place, and paste, editing
more quickly t
more quickly than
new place, and paste, editing
more quickly than ever
more quickly than ever before
and
and without
more quickly than ever before
and without your
and without your fingers
more quickly than ever before
and without your fingers ever
leaving
leaving the
and without your fingers ever
leaving the home
leaving the home row.
and without your fingers ever
leaving the home row. It's
really
really great
leaving the home row. It's
really great.
(Applause)
And
And if
(Applause)
And if you
And if you do
(Applause)
And if you do o
And if you do occasionally
want
want to
And if you do occasionally
want toook
want toook a
And if you do occasionally
want toook a physical
keyboard
keyboard to
want toook a physical
keyboard to your
keyboard to your i
want toook a physical
keyboard to your iPad
keyboard to your iPad as
want toook a physical
keyboard to your iPad as well,
we
we made
keyboard to your iPad as well,
we made that
we made that better
keyboard to your iPad as well,
we made that better than
we made that better than ever.
We
We provide
we made that better than ever.
We provide a
We provide a way
we made that better than ever.
We provide a way to
We provide a way to discover
all
all of
We provide a way to discover
all of the
all of the s
We provide a way to discover
all of the shortcuts
all of the shortcuts that
We provide a way to discover
all of the shortcuts that can
accelerate
accelerate y
all of the shortcuts that can
accelerate your
accelerate your operation
all of the shortcuts that can
accelerate your operations
accelerate your operations in
the
the a
accelerate your operations in
the applications
the applications using
accelerate your operations in
the applications using the
keyboard,
keyboard, and
the applications using the
keyboard, and we've
keyboard, and we've provide
the applications using the
keyboard, and we've provided
short
shortcuts
keyboard, and we've provided
shortcuts for
shortcuts for a
keyboard, and we've provided
shortcuts for app
shortcuts for app switching
keyboard, and we've provided
shortcuts for app switching.
This
This might
shortcuts for app switching.
This might look
This might look familiar
shortcuts for app switching.
This might look familiar to
some
some o
This might look familiar to
some of
some of y
This might look familiar to
some of you
some of you.
This might look familiar to
some of you. As
some of you. As well
This might look familiar to
some of you. As well as
some of you. As well as to
searching
searching in
some of you. As well as to
searching in spthlight
searching in spthlight.
some of you. As well as to
So
searching in spthlight.
So that's
So that's QuickType
searching in spthlight.
So that's QuickType,
So that's QuickType, but
searching in spthlight.
So that's QuickType, but now
So that's QuickType, but now I
want
want to
So that's QuickType, but now I
want to turn
want to turn to
So that's QuickType, but now I
want to turn to the
want to turn to the big
So that's QuickType, but now I
want to turn to the big one,
and
and that's
want to turn to the big one,
and that's Multitasking.
(Applause)
So
So i
(Applause)
So iPad
So iPad has
(Applause)
So iPad has always
So iPad has always supported
forms
forms of
So iPad has always supported
forms of multitasking
forms of multitasking,
So iPad has always supported
forms of multitasking, like
this
this great
forms of multitasking, like
this great graphic
this great graphical
forms of multitasking, like
this great graphical task
switcher,
switcher, a
this great graphical task
switcher, and
switcher, and these
this great graphical task
switcher, and these nice
switcher, and these nice four
this great graphical task
switcher, and these nice f
four-finger
four-finger gestures
switcher, and these nice f
four-finger gestures that
four-finger gestures that let
you
you move
four-finger gestures that let
you move between
you move between applications.
But
But for
you move between applications.
But for iOS
But for iOS 9
you move between applications.
But for iOS 9,
But for iOS 9, we
you move between applications.
But for iOS 9, we are
But for iOS 9, we are taking
you move between applications.
But for iOS 9, we are taking it
to
to a
But for iOS 9, we are taking it
to a whole
to a whole new
But for iOS 9, we are taking it
to a whole new place,
to a whole new place, and
But for iOS 9, we are taking it
to a whole new place, and I'd
like
like to
to a whole new place, and I'd
like to show
like to show that
to a whole new place, and I'd
like to show that to
like to show that to you
to a whole new place, and I'd
like to show that to you now
like to show that to you now.
(Applause)
So
So let's
(Applause)
So let's start
So let's start here
(Applause)
So let's start here on
So let's start here on my
iPad.
iPad. And
So let's start here on my
iPad. And what
iPad. And what I
So let's start here on my
iPad. And what I am
iPad. And what I am going
So let's start here on my
iPad. And what I am going to
do
do first
iPad. And what I am going to
do first is
do first is double-tap
iPad. And what I am going to
do first is double-tap on
do first is double-tap on the
Home
Home button,
do first is double-tap on the
Home button, and
Home button, and you
do first is double-tap on the
Home button, and you will
Home button, and you will see
our
our n
Home button, and you will see
our new
our new task
Home button, and you will see
our new task switch
our new task switcher.
Home button, and you will see
our new task switcher. It's
really
really gorgeous
our new task switcher. It's
really gorgeous.
really gorgeous. Big
our new task switcher. It's
really gorgeous. Big,
really gorgeous. Big, full
our new task switcher. It's
really gorgeous. Big, f
full-screen
full-screen preview
really gorgeous. Big, f
full-screen previews
full-screen previews of
really gorgeous. Big, f
full-screen previews of all
full-screen previews of all the
apps
apps.
full-screen previews of all the
apps. Just
apps. Just move
full-screen previews of all the
apps. Just move right
apps. Just move right into
Safari
Safari like
apps. Just move right into
Safari like this.
Bu
But
Safari like this.
But of
But of course,
Safari like this.
But of course, often
But of course, often when
Safari like this.
But of course, often when I
But of course, often when I am
in
in an
But of course, often when I am
in an app
in an app like
But of course, often when I am
in an app like Safari
in an app like Safari,
But of course, often when I am
in an app like Safari, I
in an app like Safari, I then
just
just want
in an app like Safari, I then
just want to
just want to quickly
in an app like Safari, I then
just want to quickly check
just want to quickly check my
message
messages
just want to quickly check my
messages.
messages. So
just want to quickly check my
messages. So n
messages. So now
just want to quickly check my
messages. So now with
messages. So now with just
just want to quickly check my
messages. So now with just a
sing
single
messages. So now with just a
single finger
single finger,
messages. So now with just a
single finger, swipe
single finger, swipe from
messages. So now with just a
single finger, swipe from the
side
side,
single finger, swipe from the
side, I
side, I can
single finger, swipe from the
side, I can slide
side, I can slide it
single finger, swipe from the
side, I can slide it right
side, I can slide it right in
with
with what
side, I can slide it right in
with what we
with what we call
side, I can slide it right in
with what we call Slide
with what we call Slide Over.
Of
Of course,
with what we call Slide Over.
Of course, i
Of course, it's
with what we call Slide Over.
Of course, it's full
Of course, it's full Yi
with what we call Slide Over.
Of course, it's ful
Of course, it's full
with what we call Slide Over.
Of course, it's fully
interactive.
interactive. I
Of course, it's fully
interactive. I can
interactive. I can take
Of course, it's fully
interactive. I can take a
quick
quick look
interactive. I can take a
quick look,
quick look, put
interactive. I can take a
quick look, put it
quick look, put it back,
interactive. I can take a
quick look, put it back, I
quick look, put it back, I am
in
in Safari.
quick look, put it back, I am
in Safari. D
in Safari. Do
quick look, put it back, I am
in Safari. Do that
in Safari. Do that again
quick look, put it back, I am
in Safari. Do that again.
From
From the
in Safari. Do that again.
From the top,
From the top, I
in Safari. Do that again.
From the top, I can
From the top, I can pull
in Safari. Do that again.
From the top, I can pull down
and
and bring
From the top, I can pull down
and bring in
and bring in other
From the top, I can pull down
and bring in other appli
applications.
applications. So
and bring in other appli
applications. So let's
applications. So let's bring
in
in Calendar
applications. So let's bring
in Calendar.
in Calendar. Of
applications. So let's bring
in Calendar. Of course
in Calendar. Of course,
applications. So let's bring
in Calendar. Of course, fully
interactive
interactive so
in Calendar. Of course, fully
interactive so I
interactive so I can
in Calendar. Of course, fully
interactive so I can tap
interactive so I can tap into
another
another day.
Let's
Let's bring
another day.
Let's bring in
Let's bring in another
another day.
Let's bring in another app.
Let's bring in another app. I
am
am going
Let's bring in another app. I
am going to
am going to b
Let's bring in another app. I
am going to bring
am going to bring in
Let's bring in another app. I
am going to bring in the
am going to bring in the new
Notes
Notes app
am going to bring in the new
Notes app.
Notes app. Just
am going to bring in the new
Notes app. Just like
Notes app. Just like that
am going to bring in the new
Notes app. Just like that.
Now,
Now, sometimes,
Notes app. Just like that.
Now, sometimes, of
Now, sometimes, of course,
Notes app. Just like that.
Now, sometimes, of course, I
want
want to
Now, sometimes, of course, I
want to s
want to stay
Now, sometimes, of course, I
want to stay working
want to stay working i
Now, sometimes, of course, I
want to stay working in
want to stay working in Notes
and
and Safari
want to stay working in Notes
and Safari both
and Safari both at
want to stay working in Notes
and Safari both at the
and Safari both at the same
time
time,
and Safari both at the same
time, so
time, so I
and Safari both at the same
time, so I can
time, so I can just
and Safari both at the same
time, so I can just t
time, so I can just tap
and Safari both at the same
time, so I can just tap here
time, so I can just tap here on
the
the divider
time, so I can just tap here on
the divider,
the divider, and
time, so I can just tap here on
the divider, and now
the divider, and now I
time, so I can just tap here on
the divider, and now I am
the divider, and now I am in
split
split view
the divider, and now I am in
split view.
split view. They
the divider, and now I am in
split view. They are
split view. They are b
the divider, and now I am in
split view. They are both
complete
completely
split view. They are both
completely a
completely active.
split view. They are both
completely active. In
completely active. In f
split view. They are both
completely active. In fact,
for
for t
completely active. In fact,
for the
for the first
completely active. In fact,
for the first time
for the first time ever
completely active. In fact,
for the first time ever,
multiapp,
multiapp, Multi-Touch
for the first time ever,
multiapp, Multi-Touch,
multiapp, Multi-Touch, I
for the first time ever,
multiapp, Multi-Touch, I can
move
move t
multiapp, Multi-Touch, I can
move them
move them both
multiapp, Multi-Touch, I can
move them both at
move them both at the
multiapp, Multi-Touch, I can
move them both at the same
move them both at the same time
multiapp, Multi-Touch, I can
move them both at the same t
time.
(Applause)
Now
Now,
(Applause)
Now, N
Now, Notes
(Applause)
Now, Notes is
Now, Notes is a
(Applause)
Now, Notes is actually
Now, Notes is actually pinned
to
to the
Now, Notes is actually pinned
to the side
to the side now,
Now, Notes is actually pinned
to the side now, so
to the side now, so I
Now, Notes is actually pinned
to the side now, so I want
to the side now, so I want to
show
show you
to the side now, so I want to
show you what
show you what happens
to the side now, so I want to
show you what happens when
show you what happens when I
switch
switch apps.
show you what happens when I
switch apps. I
switch apps. I am
show you what happens when I
switch apps. I am just
switch apps. I am just g
show you what happens when I
switch apps. I am just going
to
to move
switch apps. I am just going
to move over
to move over h
switch apps. I am just going
to move over here
to move over here to
switch apps. I am just going
to move over here to Photos
to move over here to Photos.
You
You n
to move over here to Photos.
You notice
You notice now
to move over here to Photos.
You notice now I
You notice now I have
to move over here to Photos.
You notice now I have photos
withnotes
withnotes on
You notice now I have photos
withnotes on the
withnotes on the side.
You notice now I have photos
withnotes on the side. This
withnotes on the side. This is
really
really great
withnotes on the side. This is
really great if
really great if I
withnotes on the side. This is
really great if I am
really great if I am taking
notes
notes while
really great if I am taking
notes while working
notes while working across
really great if I am taking
notes while working across a
bunch
bunch of
notes while working across a
bunch of experiences
bunch of experiences.
notes while working across a
bunch of experiences. Those
gestures
gestures c
bunch of experiences. Those
gestures continue
gestures continue to
bunch of experiences. Those
gestures continue to w
gestures continue to work
great,
great, so
gestures continue to work
great, so I
great, so I can
gestures continue to work
great, so I can swipe
great, so I can swipe my
gestures continue to work
great, so I can swipe my way
back
back to
great, so I can swipe my way
back to Safari
back to Safari.
great, so I can swipe my way
back to Safari. L
back to Safari. Let
great, so I can swipe my way
back to Safari. Let me
back to Safari. Let me t
great, so I can swipe my way
back to Safari. Let me tap
back to Safari. Let me tap on
this
this l
back to Safari. Let me tap on
this link,
this link, and
back to Safari. Let me tap on
this link, and you
this link, and you visa
back to Safari. Let me tap on
this link, and you visa fari
loads
loads it
this link, and you visa fari
loads it right
loads it right here
this link, and you visa fari
loads it right here on
loads it right here on the
side.
side. I
loads it right here on the
side. I can
side. I can adjust
loads it right here on the
side. I can adjust the
side. I can adjust the split
loads it right here on the
side. I can adjust the split.
Let
Let me
side. I can adjust the split.
Let me move
Let me move that
side. I can adjust the split.
Let me move that o
Let me move that over
side. I can adjust the split.
Let me move that over to
Let me move that over to a
side. I can adjust the split.
Let me move that over to a n
Let me move that over to a nice
50/50
50/50 view
Let me move that over to a nice
50/50 view with
50/50 view with n
Let me move that over to a nice
50/50 view with notes
50/50 view with notes and
Safari
Safari.
50/50 view with notes and
Safari. I
Safari. I can
50/50 view with notes and
Safari. I can tap
Safari. I can tap on
50/50 view with notes and
Safari. I can tap on links
Safari. I can tap on links to
other
other apps,
Safari. I can tap on links to
other apps, s
other apps, so
Safari. I can tap on links to
other apps, so let's
other apps, so let's follow
Safari. I can tap on links to
other apps, so let's follow a
link
link into
other apps, so let's follow a
link into Maps.
link into Maps. Map
other apps, so let's follow a
link into Maps. Maps
link into Maps. Maps --
other apps, so let's follow a
link into Maps. Maps -- I
really
really want
link into Maps. Maps -- I
really want l
really want location
link into Maps. Maps -- I
really want location accuracy
really want location accuracy.
Thank
Thank you
really want location accuracy.
Thank you very
Thank you very much
really want location accuracy.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very
really want location accuracy.
Thank you,very
Thank you, ery
really want location accuracy.
Thank you, vry
Thank you, very
really want location accuracy.
Thank you, very helpful.
I
I can
Thank you, very helpful.
I can follow
I can follow another
Thank you, very helpful.
I can follow another link,
Maps
Maps adjusts,
I can follow another link,
Maps adjusts, I
Maps adjusts, I am
I can follow another link,
Maps adjusts, I am able
Maps adjusts, I am able to
I can follow another link,
Maps adjusts, I am able to stay
focused
focused right
Maps adjusts, I am able to stay
focused right here
focused right here in
Maps adjusts, I am able to stay
focused right here in these
focused right here in these t
Maps adjusts, I am able to stay
focused right here in these two
apps
apps s
focused right here in these two
apps side
apps side by
focused right here in these two
apps side by side
apps side by side.
Let's
Let's say
apps side by side.
Let's say I
Let's say I now
apps side by side.
Let's say I now want
Let's say I now want to
apps side by side.
Let's say I now want to work
Notes
Notes full
Let's say I now want to work
Notes full screen.
Notes full screen. I
Let's say I now want to work
Notes full screen. I can
Notes full screen. I can pull
right
right across
Notes full screen. I can pull
right across like
right across like that
Notes full screen. I can pull
right across like that and
right across like that and I
Notes full screen. I can pull
right across like that and I am
in
in full-screen
right across like that and I am
in full-screen Notes.
This
This gives
in full-screen Notes.
This gives me
This gives me a
in full-screen Notes.
This gives me a great
opportunity
opportunity to
This gives me a great
opportunity to show
opportunity to show you
This gives me a great
opportunity to show you what's
new
new with
opportunity to show you what's
new with the
new with the QuickType
opportunity to show you what's
new with the QuickType key
keyboard.
keyboard. I
new with the QuickType key
keyboard. I have
keyboard. I have a
new with the QuickType key
keyboard. I have a to-do
keyboard. I have a to-do list
I
I am
keyboard. I have a to-do list
I am building
I am building here.
keyboard. I have a to-do list
I am building here. I
I am building here. I am
keyboard. I have a to-do list
I am building here. I am going
to
to add
I am building here. I am going
to add an
to add an item
I am building here. I am going
to add an item h
to add an item here
I am building here. I am going
to add an item here to
to add an item here to buy
I am building here. I am going
to add an item here to buy a
new
new i
to add an item here to buy a
new ice
new ice chest
to add an item here to buy a
new ice chest.
new ice chest. On
to add an item here to buy a
new ice chest. On second
thought
thought,
new ice chest. On second
thought, I
thought, I should
new ice chest. On second
thought, I should probably
borrow
borrow one.
thought, I should probably
borrow one. I
borrow one. I am
thought, I should probably
borrow one. I am g
borrow one. I am going
thought, I should probably
borrow one. I am going to
borrow one. I am going to take
two
two fingers
borrow one. I am going to take
two fingers down
two fingers down on
borrow one. I am going to take
two fingers down on the
keyboard
keyboard,
two fingers down on the
keyboard, swipe
keyboard, swipe over
two fingers down on the
keyboard, swipe over here.
keyboard, swipe over here. I
can
can reposition
keyboard, swipe over here. I
can reposition the
can reposition the cursor
keyboard, swipe over here. I
can reposition the cursor like
this
this.
can reposition the cursor like
this. Tap
this. Tap and
can reposition the cursor like
this. Tap and make
this. Tap and make a
can reposition the cursor like
this. Tap and make a sele
selection.
selection. Extend
this. Tap and make a sele
selection. Extend the
selection
selection.
selection. Extend the
selection. And
selection. And type
selection. Extend the
selection. And type "
selection. And type "borrow
selection. Extend the
selection. And type "borrow."
It's
It's really
selection. And type "borrow."
It's really easy.
It's really easy. I
selection. And type "borrow."
It's really easy. I can
It's really easy. I can make
bigger
bigger moves
It's really easy. I can make
bigger moves too
bigger moves too.
It's really easy. I can make
bigger moves too. I
bigger moves too. I can
It's really easy. I can make
bigger moves too. I can go
bigger moves too. I can go to
the
the top
bigger moves too. I can go to
the top here,
the top here, maybe
bigger moves too. I can go to
the top here, maybe s
the top here, maybe select
bigger moves too. I can go to
the top here, maybe select the
whole
whole sentence,
the top here, maybe select the
whole sentence, d
whole sentence, drag
the top here, maybe select the
whole sentence, drag d
whole sentence, drag down,
maybe
maybe d
whole sentence, drag down,
maybe do
maybe do a
whole sentence, drag down,
maybe do a checklist
maybe do a checklist like
whole sentence, drag down,
maybe do a checklist like this
maybe do a checklist like this,
and
and check
maybe do a checklist like this,
and check them
and check them off.
maybe do a checklist like this,
and check them off. Just
and check them off. Just like
that.
that. Super
and check them off. Just like
that. Super cool.
(Applause)
Next
Next I
(Applause)
Next I want
Next I want to
(Applause)
Next I want to show
Next I want to show you
multitasking
multitasking in
Next I want to show you
multitasking in the
multitasking in the context
Next I want to show you
multitasking in the context of
something
something I
multitasking in the context of
something I think
something I think we
multitasking in the context of
something I think we all
something I think we all do
quite
quite a
something I think we all do
quite a bit
quite a bit on
something I think we all do
quite a bit on our
quite a bit on our iPads,
something I think we all do
quite a bit on our iPads, which
is
is not
quite a bit on our iPads, which
is not that
is not that -
quite a bit on our iPads, which
is not that --
is not that -- which
quite a bit on our iPads, which
is not that -- which is
watching
watching ESPN
is not that -- which is
watching ESPN.
watching ESPN. So
is not that -- which is
watching ESPN. So let's
watching ESPN. So let's bring
is not that -- which is
up
watching ESPN. So let's bring
up a
up a video.
watching ESPN. So let's bring
up a video. I
up a video. I am
watching ESPN. So let's bring
up a video. I am going
up a video. I am going to
watching ESPN. So let's bring
up a video. I am going to play
right
right here
up a video. I am going to play
right here.
Now
Now,
right here.
Now, often
Now, often when
right here.
Now, often when I
Now, often when I am
right here.
Now, often when I am watching
a
a video
Now, often when I am watching
a video,
a video, I
Now, often when I am watching
a video, I m
a video, I may
Now, often when I am watching
a video, I may decide
a video, I may decide I
Now, often when I am watching
a video, I may decide I want
a video, I may decide I want to
look
look something
a video, I may decide I want to
look something up
look something up or
a video, I may decide I want to
look something up or check
something
something or
look something up or check
something or maybe
something or maybe even
look something up or check
something or maybe even get
something or maybe even get a
notification,
notification, a
something or maybe even get a
notification, and
notification, and I
something or maybe even get a
notification, and I want
notification, and I want you
something or maybe even get a
notification, and I want you to
watch
watch what
notification, and I want you to
watch what happens
watch what happens when
notification, and I want you to
watch what happens when I
watch what happens when I tap
notification, and I want you to
watch what happens when I tap.
Watch
Watch the
watch what happens when I tap.
Watch the video.
No
Now
Watch the video.
Now I
Now I have
Watch the video.
Now I have P
Now I have Picture
Watch the video.
Now I have Picture in
Now I have Picture in Picture
Watch the video.
Now I have Picture in Picture.
(Applause)
So
So I
(Applause)
So I can
So I can still
(Applause)
So I can still list
So I can still listen,
(Applause)
So I can still listen, I
So I can still listen, I can
watch
watch my
So I can still listen, I can
watch my video
watch my video,
So I can still listen, I can
watch my video, I
watch my video, I can,
So I can still listen, I can
watch my video, I can, of
course
course,
watch my video, I can, of
course, resize
course, resize the
watch my video, I can, of
course, resize the PIP
course, resize the PIP if
watch my video, I can, of
course, resize the PIP if I
want
want,
course, resize the PIP if I
want, like
want, like t
course, resize the PIP if I
want, like this.
want, like this. I
course, resize the PIP if I
want, like this. I can
want, like this. I can move
course, resize the PIP if I
want, like this. I can move it
around
around the
want, like this. I can move it
around the screen
around the screen so
want, like this. I can move it
around the screen so it's
around the screen so it's o
want, like this. I can move it
around the screen so it's out
of
of the
around the screen so it's out
of the way
of the way of
around the screen so it's out
of the way of what
of the way of what I
around the screen so it's out
of the way of what I am
of the way of what I am working
on.
on. I
of the way of what I am working
on. I can
on. I can even
of the way of what I am working
on. I can even m
on. I can even move
of the way of what I am working
on. I can even move i
on. I can even move it
of the way of what I am working
on. I can even move it off
on. I can even move it off the
side
side.
on. I can even move it off the
side. Sometimes
side. Sometimes I
on. I can even move it off the
side. Sometimes I just
side. Sometimes I just want
on. I can even move it off the
side. Sometimes I just want t
side. Sometimes I just want to
list
listen
side. Sometimes I just want to
listen for
listen for a
side. Sometimes I just want to
listen for a while
listen for a while while
side. Sometimes I just want to
listen for a while while I
listen for a while while I w
work.
work. Of
listen for a while while I w
work. Of course,
work. Of course, it
listen for a while while I w
work. Of course, it stays
work. Of course, it stays wit
listen for a while while I w
work. Of course, it stays with
me
me wherever
work. Of course, it stays with
me wherever I
me wherever I go.
work. Of course, it stays with
me wherever I go. I
me wherever I go. I can
work. Of course, it stays with
me wherever I go. I can pull
it
it back,
me wherever I go. I can pull
it back, and
it back, and when
me wherever I go. I can pull
it back, and when I
it back, and when I am
me wherever I go. I can pull
it back, and when I am done
it back, and when I am done,
just
just tap
it back, and when I am done,
just tap to
just tap to put
it back, and when I am done,
just tap to put i
just tap to put it
it back, and when I am done,
just tap to put it a
just tap to put it away.
And
And that
just tap to put it away.
And that is
And that is Multitasking
just tap to put it away.
And that is Multitasking in
iOS
iOS 9
And that is Multitasking in
iOS 9.
(Applause)
So
So iOS
(Applause)
So iOS 9
So iOS 9 d
(Applause)
So iOS 9 delivers
So iOS 9 delivers this
(Applause)
So iOS 9 delivers this great
app
app s
So iOS 9 delivers this great
app switcher,
app switcher, and
So iOS 9 delivers this great
app switcher, and o
app switcher, and of
So iOS 9 delivers this great
app switcher, and of course,
that's
that's available
app switcher, and of course,
that's available on
that's available on iPhone
app switcher, and of course,
that's available on iPhone as
well
well.
that's available on iPhone as
well. On
well. On iPad,
that's available on iPhone as
well. On iPad, we
well. On iPad, we have
that's available on iPhone as
well. On iPad, we have Slide
Over
Over so
well. On iPad, we have Slide
Over so you
Over so you can
well. On iPad, we have Slide
Over so you can bring
Over so you can bring apps
well. On iPad, we have Slide
Over so you can bring apps in
from
from t
Over so you can bring apps in
from the
from the side
Over so you can bring apps in
from the side.
from the side. You
Over so you can bring apps in
from the side. You can
from the side. You can tap
Over so you can bring apps in
from the side. You can tap and
enter
enter split
from the side. You can tap and
enter split view
enter split view for
simultaneous
simultaneous live
enter split view for
simultaneous live t
simultaneous live two
enter split view for
simultaneous live two apps
simultaneous live two apps u
enter split view for
simultaneous live two apps up.
And
And of
simultaneous live two apps up.
And of course,
And of course, Picture
simultaneous live two apps up.
And of course, Picture in
Picture
Picture.
Now,
Now, we
Picture.
Now, we provide
Now, we provide develop
Picture.
Now, we provide developer
Now, we provide developer APIs
to
to let
Now, we provide developer APIs
to let your
to let your apps
Now, we provide developer APIs
to let your apps w
to let your apps work
Now, we provide developer APIs
to let your apps work this
to let your apps work this way,
and
and the
to let your apps work this way,
and the good
and the good news
to let your apps work this way,
and the good news is
and the good news is that
you've
you've already
and the good news is that
you've already done
you've already done most
and the good news is that
you've already done most of
that
that work
you've already done most of
that work because
that work because if
you've already done most of
that work because if you've
adopted
adopted Auto
that work because if you've
adopted Auto layout
adopted Auto layout and
that work because if you've
adopted Auto layout and size
classes
classes to
adopted Auto layout and size
classes to work
classes to work great
adopted Auto layout and size
classes to work great on
classes to work great on the
iPhone
iPhone 6
classes to work great on the
iPhone 6 and
iPhone 6 and 6
classes to work great on the
iPhone 6 and 6 Plus
iPhone 6 and 6 Plus,
classes to work great on the
iPhone 6 and 6 Plus, well
iPhone 6 and 6 Plus, well,
classes to work great on the
iPhone 6 and 6 Plus, well, that
carries
carries over
iPhone 6 and 6 Plus, well, that
carries over j
carries over just
iPhone 6 and 6 Plus, well, that
carries over just like
carries over just like this
onto
onto iPad
carries over just like this
onto iPad.
onto iPad. Twitter
carries over just like this
onto iPad. Twitter came
onto iPad. Twitter came in
carries over just like this
onto iPad. Twitter came in and
was
was able
onto iPad. Twitter came in and
was able t
was able to
onto iPad. Twitter came in and
was able to do
was able to do it
onto iPad. Twitter came in and
was able to do it just
was able to do it just in
minutes.
minutes. It
was able to do it just in
minutes. It was
minutes. It was really
incredible.
Now,
Now, S
incredible.
Now, Slide
Now, Slide Over
incredible.
Now, Slide Over is
Now, Slide Over is available
for
for t
Now, Slide Over is available
for the
for the iPad
Now, Slide Over is available
for the iPad Air,
for the iPad Air, A
Now, Slide Over is available
for the iPad Air, Air
for the iPad Air, Air 2
Now, Slide Over is available
for the iPad Air, Air 2,
for the iPad Air, Air 2, mini
Now, Slide Over is available
for the iPad Air, Air 2, mini 2
and
and m
for the iPad Air, Air 2, mini 2
and mini
and mini 3
for the iPad Air, Air 2, mini 2
and mini 3,
and mini 3, a
for the iPad Air, Air 2, mini 2
and mini 3, as
and mini 3, as is
for the iPad Air, Air 2, mini 2
and mini 3, as is Picture
and mini 3, as is Picture in
Picture
Picture,
and mini 3, as is Picture in
Picture, and
Picture, and our
and mini 3, as is Picture in
Picture, and our m
Picture, and our most
and mini 3, as is Picture in
Picture, and our most powerful
split
split view
Picture, and our most powerful
split view is
split view is available
Picture, and our most powerful
split view is available o
split view is available on
Picture, and our most powerful
split view is available on our
most
most powerful
split view is available on our
most powerful i
most powerful iPad
split view is available on our
most powerful iPad,
most powerful iPad, the
split view is available on our
most powerful iPad, the iPad
Air
Air 2.
That's
That's Multitasking
Air 2.
That's Multitasking.
(Applause)
So
So we've
(Applause)
So we've seen
So we've seen some
(Applause)
So we've seen some great
So we've seen some great end
(Applause)
So we've seen some great e
end-user
end-user features,
So we've seen some great e
end-user features, but
end-user features, but of
course
course,
end-user features, but of
course, we've
course, we've also
end-user features, but of
course, we've also focused
course, we've also focused on
the
the foundations
course, we've also focused on
the foundations.
the foundations. In
performanc
performance
the foundations. In
performance,
performance, as
the foundations. In
performance, as you
performance, as you saw
the foundations. In
performance, as you saw earlier
in
in El
performance, as you saw earlier
in El Capitan
in El Capitan with
performance, as you saw earlier
in El Capitan with OS
in El Capitan with OS X
performance, as you saw earlier
in El Capitan with OS X,
in El Capitan with OS X, we've
taken
taken the
in El Capitan with OS X, we've
taken the core
taken the core frameworks
in El Capitan with OS X, we've
taken the core frameworks t
taken the core frameworks that
we
we use
taken the core frameworks that
we use for
we use for drawing
taken the core frameworks that
we use for drawing on
we use for drawing on the
system
system,
we use for drawing on the
system, Core
system, Core Animation
we use for drawing on the
system, Core Animation and
system, Core Animation and Core
Graphics
Graphics,
system, Core Animation and Core
Graphics, and
Graphics, and we
system, Core Animation and Core
Graphics, and we put
Graphics, and we put them
system, Core Animation and Core
Graphics, and we put them on
top
top of
Graphics, and we put them on
top of m
top of metal.
Graphics, and we put them on
top of metal. We
top of metal. We are
Graphics, and we put them on
top of metal. We are seeing
great
great a
top of metal. We are seeing
great acceleration
great acceleration,
top of metal. We are seeing
great acceleration, 1
great acceleration, 1.6
top of metal. We are seeing
great acceleration, 1.6 times
improvements
improvements i
great acceleration, 1.6 times
improvements in
improvements in animations
great acceleration, 1.6 times
improvements in animations and
scrolling
scrolling,
improvements in animations and
scrolling, and
scrolling, and a
improvements in animations and
scrolling, and a reduction
scrolling, and a reduction i
improvements in animations and
scrolling, and a reduction in
CPU
CPU usage
scrolling, and a reduction in
CPU usage for
CPU usage for drawing.
scrolling, and a reduction in
CPU usage for drawing. It's
really
really great.
With
With battery
really great.
With battery life,
With battery life, we
really great.
With battery life, we focused
on
on real
With battery life, we focused
on real world
on real world use
With battery life, we focused
on real world use cases
on real world use cases and
optimize
optimized
on real world use cases and
optimized them.
optimized them. And
on real world use cases and
optimized them. And we
optimized them. And we are
seeing
seeing an
optimized them. And we are
seeing an addition
seeing an addition of
optimized them. And we are
seeing an addition of one
seeing an addition of one hour
of
of typical
seeing an addition of one hour
of typical u
of typical use
seeing an addition of one hour
of typical use on
of typical use on a
seeing an addition of one hour
of typical use on a f
of typical use on a full
seeing an addition of one hour
of typical use on a full charge
on
on iPhone.
(Applause)
No
Now,
(Applause)
Now, we
Now, we know
(Applause)
Now, we know t
Now, we know that
(Applause)
Now, we know that for
Now, we know that for a
(Applause)
Now, we know that for a l
Now, we know that for a lot
(Applause)
Now, we know that for a lot of
you
you if
Now, we know that for a lot of
you if y
you if you
Now, we know that for a lot of
you if you are
you if you are running
Now, we know that for a lot of
you if you are running l
you if you are running low
Now, we know that for a lot of
you if you are running low on
power,
power, you
you if you are running low on
power, you s
power, you start
you if you are running low on
power, you start searching
power, you start searching all
over
over f
power, you start searching all
over for
over for switches
power, you start searching all
over for switches a
over for switches and
power, you start searching all
over for switches and t
over for switches and turning
off
off features
over for switches and turning
off features in
off features in the
over for switches and turning
off features in the hope
off features in the hope of
extend
extending
off features in the hope of
extending your
extending your battery
off features in the hope of
extending your battery life
extending your battery life a
little
little bit
extending your battery life a
little bit f
little bit further.
extending your battery life a
little bit further. Well
little bit further. Well,
extending your battery life a
little bit further. Well, n
little bit further. Well, now
in
in iOS
little bit further. Well, now
in iOS 9
in iOS 9,
little bit further. Well, now
in iOS 9, we
in iOS 9, we give
little bit further. Well, now
in iOS 9, we give y
in iOS 9, we give you
little bit further. Well, now
in iOS 9, we give you a
in iOS 9, we give you a single
switch
switch to
in iOS 9, we give you a single
switch to e
switch to enter
in iOS 9, we give you a single
switch to enter what
switch to enter what w
in iOS 9, we give you a single
switch to enter what we
switch to enter what we call
"low
"low p
switch to enter what we call
"low power
"low power mode
switch to enter what we call
"low power mode,"
"low power mode," and
switch to enter what we call
"low power mode," and i
"low power mode," and it
switch to enter what we call
"low power mode," and it pulls
"low power mode," and it pul
switch to enter what we call
"low power mode," and it sul
levers
levers that
"low power mode," and it sul
levers that you
levers that you didn't
"low power mode," and it sul
levers that you didn't even
know
know existed
levers that you didn't even
know existed and
know existed and i
levers that you didn't even
know existed and is
know existed and is able
levers that you didn't even
know existed and is able to
extend
extend battery
know existed and is able to
extend battery l
extend battery life
know existed and is able to
extend battery life f
extend battery life for
know existed and is able to
extend battery life for an
additional
additional three
extend battery life for an
additional three hours
additional three hours of
typical
typical use
additional three hours of
typical use on
typical use on top
additional three hours of
typical use on top of
typical use on top of that
additional
additional hour.
typical use on top of that
additional hour. It's
additional hour. It's really
great
great.
(Applause)
Now
Now,
(Applause)
Now, with
Now, with security
(Applause)
Now, with security,
Now, with security, we
(Applause)
Now, with security, we w
Now, with security, we want
(Applause)
Now, with security, we want to
protect
protect our
Now, with security, we want to
protect our use
protect our users'
Now, with security, we want to
protect our users' data
protect our users' data on
device
device and
protect our users' data on
device and in
device and in the
protect our users' data on
device and in the cloud
device and in the cloud,
protect our users' data on
device and in the cloud, and
device and in the cloud, and so
we
we are
device and in the cloud, and so
we are bringing
we are bringing two-factor
authentication
authentication and
we are bringing two-factor
authentication and making
authentication and making it
easy
easy for
authentication and making it
easy for everyone
easy for everyone to
authentication and making it
easy for everyone to protect
their
their data
easy for everyone to protect
their data in
their data in iCloud.
easy for everyone to protect
their data in iCloud. A
their data in iCloud. And
easy for everyone to protect
their data in iCloud. And with
software
software update,
their data in iCloud. And with
software update, we
software update, we want
everyone
everyone to
software update, we want
everyone to g
everyone to get
software update, we want
everyone to get to
everyone to get to iOS
software update, we want
everyone to get to iOS 9
everyone to get to iOS 9,
software update, we want
everyone to get to iOS 9, and
so
so we've
everyone to get to iOS 9, and
so we've done
so we've done major
enhancements
enhancements to
so we've done major
enhancements to the
architecture
architecture for
enhancements to the
architecture for o
architecture for our
enhancements to the
architecture for our over-the
architecture for our ove
over-the-air
over-the-air updates,
architecture for our ove
over-the-air updates, and
over-the-air updates, and we
have
have been
over-the-air updates, and we
have been able
have been able to
over-the-air updates, and we
have been able to reduce
have been able to reduce the
amount
amount of
have been able to reduce the
amount of f
amount of free
have been able to reduce the
amount of free space
amount of free space you
have been able to reduce the
amount of free space you need
to
to g
amount of free space you need
to get
to get to
amount of free space you need
to get to iOS
to get to iOS 9
amount of free space you need
to get to iOS 9 f
to get to iOS 9 from
amount of free space you need
to get to iOS 9 from t
to get to iOS 9 from the
amount of free space you need
to get to iOS 9 from the 4
to get to iOS 9 from the 4.6
gigs
gigs that
to get to iOS 9 from the 4.6
gigs that it
gigs that it took
to get to iOS 9 from the 4.6
gigs that it took to
gigs that it took to get
to get to iOS 9 from the 4.6
gigs that it took to get to
gigs that it took to get to iOS
8 down
8 down t
gigs that it took to get to iOS
8 down to
8 down to just
gigs that it took to get to iOS
8 down to just 1
8 down to just 1.3,
gigs that it took to get to iOS
8 down to just 1.3, so
8 down to just 1.3, so w
gigs that it took to get to iOS
8 down to just 1.3, so we
8 down to just 1.3, so we think
everybody
everybody is
8 down to just 1.3, so we think
everybody is going
everybody is going to
8 down to just 1.3, so we think
everybody is going to be
getting
getting into
everybody is going to be
getting into iOS
getting into iOS 9
everybody is going to be
getting into iOS 9.
(Applause)
So
So iOS
(Applause)
So iOS 9
So iOS 9,
(Applause)
So iOS 9, intelligence
throughout
throughout the
So iOS 9, intelligence
throughout the system,
throughout the system, Apple
Pay,
Pay, enhancements
throughout the system, Apple
Pay, enhancements to
Pay, enhancements to really
popular
popular a
Pay, enhancements to really
popular apps
popular apps l
Pay, enhancements to really
popular apps like
popular apps like Notes
Pay, enhancements to really
popular apps like Notes and
Maps
Maps,
popular apps like Notes and
Maps, an
Maps, an all
popular apps like Notes and
Maps, an all-n
Maps, an all-new
popular apps like Notes and
Maps, an all-new News
Maps, an all-new News app
popular apps like Notes and
Maps, an all-new News app,
Maps, an all-new News app, and
incredible
incredible f
Maps, an all-new News app, and
incredible features
incredible features now
Maps, an all-new News app, and
incredible features now for
iPad
iPad with
incredible features now for
iPad with multitasking
iPad with multitasking and
QuickType,
QuickType, and
iPad with multitasking and
QuickType, and of
QuickType, and of course
iPad with multitasking and
QuickType, and of course,
enhancements
enhancements t
QuickType, and of course,
enhancements to
enhancements to t
QuickType, and of course,
enhancements to the
enhancements to the foundations
QuickType, and of course,
enhancements to the found
foundations.
Now,
Now, iOS
foundations.
Now, iOS 9
Now, iOS 9 is
foundations.
Now, iOS 9 is a
Now, iOS 9 is a great
foundations.
Now, iOS 9 is a great release
for
for our
Now, iOS 9 is a great release
for our users
for our users,
Now, iOS 9 is a great release
for our users, but
for our users, but once
Now, iOS 9 is a great release
for our users, but once again,
it's
it's a
for our users, but once again,
it's a fantastic
it's a fantastic release
for our users, but once again,
it's a fantastic release for
all
all of
it's a fantastic release for
all of you
all of you developers,
it's a fantastic release for
all of you developers, bringing
a
a ton
all of you developers, bringing
a ton of
a ton of new
all of you developers, bringing
a ton of new features.
a ton of new features. You
all of you developers, bringing
a ton of new features. You saw
search
search extensibility
a ton of new features. You saw
search extensibility.
search extensibility. We
a ton of new features. You saw
search extensibility. We are
using
using UI
search extensibility. We are
using UI testing
using UI testing to
search extensibility. We are
using UI testing to X
using UI testing to Xcode.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
using UI testing to Xcode.
(Cheers and applause)
Yes!
We
We have
Yes!
We have a
We have a new
Yes!
We have a new technology
called
called App
We have a new technology
called App t
called App thinning,
We have a new technology
called App thinning, w
called App thinning, which
optimize
optimizes
called App thinning, which
optimizes your
optimizes your downloads
called App thinning, which
optimizes your downloads t
optimizes your downloads to
exactly
exactly t
optimizes your downloads to
exactly the
exactly the subset
optimizes your downloads to
exactly the subset of
exactly the subset of resources
needed
needed for
exactly the subset of resources
needed for that
needed for that use
exactly the subset of resources
needed for that user'
needed for that user's
exactly the subset of resources
needed for that user's device
needed for that user's device,
so
so you
needed for that user's device,
so you are
so you are able
needed for that user's device,
so you are able to
so you are able to get
needed for that user's device,
so you are able to get -
so you are able to get --
needed for that user's device,
so you are able to get -- take
less
less space
so you are able to get -- take
less space on
less space on device.
so you are able to get -- take
less space on device. It's
really
really great.
Now,
Now, when
really great.
Now, when it
Now, when it comes
really great.
Now, when it comes t
Now, when it comes to
really great.
Now, when it comes to gaming,
we've
we've enhanced
Now, when it comes to gaming,
we've enhanced SpriteKit,
SceneKit
SceneKit,
we've enhanced SpriteKit,
SceneKit, and
SceneKit, and Metal
we've enhanced SpriteKit,
SceneKit, and Metal a
SceneKit, and Metal and
introduced
introduced three
SceneKit, and Metal and
introduced three new
frameworks,
frameworks, G
introduced three new
frameworks, Gameplay
frameworks, GameplayKit
introduced three new
frameworks, GameplayKit to
bring
bring artificial
frameworks, GameplayKit to
bring artificial intelligence
with
with path
bring artificial intelligence
with path avoid,
with path avoid, optical
avoidance
avoidance and
with path avoid, optical
avoidance and path
avoidance and path finding;
model
model I
avoidance and path finding;
model I/O
model I/O to
avoidance and path finding;
model I/O to provide
model I/O to provide beautiful
lighting
lighting on
model I/O to provide beautiful
lighting on your
lighting on your 3D
model I/O to provide beautiful
lighting on your 3D models
lighting on your 3D models;
model I/O to provide beautiful
lighting on your 3D models; and
ReplayKit.
ReplayKit. It
lighting on your 3D models; and
ReplayKit. It lets
ReplayKit. It lets you
lighting on your 3D models; and
ReplayKit. It lets you enhance
your
your a
ReplayKit. It lets you enhance
your applications
your applications to
ReplayKit. It lets you enhance
your applications to let
your applications to let users
record
record their
your applications to let users
record their game
record their game play
your applications to let users
record their game play as
record their game play as video
your applications to let users
and
record their game play as video
and share
and share it
record their game play as video
and share it.
and share it. It's
record their game play as video
and share it. It's really
great.
(Applause)
No
Now
(Applause)
Now,
Now, HealthKit
(Applause)
Now, HealthKit has
Now, HealthKit has been
(Applause)
Now, HealthKit has been on
fire,
fire, so
Now, HealthKit has been on
fire, so w
fire, so we've
Now, HealthKit has been on
fire, so we've continued
fire, so we've continued --
well,
well, we
fire, so we've continued --
well, we a
well, we add
fire, so we've continued --
well, we added
well, we added W
fire, so we've continued --
well, we added Water,
well, we added Water, actually,
to
to HealthKit
well, we added Water, actually,
to HealthKit.
to HealthKit. We
well, we added Water, actually,
to HealthKit. We are
to HealthKit. We are not
trying
trying to
to HealthKit. We are not
trying to put
trying to put out
to HealthKit. We are not
trying to put out the
trying to put out the fire.
We
We are
trying to put out the fire.
We are add
We are add lots
trying to put out the fire.
We are add lots of
We are add lots of additional
metrics
metrics to
We are add lots of additional
metrics to be
metrics to be track
We are add lots of additional
metrics to be tracked,
metrics to be tracked, for
instance
instance,
metrics to be tracked, for
instance, hydration
instance, hydration,
metrics to be tracked, for
instance, hydration, U
instance, hydration, UV
exposure
exposure,
instance, hydration, UV
exposure, a
exposure, and
instance, hydration, UV
exposure, and reproductive
health.
Now,
Now, H
health.
Now, HomeKit
Now, HomeKit has
health.
Now, HomeKit has been
Now, HomeKit has been taking
off
off with
Now, HomeKit has been taking
off with manufacturers
introducing
introducing HomeKit
off with manufacturers
introducing HomeKit peripherals
to
to the
introducing HomeKit peripherals
to the market
to the market now
introducing HomeKit peripherals
to the market now in
to the market now in a
introducing HomeKit peripherals
to the market now in areas
to the market now in areas like
thermometers
thermometers,
to the market now in areas like
thermometers, locks
thermometers, locks,
to the market now in areas like
thermometers, locks, and
thermometers, locks, and lights
to the market now in areas like
thermometers, locks, and li
lights.
lights. And
thermometers, locks, and li
lights. And now
lights. And now in
thermometers, locks, and li
lights. And now in i
lights. And now in iOS
thermometers, locks, and li
lights. And now in iOS 9
lights. And now in iOS 9,
thermometers, locks, and li
lights. And now in iOS 9, we
are
are a
lights. And now in iOS 9, we
are adding
are adding support
lights. And now in iOS 9, we
are adding support f
are adding support for
lights. And now in iOS 9, we
are adding support for window
shades
shades,
are adding support for window
shades, sensors
shades, sensors of
are adding support for window
shades, sensors of a
shades, sensors of all
are adding support for window
shades, sensors of all kinds.
For
For instance,
shades, sensors of all kinds.
For instance, c
For instance, carbon
shades, sensors of all kinds.
For instance, carbon m
For instance, carbon monoxide
sensor
sensors,
For instance, carbon monoxide
sensors, motion
sensors, motion sensors.
For instance, carbon monoxide
sensors, motion sensors. And
we're
we're a
sensors, motion sensors. And
we're adding
we're adding support
sensors, motion sensors. And
we're adding support for
security
security s
we're adding support for
security systems
security systems as
we're adding support for
security systems as well
security systems as well.
Pe
Perhaps
security systems as well.
Perhaps m
Perhaps most
security systems as well.
Perhaps most important
Perhaps most importantly
security systems as well.
Perhaps most importantly,
Perhaps most importantly, we
are
are allowing
Perhaps most importantly, we
are allowing you
are allowing you to
Perhaps most importantly, we
are allowing you to access
are allowing you to access your
home
home remotely
are allowing you to access your
home remotely a
home remotely and
are allowing you to access your
home remotely and securely
home remotely and securely v
are allowing you to access your
home remotely and securely via
iCloud.
iCloud. So
home remotely and securely via
iCloud. So no
iCloud. So no matter
home remotely and securely via
iCloud. So no matter where
iCloud. So no matter where you
are,
are, you
iCloud. So no matter where you
are, you can
are, you can control
iCloud. So no matter where you
are, you can control all
are, you can control all of
your
your HomeKit
are, you can control all of
your HomeKit devices
your HomeKit devices.
(Applause)
Next
Next,
(Applause)
Next, CarPlay.
Next, CarPlay. S
(Applause)
Next, CarPlay. So
Next, CarPlay. So CarPlay
supports
supports a
Next, CarPlay. So CarPlay
supports audio
supports audio apps
Next, CarPlay. So CarPlay
supports audio apps and
supports audio apps and n
Next, CarPlay. So CarPlay
supports audio apps and now
supports audio apps and now,
Next, CarPlay. So CarPlay
supports audio apps and now, in
iOS
iOS 9
supports audio apps and now, in
iOS 9,
iOS 9, it
supports audio apps and now, in
iOS 9, it also
iOS 9, it also supports
supports audio apps and now, in
iOS 9, it also supports apps
iOS 9, it also supports apps by
the
the auto
iOS 9, it also supports apps by
the auto maker
the auto maker to
iOS 9, it also supports apps by
the auto maker to control
things
things i
the auto maker to control
things in
things in your
the auto maker to control
things in your own
things in your own car
the auto maker to control
things in your own car without
leaving
leaving the
things in your own car without
leaving the CarPlay
leaving the CarPlay experience.
And
And CarPlay
leaving the CarPlay experience.
And CarPlay is
And CarPlay is support
leaving the CarPlay experience.
And CarPlay is supporting
And CarPlay is supporting more
kinds
kinds o
And CarPlay is supporting more
kinds of
kinds of screens
And CarPlay is supporting more
kinds of screens,
kinds of screens, wide
And CarPlay is supporting more
kinds of screens, wider
kinds of screens, wider aspect
ratios
ratios,
kinds of screens, wider aspect
ratios, high
ratios, high DPI.
But
But mo
ratios, high DPI.
But most
But most significantly
ratios, high DPI.
But most significantly with
CarPlay
CarPlay,
But most significantly with
CarPlay, we
CarPlay, we are
But most significantly with
CarPlay, we are pulling
CarPlay, we are pulling the
cord.
cord. In
CarPlay, we are pulling the
cord. In future
cord. In future c
CarPlay, we are pulling the
cord. In future cars,
cord. In future cars, you
CarPlay, we are pulling the
cord. In future cars, you will
be
be able
cord. In future cars, you will
be able to
be able to get
cord. In future cars, you will
be able to get in
be able to get in your
cord. In future cars, you will
be able to get in your car
without
without taking
be able to get in your car
without taking your
without taking your phone
be able to get in your car
without taking your phone o
without taking your phone out
of
of your
without taking your phone out
of your bag
of your bag or
without taking your phone out
of your bag or out
of your bag or out of
without taking your phone out
of your bag or out of your
pocket
pocket a
of your bag or out of your
pocket and
pocket and start
of your bag or out of your
pocket and start peernsing
pocket and start peer
of your bag or out of your
pocket and start experiencing
CarPlay
CarPlay effortless
pocket and start experiencing
CarPlay effortlessly
CarPlay effortlessly.
pocket and start experiencing
CarPlay effortlessly. It's
going
going to
CarPlay effortlessly. It's
going to be
going to be really
CarPlay effortlessly. It's
going to be really great.
(Applause)
Final
Finally,
(Applause)
Finally, let's
Finally, let's talk
(Applause)
Finally, let's talk about
Swift.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
Swift.
(Cheers and applause)
You
You all
(Cheers and applause)
You all k
You all know
(Cheers and applause)
You all know that
You all know that the
(Cheers and applause)
You all know that the g
You all know that the growth
that
that Swift
You all know that the growth
that Swift has
that Swift has been
experiencing
experiencing is
that Swift has been
experiencing is just
unprecedented
unprecedented,
experiencing is just
unprecedented, and
unprecedented, and we've
experiencing is just
unprecedented, and we've all
seen
seen it
unprecedented, and we've all
seen it with
seen it with the
unprecedented, and we've all
seen it with the flood
seen it with the flood of
applications
applications coming
seen it with the flood of
applications coming in
applications coming in to
seen it with the flood of
applications coming in to the
App
App Store
applications coming in to the
App Store.
Well
Well,
App Store.
Well, now
Well, now we
App Store.
Well, now we are
Well, now we are stepping
App Store.
Well, now we are stepping on
the
the g
Well, now we are stepping on
the gas
the gas t
Well, now we are stepping on
the gas this
the gas this year
Well, now we are stepping on
the gas this year with
the gas this year with S
Well, now we are stepping on
the gas this year with Swift
the gas this year with Swift 2
Well, now we are stepping on
the gas this year with Swift 2.
Now
Now,
the gas this year with Swift 2.
Now, Swift
Now, Swift was
the gas this year with Swift 2.
Now, Swift was d
Now, Swift was designed
the gas this year with Swift 2.
Now, Swift was designed from
the
the beginning
Now, Swift was designed from
the beginning t
the beginning to
Now, Swift was designed from
the beginning to be
the beginning to be fast,
Now, Swift was designed from
the beginning to be fast, and
we've
we've continued
the beginning to be fast, and
we've continued t
we've continued to
the beginning to be fast, and
we've continued to roll
we've continued to roll out
target
targeted
we've continued to roll out
targeted optimization
targeted optimizations
we've continued to roll out
targeted optimizations all
targeted optimizations all y
we've continued to roll out
targeted optimizations all year
long
long,
targeted optimizations all year
long, and
long, and now
targeted optimizations all year
long, and now with
long, and now with Swift
targeted optimizations all year
long, and now with Swift 2,
long, and now with Swift 2, we
have
have a
long, and now with Swift 2, we
have an
have an all
long, and now with Swift 2, we
have an all-n
have an all-new
long, and now with Swift 2, we
have an all-new optimization
technology
technology that's
have an all-new optimization
technology that's e
technology that's especially
great
great for
technology that's especially
great for complex
great for complex applications
and
and object-oriented
great for complex applications
and object-oriented p
and object-oriented programming
that
that w
and object-oriented programming
that we
that we c
and object-oriented programming
that we call
that we call Whole
and object-oriented programming
that we call Whole Module
Optimization
Optimization,
that we call Whole Module
Optimization, a
Optimization, and
that we call Whole Module
Optimization, and the
Optimization, and the r
that we call Whole Module
Optimization, and the results
are
are really
Optimization, and the results
are really f
are really fantastic.
In
In addition,
are really fantastic.
In addition, we
In addition, we are
are really fantastic.
In addition, we are bringing
the
the language
In addition, we are bringing
the language features
the language features that
you've
you've asked
the language features that
you've asked f
you've asked for
the language features that
you've asked for m
you've asked for most,
the language features that
you've asked for most, an
elegant
elegant new
you've asked for most, an
elegant new error
elegant new error handling
model,
model, the
elegant new error handling
model, the ability
model, the ability to
elegant new error handling
model, the ability to see
model, the ability to see your
interfaces
interfaces a
model, the ability to see your
interfaces as
interfaces as synthesize
model, the ability to see your
interfaces as synthesized
headers
headers i
interfaces as synthesized
headers in
headers in Xcode
interfaces as synthesized
headers in Xcode,
headers in Xcode, and
interfaces as synthesized
headers in Xcode, and the
feature
feature that
headers in Xcode, and the
feature that Tim
feature that Tim has
headers in Xcode, and the
feature that Tim has been
begging
begging for
feature that Tim has been
begging for all
begging for all y
feature that Tim has been
begging for all year
begging for all year,
feature that Tim has been
begging for all year, pr
begging for all year, protocol
extension
extensions
begging for all year, protocol
extensions.
extensions. You
begging for all year, protocol
extensions. You are
extensions. You are all
begging for all year, protocol
extensions. You are all going
to
to lov
extensions. You are all going
to love
to love it
extensions. You are all going
to love it.
Now,
Now, we
to love it.
Now, we think
Now, we think Swift
to love it.
Now, we think Swift i
Now, we think Swift is
to love it.
Now, we think Swift is the
next
next big
Now, we think Swift is the
next big programming
next big programming language
Now, we think Swift is the
next big programming language,
the
the one
next big programming language,
the one that
the one that we
next big programming language,
the one that we will
the one that we will all
next big programming language,
the one that we will all be
doing
doing application
the one that we will all be
doing application and
doing application and systems
programming
programming on
doing application and systems
programming on f
programming on for
doing application and systems
programming on for 20
programming on for 20 years
doing application and systems
programming on for 20 years to
come.
come. And
programming on for 20 years to
come. And we
come. And we think
programming on for 20 years to
come. And we think Swift
should
should be
come. And we think Swift
should be every
should be everywhere
come. And we think Swift
should be everywhere a
should be everywhere and
come. And we think Swift
should be everywhere and used
by
by everyone
should be everywhere and used
by everyone,
by everyone, and
should be everywhere and used
by everyone, and so
by everyone, and so we're
should be everywhere and used
by everyone, and so we're going
to
to be
by everyone, and so we're going
to be d
to be doing
by everyone, and so we're going
to be doing something
to be doing something really
big.
big. Today
to be doing something really
big. Today w
big. Today we
to be doing something really
big. Today we are
big. Today we are announce
to be doing something really
big. Today we are announcing
that
that Swift
big. Today we are announcing
that Swift will
that Swift will be
big. Today we are announcing
that Swift will be open
that Swift will be open source.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
(Cheers and applause)
We
We will
We will be
We will be rolling
We will be rolling out
We will be rolling out the
compile
compiler
We will be rolling out the
compiler and
compiler and the
We will be rolling out the
compiler and the standard
libraries
libraries for
compiler and the standard
libraries for iOS,
libraries for iOS, O
compiler and the standard
libraries for iOS, OS
libraries for iOS, OS X
compiler and the standard
libraries for iOS, OS X,
libraries for iOS, OS X, and
Linux.
Linux. And
libraries for iOS, OS X, and
Linux. And i
Linux. And it
libraries for iOS, OS X, and
Linux. And it will
Linux. And it will a
libraries for iOS, OS X, and
Linux. And it will all
Linux. And it will all be
libraries for iOS, OS X, and
Linux. And it will all be out
there
there by
Linux. And it will all be out
there by the
there by the end
Linux. And it will all be out
there by the end of
there by the end of the
Linux. And it will all be out
there by the end of the year
there by the end of the year.
So
So that's
there by the end of the year.
So that's Swift,
So that's Swift, and
there by the end of the year.
So that's Swift, and that
So that's Swift, and that is
iOS
iOS 9.
So that's Swift, and that is
iOS 9. W
iOS 9. We
So that's Swift, and that is
iOS 9. We are
iOS 9. We are doing
So that's Swift, and that is
iOS 9. We are doing a
developer
developer beta
iOS 9. We are doing a
developer beta --
developer beta -- you
iOS 9. We are doing a
developer beta -- you g
developer beta -- you guessed
it
it --
developer beta -- you guessed
it -- today,
it -- today, a
developer beta -- you guessed
it -- today, and
it -- today, and for
developer beta -- you guessed
it -- today, and for the
it -- today, and for the first
time
time for
it -- today, and for the first
time for a
time for a m
it -- today, and for the first
time for a major
time for a major i
it -- today, and for the first
time for a major iOS
time for a major iOS release,
it -- today, and for the first
time for a major iOS release, a
public
public bet
time for a major iOS release, a
public beta,
public beta, so
time for a major iOS release, a
public beta, so sign
public beta, so sign u
time for a major iOS release, a
public beta, so sign up
public beta, so sign up now
time for a major iOS release, a
public beta, so sign up now a
public beta, so sign up now at
beta
beta.apple.com,
public beta, so sign up now at
beta.apple.com, and
beta.apple.com, and you
public beta, so sign up now at
beta.apple.com, and you can
beta.apple.com, and you can get
the
the bet
beta.apple.com, and you can get
the beta
the beta when
beta.apple.com, and you can get
the beta when it
the beta when it comes
beta.apple.com, and you can get
the beta when it comes out
the beta when it comes out in
July
July.
the beta when it comes out in
July. And
July. And of
the beta when it comes out in
July. And of course,
July. And of course, we
the beta when it comes out in
July. And of course, we will
be
be r
July. And of course, we will
be rolling
be rolling i
July. And of course, we will
be rolling it
be rolling it out
July. And of course, we will
be rolling it out as
be rolling it out as a
July. And of course, we will
be rolling it out as a f
be rolling it out as a free
upgrade
upgrade in
be rolling it out as a free
upgrade in t
upgrade in the
be rolling it out as a free
upgrade in the fall.
upgrade in the fall. And
be rolling it out as a free
upgrade in the fall. And iOS
upgrade in the fall. And iOS 9
will
will support
upgrade in the fall. And iOS 9
will support all
will support all of
upgrade in the fall. And iOS 9
will support all of the
will support all of the devices
that
that were
will support all of the devices
that were supported
that were supported by
will support all of the devices
that were supported by iOS
that were supported by iOS 8
will support all of the devices
that were supported by iOS 8.
We
We are
that were supported by iOS 8.
We are not
We are not dropping
that were supported by iOS 8.
We are not dropping any
We are not dropping any this
year
year because
We are not dropping any this
year because we
year because we want
We are not dropping any this
year because we want everyone
to
to get
year because we want everyone
to get iOS
to get iOS 9
year because we want everyone
to get iOS 9.
(Applause)
That's
That's iOS
(Applause)
That's iOS 9.
That's iOS 9. I
(Applause)
That's iOS 9. I really
appreciate
appreciate your
That's iOS 9. I really
appreciate your time.
appreciate your time. Have
That's iOS 9. I really
appreciate your time. Have a
fantastic
fantastic conference.
appreciate your time. Have a
fantastic conference. Thank
you.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
you.
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> TIM
(Cheers and applause)
>> TIM COOK:
>> TIM COOK: Thanks
(Cheers and applause)
>> TIM COOK: Thanks,
>> TIM COOK: Thanks, Craig
(Cheers and applause)
>> TIM COOK: Thanks, Craig.
iOS
iOS just
>> TIM COOK: Thanks, Craig.
iOS just keeps
iOS just keeps getting
>> TIM COOK: Thanks, Craig.
iOS just keeps getting bet
iOS just keeps getting better
and
and b
iOS just keeps getting better
and better
and better for
iOS just keeps getting better
and better for our
and better for our many
hundreds
hundreds of
and better for our many
hundreds of millions
hundreds of millions of
and better for our many
hundreds of millions of users,
and
and iOS
hundreds of millions of users,
and iOS 9
and iOS 9 takes
hundreds of millions of users,
and iOS 9 takes i
and iOS 9 takes it
hundreds of millions of users,
and iOS 9 takes it to
and iOS 9 takes it to an
hundreds of millions of users,
and iOS 9 takes it to an even
greater
greater level
and iOS 9 takes it to an even
greater level with
greater level with incredible
new
new apps
greater level with incredible
new apps and
new apps and i
greater level with incredible
new apps and intelligence
new apps and intelligence built
greater level with incredible
right
new apps and intelligence built
right into
right into iOS
new apps and intelligence built
right into iOS.
right into iOS. And
new apps and intelligence built
right into iOS. And as
right into iOS. And as an
new apps and intelligence built
right into iOS. And as an avid
iPad
iPad user,
right into iOS. And as an avid
iPad user, I
iPad user, I am
right into iOS. And as an avid
iPad user, I am also
iPad user, I am also incredibly
excited
excited about
iPad user, I am also incredibly
excited about how
excited about how far
iPad user, I am also incredibly
excited about how far i
excited about how far it
extends
extends t
excited about how far it
extends the
extends the iPad
excited about how far it
extends the iPad experience
extends the iPad experience as
we
we continue
extends the iPad experience as
we continue to
we continue to lead
extends the iPad experience as
we continue to lead in
we continue to lead in the
extends the iPad experience as
we continue to lead in the post
we continue to lead in the p
post-PC
post-PC era
we continue to lead in the p
post-PC era.
Without
Without E
post-PC era.
Without El
Without El Capitan
post-PC era.
Without El Capitan,
Without El Capitan, we've
created
created a
Without El Capitan, we've
created a n
created a new
Without El Capitan, we've
created a new version
created a new version of
Without El Capitan, we've
created a new version of OS
created a new version of OS X
that
that d
created a new version of OS X
that dramatically
that dramatically improves
created a new version of OS X
that dramatically improves the
experience
experience and
that dramatically improves the
experience and the
experience and the user
experience
experience and
experience and the user
experience and the
experience and the performance
of
of the
experience and the performance
of the M
of the Macintosh
experience and the performance
of the Macintosh.
An
And
of the Macintosh.
And of
And of course,
of the Macintosh.
And of course, Swift.
And of course, Swift. You've
just
just heard
And of course, Swift. You've
just heard Swift
just heard Swift p
And of course, Swift. You've
just heard Swift provides
just heard Swift provides a
single
single language
just heard Swift provides a
single language for
single language for you
just heard Swift provides a
single language for you to
create
create apps
single language for you to
create apps for
create apps for both
single language for you to
create apps for both O
create apps for both OS
single language for you to
create apps for both OS X
create apps for both OS X and
iOS
iOS.
There's
There's really
iOS.
There's really s
There's really so
iOS.
There's really so many
possibilities
possibilities for
There's really so many
possibilities for you
possibilities for you to
There's really so many
possibilities for you to use
these
these platforms
possibilities for you to use
these platforms and
these platforms and these
possibilities for you to use
these platforms and these tools
to
to c
these platforms and these tools
to create
to create unbelievable
these platforms and these tools
to create unbelievable apps
that
that w
to create unbelievable apps
that will
that will impact
to create unbelievable apps
that will impact business
that will impact business and
healthcare
healthcare and
that will impact business and
healthcare and education
healthcare and education and
really
really everything
healthcare and education and
really everything i
really everything in
healthcare and education and
really everything in our
really everything in our lives
healthcare and education and
really everything in our lives.
There's
There's seemingly
really everything in our lives.
There's seemingly n
There's seemingly no
really everything in our lives.
There's seemingly no limit
There's seemingly no limit to
what
what y
There's seemingly no limit to
what you
what you can
There's seemingly no limit to
what you can do.
An
And
what you can do.
And of
And of course,
what you can do.
And of course, underpinning
this,
this, the
And of course, underpinning
this, the App
this, the App Store
And of course, underpinning
this, the App Store i
this, the App Store is
And of course, underpinning
this, the App Store is very
this, the App Store is very key
And of course, underpinning
this, the App Store is very k
key.
key. It's
this, the App Store is very k
key. It's hard
key. It's hard t
this, the App Store is very k
key. It's hard to
key. It's hard to believe
this, the App Store is very k
key. It's hard to believe t
key. It's hard to believe that
the
the App
key. It's hard to believe that
the App Store
the App Store was
key. It's hard to believe that
the App Store was launch
the App Store was launched
key. It's hard to believe that
the App Store was launched only
seven
seven years
the App Store was launched only
seven years ago.
seven years ago. It's
the App Store was launched only
seven years ago. It's hard
seven years ago. It's hard to
remember
remember a
seven years ago. It's hard to
remember a d
remember a day
seven years ago. It's hard to
remember a day without
remember a day without it
seven years ago. It's hard to
remember a day without it.
Now
Now,
remember a day without it.
Now, I'm
Now, I'm happy
remember a day without it.
Now, I'm happy to
Now, I'm happy to announce
that
that the
Now, I'm happy to announce
that the App
that the App Store
Now, I'm happy to announce
that the App Store recently
passed
passed a
that the App Store recently
passed a major
passed a major milestone.
that the App Store recently
passed a major milestone. The
App
App Store
passed a major milestone. The
App Store h
App Store has
passed a major milestone. The
App Store has passed
App Store has passed 1
passed a major milestone. The
App Store has passed 100
billion
billion apps
App Store has passed 100
billion apps downloads
billion apps downloads.
App Store has passed 100
(Applause)
Th
The
(Applause)
The rate
The rate of
(Applause)
The rate of growth
The rate of growth and
(Applause)
The rate of growth and the
momentum
momentum is
The rate of growth and the
momentum is absolutely
staggering
staggering.
momentum is absolutely
staggering. The
staggering. The industry
momentum is absolutely
staggering. The industry has
never
never seen
staggering. The industry has
never seen anything
never seen anything like
staggering. The industry has
never seen anything like this
before
before.
never seen anything like this
before. The
before. The App
never seen anything like this
before. The App Store
before. The App Store h
never seen anything like this
before. The App Store has
forever
forever changed
before. The App Store has
forever changed software
forever changed software and
software
software distribution.
forever changed software and
software distribution. And
it's
it's also
software distribution. And
it's also been
it's also been a
software distribution. And
it's also been an
it's also been an economic
software distribution. And
it's also been an economic b
boon.
boon. We've
it's also been an economic b
boon. We've now
boon. We've now paid
it's also been an economic b
boon. We've now paid ove
boon. We've now paid over
it's also been an economic b
boon. We've now paid over $30
billion
billion to
boon. We've now paid over $30
billion to develop
billion to developers.
(Applause)
Th
The
(Applause)
The App
The App Store
(Applause)
The App Store continues
The App Store continues to
(Applause)
The App Store continues to be
the
the m
The App Store continues to be
the most
the most profitable
The App Store continues to be
the most profitable a
the most profitable app
marketplace
marketplace on
the most profitable app
marketplace on the
marketplace on the planet.
Now,
Now, we
marketplace on the planet.
Now, we could
Now, we could not
marketplace on the planet.
Now, we could not b
Now, we could not be
marketplace on the planet.
Now, we could not be more
proud
proud o
Now, we could not be more
proud of
proud of the
Now, we could not be more
proud of the work
proud of the work that
Now, we could not be more
proud of the work that you
proud of the work that you are
doing.
doing. M
proud of the work that you are
doing. More
doing. More a
proud of the work that you are
doing. More and
doing. More and more
proud of the work that you are
doing. More and more,
doing. More and more, dev
developers
developers are
doing. More and more, dev
developers are transforming
developers are transforming,
empowering,
empowering, and
developers are transforming,
empowering, and reimagining
empowering, and reimagining t
developers are transforming,
empowering, and reimagining the
very
very important
empowering, and reimagining the
very important things
very important things that
empowering, and reimagining the
very important things that we
do
do in
very important things that we
do in our
do in our daily
very important things that we
do in our daily lives.
do in our daily lives. We've
made
made a
do in our daily lives. We've
made a video
made a video about
do in our daily lives. We've
made a video about y
made a video about your
incredible
incredible i
made a video about your
incredible impact
incredible impact a
made a video about your
incredible impact and
incredible impact and just
made a video about your
incredible impact and just how
far
far you've
incredible impact and just how
far you've come
far you've come in
incredible impact and just how
far you've come in such
far you've come in such a
incredible impact and just how
far you've come in such a short
period
period of
far you've come in such a short
period of time
period of time,
far you've come in such a short
period of time, and
period of time, and I'd
far you've come in such a short
period of time, and I'd love
period of time, and I'd love to
run
run it
period of time, and I'd love to
run it for
run it for you
period of time, and I'd love to
run it for you now
run it for you now.
>>
>> Eight
>> Eight years
>> Eight years ago,
>> Eight years ago, when
>> Eight years ago, when the
iPhone
iPhone was
>> Eight years ago, when the
iPhone was launched,
iPhone was launched, it
>> Eight years ago, when the
iPhone was launched, it didn't
have
have an
iPhone was launched, it didn't
have an App
have an App Store
iPhone was launched, it didn't
have an App Store.
have an App Store. And
iPhone was launched, it didn't
have an App Store. And t
have an App Store. And there
was
was tremendous
have an App Store. And there
was tremendous desire
was tremendous desire on
have an App Store. And there
was tremendous desire on the
part
part of
was tremendous desire on the
part of developers
part of developers and
customers
customers for
part of developers and
customers for Apple
customers for Apple to
part of developers and
customers for Apple to let
third
third-party
customers for Apple to let
third-party application
third-party applications
customers for Apple to let
third-party applications be
created
created.
third-party applications be
We
created.
We all
We all had
created.
We all had this
We all had this dream
created.
We all had this dream that
apps
apps were
We all had this dream that
apps were going
apps were going to
We all had this dream that
apps were going to become
really
really important
apps were going to become
really important,
really important, but
apps were going to become
really important, but it
really important, but it took
some
some time
really important, but it took
some time to
some time to realize
really important, but it took
some time to realize how
some time to realize how they
would
would aff
some time to realize how they
would affect
would affect everything
some time to realize how they
would affect everything that
would affect everything that we
care
care about,
would affect everything that we
care about, a
care about, and
would affect everything that we
care about, and as
care about, and as t
would affect everything that we
care about, and as that
cumulative
cumulative effect
care about, and as that
cumulative effect appeared
cumulative effect appeared,
then
then we
cumulative effect appeared,
then we all
then we all start
cumulative effect appeared,
then we all start to
then we all start to realize,
oh,
oh, my
then we all start to realize,
oh, my goodness,
oh, my goodness, this
then we all start to realize,
oh, my goodness, this is
oh, my goodness, this is bigger
than
than any
oh, my goodness, this is bigger
than any of
than any of us
oh, my goodness, this is bigger
than any of us imagine
than any of us imagined.
>>
>> Apps
>> Apps plus
>> Apps plus hand
>> Apps plus handheld
>> Apps plus handheld devices
>> Apps plus handheld devices,
I
I think
>> Apps plus handheld devices,
I think that's
I think that's a
>> Apps plus handheld devices,
I think that's a water
I think that's a watersh
>> Apps plus handheld devices,
I think that's a watershed
moment
moment i
I think that's a watershed
moment in
moment in civilization.
I think that's a watershed
moment in civilization. I
moment in civilization. I put
it
it up
moment in civilization. I put
it up t
it up there
moment in civilization. I put
it up there with
it up there with the
moment in civilization. I put
it up there with the i
it up there with the invention
of
of the
it up there with the invention
of the microscope
of the microscope and
it up there with the invention
of the microscope and the
telescope.
telescope. We
of the microscope and the
telescope. We live
telescope. We live in
of the microscope and the
telescope. We live in a
telescope. We live in a time
where
where the
telescope. We live in a time
where the most
where the most powerful
telescope. We live in a time
where the most powerful tools
ever
ever i
where the most powerful tools
ever imagined
ever imagined to
where the most powerful tools
ever imagined to investigate
and
and probe
ever imagined to investigate
and probe our
and probe our world
ever imagined to investigate
and probe our world are
and probe our world are in
ever imagined to investigate
and probe our world are in the
hand
hand o
and probe our world are in the
hand of
hand of essential
and probe our world are in the
hand of essentially
hand of essentially everyone.
If
I
hand of essentially everyone.
>>
>> If
>> If you
>> If you think
>> If you think the
>> If you think the industrial
revolution
revolution was
>> If you think the industrial
revolution was transformation
revolution was transformational
>> If you think the industrial
revolution was transfo
transformational,
transformational, the
revolution was transfo
transformational, the App
transformational, the App Store
is
is way
transformational, the App Store
is way bigger.
is way bigger. I
transformational, the App Store
is way bigger. I don't
is way bigger. I don't think
we've
we've reached
is way bigger. I don't think
we've reached anything
we've reached
is way bigger. I don't think
we've seached
we've seenhed
is way bigger. I don't think
we've seen ed
we've seen ad
is way bigger. I don't think
we've seen anything
we've seen anything reach
is way bigger. I don't think
we've seen anything reach a
mass
mass adoption
we've seen anything reach a
mass adoption at
mass adoption at close
we've seen anything reach a
mass adoption at close to
mass adoption at close to this
pace.
pace. It
mass adoption at close to this
pace. It took,
pace. It took, f
mass adoption at close to this
pace. It took, for
pace. It took, for example,
electricity
electricity over
pace. It took, for example,
electricity over a
electricity over a hundred
years
years to
electricity over a hundred
years to get
years to get to
electricity over a hundred
years to get to its
years to get to its first
million
million u
years to get to its first
million users.
million users. It
years to get to its first
million users. It took
television
television 13
million users. It took
television 13 years
television 13 years,
million users. It took
television 13 years, and
television 13 years, and the
App
App Store
television 13 years, and the
App Store got
App Store got to
television 13 years, and the
App Store got to 5
App Store got to 50
television 13 years, and the
App Store got to 50 million
users
users in
App Store got to 50 million
users in only
users in only 17
App Store got to 50 million
users in only 17 m
users in only 17 months
App Store got to 50 million
users in only 17 months.
>>
>> The
>> The thing
>> The thing the
>> The thing the App
>> The thing the App Store
>> The thing the App Store did
was
was give
>> The thing the App Store did
was give each
was give each and
>> The thing the App Store did
was give each and every
developer
developer a
was give each and every
developer a voice.
developer a voice. It's
was give each and every
developer a voice. It's a
testament
testament tha
developer a voice. It's a
testament that
testament that two
developer a voice. It's a
testament that two guy
testament that two guys
developer a voice. It's a
testament that two guys in
testament that two guys in a
room
room working
testament that two guys in a
room working on
room working on an
testament that two guys in a
room working on an idea
room working on an idea can
launch
launch a
room working on an idea can
launch an
launch an app
room working on an idea can
launch an app and
launch an app and instantly
have
have hundred
launch an app and instantly
have hundreds
have hundreds of
launch an app and instantly
have hundreds of millions
have hundreds of millions of
launch an app and instantly
people
have hundreds of millions of
people very
people very quickly.
have hundreds of millions of
people very quickly. T
people very quickly. The
iPhone
iPhone made
people very quickly. The
iPhone made photograph
iPhone made photography
universally
universally accessible
iPhone made photography
universally accessible.
>>
>> I
universally accessible.
>> I cannot
>> I cannot t
universally accessible.
>> I cannot think
>> I cannot think o
universally accessible.
>> I cannot think of
>> I cannot think of a
universally accessible.
>> I cannot think of a single
industry
industry that
>> I cannot think of a single
industry that doesn't
industry that doesn't need
>> I cannot think of a single
industry that doesn't need a
industry that doesn't need an
app
app.
industry that doesn't need an
app. People
app. People want
industry that doesn't need an
app. People want d
app. People want data
industry that doesn't need an
app. People want data at
app. People want data at their
fingertips
fingertips.
app. People want data at their
fingertips. They
fingertips. They wan
app. People want data at their
fingertips. They want
personalized
personalized experience
fingertips. They want
personalized experiences.
personalized experiences. They
want
want power
personalized experiences. They
want power over
want power over their
personalized experiences. They
want power over their m
want power over their money.
And
And it's
want power over their money.
And it's not
And it's not just
want power over their money.
And it's not just for
And it's not just for banking;
it's
it's f
And it's not just for banking;
it's for
it's for every
And it's not just for banking;
it's for every industry
it's for every industry.
And it's not just for banking;
it's for every industry. The
App
App Store
it's for every industry. The
App Store h
App Store has
it's for every industry. The
App Store has fundamentally
shift
shifted
App Store has fundamentally
shifted how
shifted how we
App Store has fundamentally
shifted how we a
shifted how we all
App Store has fundamentally
shifted how we all need
shifted how we all need to
deliver
deliver.
shifted how we all need to
deliver. It's
deliver. It's leveling
shifted how we all need to
deliver. It's leveling the
playing
playing field
deliver. It's leveling the
playing field.
>>
>> We
playing field.
>> We don't
>> We don't have
playing field.
>> We don't have to
>> We don't have to own
things.
things. We
>> We don't have to own
things. We don't
things. We don't have
>> We don't have to own
things. We don't have to
things. We don't have to own
our
our own
things. We don't have to own
our own cars.
our own cars. We
things. We don't have to own
our own cars. We don't
our own cars. We don't have
things. We don't have to own
our own cars. We don't have to
own
own our
our own cars. We don't have to
own our own
own our own music.
our own cars. We don't have to
own our own music. We
own our own music. We can
our own cars. We don't have to
own our own music. We can call
it
it up
own our own music. We can call
it up when
it up when we
own our own music. We can call
it up when we need
it up when we need it.
own our own music. We can call
it up when we need it. That's
a
a big
it up when we need it. That's
a big change
a big change,
it up when we need it. That's
a big change, all
a big change, all flowing
it up when we need it. That's
a big change, all flowing from
the
the idea
a big change, all flowing from
the idea o
the idea of
a big change, all flowing from
the idea of not
the idea of not just
convenience
convenience but
the idea of not just
convenience but people
convenience but people building
up
up an
convenience but people building
up an infrastructure
up an infrastructure around
that.
We
We are
that.
We are now
We are now talking
that.
We are now talking not
We are now talking not about
hundreds
hundreds o
We are now talking not about
hundreds of
hundreds of people
We are now talking not about
hundreds of people getting
hundreds of people getting the
benefit
benefit of
hundreds of people getting the
benefit of an
benefit of an idea,
hundreds of people getting the
benefit of an idea, but
millions
millions.
>>
>> If
>> If you
>> If you had
>> If you had told
>> If you had told me
>> If you had told me when
>> If you had told me when I
was
was a
>> If you had told me when I
was a k
was a kid
>> If you had told me when I
was a kid that
was a kid that you
>> If you had told me when I
was a kid that you w
was a kid that you would
>> If you had told me when I
was a kid that you would be
able
able t
was a kid that you would be
able to
able to write
was a kid that you would be
able to write an
able to write an idea
was a kid that you would be
able to write an idea a
able to write an idea and
was a kid that you would be
able to write an idea and then
film
film that
able to write an idea and then
film that i
film that idea
able to write an idea and then
film that idea and
film that idea and then
distribute
distribute it
film that idea and then
distribute it to
distribute it to t
film that idea and then
distribute it to the
distribute it to the world
film that idea and then
distribute it to the world on
distribute it to the world on a
device
device that
distribute it to the world on a
device that you
device that you c
distribute it to the world on a
device that you could
device that you could also
distribute it to the world on a
device that you could also put
in
in your
device that you could also put
in your p
in your pocket
device that you could also put
in your pocket,
in your pocket, I
device that you could also put
in your pocket, I would
in your pocket, I would never
have
have stopped
in your pocket, I would never
have stopped laughing,
have stopped laughing, and
in your pocket, I would never
have stopped laughing, and I
would
would have
have stopped laughing, and I
would have thought
would have thought you
have stopped laughing, and I
would have thought you were
insane.
The
The App
insane.
The App Store
The App Store gives
insane.
The App Store gives everyone
access
access to
The App Store gives everyone
access to incredibly
access to incredibly powerful
tools
tools,
access to incredibly powerful
tools, and
tools, and there's
access to incredibly powerful
tools, and there's a
tools, and there's an
incredible
incredible generation
tools, and there's an
incredible generation of
filmmakers
filmmakers and
incredible generation of
filmmakers and storytellers
filmmakers and storytellers to
come
come.
>>
>> Kids
>> Kids love
>> Kids love technology,
>> Kids love technology, and
they
they love
>> Kids love technology, and
they love i
they love interacting
>> Kids love technology, and
they love interacting w
they love interacting with
>> Kids love technology, and
they love interacting with the
iPad
iPad and
they love interacting with the
iPad and with
iPad and with apps
they love interacting with the
iPad and with apps.
That
That wonder
iPad and with apps.
That wonder and
That wonder and awe
iPad and with apps.
That wonder and awe that
That wonder and awe that gets
ignite
ignited
That wonder and awe that gets
ignited is
ignited is actual
That wonder and awe that gets
ignited is actually
ignited is actually being
utilized
utilized to
ignited is actually being
utilized to help
utilized to help that
ignited is actually being
utilized to help that p
utilized to help that person
learn.
learn. Certainly
utilized to help that person
learn. Certainly in
learn. Certainly in education
there's
there's so
learn. Certainly in education
there's so much
there's so much potential
learn. Certainly in education
there's so much potential to
take
take the
there's so much potential to
take the classroom
take the classroom with
there's so much potential to
take the classroom with you
take the classroom with you any
there's so much potential to
take the classroom with you a
anywhere.
>>
>> We
>> We all
>> We all k
>> We all know
>> We all know we
>> We all know we are
>> We all know we are in
>> We all know we are in this
magic
magic moment
>> We all know we are in this
magic moment.
magic moment. There
>> We all know we are in this
magic moment. There are
magic moment. There are so
many
many incredible
magic moment. There are so
many incredible apps
many incredible apps,
magic moment. There are so
many incredible apps, and
many incredible apps, and they
do
do things
many incredible apps, and they
do things for
do things for people
many incredible apps, and they
do things for people that
change
change their
do things for people that
change their lives.
>>
>> Music
change their lives.
>> Music for
>> Music for me,
change their lives.
>> Music for me, it's
>> Music for me, it's like
everything
everything.
>> Music for me, it's like
everything. It's
everything. It's really
special
special.
everything. It's really
special. This
special. This amazing
everything. It's really
special. This amazing feeling
that
that music
special. This amazing feeling
that music gives
that music gives me,
special. This amazing feeling
that music gives me, I
that music gives me, I want
everyone
everyone to
that music gives me, I want
everyone to have
everyone to have that
that music gives me, I want
everyone to have that.
everyone to have that,
that music gives me, I want
everyone to have that, even
everyone to have that, even if
the
the person
everyone to have that, even if
the person cannot
the person cannot hear
everyone to have that, even if
the person cannot hear.
So
So the
the person cannot hear.
So the idea
So the idea of
the person cannot hear.
So the idea of the
So the idea of the app
the person cannot hear.
So the idea of the app is
So the idea of the app is to
introduce
introduce music
So the idea of the app is to
introduce music for
introduce music for deaf
people.
people. I
introduce music for deaf
people. I am
people. I am going
introduce music for deaf
people. I am going to
people. I am going to put
these
these on
people. I am going to put
these on your
these on your wrist,
people. I am going to put
these on your wrist, so
these on your wrist, so if
people. I am going to put
these on your wrist, so if you
play
play,
these on your wrist, so if you
play, you
play, you can
these on your wrist, so if you
play, you can feel
play, you can feel the
vibration
vibrations
play, you can feel the
vibrations.
>>
>> I
vibrations.
>> I can
>> I can feel
vibrations.
>> I can feel it.
>>
>> Did
>> I can feel it.
>> Did you
>> Did you feel
>> I can feel it.
>> Did you feel that,
>> Did you feel that, R
>> I can feel it.
>> Did you feel that, Rob
>> Did you feel that, Rob?
>> I can feel it.
My
>> Did you feel that, Rob?
My dream
My dream is
>> Did you feel that, Rob?
My dream is to
My dream is to b
>> Did you feel that, Rob?
My dream is to bring
My dream is to bring music
>> Did you feel that, Rob?
My dream is to bring music to
everyone.
>>
>> It
everyone.
>> It is
>> It is an
everyone.
>> It is an amazing
>> It is an amazing time
everyone.
>> It is an amazing time to
>> It is an amazing time to be
a
a develop
>> It is an amazing time to be
a developer.
a developer. We
>> It is an amazing time to be
a developer. We are
a developer. We are still
>> It is an amazing time to be
a developer. We are still just
at
at the
a developer. We are still just
at the beginning
at the beginning of
a developer. We are still just
at the beginning of all
at the beginning of all this,
this
this moment
at the beginning of all this,
this moment where
this moment where the
technology
technology of
this moment where the
technology of an
technology of an iPhone
this moment where the
technology of an iPhone and
technology of an iPhone and an
iPad
iPad and
technology of an iPhone and an
iPad and the
iPad and the Watch
technology of an iPhone and an
iPad and the Watch enable
iPad and the Watch enable so
many
many incredible
iPad and the Watch enable so
many incredible things.
There's
There's so
many incredible things.
There's so much
There's so much that
many incredible things.
There's so much that can
There's so much that can still
change
change and
There's so much that can still
change and evolve
change and evolve due
There's so much that can still
change and evolve due to
change and evolve due to the
power
power of
change and evolve due to the
power of applicat
power of applications
change and evolve due to the
power of applications.
(Applause)
>>
>> TIM
>> TIM COOK:
>> TIM COOK: On
>> TIM COOK: On behalf
>> TIM COOK: On behalf of
everyone
everyone at
>> TIM COOK: On behalf of
everyone at Apple,
everyone at Apple, we
>> TIM COOK: On behalf of
everyone at Apple, we want
everyone at Apple, we want to
thank
thank the
everyone at Apple, we want to
thank the developer
thank the developer community
for
for everything
thank the developer community
for everything that
for everything that you've
thank the developer community
for everything that you've d
done.
done. Thank
for everything that you've d
done. Thank you.
(Applause)
You
You have
(Applause)
You have changed
You have changed so
(Applause)
You have changed so many
You have changed so many parts
of
of all
You have changed so many parts
of all of
of all of our
You have changed so many parts
of all of our lives
of all of our lives and
transformed
transformed the
of all of our lives and
transformed the world
transformed the world in
of all of our lives and
transformed the world in the
process
process.
transformed the world in the
Now
process.
Now,
Now, we
process.
Now, we want
Now, we want to
process.
Now, we want to talk
Now, we want to talk about
process.
Now, we want to talk about now
the
the next
Now, we want to talk about now
the next opportunity
the next opportunity to
transform
transform the
the next opportunity to
transform the world.
transform the world. And
that's
that's the
transform the world. And
that's the opportunity
that's the opportunity to
transform the world. And
that's the opportunity to bring
native
native apps
that's the opportunity to bring
native apps to
native apps to the
that's the opportunity to bring
native apps to the Watch
native apps to the Watch with
that's the opportunity to bring
native apps to the Watch with a
new
new version
native apps to the Watch with a
new version of
new version of watchOS
native apps to the Watch with a
new version of watchOS.
(Applause)
For
For us
(Applause)
For us,
For us, this
(Applause)
For us, this is
For us, this is a
(Applause)
For us, this is a giant
For us, this is a giant mo
moment.
moment. This
For us, this is a giant mo
moment. This is
moment. This is how
For us, this is a giant mo
moment. This is how we
moment. This is how we felt
when
when we
moment. This is how we felt
when we launched
when we launched the
moment. This is how we felt
when we launched the App
when we launched the App Store
moment. This is how we felt
when we launched the App Store.
Opening
Opening a
when we launched the App Store.
Opening a new
Opening a new platform
when we launched the App Store.
Opening a new platform to
develop
developers
Opening a new platform to
developers to
developers to create
Opening a new platform to
developers to create new
applications
applications that
developers to create new
applications that can
applications that can r
developers to create new
applications that can really
change
change people
applications that can really
change people's
change people's lives.
applications that can really
change people's lives. We
really
really believe
change people's lives. We
really believe deep
really believe deeply
change people's lives. We
really believe deeply in
really believe deeply in this
space
space.
really believe deeply in this
space. We
space. We believe
really believe deeply in this
space. We believe i
space. We believe in
technology
technology designed
space. We believe in
technology designed for
technology designed for the
wrist.
wrist. And
technology designed for the
wrist. And we
wrist. And we believe
technology designed for the
wrist. And we believe by
opening
opening up
wrist. And we believe by
opening up the
opening up the p
wrist. And we believe by
opening up the platform
opening up the platform that
you
you w
opening up the platform that
you will
you will create
opening up the platform that
you will create n
you will create new
opening up the platform that
you will create new and
powerful
powerful use
you will create new and
powerful uses
powerful uses that
you will create new and
powerful uses that today
powerful uses that today we
you will create new and
powerful uses that today we c
powerful uses that today we can
you will create new and
only
powerful uses that today we can
only b
only begin
powerful uses that today we can
only begin to
only begin to i
powerful uses that today we can
only begin to imagine.
We
We began
only begin to imagine.
We began making
We began making the
only begin to imagine.
We began making the Apple
Watch
Watch available
We began making the Apple
Watch available just
Watch available just six
We began making the Apple
Watch available just six weeks
ago
ago,
Watch available just six weeks
ago, and
ago, and it's
Watch available just six weeks
ago, and it's pretty
ago, and it's pretty a
Watch available just six weeks
ago, and it's pretty amazing
that
that today
ago, and it's pretty amazing
that today we're
that today we're already
talking
talking about
that today we're already
talking about the
talking about the n
that today we're already
talking about the next
talking about the next version
of
of t
talking about the next version
of the
of the watchOS.
talking about the next version
of the watchOS. This
of the watchOS. This new
version
version will
of the watchOS. This new
version will have
version will have g
of the watchOS. This new
version will have great
version will have great new
capabilities
capabilities,
version will have great new
capabilities, and
capabilities, and it
version will have great new
capabilities, and it w
capabilities, and it will
version will have great new
capabilities, and it will bring
native
native apps
capabilities, and it will bring
native apps r
native apps right
capabilities, and it will bring
native apps right to
native apps right to y
capabilities, and it will bring
native apps right to your
native apps right to your wris
capabilities, and it will bring
native apps right to your wr
wrist.
To
To tell
wrist.
To tell you
To tell you all
wrist.
To tell you all about
To tell you all about it
wrist.
To tell you all about it,
To tell you all about it, I'd
like
like to
To tell you all about it, I'd
like to invite
like to invite up
To tell you all about it, I'd
like to invite up my
like to invite up my friend
To tell you all about it, I'd
like to invite up my friend and
colleague
colleague Kevin
like to invite up my friend and
colleague Kevin Lynch
colleague Kevin Lynch.
like to invite up my friend and
colleague Kevin Lynch. Kevin
colleague Kevin Lynch. Kevin.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> KEVIN
>> KEVIN LYNCH:
>> KEVIN LYNCH: Hi
>> KEVIN LYNCH: Hi.
>> KEVIN LYNCH: Hi. So
>> KEVIN LYNCH: Hi. So we're
moving
moving really
>> KEVIN LYNCH: Hi. So we're
moving really fast
moving really fast on
>> KEVIN LYNCH: Hi. So we're
moving really fast on watchOS
moving really fast on watchOS,
and
and I
moving really fast on watchOS,
and I am
and I am super
moving really fast on watchOS,
and I am super excited
and I am super excited to
moving really fast on watchOS,
and I am super excited to talk
with
with you
and I am super excited to talk
with you about
with you about the
and I am super excited to talk
with you about the enhancements
that
that are
with you about the enhancements
that are coming
that are coming in
with you about the enhancements
that are coming in w
that are coming in watchOS
with you about the enhancements
that are coming in watchOS,
that are coming in watchOS, as
well
well as
that are coming in watchOS, as
well as t
well as the
that are coming in watchOS, as
well as the powerful
well as the powerful new
abilities
abilities for
well as the powerful new
abilities for app
abilities for app development.
Let's
Let's start
Let's start with
Let's start with the
enhancements
enhancements.
Let's start with the
enhancements. The
enhancements. The enhancements
include
include great
enhancements. The enhancements
include great new
include great new timepiece
functions
functions,
include great new timepiece
functions, improvements
functions, improvements i
include great new timepiece
functions, improvements in
communication
communication as
functions, improvements in
communication as well
communication as well as
functions, improvements in
communication as well as i
communication as well as in
health
hea
communication as well as in
Health
Health &
communication as well as in
Health & Fitness
Health & Fitness,
communication as well as in
Health & Fitness, and
Health & Fitness, and support
for
for new
Health & Fitness, and support
for new capabilities
for new capabilities in
Health & Fitness, and support
for new capabilities in Apple
Pay
Pay,
for new capabilities in Apple
Pay, Maps,
Pay, Maps, and
for new capabilities in Apple
Pay, Maps, and Siri
Pay, Maps, and Siri.
Let's
Let's start
Pay, Maps, and Siri.
Let's start with
Let's start with timepiece.
Now,
Now, a
Let's start with timepiece.
Now, already
Now, already,
Let's start with timepiece.
Now, already, Apple
Now, already, Apple Watch
Let's start with timepiece.
Now, already, Apple Watch is
Now, already, Apple Watch is a
really
really great
Now, already, Apple Watch is a
really great timepiece
really great timepiece,
Now, already, Apple Watch is a
really great timepiece, m
really great timepiece, most
customize
customizable
really great timepiece, most
customizable one
customizable one in
really great timepiece, most
customizable one in the
customizable one in the world,
and
and a
customizable one in the world,
and a lot
and a lot of
customizable one in the world,
and a lot of that
and a lot of that is
customizable one in the world,
and a lot of that is due
and a lot of that is due to
customizable one in the world,
and a lot of that is due to the
watch
watch faces
and a lot of that is due to the
watch faces and
watch faces and how
and a lot of that is due to the
watch faces and how you
watch faces and how you can
change
change them.
watch faces and how you can
change them. We
change them. We are
watch faces and how you can
change them. We are adding
some
some new
change them. We are adding
some new watch
some new watch faces
change them. We are adding
some new watch faces in
some new watch faces in watch
change them. We are adding
some new watch faces in watchOS
2.
2. That
some new watch faces in watchOS
2. That includes
2. That includes a
some new watch faces in watchOS
2. That includes a beautiful
new
new Photos
2. That includes a beautiful
new Photos face
new Photos face to
2. That includes a beautiful
new Photos face to be
new Photos face to be able
2. That includes a beautiful
new Photos face to be able to
select
select any
new Photos face to be able to
select any photo
select any photos
new Photos face to be able to
select any photos you
select any photos you have
new Photos face to be able to
select any photos you have and
create
create a
select any photos you have and
create a w
create a watch
select any photos you have and
create a watch face
create a watch face out
select any photos you have and
create a watch face out of
create a watch face out of them
select any photos you have and
create a watch face out of t
them.
them. You
create a watch face out of t
them. You can
them. You can create
create a watch face out of t
them. You can create more
them. You can create more than
one
one and
them. You can create more than
one and s
one and switch
them. You can create more than
one and switch between
one and switch between them
them. You can create more than
one and switch between them if
you
you like.
one and switch between them if
you like. O
you like. Or
one and switch between them if
you like. Or you
you like. Or you can
one and switch between them if
you like. Or you can select
you like. Or you can select a
photo
photo album,
you like. Or you can select a
photo album, and
photo album, and every
you like. Or you can select a
photo album, and every time
photo album, and every time you
raise
raise your
photo album, and every time you
raise your wrist
raise your wrist,
photo album, and every time you
raise your wrist, you
raise your wrist, you will
photo album, and every time you
raise your wrist, you will see
a
a different
raise your wrist, you will see
a different photo
a different photo from
raise your wrist, you will see
a different photo from y
a different photo from your
album
album show
a different photo from your
album show up.
album show up. It's
a different photo from your
album show up. It's a
album show up. It's a great
way
way o
album show up. It's a great
way of
way of seeing
album show up. It's a great
way of seeing your
way of seeing your photos
throughout
throughout the
way of seeing your photos
throughout the day.
We
We went
throughout the day.
We went a
We went a little
throughout the day.
We went a little further
We went a little further with
this
this,
We went a little further with
this, shot
this, shot some
We went a little further with
this, shot some photo
this, shot some photos
ourselves.
ourselves. We
this, shot some photos
ourselves. We did
ourselves. We did some
this, shot some photos
ourselves. We did some time
lapse
lapse photograph
ourselves. We did some time
lapse photography
lapse photography in
ourselves. We did some time
lapse photography in s
lapse photography in some
beautiful
beautiful locations
lapse photography in some
beautiful locations around
beautiful locations around the
world
world.
beautiful locations around the
world. The
world. The way
beautiful locations around the
world. The way this
world. The way this works
beautiful locations around the
world. The way this works is
when
when y
world. The way this works is
when you
when you raise
world. The way this works is
when you raise your
when you raise your wrist
world. The way this works is
when you raise your wrist,
when you raise your wrist, you
will
will see
when you raise your wrist, you
will see t
will see this
when you raise your wrist, you
will see this 24
will see this 24-h
when you raise your wrist, you
will see this 24-hour
will see this 24-hour s
when you raise your wrist, you
will see this 24-hour shoot
will see this 24-hour shoot we
have
have done
will see this 24-hour shoot we
have done,
have done, and
will see this 24-hour shoot we
have done, and it
have done, and it will
will see this 24-hour shoot we
have done, and it will be
have done, and it will be the
current
current time
have done, and it will be the
current time there.
current time there. If
have done, and it will be the
current time there. If it's
current time there. If it's i
have done, and it will be the
current time there. If it's in
noon
noon,
current time there. If it's in
noon, you
noon, you will
current time there. If it's in
noon, you will see
noon, you will see noon
current time there. If it's in
noon, you will see noon i
noon, you will see noon in
London.
London. We've
noon, you will see noon in
London. We've done
London. We've done this
noon, you will see noon in
London. We've done this not
only
only for
London. We've done this not
only for London
only for London,
London. We've done this not
only for London, but
only for London, but other
locations
locations too
only for London, but other
locations too.
locations too. You
only for London, but other
locations too. You can
locations too. You can c
only for London, but other
locations too. You can choose
from
from H
locations too. You can choose
from Hong
from Hong Kong,
locations too. You can choose
from Hong Kong, M
from Hong Kong, Mack
locations too. You can choose
from Hong Kong, Mack Lake
from Hong Kong, Mack Lake --
which
which a
from Hong Kong, Mack Lake --
which a beautiful
which a beautiful place
from Hong Kong, Mack Lake --
which a beautiful place in
which a beautiful place in t
from Hong Kong, Mack Lake --
which a beautiful place in the
Sierra
Sierras
which a beautiful place in the
Sierras --
Sierras -- as
which a beautiful place in the
Sierras -- as well
Sierras -- as well as
which a beautiful place in the
Sierras -- as well as New
Sierras -- as well as New York,
Shanghai,
Shanghai, and
Sierras -- as well as New York,
Shanghai, and L
Shanghai, and London.
Sierras -- as well as New York,
Shanghai, and London. It's
Shanghai, and London. It's a
great
great way
Shanghai, and London. It's a
great way to
great way to see
Shanghai, and London. It's a
great way to see really
beautiful
beautiful imagery
great way to see really
beautiful imagery,
beautiful imagery, both
great way to see really
beautiful imagery, both your
own
own and
beautiful imagery, both your
own and these
own and these time
beautiful imagery, both your
own and these time lapse
own and these time lapse images
beautiful imagery, both your
own and these time lapse im
images.
You
You can
images.
You can customize
You can customize your
images.
You can customize your watch
with
with these
You can customize your watch
with these i
with these images
You can customize your watch
with these images but
with these images but can
You can customize your watch
with these images but can also
choose
choose to
with these images but can also
choose to show
choose to show what
with these images but can also
choose to show what you
choose to show what you like
with these images but can also
choose to show what you like on
the
the w
choose to show what you like on
the watch
the watch face
choose to show what you like on
the watch face with
the watch face with som
choose to show what you like on
the watch face with something
in
in t
the watch face with something
in tradition
in traditional
the watch face with something
in traditional watch
in traditional watch terms
called
called C
in traditional watch terms
called Complications.
called Complications. W
in traditional watch terms
called Complications. With
watchOS
watchOS 2,
called Complications. With
watchOS 2, w
watchOS 2, we
called Complications. With
watchOS 2, we are
watchOS 2, we are really
excited
excited t
watchOS 2, we are really
excited to
excited to e
watchOS 2, we are really
excited to enable
excited to enable developers
watchOS 2, we are really
excited to enable developers to
make
make your
excited to enable developers to
make your own
make your own Complications
excited to enable developers to
make your own Complications.
(Applause)
So
So be
(Applause)
So be able
So be able to
(Applause)
So be able to do
So be able to do things
(Applause)
So be able to do things like
show
show your
So be able to do things like
show your flight
show your flight time
So be able to do things like
show your flight time from
United,
United, see
show your flight time from
United, see t
United, see the
show your flight time from
United, see the state
United, see the state of
show your flight time from
United, see the state of your
home
home control
United, see the state of your
home control system
home control system,
United, see the state of your
home control system, look
home control system, look at
the
the charge
home control system, look at
the charge level
the charge level of
home control system, look at
the charge level of your
electric
electric car,
the charge level of your
electric car, or
electric car, or see
the charge level of your
electric car, or see sports
scores
scores,
electric car, or see sports
scores, for
scores, for example,
electric car, or see sports
scores, for example, f
scores, for example, from
electric car, or see sports
scores, for example, from the
MLB
MLB app
scores, for example, from the
MLB app.
MLB app. You
scores, for example, from the
MLB app. You can
MLB app. You can choose
scores, for example, from the
MLB app. You can choose the
information
information that
MLB app. You can choose the
information that you
information that you most
MLB app. You can choose the
information that you most like
to
to see
information that you most like
to see right
to see right on
information that you most like
to see right on your
to see right on your watch
information that you most like
to see right on your watch f
face.
face. It's
to see right on your watch f
face. It's going
face. It's going to
to see right on your watch f
face. It's going to be
face. It's going to be really,
really
really cool
face. It's going to be really,
really cool.
really cool. And
face. It's going to be really,
really cool. And this
really cool. And this will
work
work not
really cool. And this will
work not only
work not only on
really cool. And this will
work not only on the
work not only on the m
really cool. And this will
work not only on the modular
face
face but
work not only on the modular
face but a
face but across
work not only on the modular
face but across the
face but across the others
work not only on the modular
face but across the others that
support
support Complications
face but across the others that
support Complications as
support Complications as well.
Yo
You
You will
You will be
You will be able
You will be able to
You will be able to choose
from
from a
You will be able to choose
from a variety
from a variety of
You will be able to choose
from a variety of templates
from a variety of templates,
and
and we'll
from a variety of templates,
and we'll make
and we'll make those
from a variety of templates,
and we'll make those look
beautiful
beautiful i
and we'll make those look
beautiful in
beautiful in each
and we'll make those look
beautiful in each of
beautiful in each of the
different
different watch
beautiful in each of the
different watch faces
different watch faces.
beautiful in each of the
different watch faces. So
different watch faces. So it's
going
going to
different watch faces. So it's
going to be
going to be a
different watch faces. So it's
going to be a really
going to be a really f
different watch faces. So it's
going to be a really fast
going to be a really fast way
to
to look
going to be a really fast way
to look at
to look at this
going to be a really fast way
to look at this information.
Now
Now,
to look at this information.
Now, we
Now, we went
to look at this information.
Now, we went further
Now, we went further than
this.
this. We
Now, we went further than
this. We thought
this. We thought it's
Now, we went further than
this. We thought it's really
great
great to
this. We thought it's really
great to be
great to be able
this. We thought it's really
great to be able to
great to be able to see
this. We thought it's really
great to be able to see the
current
current information
great to be able to see the
current information,
current information, but
great to be able to see the
current information, but what
about
about future
current information, but what
about future information
about future information,
current information, but what
about future information, like
the
the weather
about future information, like
the weather later
the weather later today
about future information, like
the weather later today or
the weather later today or y
about future information, like
the weather later today or your
meeting
meeting after
the weather later today or your
meeting after the
meeting after the current
the weather later today or your
meeting after the current o
meeting after the current one?
And
And w
meeting after the current one?
And what
And what if
meeting after the current one?
And what if you
And what if you could
meeting after the current one?
And what if you could go
forward
forward i
And what if you could go
forward in
forward in time
And what if you could go
forward in time and
forward in time and actually
see
see that
forward in time and actually
see that information
see that information update
forward in time and actually
see that information update on
your
your watch
see that information update on
your watch face?
your watch face? Well
see that information update on
your watch face? Well,
your watch face? Well, we
see that information update on
your watch face? Well, we are
supporting
supporting that
your watch face? Well, we are
supporting that in
supporting that in watchOS
your watch face? Well, we are
supporting that in watchOS 2
with
with something
supporting that in watchOS 2
with something we
with something we call
supporting that in watchOS 2
with something we call Time
Travel.
Travel. And
with something we call Time
Travel. And you
Travel. And you will
with something we call Time
Travel. And you will be
Travel. And you will be able
to
to rotate
Travel. And you will be able
to rotate your
to rotate your Digital
Travel. And you will be able
to rotate your Digital Crown,
and
and you
to rotate your Digital Crown,
and you can
and you can go
to rotate your Digital Crown,
and you can go both
and you can go both forward
to rotate your Digital Crown,
and you can go both forward and
backward
backward through
and you can go both forward and
backward through t
backward through time,
and you can go both forward and
backward through time, and
backward through time, and the
information
information will
backward through time, and the
information will update
information will update right
on
on your
information will update right
on your screen.
Let's
Let's take
on your screen.
Let's take a
Let's take a look
on your screen.
Let's take a look here
Let's take a look here.
on your screen.
Let's take a look here. So
I've
I've got
Let's take a look here. So
I've got my
I've got my meeting
Let's take a look here. So
I've got my meeting in
I've got my meeting in the
Let's take a look here. So
middle
I've got my meeting in the
middle there
middle there and
I've got my meeting in the
middle there and weather
middle there and weather and
the
the charge
middle there and weather and
the charge level
the charge level of
middle there and weather and
the charge level of the
the charge level of the car
middle there and weather and
the charge level of the car and
time
time i
the charge level of the car and
time in
time in London
the charge level of the car and
time in London.
time in London. When
the charge level of the car and
time in London. When I
time in London. When I rotate
the
the crown,
time in London. When I rotate
the crown, you
the crown, you can
time in London. When I rotate
the crown, you can see
the crown, you can see it's
changing
changing t
the crown, you can see it's
changing the
changing the time
the crown, you can see it's
changing the time and
changing the time and showing
me
me things
changing the time and showing
me things that
me things that are
changing the time and showing
me things that are coming
me things that are coming up
changing the time and showing
me things that are coming up.
Now,
Now, we
me things that are coming up.
Now, we know
Now, we know a
me things that are coming up.
Now, we know a really
Now, we know a really popular
one
one here
Now, we know a really popular
one here might
one here might be
Now, we know a really popular
one here might be the
one here might be the stocks
Complication
Complication,
one here might be the stocks
Complication, but
Complication, but we
one here might be the stocks
Complication, but we haven't
cracked
cracked t
Complication, but we haven't
cracked that
cracked that one
Complication, but we haven't
cracked that one yet
cracked that one yet.
Complication, but we haven't
cracked that one yet. We
cracked that one yet. We are
working
working on
cracked that one yet. We are
working on it
working on it.
You
You can
working on it.
You can keep
You can keep rotating
working on it.
You can keep rotating,
You can keep rotating, keep
going
going forward,
You can keep rotating, keep
going forward, get
going forward, get all
You can keep rotating, keep
going forward, get all the
going forward, get all the way
to
to tonight.
going forward, get all the way
to tonight. You
to tonight. You can
going forward, get all the way
to tonight. You can see
to tonight. You can see I
going forward, get all the way
to tonight. You can see I have
a
a date
to tonight. You can see I have
a date n
a date night
to tonight. You can see I have
a date night tonight
a date night tonight,
to tonight. You can see I have
a date night tonight, weather
is
is going
a date night tonight, weather
is going to
is going to be
a date night tonight, weather
is going to be good,
is going to be good, time
a date night tonight, weather
is going to be good, time in
London
London will
is going to be good, time in
London will be
London will be 2:00
is going to be good, time in
London will be 2:00 a.m.
London will be 2:00 a.m. Y
is going to be good, time in
London will be 2:00 a.m. You
can
can have
London will be 2:00 a.m. You
can have all
can have all the
London will be 2:00 a.m. You
can have all the information
you
you want
can have all the information
you want to
you want to see
can have all the information
you want to see in
you want to see in the
can have all the information
you want to see in the time
you want to see in the time you
want
want to
you want to see in the time you
want to look
want to look at
you want to see in the time you
want to look at it
want to look at it.
you want to see in the time you
want to look at it. Really,
really
really f
want to look at it. Really,
really fun
really fun w
want to look at it. Really,
really fun way
really fun way to
want to look at it. Really,
really fun way to interact
really fun way to interact with
time
time on
really fun way to interact with
time on y
time on your
really fun way to interact with
time on your watch
time on your watch.
That's
That's Time
time on your watch.
That's Time Travel.
(Applause)
No
Now,
(Applause)
Now, we
Now, we also
(Applause)
Now, we also thought
Now, we also thought w
(Applause)
Now, we also thought what
would
would be
Now, we also thought what
would be a
would be a great
Now, we also thought what
would be a great experience
would be a great experience for
the
the watch
would be a great experience for
the watch when
the watch when it's
would be a great experience for
the watch when it's on
the watch when it's on y
would be a great experience for
the watch when it's on your
night
night stand
the watch when it's on your
night stand and
night stand and charging?
Well,
Well, we've
night stand and charging?
Well, we've come
Well, we've come u
night stand and charging?
Well, we've come up
Well, we've come up with
night stand and charging?
Well, we've come up with a
Well, we've come up with a new
user
user interface
Well, we've come up with a new
user interface for
user interface for this
Well, we've come up with a new
user interface for this in
watch
watchOS
user interface for this in
watchOS 2
watchOS 2 called
user interface for this in
watchOS 2 called Nightstand
Mode.
Mode. When
watchOS 2 called Nightstand
Mode. When you
Mode. When you put
watchOS 2 called Nightstand
Mode. When you put your
Mode. When you put your watch
on
on its
Mode. When you put your watch
on its side
on its side and
Mode. When you put your watch
on its side and it's
on its side and it's charging,
you
you will
on its side and it's charging,
you will get
you will get t
on its side and it's charging,
you will get this
you will get this beautiful
display
display now
you will get this beautiful
display now o
display now of
you will get this beautiful
display now of the
display now of the time,
you will get this beautiful
display now of the time, and
display now of the time, and of
course
course,
display now of the time, and of
course, you
course, you can
display now of the time, and of
course, you can set
course, you can set an
display now of the time, and of
course, you can set an alarm
that
that will
course, you can set an alarm
that will wake
that will wake you
course, you can set an alarm
that will wake you up
that will wake you up in
course, you can set an alarm
that will wake you up in the
morning,
morning, and
that will wake you up in the
morning, and it
morning, and it will
that will wake you up in the
morning, and it will go
something
something like
morning, and it will go
something like t
something like this
morning, and it will go
something like this.
(A
(Alarm
something like this.
(Alarm tone)
So
So a
(Alarm tone)
So a beautiful
So a beautiful little
(Alarm tone)
So a beautiful little bedside
alarm
alarm clock
So a beautiful little bedside
alarm clock now
alarm clock now with
So a beautiful little bedside
alarm clock now with Apple
Watch
Watch,
alarm clock now with Apple
Watch, and
Watch, and the
alarm clock now with Apple
Watch, and the b
Watch, and the buttons
alarm clock now with Apple
Watch, and the buttons on
Watch, and the buttons on the
side
side and
Watch, and the buttons on the
side and the
side and the Crown
Watch, and the buttons on the
side and the Crown act
side and the Crown act as
Watch, and the buttons on the
side and the Crown act as your
snooze
snooze and
side and the Crown act as your
snooze and O
snooze and Off
side and the Crown act as your
snooze and Off button
snooze and Off button.
side and the Crown act as your
snooze and Off button. A
really
really fun
snooze and Off button. A
really fun way
really fun way to
snooze and Off button. A
really fun way to have
really fun way to have a
Nightstand
Nightstand view
really fun way to have a
Nightstand view on
Nightstand view on your
really fun way to have a
Nightstand view on your watch.
Those
Those a
Those are
Those are some
Those are some of
Those are some of the
Those are some of the great
new
new timepiece
Those are some of the great
new timepiece function
new timepiece functions
Those are some of the great
new timepiece functions that
are
are c
new timepiece functions that
are coming
are coming in
new timepiece functions that
are coming in watch
are coming in watchOS
new timepiece functions that
are coming in watchOS 2
are coming in watchOS 2.
Let's
Let's look
are coming in watchOS 2.
Let's look at
Let's look at communication.
Now
Now,
Let's look at communication.
Now, already
Now, already Apple
Let's look at communication.
Now, already Apple Watch
Now, already Apple Watch is
great
great at
Now, already Apple Watch is
great at communicating
great at communicating with
your
your friends.
great at communicating with
your friends. Y
your friends. You
great at communicating with
your friends. You can
your friends. You can just
press
press the
your friends. You can just
press the s
press the side
your friends. You can just
press the side button
press the side button and
your friends. You can just
press the side button and see
your
your 1
press the side button and see
your 12
your 12 friends
press the side button and see
your 12 friends that
your 12 friends that you
press the side button and see
your 12 friends that you have
select
selected.
your 12 friends that you have
selected. Now
selected. Now,
your 12 friends that you have
selected. Now, we
selected. Now, we realize
your 12 friends that you have
selected. Now, we realize that
some
some of
selected. Now, we realize that
some of you
some of you have
selected. Now, we realize that
some of you have more
some of you have more than
selected. Now, we realize that
some of you have more than 12
friends
friends,
some of you have more than 12
friends, so
friends, so now
some of you have more than 12
friends, so now i
friends, so now in
some of you have more than 12
friends, so now in watch
friends, so now in watchOS
some of you have more than 12
friends, so now in watchOS 2
friends, so now in watchOS 2,
you
you have
friends, so now in watchOS 2,
you have different
you have different friends
friends, so now in watchOS 2,
you have different friends you
can
can select,
you have different friends you
can select, and
can select, and you
you have different friends you
can select, and you can
can select, and you can add
you have different friends you
can select, and you can add a
friend
friend by
can select, and you can add a
friend by p
friend by pressing
can select, and you can add a
friend by pressing the
friend by pressing the plus
sign
sign and
friend by pressing the plus
sign and add
sign and add a
friend by pressing the plus
sign and add a friend
sign and add a friend right
there.
there. Isn't
sign and add a friend right
there. Isn't that
there. Isn't that cool?
(Applause)
Now
Now,
(Applause)
Now, when
Now, when you
(Applause)
Now, when you are
communicating
communicating with
Now, when you are
communicating with someone,
communicating with someone, you
can
can make
communicating with someone, you
can make a
can make a phone
communicating with someone, you
can make a phone c
can make a phone call
communicating with someone, you
can make a phone call or
can make a phone call or send
communicating with someone, you
can make a phone call or send a
message
message or
can make a phone call or send a
message or send
message or send a
can make a phone call or send a
message or send a drawing
message or send a drawing with
Digital
Digital Touch
message or send a drawing with
Digital Touch,
Digital Touch, and
message or send a drawing with
Digital Touch, and now
Digital Touch, and now in
watchOS
watchOS 2
Digital Touch, and now in
watchOS 2,
watchOS 2, you
Digital Touch, and now in
watchOS 2, you will
watchOS 2, you will be
Digital Touch, and now in
watchOS 2, you will be able
watchOS 2, you will be able to
use
use multiple
watchOS 2, you will be able to
use multiple colors
use multiple colors in
watchOS 2, you will be able to
use multiple colors in your
drawings
drawings,
use multiple colors in your
drawings, so
drawings, so you
use multiple colors in your
drawings, so you can
drawings, so you can draw
use multiple colors in your
drawings, so you can draw a
beautiful
beautiful flower
drawings, so you can draw a
beautiful flower t
beautiful flower that
drawings, so you can draw a
beautiful flower that has
beautiful flower that has more
than
than just
beautiful flower that has more
than just o
than just one
beautiful flower that has more
than just one color
than just one color.
beautiful flower that has more
than just one color. Even
than just one color. Even my
drawings
drawings are
than just one color. Even my
drawings are starting
drawings are starting to
than just one color. Even my
drawings are starting to l
drawings are starting to look
better
better now
drawings are starting to look
better now with
better now with this.
Also
Also a
better now with this.
Also an
Also an email
better now with this.
Also an email.
Also an email. You
better now with this.
Also an email. You can
already
already read
Also an email. You can
already read e
already read email
Also an email. You can
already read email on
already read email on your
watch
watch.
already read email on your
watch. With
watch. With watch
already read email on your
watch. With watchOS
watch. With watchOS 2
already read email on your
watch. With watchOS 2,
watch. With watchOS 2, you
will
will be
watch. With watchOS 2, you
will be a
will be able
watch. With watchOS 2, you
will be able to
will be able to he
watch. With watchOS 2, you
will be able to he are
will be able to he are ply
watch. With watchOS 2, you
will be able to he are p
will be able to he p
watch. With watchOS 2, you
will be able to reply p
will be able to reply to
watch. With watchOS 2, you
will be able to reply to email.
(Applause)
And
And with
(Applause)
And with the
And with the phone,
(Applause)
And with the phone, you
And with the phone, you can
already
already take
And with the phone, you can
already take phone
already take phone calls
And with the phone, you can
already take phone calls on
your
your watch
already take phone calls on
your watch.
your watch. We
already take phone calls on
your watch. We are
your watch. We are now
already take phone calls on
your watch. We are now going
to
to support
your watch. We are now going
to support FaceTime
to support FaceTime Audio
your watch. We are now going
to support FaceTime Audio,
to support FaceTime Audio, so
you
you will
to support FaceTime Audio, so
you will get
you will get really
high-fidelity
high-fidelity calls
you will get really
high-fidelity calls right
high-fidelity calls right on
your
your wrist.
(Applause)
And
And with
And with Health
And with Health &
And with Health & Fitness
And with Health & Fitness,
already
already Apple
And with Health & Fitness,
already Apple Watch
already Apple Watch is
And with Health & Fitness,
already Apple Watch is a
already Apple Watch is a great
partner
partner for
already Apple Watch is a great
partner for H
partner for Health
already Apple Watch is a great
partner for Health &
partner for Health & Fitness
already Apple Watch is a great
partner for Health & Fitness.
With
With watchOS
partner for Health & Fitness.
With watchOS 2,
With watchOS 2, we
partner for Health & Fitness.
With watchOS 2, we are
With watchOS 2, we are enabling
your
your favorite
With watchOS 2, we are enabling
your favorite fit
your favorite fitness
With watchOS 2, we are enabling
your favorite fitness apps
your favorite fitness apps t
With watchOS 2, we are enabling
your favorite fitness apps to
run
run native
your favorite fitness apps to
run natively
run natively on
your favorite fitness apps to
run natively on your
run natively on your watch
your favorite fitness apps to
run natively on your watch so
you
you can
run natively on your watch so
you can use
you can use t
run natively on your watch so
you can use them
you can use them wherever
run natively on your watch so
you can use them wherever you
are,
are, and
you can use them wherever you
are, and your
are, and your workouts
you can use them wherever you
are, and your workouts with
these
these a
are, and your workouts with
these apps
these apps will
are, and your workouts with
these apps will contribute
directly
directly to
these apps will contribute
directly to your
directly to your all
these apps will contribute
directly to your all-d
directly to your all-day
activity,
activity, w
directly to your all-day
activity, which
activity, which w
directly to your all-day
activity, which will
activity, which will be
directly to your all-day
activity, which will be really
great,
great, so
activity, which will be really
great, so if
great, so if y
activity, which will be really
great, so if you
great, so if you go
activity, which will be really
great, so if you go on
great, so if you go on a
activity, which will be really
great, so if you go on a bike
ride,
ride, it
great, so if you go on a bike
ride, it will
ride, it will count.
(Applause)
We
We are
(Applause)
We are also
We are also enabling
(Applause)
We are also enabling Siri
We are also enabling Siri to
start
start workouts,
We are also enabling Siri to
start workouts, s
start workouts, so
We are also enabling Siri to
start workouts, so you
start workouts, so you can
We are also enabling Siri to
start workouts, so you can just
raise
raise your
start workouts, so you can just
raise your wrist
raise your wrist and
start workouts, so you can just
raise your wrist and say
raise your wrist and say hay,
sir
sir v
raise your wrist and say hay,
sir vrj
sir vrj,
raise your wrist and say hay,
sir vrj, start
sir vrj, start a
raise your wrist and say hay,
sir vrj, start a 30
sir vrj, start a 30-m
raise your wrist and say hay,
sir vrj, start a 30-minute
sir vrj, start a 30-minute run
in
in the
sir vrj, start a 30-minute run
in the park,
in the park, and
sir vrj, start a 30-minute run
in the park, and it
in the park, and it will
sir vrj, start a 30-minute run
in the park, and it will s
in the park, and it will start
the
the W
in the park, and it will start
the Workout
the Workout app
in the park, and it will start
the Workout app.
the Workout app. Y
in the park, and it will start
the Workout app. You
the Workout app. You can
in the park, and it will start
the Workout app. You can also
say
say things
the Workout app. You can also
say things like
say things like go
the Workout app. You can also
say things like go f
say things like go for
the Workout app. You can also
say things like go for a
say things like go for a 5
the Workout app. You can also
say things like go for a 5-mile
run
run,
say things like go for a 5-mile
run, and
run, and it
say things like go for a 5-mile
run, and it will
run, and it will start
say things like go for a 5-mile
run, and it will start the
workout
workout for
run, and it will start the
workout for you
workout for you without
run, and it will start the
workout for you without h
workout for you without having
to
to t
workout for you without having
to touch
to touch the
workout for you without having
to touch the watch
to touch the watch at
workout for you without having
to touch the watch at all
to touch the watch at all.
When
When you
to touch the watch at all.
When you achieve
When you achieve something,
there
there are
When you achieve something,
there are some
there are some beautiful
When you achieve something,
there are some beautiful new
achievements
achievements you
there are some beautiful new
achievements you will
achievements you will see
there are some beautiful new
achievements you will see that
look
look like
achievements you will see that
look like this.
look like this. They
achievements you will see that
look like this. They spin
right
right in,
look like this. They spin
right in, y
right in, you
look like this. They spin
right in, you can
right in, you can play
look like this. They spin
right in, you can play with
them
them in
right in, you can play with
them in 3D
them in 3D on
right in, you can play with
them in 3D on the
them in 3D on the watch
right in, you can play with
them in 3D on the watch,
them in 3D on the watch, t
right in, you can play with
them in 3D on the watch, they
are
are engraved
them in 3D on the watch, they
are engraved o
are engraved on
them in 3D on the watch, they
are engraved on the
are engraved on the back
them in 3D on the watch, they
are engraved on the back with
your
your name
are engraved on the back with
your name are
your name are,
are engraved on the back with
your name are, and
your name are, and y
are engraved on the back with
your name are, and you
your name are, and you can
share
share these
your name are, and you can
share these with
share these with people
your name are, and you can
share these with people over
Messages
Messages,
share these with people over
Messages, Facebook,
Messages, Facebook, or
share these with people over
Messages, Facebook, or T
Messages, Facebook, or Twitter.
Really
Really cool
Messages, Facebook, or Twitter.
Really cool Health
Really cool Health &
Messages, Facebook, or Twitter.
Really cool Health & Fitness
Really cool Health & Fitness.
(Applause)
With
With Apple
(Applause)
With Apple Pay,
With Apple Pay, y
(Applause)
With Apple Pay, you
With Apple Pay, you saw
(Applause)
With Apple Pay, you saw some
of
of the
With Apple Pay, you saw some
of the g
of the great
With Apple Pay, you saw some
of the great new
of the great new support
With Apple Pay, you saw some
of the great new support we
of the great new support we are
bringing
bringing f
of the great new support we are
bringing for
bringing for store
of the great new support we are
bringing for store c
bringing for store cards
of the great new support we are
bringing for store cards and
rewards
rewards cards
bringing for store cards and
rewards cards.
rewards cards. We
bringing for store cards and
rewards cards. We are
supporting
supporting that
rewards cards. We are
supporting that in
supporting that in the
rewards cards. We are
supporting that in the watch
supporting that in the watch,
so
so you
supporting that in the watch,
so you can
so you can select
supporting that in the watch,
so you can select a
so you can select a store
supporting that in the watch,
so you can select a store card
and
and use
so you can select a store card
and use it
and use it right
so you can select a store card
and use it right in
and use it right in your
so you can select a store card
and use it right in your watch
in
in a
and use it right in your watch
in a merchant
in a merchant terminal
and use it right in your watch
in a merchant terminal jus
in a merchant terminal just
and use it right in your watch
in a merchant terminal just by
waving
waving i
in a merchant terminal just by
waving it
waving it at
in a merchant terminal just by
waving it at the
waving it at the store
in a merchant terminal just by
waving it at the store stand
there
there.
waving it at the store stand
there. And
there. And W
waving it at the store stand
there. And Wallet
there. And Wallet coming
waving it at the store stand
there. And Wallet coming to
watch
watch,
there. And Wallet coming to
watch, all
watch, all of
there. And Wallet coming to
watch, all of your
watch, all of your r
there. And Wallet coming to
watch, all of your rewards
cards
cards will
watch, all of your rewards
cards will be
cards will be right
watch, all of your rewards
cards will be right t
cards will be right there,
watch, all of your rewards
cards will be right there, and
you
you can
cards will be right there, and
you can also
you can also use
cards will be right there, and
you can also use those
you can also use those right
from
from your
you can also use those right
from your watch
from your watch as
you can also use those right
from your watch as you
from your watch as you are
doing
doing p
from your watch as you are
doing purchases.
With
With Transit,
doing purchases.
With Transit, we
With Transit, we are
supporting,
supporting, of
With Transit, we are
supporting, of course,
supporting, of course, the
With Transit, we are
supporting, of course, the mass
transit
transit capabilities
supporting, of course, the mass
transit capabilities in
transit capabilities in M
supporting, of course, the mass
transit capabilities in Maps
now,
now, so
transit capabilities in Maps
now, so y
now, so you
transit capabilities in Maps
now, so you will
now, so you will be
transit capabilities in Maps
now, so you will be able
now, so you will be able to
transit capabilities in Maps
now, so you will be able to see
the
the t
now, so you will be able to see
the transit
the transit lines
now, so you will be able to see
the transit lines o
the transit lines on
now, so you will be able to see
the transit lines on your
the transit lines on your wrist
now, so you will be able to see
the transit lines on your wr
wrist.
wrist. You
the transit lines on your wr
wrist. You can
wrist. You can actually
the transit lines on your wr
wrist. You can actually see
the
the d
wrist. You can actually see
the departure
the departure times
wrist. You can actually see
the departure times for
different
different stations
the departure times for
different stations you
different stations you are
near.
near. When
different stations you are
near. When you
near. When you are
different stations you are
near. When you are navigating
near. When you are navigating,
you
you will
near. When you are navigating,
you will get
you will get s
near. When you are navigating,
you will get step-by-step
direction
directions
you will get step-by-step
directions about
directions about getting
through
through the
directions about getting
through the different
through the different mass
transit
transit you
through the different mass
transit you use
transit you use.
With
With Siri,
transit you use.
With Siri, we
With Siri, we are
transit you use.
With Siri, we are continuing
to
to add
With Siri, we are continuing
to add new
to add new domains
With Siri, we are continuing
to add new domains for
to add new domains for S
With Siri, we are continuing
to add new domains for Siri.
In
In watchOS
to add new domains for Siri.
In watchOS 2,
In watchOS 2, we
to add new domains for Siri.
In watchOS 2, we are
In watchOS 2, we are enabling
Siri
Siri to
In watchOS 2, we are enabling
Siri to get
Siri to get you
In watchOS 2, we are enabling
Siri to get you mass
Siri to get you mass transit
directions
directions,
Siri to get you mass transit
directions, like
directions, like bus
Siri to get you mass transit
directions, like bus d
directions, like bus directions
to
to t
directions, like bus directions
to the
to the Ferry
directions, like bus directions
to the Ferry Building
to the Ferry Building,
directions, like bus directions
to the Ferry Building, which
will
will look
to the Ferry Building, which
will look like
will look like this
to the Ferry Building, which
will look like this and
will look like this and you
to the Ferry Building, which
will look like this and you can
just
just s
will look like this and you can
just start
just start navigating
will look like this and you can
just start navigating.
just start navigating. O
will look like this and you can
just start navigating. Or
just start navigating. Or you
can
can control
just start navigating. Or you
can control things
can control things in
just start navigating. Or you
can control things in your
can control things in your home
with
with S
can control things in your home
with Siri,
with Siri, y
can control things in your home
with Siri, you
with Siri, you can
can control things in your home
with Siri, you can say
with Siri, you can say things
like
like "hey
with Siri, you can say things
like "hey Siri
like "hey Siri set
with Siri, you can say things
like "hey Siri set t
like "hey Siri set the
with Siri, you can say things
like "hey Siri set the dinner
scene
scene,"
like "hey Siri set the dinner
scene," an
scene," and
like "hey Siri set the dinner
scene," and it
scene," and it w
like "hey Siri set the dinner
scene," and it will
scene," and it will enable
like "hey Siri set the dinner
scene," and it will enable the
lights
lights in
scene," and it will enable the
lights in your
lights in your house
scene," and it will enable the
lights in your house and
lights in your house and s
scene," and it will enable the
lights in your house and set
them
them j
lights in your house and set
them just
them just how
lights in your house and set
them just how you
them just how you want
lights in your house and set
them just how you want them.
Isn't
Isn't that
them just how you want them.
Isn't that cool
Isn't that cool?
them just how you want them.
Isn't that cool? It's
Isn't that cool? It's going
them just how you want them.
Isn't that cool? It's going to
be
be great.
(Applause)
An
Another
(Applause)
Another great
Another great thing
(Applause)
Another great thing is
Another great thing is you
(Applause)
Another great thing is you can
actually
actually a
Another great thing is you can
actually ask
actually ask for
Another great thing is you can
actually ask for any
actually ask for any of
Another great thing is you can
actually ask for any of the
Glances
Glances you
actually ask for any of the
Glances you have,
Glances you have, so
actually ask for any of the
Glances you have, so you
Glances you have, so you can
say
say hey,
Glances you have, so you can
say hey, Siri,
say hey, Siri, s
Glances you have, so you can
say hey, Siri, show
say hey, Siri, show me
Glances you have, so you can
say hey, Siri, show me the
Instagram
Instagram G
say hey, Siri, show me the
Instagram Glance
Instagram Glance,
say hey, Siri, show me the
Instagram Glance, and
Instagram Glance, and it
say hey, Siri, show me the
Instagram Glance, and it will
show
show up
Instagram Glance, and it will
show up right
show up right on
Instagram Glance, and it will
show up right on your
show up right on your watch
face.
face. This
show up right on your watch
face. This could
face. This could be
show up right on your watch
face. This could be a
face. This could be a glance
you
you don't
face. This could be a glance
you don't have
you don't have currently
selected
selected.
you don't have currently
selected. It's
selected. It's a
you don't have currently
selected. It's a great
selected. It's a great way
you don't have currently
selected. It's a great way to
show
show information
selected. It's a great way to
show information from
third-party
third-party apps
show information from
third-party apps right
third-party apps right t
show information from
third-party apps right there
third-party apps right there in
Siri
Siri.
So
So t
Siri.
So those
So those are
Siri.
So those are just
So those are just some
Siri.
So those are just some of
So those are just some of the
highlights
highlights o
So those are just some of the
highlights of
highlights of what's
So those are just some of the
highlights of what's coming
highlights of what's coming in
watchOS
watchOS 2
highlights of what's coming in
watchOS 2.
watchOS 2. We
highlights of what's coming in
watchOS 2. We think
watchOS 2. We think it's
highlights of what's coming in
watchOS 2. We think it's going
to
to be
watchOS 2. We think it's going
to be a
to be a really,
watchOS 2. We think it's going
to be a really, really
to be a really, really g
watchOS 2. We think it's going
to be a really, really great
update
update to
to be a really, really great
update to the
update to the Watch.
(Ap
(Applause)
Now,
Now, that's
(Applause)
Now, that's not
Now, that's not all
(Applause)
Now, that's not all.
Now, that's not all. We
(Applause)
Now, that's not all. We also
Now, that's not all. We also,
of
of course,
Now, that's not all. We also,
of course, focused
of course, focused on
Now, that's not all. We also,
of course, focused on what
of course, focused on what we
can
can do
of course, focused on what we
can do for
can do for developers,
of course, focused on what we
can do for developers, and
already
already,
can do for developers, and
already, out
already, out of
can do for developers, and
already, out of the
already, out of the gate
can do for developers, and
already, out of the gate on
already, out of the gate on day
one
one,
already, out of the gate on day
one, you
one, you can
already, out of the gate on day
one, you can build
one, you can build apps
already, out of the gate on day
one, you can build apps for
Apple
Apple Watch
one, you can build apps for
Apple Watch using
Apple Watch using something
called
called WatchKit
Apple Watch using something
called WatchKit,
called WatchKit, and
Apple Watch using something
called WatchKit, and that
called WatchKit, and that has
enabled
enabled many
called WatchKit, and that has
enabled many thousands
enabled many thousands of
called WatchKit, and that has
enabled many thousands of a
enabled many thousands of apps
now
now to
enabled many thousands of apps
now to be
now to be created
enabled many thousands of apps
now to be created for
now to be created for Apple
Watch,
Watch, and
now to be created for Apple
Watch, and these
Watch, and these apps
now to be created for Apple
Watch, and these apps today
function
function b
Watch, and these apps today
function by
function by relying
Watch, and these apps today
function by relying on
function by relying on your
phone
phone.
function by relying on your
phone. So
phone. So you
function by relying on your
phone. So you might
phone. So you might have,
function by relying on your
phone. So you might have, for
example,
example, a
phone. So you might have, for
example, an
example, an app
phone. So you might have, for
example, an app on
example, an app on your
phone. So you might have, for
example, an app on your watch
and
and the
example, an app on your watch
and the user
and the user interface
example, an app on your watch
and the user interface runs
and the user interface runs on
your
your phone
and the user interface runs on
your phone and
your phone and the
and the user interface runs on
your phone and the u
your phone and the use
and the user interface runs on
your phone and the user
interface
interface is
your phone and the user
interface is on
interface is on the
your phone and the user
interface is on the Watch
interface is on the Watch,
your phone and the user
interface is on the Watch, but
all
all the
interface is on the Watch, but
all the lo
all the logic
interface is on the Watch, but
all the logic for
all the logic for your
interface is on the Watch, but
all the logic for your app
today
today runs
all the logic for your app
today runs o
today runs on
all the logic for your app
today runs on your
today runs on your phone
all the logic for your app
today runs on your phone.
today runs on your phone. With
native
native apps,
today runs on your phone. With
native apps, you
native apps, you will
today runs on your phone. With
native apps, you will be
native apps, you will be able
to
to move
native apps, you will be able
to move that
to move that logic
native apps, you will be able
to move that logic to
to move that logic to the
native apps, you will be able
to move that logic to the watch
soeth
soeth bo
to move that logic to the watch
soeth bo the
soeth bo the UI
to move that logic to the watch
soeth bo the UI and
soeth bo the UI and logic
to move that logic to the watch
soeth bo the UI and logic are
there,
there, i
soeth bo the UI and logic are
there, it
there, it will
soeth bo the UI and logic are
there, it will all
there, it will all run
soeth bo the UI and logic are
there, it will all run locally
there, it will all run locally,
performance
performance will
there, it will all run locally,
performance will be
performance will be great,
responsiveness
responsiveness will
performance will be great,
responsiveness will be
responsiveness will be great,
it's
it's going
responsiveness will be great,
it's going to
it's going to be
responsiveness will be great,
it's going to be a
it's going to be a g
responsiveness will be great,
it's going to be a great
it's going to be a great new
frontier
frontier for
it's going to be a great new
frontier for apps
frontier for apps on
it's going to be a great new
frontier for apps on Apple
Watch
Watch with
frontier for apps on Apple
Watch with n
Watch with native
frontier for apps on Apple
Watch with native app
Watch with native app support
frontier for apps on Apple
Watch with native app support.
(Applause)
When
When you
When you are
When you are actually
wandering
wandering away
When you are actually
wandering away from
wandering away from y
When you are actually
wandering away from your
wandering away from your phone
sometimes,
sometimes, y
wandering away from your phone
sometimes, your
sometimes, your apps
wandering away from your phone
sometimes, your apps will
sometimes, your apps will be
able
able to
sometimes, your apps will be
able to c
able to communicate
sometimes, your apps will be
able to communicate directly
with
with the
able to communicate directly
with the network
with the network with
able to communicate directly
with the network with can
with the network with can known
wi-fi
wi-fi n
with the network with can known
wi-fi networks
wi-fi networks,
with the network with can known
wi-fi networks, so
wi-fi networks, so you
with the network with can known
wi-fi networks, so you can
wi-fi networks, so you can get
the
the information
wi-fi networks, so you can get
the information you
the information you want
wherever
wherever y
the information you want
wherever you
wherever you are
the information you want
wherever you are w
wherever you are with
the information you want
wherever you are with your
watch.
(Applause)
So
So we
(Applause)
So we heard
So we heard from
(Applause)
So we heard from you
So we heard from you as
(Applause)
So we heard from you as we
were
were working
So we heard from you as we
were working on
were working on native
So we heard from you as we
were working on native apps
were working on native apps,
So we heard from you as we
were working on native apps, a
lot
lot of
were working on native apps, a
lot of feature
lot of feature requests
were working on native apps, a
lot of feature requests of
things
things you
lot of feature requests of
things you would
things you would like
lot of feature requests of
things you would like to
things you would like to do
lot of feature requests of
things you would like to do o
things you would like to do on
the
the Watch.
things you would like to do on
the Watch. These
the Watch. These are
things you would like to do on
the Watch. These are au
the Watch. These are au about
of
of things
the Watch. These are au about
of things that
of things that we've
the Watch. These are au about
of things that we've heard.
of things that we've heard. S
the Watch. These are au about
of things that we've heard. So
we've
we've been
of things that we've heard. So
we've been l
we've been listening
of things that we've heard. So
we've been listening to
we've been listening to t
of things that we've heard. So
we've been listening to that.
Let's
Let's go
we've been listening to that.
Let's go through
Let's go through some
we've been listening to that.
Let's go through some of
Let's go through some of the
things
things that
Let's go through some of the
things that will
things that will be
Let's go through some of the
things that will be possible
now
now i
things that will be possible
now in
now in watchOS
things that will be possible
now in watchOS 2.
now in watchOS 2. Y
things that will be possible
now in watchOS 2. You
now in watchOS 2. You can
things that will be possible
now in watchOS 2. You can see
how
how we
now in watchOS 2. You can see
how we did
how we did on
now in watchOS 2. You can see
how we did on this.
So
So one
how we did on this.
So one of
So one of the
how we did on this.
So one of the things
So one of the things we
how we did on this.
So one of the things we heard
was
was really
So one of the things we heard
was really wanted
was really wanted to
So one of the things we heard
was really wanted to access
was really wanted to access the
microphone
microphone on
was really wanted to access the
microphone on the
microphone on the Watch.
was really wanted to access the
microphone on the Watch. So
yes,
yes, i
microphone on the Watch. So
yes, in
yes, in w
microphone on the Watch. So
yes, in watchOS
yes, in watchOS 2,
microphone on the Watch. So
yes, in watchOS 2, y
yes, in watchOS 2, you
microphone on the Watch. So
yes, in watchOS 2, you can
access
access the
yes, in watchOS 2, you can
access the microphone
access the microphone right
yes, in watchOS 2, you can
access the microphone right on
the
the watch
access the microphone right on
the watch and
the watch and bring
access the microphone right on
the watch and bring t
the watch and bring that
access the microphone right on
the watch and bring that audio
right
right into
the watch and bring that audio
right into your
right into your app.
(Applause)
We
We also
(Applause)
We also heard
We also heard you
(Applause)
We also heard you want
We also heard you want to
(Applause)
We also heard you want to play
audio
audio out
We also heard you want to play
audio out of
audio out of the
We also heard you want to play
audio out of the speaker.
audio out of the speaker. You
can
can d
audio out of the speaker. You
can do
can do t
audio out of the speaker. You
can do that.
can do that. Watch
audio out of the speaker. You
can do that. WatchOS
can do that. WatchOS 2
audio out of the speaker. You
can do that. WatchOS 2 w
can do that. WatchOS 2 with
native
native apps,
can do that. WatchOS 2 with
native apps, you
native apps, you can
can do that. WatchOS 2 with
native apps, you can play
native apps, you can play back
through
through the
native apps, you can play back
through the watch
through the watch speak
native apps, you can play back
through the watch speaker
through the watch speaker or
play
play a
through the watch speaker or
play audio
play audio to
through the watch speaker or
play audio to a
play audio to a Bluetooth
through the watch speaker or
play audio to a Bluetooth head
play audio to a Bluetooth h
headphone.
Vi
Video
headphone.
Video.
Video. You
headphone.
Video. You can
Video. You can play
headphone.
Video. You can play back
short
short-form
Video. You can play back
short-form video
short-form video right
Video. You can play back
short-form video right on
short-form video right on t
Video. You can play back
short-form video right on the
watch
watch face.
short-form video right on the
watch face. It
watch face. It looks
short-form video right on the
watch face. It looks beautiful
on
on t
watch face. It looks beautiful
on the
on the Watch
watch face. It looks beautiful
on the Watch display
on the Watch display.
Access
Access to
on the Watch display.
Access to HealthKit.
Access to HealthKit. We
definitely
definitely heard
Access to HealthKit. We
definitely heard that
definitely heard that.
Access to HealthKit. We
definitely heard that. You
definitely heard that. You now
will
will have
definitely heard that. You now
will have a
will have access,
definitely heard that. You now
will have access, native
HealthKit
HealthKit on
will have access, native
HealthKit on the
HealthKit on the watch,
including
including s
HealthKit on the watch,
including streaming
including streaming heart
HealthKit on the watch,
including streaming heart rate
data,
data, so
including streaming heart rate
data, so i
data, so if
including streaming heart rate
data, so if y
data, so if you
including streaming heart rate
data, so if you are
data, so if you are doing,
including streaming heart rate
data, so if you are doing, for
example
example,
data, so if you are doing, for
example, a
example, a bike
data, so if you are doing, for
example, a bike ride
example, a bike ride with
Strava
Strava,
example, a bike ride with
Strava, you
Strava, you can
example, a bike ride with
Strava, you can s
Strava, you can see
example, a bike ride with
Strava, you can see what
Strava, you can see what heart
rate
rate zone
Strava, you can see what heart
rate zone you
rate zone you are
Strava, you can see what heart
rate zone you are i
rate zone you are in
Strava, you can see what heart
rate zone you are in while
rate zone you are in while you
are
are biking.
(Applause)
Ho
HomeKit
(Applause)
HomeKit is
HomeKit is n
(Applause)
HomeKit is natively
HomeKit is natively o
(Applause)
HomeKit is natively on
HomeKit is natively on the
watch
watch so
HomeKit is natively on the
watch so you
watch so you will
HomeKit is natively on the
watch so you will be
watch so you will be able
HomeKit is natively on the
watch so you will be able to
talk
talk t
watch so you will be able to
talk to
talk to your
watch so you will be able to
talk to your HomeKit
talk to your HomeKit device
watch so you will be able to
talk to your HomeKit devices
from
from your
talk to your HomeKit devices
from your watch
from your watch and
talk to your HomeKit devices
from your watch and control
them
them.
from your watch and control
them. We
them. We think
from your watch and control
them. We think this
them. We think this is
from your watch and control
them. We think this is going
to
to be
them. We think this is going
to be a
to be a great
them. We think this is going
to be a great future
to be a great future for
control
control right
to be a great future for
control right from
control right from your
to be a great future for
control right from your wrist.
You
You will
You will be
You will be a
You will be able
You will be able to
You will be able to access
You will be able to access the
Accelerometer
Accelerometer so
You will be able to access the
Accelerometer so you
Accelerometer so you can
You will be able to access the
Accelerometer so you can get
movement
movement d
Accelerometer so you can get
movement data.
movement data. S
Accelerometer so you can get
movement data. So
movement data. So for
Accelerometer so you can get
movement data. So for example,
from
from a
movement data. So for example,
from a ping
from a ping g
movement data. So for example,
from a ping golf
from a ping golf app
movement data. So for example,
from a ping golf app h
from a ping golf app here,
movement data. So for example,
from a ping golf app here, you
can
can check
from a ping golf app here, you
can check out
can check out your
from a ping golf app here, you
can check out your golf
can check out your golf swing
temp
tempo
can check out your golf swing
tempo as
tempo as y
can check out your golf swing
tempo as you
tempo as you are
can check out your golf swing
tempo as you are swinging
tempo as you are swinging the
golf
golf club
tempo as you are swinging the
golf club with
golf club with your
tempo as you are swinging the
golf club with your w
golf club with your watch
tempo as you are swinging the
golf club with your watch on
golf club with your watch on.
Taptic
Taptic Engine
golf club with your watch on.
Taptic Engine is
Taptic Engine is one
golf club with your watch on.
Taptic Engine is one of
Taptic Engine is one of the
things
things we've
Taptic Engine is one of the
things we've really
things we've really done
Taptic Engine is one of the
things we've really done a
things we've really done a l
Taptic Engine is one of the
things we've really done a lot
of
of focused
things we've really done a lot
of focused work
of focused work on
things we've really done a lot
of focused work on to
of focused work on to make
things we've really done a lot
of focused work on to make it
of focused work on to make it a
great
great experience
of focused work on to make it a
great experience on
great experience on the
of focused work on to make it a
great experience on the wrist
great experience on the wrist.
We
We are
great experience on the wrist.
We are bringing
We are bringing access
great experience on the wrist.
We are bringing access to
We are bringing access to the
Taptic
Taptic Engine
We are bringing access to the
Taptic Engine for
Taptic Engine for you
We are bringing access to the
Taptic Engine for you for
Taptic Engine for you for your
app
app development.
Taptic Engine for you for your
app development. Y
app development. You
Taptic Engine for you for your
app development. You will
app development. You will be
able
able to
app development. You will be
able to choose
able to choose from
app development. You will be
able to choose from a
able to choose from a range
app development. You will be
able to choose from a range of
different
different feelings
able to choose from a range of
different feelings as
different feelings as well
able to choose from a range of
different feelings as well as
audio
audio that
different feelings as well as
audio that will
audio that will come
different feelings as well as
audio that will come out
audio that will come out the
speak
speaker.
audio that will come out the
speaker. So
speaker. So for
audio that will come out the
speaker. So for example
speaker. So for example,
audio that will come out the
speaker. So for example, if
speaker. So for example, if I
am
am unlocking
speaker. So for example, if I
am unlocking m
am unlocking my
speaker. So for example, if I
am unlocking my car
am unlocking my car here
speaker. So for example, if I
am unlocking my car here,
am unlocking my car here, I
will
will get
am unlocking my car here, I
will get feedback
will get feedback on
am unlocking my car here, I
will get feedback on my
will get feedback on my wrist,
both
both a
will get feedback on my wrist,
both audio
both audio a
will get feedback on my wrist,
both audio and
both audio and felt
will get feedback on my wrist,
both audio and felt.
Just
Justike
both audio and felt.
Justike that.
Another
Another great
Justike that.
Another great interaction
Another great interaction on
the
the W
Another great interaction on
the Watch
the Watch is
Another great interaction on
the Watch is using
the Watch is using the
Another great interaction on
the Watch is using the Digital
Crown
Crown to
the Watch is using the Digital
Crown to manipulate
Crown to manipulate the
the Watch is using the Digital
Crown to manipulate the UI,
Crown to manipulate the UI, and
we
we are
Crown to manipulate the UI, and
we are enabling
we are enabling access
Crown to manipulate the UI, and
we are enabling access to
Digital
Digital Crown
we are enabling access to
Digital Crown as
Digital Crown as well
we are enabling access to
Digital Crown as well with
watchOS
watchOS 2
Digital Crown as well with
watchOS 2.
watchOS 2. You
Digital Crown as well with
watchOS 2. You will
watchOS 2. You will be
Digital Crown as well with
watchOS 2. You will be a
watchOS 2. You will be able
Digital Crown as well with
watchOS 2. You will be able to
control
control custom
watchOS 2. You will be able to
control custom UI
control custom UI element
watchOS 2. You will be able to
control custom UI element like
changing
changing the
control custom UI element like
changing the temperature
changing the temperature here
just
just by
changing the temperature here
just by rotating
just by rotating the
changing the temperature here
just by rotating the crown
just by rotating the crown like
this.
this. Sup
just by rotating the crown like
this. Super
this. Super easy
just by rotating the crown like
this. Super easy w
this. Super easy way
just by rotating the crown like
this. Super easy way to
interact
interact with
this. Super easy way to
interact with your
interact with your watch.
this. Super easy way to
(Applause)
So
So we've
(Applause)
So we've done
So we've done a
(Applause)
So we've done a great
So we've done a great job
bringing
bringing a
So we've done a great job
bringing a lot
bringing a lot of
So we've done a great job
bringing a lot of access
bringing a lot of access to
So we've done a great job
bringing a lot of access to t
bringing a lot of access to the
Watch
Watch now
bringing a lot of access to the
Watch now with
Watch now with n
bringing a lot of access to the
Watch now with native
Watch now with native apps
bringing a lot of access to the
Watch now with native apps.
Watch now with native apps. I
would
would like
Watch now with native apps. I
would like to
would like to show
Watch now with native apps. I
would like to show you
would like to show you a
Watch now with native apps. I
would like to show you a demo
now
now with
would like to show you a demo
now with some
now with some examples.
(Applause)
So
So I've
(Applause)
So I've got
So I've got a
(Applause)
So I've got a watch
So I've got a watch here,
(Applause)
So I've got a watch here, am
going
going to
So I've got a watch here, am
going to put
going to put it
So I've got a watch here, am
going to put it on.
going to put it on. It's
connected
connected to
going to put it on. It's
connected to the
connected to the display
going to put it on. It's
connected to the display here
through
through t
connected to the display here
through this
through this little
connected to the display here
through this little cable.
Al
All
through this little cable.
All right
All right.
through this little cable.
All right. L
All right. Let's
through this little cable.
All right. Let's start
All right. Let's start by
looking
looking at
All right. Let's start by
looking at three
looking at three examples
All right. Let's start by
looking at three examples of
new
new features
looking at three examples of
new features in
new features in w
looking at three examples of
new features in watchOS
new features in watchOS 2
looking at three examples of
new features in watchOS 2,
new features in watchOS 2, then
I
I will
new features in watchOS 2, then
I will he
I will he show
new features in watchOS 2, then
I will he show y
I will he show you
new features in watchOS 2, then
I will he show you three
I will he show you three apps
new features in watchOS 2, then
I will he show you three apps.
Let's
Let's start
I will he show you three apps.
Let's start with
Let's start with making
I will he show you three apps.
Let's start with making a
Let's start with making a photo
face
face,
Let's start with making a photo
face, so
face, so I
Let's start with making a photo
face, so I will
face, so I will press
Let's start with making a photo
face, so I will press my
Digital
Digital Crown
face, so I will press my
Digital Crown here,
Digital Crown here, g
face, so I will press my
Digital Crown here, go
Digital Crown here, go to
face, so I will press my
Digital Crown here, go to t
Digital Crown here, go to the
Home
Home screen.
Digital Crown here, go to the
Home screen. There's
Home screen. There's my
Photos.
Photos. You
Home screen. There's my
Photos. You can
Photos. You can see
Home screen. There's my
Photos. You can see I've
Photos. You can see I've got
Home screen. There's my
Photos. You can see I've got a
bunch
bunch of
Photos. You can see I've got a
bunch of photos
bunch of photos on
Photos. You can see I've got a
bunch of photos on here.
bunch of photos on here. I
Photos. You can see I've got a
bunch of photos on here. I can
zoom
zoom in
bunch of photos on here. I can
zoom in with
zoom in with the
bunch of photos on here. I can
zoom in with the C
zoom in with the Crown
bunch of photos on here. I can
zoom in with the Crown,
zoom in with the Crown, pan
around,
around, and
zoom in with the Crown, pan
around, and I
around, and I can
zoom in with the Crown, pan
around, and I can pick
around, and I can pick a
zoom in with the Crown, pan
around, and I can pick a photo
that
that might
around, and I can pick a photo
that might make
that might make a
around, and I can pick a photo
that might make a nice
that might make a nice watch
face
face like
that might make a nice watch
face like that
face like that o
that might make a nice watch
face like that one.
face like that one. I
that might make a nice watch
face like that one. I want
face like that one. I want to
zoom
zoom in
face like that one. I want to
zoom in and
zoom in and c
face like that one. I want to
zoom in and crop
zoom in and crop it
face like that one. I want to
zoom in and crop it a
zoom in and crop it a little
more
more.
zoom in and crop it a little
more. I
more. I am
zoom in and crop it a little
more. I am going
more. I am going t
zoom in and crop it a little
more. I am going to
more. I am going to zoom
zoom in and crop it a little
more. I am going to zoom i
more. I am going to zoom in
zoom in and crop it a little
more. I am going to zoom in a
little
little m
more. I am going to zoom in a
little more,
little more, m
more. I am going to zoom in a
little more, move
little more, move it
more. I am going to zoom in a
little more, move it over
little more, move it over l
more. I am going to zoom in a
little more, move it over like
that
that to
little more, move it over like
that to get
that to get it
little more, move it over like
that to get it just
that to get it just right
little more, move it over like
that to get it just right.
that to get it just right. I
think
think that's
that to get it just right. I
think that's going
think that's going to
that to get it just right. I
think that's going to m
think that's going to make
that to get it just right. I
think that's going to make a
great
great watch
think that's going to make a
great watch face
great watch face,
think that's going to make a
great watch face, so
great watch face, so I
think that's going to make a
great watch face, so I will
Force
Force Touch
great watch face, so I will
Force Touch,
Force Touch, create
great watch face, so I will
Force Touch, create new
Force Touch, create new watch
face
face,
Force Touch, create new watch
face, and
face, and there
Force Touch, create new watch
face, and there you
face, and there you go,
Force Touch, create new watch
face, and there you go, a
beautiful
beautiful new
face, and there you go, a
beautiful new watch
beautiful new watch face.
(Applause)
Le
Let's
(Applause)
Let's look
Let's look a
(Applause)
Let's look at
Let's look at Time
(Applause)
Let's look at Time Travel
Let's look at Time Travel.
(Applause)
Let's look at Time Travel. I
will
will go
Let's look at Time Travel. I
will go o
will go over
Let's look at Time Travel. I
will go over to
will go over to my
Let's look at Time Travel. I
will go over to my modular
will go over to my modular f
face,
face, got
will go over to my modular f
face, got some
face, got some more
will go over to my modular f
face, got some more information
here
here.
face, got some more information
here. I
here. I have
face, got some more information
here. I have flight
here. I have flight times
face, got some more information
here. I have flight times here
on
on U
here. I have flight times here
on United
on United.
here. I have flight times here
on United. I
on United. I can
here. I have flight times here
on United. I can see
on United. I can see the
temperature
temperature,
on United. I can see the
temperature, my
temperature, my V
on United. I can see the
temperature, my VW
temperature, my VW car
on United. I can see the
temperature, my VW car's
temperature, my VW car's charge
level,
level, and
temperature, my VW car's charge
level, and t
level, and time
temperature, my VW car's charge
level, and time in
level, and time in London
temperature, my VW car's charge
level, and time in London.
level, and time in London. So
I
I just
level, and time in London. So
I just rotate
I just rotate the
level, and time in London. So
I just rotate the c
I just rotate the crown
level, and time in London. So
I just rotate the crown here,
I just rotate the crown here, I
can
can go
I just rotate the crown here, I
can go forward
can go forward in
I just rotate the crown here, I
can go forward in time
can go forward in time.
I just rotate the crown here, I
can go forward in time. Time
is
is u
can go forward in time. Time
is updating
is updating.
can go forward in time. Time
is updating. My
is updating. My flight
can go forward in time. Time
is updating. My flight is
leaving,
leaving, you
is updating. My flight is
leaving, you can
leaving, you can see,
is updating. My flight is
leaving, you can see, at
leaving, you can see, at 1
is updating. My flight is
leaving, you can see, at 1:45.
I
I wonder
leaving, you can see, at 1:45.
I wonder if
I wonder if my
leaving, you can see, at 1:45.
I wonder if my charge
I wonder if my charge l
leaving, you can see, at 1:45.
I wonder if my charge level
will
will be
I wonder if my charge level
will be enough
will be enough to
I wonder if my charge level
will be enough to get
will be enough to get to
I wonder if my charge level
will be enough to get to the
airport.
airport. S
will be enough to get to the
airport. So
airport. So if
will be enough to get to the
airport. So if I
airport. So if I k
will be enough to get to the
airport. So if I keep
airport. So if I keep going
forward
forward in
airport. So if I keep going
forward in time
forward in time h
airport. So if I keep going
forward in time here,
forward in time here, we
airport. So if I keep going
forward in time here, we w
forward in time here, we will
get
get to
forward in time here, we will
get to 1
get to 1:4
forward in time here, we will
get to 1:45,
get to 1:45, and
forward in time here, we will
get to 1:45, and you
get to 1:45, and you can
forward in time here, we will
get to 1:45, and you can see
get to 1:45, and you can see my
charge
charge level
get to 1:45, and you can see my
charge level is
charge level is just
get to 1:45, and you can see my
charge level is just going
charge level is just going to
be
be great
charge level is just going to
be great to
be great to get
charge level is just going to
be great to get to
be great to get to the
charge level is just going to
be great to get to the airport.
I
In
be great to get to the airport.
In fact,
In fact, you
be great to get to the airport.
In fact, you can
In fact, you can keep
be great to get to the airport.
In fact, you can keep going
and
and look
In fact, you can keep going
and look at
and look at boarding
In fact, you can keep going
and look at boarding t
and look at boarding time
In fact, you can keep going
and look at boarding time and
arrival
arrival time
and look at boarding time and
arrival time for
arrival time for your
and look at boarding time and
arrival time for your flight.
So
So you
arrival time for your flight.
So you can
So you can get
arrival time for your flight.
So you can get a
So you can get a great
arrival time for your flight.
So you can get a great preview
of
of you
So you can get a great preview
of your
of your day
So you can get a great preview
of your day just
of your day just b
So you can get a great preview
of your day just by
of your day just by rotating
the
the crown
of your day just by rotating
the crown right
the crown right on
of your day just by rotating
the crown right on the
the crown right on the watch
face
face.
the crown right on the watch
face. It's
face. It's a
the crown right on the watch
face. It's a l
face. It's a lot
the crown right on the watch
face. It's a lot of
face. It's a lot of fun
the crown right on the watch
face. It's a lot of fun.
face. It's a lot of fun. Just
press
press the
face. It's a lot of fun. Just
press the crown
press the crown and
face. It's a lot of fun. Just
press the crown and go
press the crown and go back
face. It's a lot of fun. Just
press the crown and go back to
Home.
If
If you
Home.
If you get
If you get an
Home.
If you get an email,
If you get an email, you
Home.
If you get an email, you can
reply
reply to
If you get an email, you can
reply to email
reply to email now
If you get an email, you can
reply to email now in
reply to email now in watchOS
2.
2. Here
reply to email now in watchOS
2. Here is
2. Here is an
reply to email now in watchOS
2. Here is an email
2. Here is an email that's
just
just come
2. Here is an email that's
just come in
just come in from
2. Here is an email that's
just come in from M
just come in from Marc.
2. Here is an email that's
just come in from Marc. I
just come in from Marc. I can
reply
reply to
just come in from Marc. I can
reply to t
reply to this
just come in from Marc. I can
reply to this by
reply to this by pressing
just come in from Marc. I can
reply to this by pressing the
button
button right
reply to this by pressing the
button right below
button right below the
reply to this by pressing the
button right below the message
button right below the message,
or
or y
button right below the message,
or you
or you can
button right below the message,
or you can use
or you can use Siri
button right below the message,
or you can use Siri to
or you can use Siri to reply
button right below the message,
or you can use Siri to reply t
or you can use Siri to reply to
a
a message
or you can use Siri to reply to
a message right
a message right from
or you can use Siri to reply to
a message right from a
notification.
notification. If
a message right from a
notification. If I
notification. If I just
a message right from a
notification. If I just use
Siri
Siri here,
notification. If I just use
Siri here, I
Siri here, I can
notification. If I just use
Siri here, I can reply
Siri here, I can reply like
this.
Reply
Reply:
this.
Reply: I
Reply: I would
this.
Reply: I would love
Reply: I would love to
this.
Reply: I would love to.
So
So Siri
Reply: I would love to.
So Siri i
So Siri is
Reply: I would love to.
So Siri is making
So Siri is making the
Reply: I would love to.
So Siri is making the message
there
there.
So Siri is making the message
there. It's
there. It's create
So Siri is making the message
there. It's created
there. It's created a
So Siri is making the message
there. It's created a res
response.
response. I
there. It's created a res
response. I just
response. I just press
there. It's created a res
response. I just press Send,
and
and i
response. I just press Send,
and it
and it now
response. I just press Send,
and it now goes
and it now goes off
response. I just press Send,
and it now goes off to
and it now goes off to Marc.
So
So just
and it now goes off to Marc.
So just by
So just by pressing
and it now goes off to Marc.
So just by pressing t
So just by pressing the
and it now goes off to Marc.
So just by pressing the c
So just by pressing the crown,
you
you can
So just by pressing the crown,
you can use
you can use Siri
So just by pressing the crown,
you can use Siri to
you can use Siri to send
So just by pressing the crown,
you can use Siri to send a
message
message right
you can use Siri to send a
message right from
message right from your
you can use Siri to send a
message right from your wrist.
Now,
Now, let's
Now, let's look
Now, let's look at
Now, let's look at a
Now, let's look at a few
third-party
third-party apps.
Now, let's look at a few
third-party apps. Let's
third-party apps. Let's look
at
at the
third-party apps. Let's look
at the VW
at the VW app
third-party apps. Let's look
at the VW app you
at the VW app you saw
third-party apps. Let's look
at the VW app you saw on
at the VW app you saw on slides
a
a second
at the VW app you saw on slides
a second ago.
a second ago. I
at the VW app you saw on slides
a second ago. I will
a second ago. I will show
at the VW app you saw on slides
a second ago. I will show you
how
how that
a second ago. I will show you
how that works
how that works.
a second ago. I will show you
how that works. Here
how that works. Here it
a second ago. I will show you
how that works. Here it is
how that works. Here it is.
Now
Now,
how that works. Here it is.
Now, I
Now, I can
how that works. Here it is.
Now, I can lock
Now, I can lock my
how that works. Here it is.
Now, I can lock my car
Now, I can lock my car j
how that works. Here it is.
Now, I can lock my car just
Now, I can lock my car just by
pressing
pressing this
Now, I can lock my car just by
pressing this control
pressing this control right
here
here.
pressing this control right
here. It
here. It responds
pressing this control right
here. It responds right
here. It responds right a
pressing this control right
here. It responds right away.
You
You can
here. It responds right away.
You can see
You can see the
here. It responds right away.
You can see the app
You can see the app also
here. It responds right away.
You can see the app also opened
very
very quickly
You can see the app also opened
very quickly.
very quickly. And
You can see the app also opened
very quickly. And I
very quickly. And I can
control
control the
very quickly. And I can
control the temperature
control the temperature here
that
that we
control the temperature here
that we were
that we were looking
control the temperature here
that we were looking at
that we were looking at before
by
by just
that we were looking at before
by just rotating
by just rotating the
that we were looking at before
by just rotating the crown.
You
You can
by just rotating the crown.
You can see
You can see how
by just rotating the crown.
You can see how responsive
You can see how responsive it
is
is a
You can see how responsive it
is as
is as I
You can see how responsive it
is as I go
is as I go u
You can see how responsive it
is as I go up
is as I go up and
You can see how responsive it
is as I go up and down
is as I go up and down through
temperatures
temperatures here
is as I go up and down through
temperatures here.
temperatures here. Really,
really
really cool.
temperatures here. Really,
really cool. I
really cool. I will
temperatures here. Really,
really cool. I will get
really cool. I will get it
nice
nice and
really cool. I will get it
nice and w
nice and warm
really cool. I will get it
nice and warm for
nice and warm for me
really cool. I will get it
nice and warm for me s
nice and warm for me so
really cool. I will get it
nice and warm for me so when
nice and warm for me so when I
get
get down
nice and warm for me so when I
get down there
get down there,
nice and warm for me so when I
get down there, it
get down there, it will
nice and warm for me so when I
get down there, it will be
get down there, it will be n
nice and warm for me so when I
get down there, it will be nice
and
and toasty.
get down there, it will be nice
and toasty. Okay.
and toasty. Okay. Turn
get down there, it will be nice
and toasty. Okay. Turn i
and toasty. Okay. Turn it
get down there, it will be nice
and toasty. Okay. Turn it on
and toasty. Okay. Turn it on.
All
All right.
and toasty. Okay. Turn it on.
All right. I
All right. I've
and toasty. Okay. Turn it on.
All right. I've g
All right. I've got
confirmation
confirmation t
All right. I've got
confirmation that
confirmation that it
All right. I've got
confirmation that it actually
enabled
enabled that
confirmation that it actually
enabled that o
enabled that on
confirmation that it actually
enabled that on my
enabled that on my car
confirmation that it actually
enabled that on my car now.
Ac
Access
enabled that on my car now.
Access to
Access to the
enabled that on my car now.
Access to the mic
Access to the mic is
enabled that on my car now.
Access to the mic is going
Access to the mic is going to
be
be really
Access to the mic is going to
be really helpful
be really helpful in
Access to the mic is going to
be really helpful in apps,
be really helpful in apps, and
some
some of
be really helpful in apps, and
some of the
some of the apps
be really helpful in apps, and
some of the apps that
some of the apps that will
really
really benefit
some of the apps that will
really benefit are
communication
communication acts
really benefit are
communication acts like
communication acts like W
really benefit are
communication acts like We
communication acts like We C
Chat.
Chat. A
communication acts like We C
Chat. A lot
Chat. A lot of
communication acts like We C
Chat. A lot of messages
Chat. A lot of messages sent
via
via We
Chat. A lot of messages sent
via WeChat
via WeChat are
Chat. A lot of messages sent
via WeChat are audio
via WeChat are audio messages
Chat. A lot of messages sent
via WeChat are audio messages,
so
so let's
via WeChat are audio messages,
so let's see
so let's see how
via WeChat are audio messages,
so let's see how that
so let's see how that w
via WeChat are audio messages,
so let's see how that will
so let's see how that will work
via WeChat are audio messages,
with
so let's see how that will work
with watchOS
with watchOS 2
so let's see how that will work
with watchOS 2.
with watchOS 2. I
so let's see how that will work
with watchOS 2. I have
with watchOS 2. I have a
message
message f
with watchOS 2. I have a
message from
message from Becky
with watchOS 2. I have a
message from Becky.
message from Becky. I
with watchOS 2. I have a
message from Becky. I can
reply
reply by
message from Becky. I can
reply by pressing
reply by pressing t
message from Becky. I can
reply by pressing the
reply by pressing the Reply
button
button,
reply by pressing the Reply
button, and
button, and I
reply by pressing the Reply
button, and I have
button, and I have a
reply by pressing the Reply
button, and I have a microphone
now
now so
button, and I have a microphone
now so I
now so I can
button, and I have a microphone
now so I can do
now so I can do a
button, and I have a microphone
now so I can do an
now so I can do an audio
response.
response. L
now so I can do an audio
response. Let's
response. Let's do
now so I can do an audio
response. Let's do that
response. Let's do that.
now so I can do an audio
response. Let's do that. That
sounds
sounds great
response. Let's do that. That
sounds great.
sounds great. Y
response. Let's do that. That
sounds great. You
sounds great. You can
response. Let's do that. That
sounds great. You can see
sounds great. You can see as
response. Let's do that. That
sounds great. You can see as I
was
was record
sounds great. You can see as I
was recording
was recording it,
sounds great. You can see as I
was recording it, it
was recording it, it g
sounds great. You can see as I
was recording it, it got
was recording it, it got the
audio
audio levels
was recording it, it got the
audio levels of
audio levels of my
was recording it, it got the
audio levels of my voice
audio levels of my voice and
sent
sent that
audio levels of my voice and
sent that to
sent that to Becky
audio levels of my voice and
sent that to Becky.
I
I can
sent that to Becky.
I can also
I can also reply
sent that to Becky.
I can also reply with
I can also reply with stickers
here.
here. There
I can also reply with stickers
here. There's
here. There's different
categories
categories of
here. There's different
categories of them.
categories of them. With
here. There's different
categories of them. With t
categories of them. With the
Digital
Digital Crown
categories of them. With the
Digital Crown now
Digital Crown now being
categories of them. With the
Digital Crown now being able
Digital Crown now being able to
connect
connect to
Digital Crown now being able to
connect to t
connect to the
Digital Crown now being able to
connect to the UI,
connect to the UI, I
Digital Crown now being able to
connect to the UI, I can
connect to the UI, I can flip
through
through recent
connect to the UI, I can flip
through recent stickers
through recent stickers,
connect to the UI, I can flip
through recent stickers, pick
one
one qui
through recent stickers, pick
one quickly
one quickly that
through recent stickers, pick
one quickly that I
one quickly that I like,
through recent stickers, pick
one quickly that I like, a
one quickly that I like, and
just
just send
one quickly that I like, and
just send t
just send that
one quickly that I like, and
just send that one
just send that one as
one quickly that I like, and
just send that one as well.
just send that one as well. So
very
very f
just send that one as well. So
very fast
very fast to
just send that one as well. So
very fast to interact
very fast to interact n
just send that one as well. So
very fast to interact now
very fast to interact now with
all
all t
very fast to interact now with
all these
all these new
very fast to interact now with
all these new controls
all these new controls y
very fast to interact now with
all these new controls you
all these new controls you have
available
available in
all these new controls you have
available in watch
available in watchOS
all these new controls you have
available in watchOS 2
available in watchOS 2.
Now,
Now, let's
available in watchOS 2.
Now, let's look
Now, let's look a
available in watchOS 2.
Now, let's look at
Now, let's look at the
available in watchOS 2.
Now, let's look at the Vine
glance
glance.
Now, let's look at the Vine
glance. Vine
glance. Vine is
Now, let's look at the Vine
glance. Vine is a
glance. Vine is a great
example
example of
glance. Vine is a great
example of playing
example of playing back
glance. Vine is a great
example of playing back video
on
on the
example of playing back video
on the Watch
on the Watch,
example of playing back video
on the Watch, and
on the Watch, and its
example of playing back video
on the Watch, and its format
on the Watch, and its format is
really
really perfect
on the Watch, and its format is
really perfect f
really perfect for
on the Watch, and its format is
really perfect for t
really perfect for the
on the Watch, and its format is
really perfect for the Watch
face
face.
really perfect for the Watch
face. Here
face. Here is
really perfect for the Watch
face. Here is a
face. Here is a recent
really perfect for the Watch
face. Here is a recent one
face. Here is a recent one on
Vine
Vine.
So
So that's
So that's video
So that's video p
So that's video playing
So that's video playing back
right
right on
So that's video playing back
right on the
right on the watch
So that's video playing back
right on the watch face
right on the watch face.
So that's video playing back
right on the watch face. So
those
those are
right on the watch face. So
those are just
those are just some
right on the watch face. So
those are just some examples
those are just some examples of
what
what you
those are just some examples of
what you can
what you can do
those are just some examples of
what you can do now
what you can do now with
watchOS
watchOS 2,
what you can do now with
watchOS 2, and
watchOS 2, and I
what you can do now with
watchOS 2, and I am
watchOS 2, and I am s
what you can do now with
watchOS 2, and I am super
excited
excited to
watchOS 2, and I am super
excited to see
excited to see wha
watchOS 2, and I am super
excited to see what
excited to see what all
watchOS 2, and I am super
excited to see what all you
guys
guys do
excited to see what all you
guys do with
guys do with all
excited to see what all you
guys do with all this
guys do with all this stuff.
(Applause)
So
So some
(Applause)
So some great
So some great new
(Applause)
So some great new enhancements
coming
coming,
So some great new enhancements
coming, as
coming, as well
So some great new enhancements
coming, as well as
coming, as well as some
So some great new enhancements
coming, as well as some super
powerful
powerful app
coming, as well as some super
powerful app development
powerful app development tools
for
for you.
powerful app development tools
for you. And
for you. And we've
powerful app development tools
for you. And we've been
working
working really
for you. And we've been
working really hard
working really hard on
for you. And we've been
working really hard on this,
and
and I
working really hard on this,
and I am
and I am really
working really hard on this,
and I am really happy
and I am really happy to
working really hard on this,
and I am really happy to say
that
that t
and I am really happy to say
that this
that this stuff
and I am really happy to say
that this stuff is
that this stuff is a
and I am really happy to say
that this stuff is all
available
available to
that this stuff is all
available to you
available to you today
that this stuff is all
available to you today to
available to you today to start
building
building these
available to you today to start
building these native
building these native apps
available to you today to start
building these native apps.
(Applause)
Ju
Just
(Applause)
Just s
Just six
(Applause)
Just six weeks
Just six weeks from
(Applause)
Just six weeks from our
launch,
launch, i
Just six weeks from our
launch, it's
launch, it's u
Just six weeks from our
launch, it's unbelievable.
Then
Then it
launch, it's unbelievable.
Then it w
Then it will
launch, it's unbelievable.
Then it will be
Then it will be available
launch, it's unbelievable.
Then it will be available in
the
the fall
Then it will be available in
the fall to
the fall to everyone,
Then it will be available in
the fall to everyone, a
the fall to everyone, and
Then it will be available in
the fall to everyone, and we
will
will w
the fall to everyone, and we
will work
will work across
the fall to everyone, and we
will work across all
will work across all the
watches
watches,
will work across all the
watches, of
watches, of course
will work across all the
watches, of course,
watches, of course, and
will work across all the
watches, of course, and it
watches, of course, and it will
be
be f
watches, of course, and it will
be free.
be free. So
watches, of course, and it will
be free. So this
be free. So this has
watches, of course, and it will
be free. So this has been
be free. So this has been a
great
great adventure
be free. So this has been a
great adventure.
great adventure. We
be free. So this has been a
great adventure. We are
great adventure. We are just
getting
getting start
great adventure. We are just
getting started
getting started here,
great adventure. We are just
getting started here, a
getting started here, and
great adventure. We are just
getting started here, and I
getting started here, and I am
really
really looking
getting started here, and I am
really looking forward
really looking forward to
getting started here, and I am
really looking forward to the
journey
journey ahead
really looking forward to the
journey ahead with
journey ahead with all
really looking forward to the
journey ahead with all of
journey ahead with all of you
on
on A
journey ahead with all of you
on Apple
on Apple Watch
journey ahead with all of you
on Apple Watch.
on Apple Watch. Thank
journey ahead with all of you
on Apple Watch. Thank you
on Apple Watch. Thank you very
much.
much. Back
on Apple Watch. Thank you very
much. Back to
much. Back to Tim.
(Applause)
Thank
Thank you,
(Applause)
Thank you, Tim.
>>
>> TIM
Thank you, Tim.
>> TIM COOK:
>> TIM COOK: Thanks
Thank you, Tim.
>> TIM COOK: Thanks,
>> TIM COOK: Thanks, Kevin
Thank you, Tim.
>> TIM COOK: Thanks, Kevin.
We're
We're really
>> TIM COOK: Thanks, Kevin.
We're really excited
We're really excited to
>> TIM COOK: Thanks, Kevin.
We're really excited to have
Apple
Apple W
We're really excited to have
Apple Watch
Apple Watch out
We're really excited to have
Apple Watch out in
Apple Watch out in t
We're really excited to have
Apple Watch out in the
Apple Watch out in the world,
and
and w
Apple Watch out in the world,
and we
and we can't
Apple Watch out in the world,
and we can't wait
and we can't wait to
Apple Watch out in the world,
and we can't wait to see
and we can't wait to see what
you
you do
and we can't wait to see what
you do with
you do with watchOS
and we can't wait to see what
you do with watchOS.
you do with watchOS. A
and we can't wait to see what
you do with watchOS. And
you do with watchOS. And we
couldn't
couldn't be
you do with watchOS. And we
couldn't be more
couldn't be more e
you do with watchOS. And we
couldn't be more excited
couldn't be more excited about
how
how d
couldn't be more excited about
how developers
how developers and
couldn't be more excited about
how developers and use
how developers and users
couldn't be more excited about
how developers and users will
use
use this
how developers and users will
use this p
use this powerful
how developers and users will
use this powerful ecosystems
use this powerful ecosystems of
both
both products
use this powerful ecosystems of
both products and
both products and platforms
use this powerful ecosystems of
both products and platforms,
three
three amazing
both products and platforms,
three amazing platforms
three amazing platforms.
both products and platforms,
three amazing platforms. T
three amazing platforms. The
opportunities
opportunities really
three amazing platforms. The
opportunities really are
opportunities really are li
limitless
limitless.
Now,
Now, before
limitless.
Now, before we
Now, before we close
limitless.
Now, before we close this
morning
morning,
Now, before we close this
morning, we
morning, we do
Now, before we close this
morning, we do have
morning, we do have ...
Now, before we close this
morning, we do have ... one
more
more thing.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
more thing.
(Cheers and applause)
(Cheers and applause) I'd
more thing.
(Cheers and applause) I'd like
to
to tell
(Cheers and applause) I'd like
to tell you
to tell you about
(Cheers and applause) I'd like
to tell you about something
that
that we've
to tell you about something
that we've been
that we've been working
to tell you about something
that we've been working really
hard
hard on
that we've been working really
hard on and
hard on and something
that we've been working really
hard on and something we
hard on and something we are
super
super excited
hard on and something we are
super excited a
super excited about
hard on and something we are
super excited about.
super excited about. I
hard on and something we are
super excited about. I know,
we
we love
super excited about. I know,
we love m
we love music
super excited about. I know,
we love music,
we love music, and
super excited about. I know,
we love music, and music
we love music, and music is
such
such an
we love music, and music is
such an important
such an important p
we love music, and music is
such an important part
such an important part of
we love music, and music is
such an important part of our
lives
lives and
such an important part of our
lives and our
lives and our culture.
such an important part of our
lives and our culture. We've
had
had a
lives and our culture. We've
had a long
had a long relationship
lives and our culture. We've
had a long relationship with
music
music at
had a long relationship with
music at Apple,
music at Apple, a
had a long relationship with
music at Apple, and
music at Apple, and music
had a long relationship with
music at Apple, and music has
had
had a
music at Apple, and music has
had a very
had a very rich
music at Apple, and music has
had a very rich h
had a very rich history
music at Apple, and music has
had a very rich history of
change,
change, some
had a very rich history of
change, some o
change, some of
had a very rich history of
change, some of which
change, some of which we've
played
played a
change, some of which we've
played a part
played a part in.
change, some of which we've
played a part in. W
played a part in. We've
change, some of which we've
played a part in. We've made
played a part in. We've made a
great
great video
played a part in. We've made a
great video about
great video about the
played a part in. We've made a
great video about the h
great video about the history
of
of m
great video about the history
of music,
of music, and
great video about the history
of music, and I
of music, and I would
great video about the history
of music, and I would like
of music, and I would like to
play
play it
of music, and I would like to
play it for
play it for you
of music, and I would like to
play it for you this
play it for you this morning
of music, and I would like to
play it for you this morning.
(Music)
(Cheers
(Cheers and
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> TIM
>> TIM COOK:
>> TIM COOK: Today
>> TIM COOK: Today we're
announcing
announcing Apple
>> TIM COOK: Today we're
announcing Apple Music,
announcing Apple Music, the
next
next chapter
announcing Apple Music, the
next chapter in
next chapter in music,
announcing Apple Music, the
next chapter in music, and
next chapter in music, and I
know
know you
next chapter in music, and I
know you are
know you are going
next chapter in music, and I
know you are going to
know you are going to love
next chapter in music, and I
know you are going to love it.
It
It will
know you are going to love it.
It will change
It will change the
know you are going to love it.
It will change the way
It will change the way that
know you are going to love it.
It will change the way that you
experience
experience music
It will change the way that you
experience music forever
experience music forever.
To
To tell
experience music forever.
To tell you
To tell you more
experience music forever.
To tell you more a
To tell you more about
experience music forever.
To tell you more about it
To tell you more about it,
experience music forever.
To tell you more about it, I'd
like
like t
To tell you more about it, I'd
like to
like to bring
To tell you more about it, I'd
like to bring up
like to bring up someone
To tell you more about it, I'd
like to bring up someone who
know
knows
like to bring up someone who
knows mor
knows more
like to bring up someone who
knows more about
knows more about music
like to bring up someone who
knows more about music and
knows more about music and the
music
music experience
knows more about music and the
music experience than
music experience than anyone
knows more about music and the
music experience than anyone I
know
know.
music experience than anyone I
know. He's
know. He's worked
music experience than anyone I
know. He's worked with
know. He's worked with amazing
art
artis
know. He's worked with amazing
artists
artists f
know. He's worked with amazing
artists from
artists from B
know. He's worked with amazing
artists from Bruce
artists from Bruce Springsteen
to
to John
artists from Bruce Springsteen
to John Lennon
to John Lennon and
artists from Bruce Springsteen
to John Lennon and countless
others
others.
to John Lennon and countless
others. We
others. We are
to John Lennon and countless
others. We are thrilled
others. We are thrilled to
have
have him
others. We are thrilled to
have him a
have him a part
others. We are thrilled to
have him a part of
have him a part of the
others. We are thrilled to
have him a part of the Apple
team.
team. Please
have him a part of the Apple
team. Please j
team. Please join
have him a part of the Apple
team. Please join me
team. Please join me in
welcoming
welcoming Jimmy
team. Please join me in
welcoming Jimmy Iovine
welcoming Jimmy Iovine.
team. Please join me in
welcoming Jimmy Iovine. Jimmy.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> JIMMY
>> JIMMY IOVINE:
>> JIMMY IOVINE: Thanks,
>> JIMMY IOVINE: Thanks, Tim
>> JIMMY IOVINE: Thanks, Tim.
Well,
Well, it's
>> JIMMY IOVINE: Thanks, Tim.
Well, it's really
Well, it's really an
>> JIMMY IOVINE: Thanks, Tim.
Well, it's really an honor
Well, it's really an honor to
be
be here.
Well, it's really an honor to
be here. I'm
be here. I'm here
Well, it's really an honor to
be here. I'm here because
be here. I'm here because in
2003,
2003, the
be here. I'm here because in
2003, the record
2003, the record i
be here. I'm here because in
2003, the record industry
2003, the record industry was
be here. I'm here because in
2003, the record industry was a
ball
ball of
2003, the record industry was a
ball of confusion
ball of confusion.
2003, the record industry was a
ball of confusion. We
ball of confusion. We had
Napster
Napster,
ball of confusion. We had
Napster, we
Napster, we had
ball of confusion. We had
Napster, we had L
Napster, we had Lime
ball of confusion. We had
Napster, we had Lime Wire,
Napster, we had Lime Wire, we
had
had Bit
Napster, we had Lime Wire, we
had Bit Torrent
had Bit Torrent.
Napster, we had Lime Wire, we
had Bit Torrent. This
had Bit Torrent. This giant
invader
invader from
had Bit Torrent. This giant
invader from the
invader from the north,
technology
technology.
invader from the north,
technology. I'm
technology. I'm looking
invader from the north,
technology. I'm looking at
technology. I'm looking at my
guy
guys
technology. I'm looking at my
guys saying
guys saying,
technology. I'm looking at my
guys saying, well,
guys saying, well, what
technology. I'm looking at my
guys saying, well, what do
guys saying, well, what do we
do
do with
guys saying, well, what do we
do with this?
do with this? So
guys saying, well, what do we
do with this? So I
do with this? So I go
guys saying, well, what do we
do with this? So I go up
do with this? So I go up to
Apple
Apple,
do with this? So I go up to
Apple, and
Apple, and I
do with this? So I go up to
Apple, and I s
Apple, and I see
do with this? So I go up to
Apple, and I see Steve
Apple, and I see Steve Jobs
do with this? So I go up to
Apple, and I see Steve Jobs and
Eddy
Eddy Cue,
Apple, and I see Steve Jobs and
Eddy Cue, a
Eddy Cue, and
Apple, and I see Steve Jobs and
Eddy Cue, and they
Eddy Cue, and they showed
Apple, and I see Steve Jobs and
Eddy Cue, and they showed m
Eddy Cue, and they showed me
something
something brilliant
Eddy Cue, and they showed me
something brilliant a
something brilliant and
groundbreaking
groundbreaking,
something brilliant and
groundbreaking, a
groundbreaking, a simple,
elegant
elegant way
groundbreaking, a simple,
elegant way to
elegant way to buy
groundbreaking, a simple,
elegant way to buy music
online,
online, iTunes.
I'
I'm
online, iTunes.
I'm like
I'm like,
online, iTunes.
I'm like, wow
I'm like, wow,
online, iTunes.
I'm like, wow, t
I'm like, wow, the
online, iTunes.
I'm like, wow, the ads
I'm like, wow, the ads are
real.
real. These
I'm like, wow, the ads are
real. These guys
real. These guys really
I'm like, wow, the ads are
real. These guys really d
real. These guys really do
think
think different
real. These guys really do
think different.
(Laughter)
So
So t
(Laughter)
So they
So they could
(Laughter)
So they could help
So they could help move
culture
culture the
So they could help move
culture the s
culture the same
So they could help move
culture the same way
culture the same way that
So they could help move
culture the same way that art
moves
moves culture.
culture the same way that art
moves culture. Technology
moves culture. Technology a
culture the same way that art
moves culture. Technology and
art
art can
moves culture. Technology and
art can work
art can work together,
moves culture. Technology and
art can work together, a
art can work together, at
moves culture. Technology and
art can work together, at least
at
at Apple
art can work together, at least
at Apple.
So
So now
at Apple.
So now 2015
So now 2015,
at Apple.
So now 2015, music
So now 2015, music industry
at Apple.
So now 2015, music industry is
a
a fragment
So now 2015, music industry is
a fragmented
a fragmented mess.
So now 2015, music industry is
a fragmented mess. If
a fragmented mess. If you
So now 2015, music industry is
a fragmented mess. If you want
to
to stream
a fragmented mess. If you want
to stream music
to stream music,
a fragmented mess. If you want
to stream music, you
to stream music, you can
a fragmented mess. If you want
to stream music, you can go
over
over here.
to stream music, you can go
over here. If
over here. If you
to stream music, you can go
over here. If you want
over here. If you want to
stream
stream some
over here. If you want to
stream some video,
stream some video, you
over here. If you want to
stream some video, you can
check
check some
stream some video, you can
check some of
check some of these
stream some video, you can
check some of these places
check some of these places out.
If
If you
check some of these places out.
If you want
If you want to
check some of these places out.
If you want to follow
If you want to follow some
check some of these places out.
If you want to follow some a
artist,
artist, there's
If you want to follow some a
artist, there's more
artist, there's more confusion
for
for t
artist, there's more confusion
for that.
for that. So
artist, there's more confusion
for that. So I
for that. So I reached
artist, there's more confusion
for that. So I reached out
for that. So I reached out to
artist, there's more confusion
Tim
for that. So I reached out to
Tim Cook
Tim Cook and
for that. So I reached out to
Tim Cook and Eddy
Tim Cook and Eddy Cue,
for that. So I reached out to
Tim Cook and Eddy Cue, and
Tim Cook and Eddy Cue, and I
said
said guys,
Tim Cook and Eddy Cue, and I
said guys, can
said guys, can we
Tim Cook and Eddy Cue, and I
said guys, can we build
said guys, can we build a
bigger
bigger and
said guys, can we build a
bigger and better
bigger and better ecosystem
with
with the
bigger and better ecosystem
with the elegance
with the elegance and
simplicity
simplicity that
with the elegance and
simplicity that only
simplicity that only Apple
with the elegance and
simplicity that only Apple can
do
do?
simplicity that only Apple can
do? One
do? One complete
simplicity that only Apple can
do? One complete thought
around
around music
do? One complete thought
around music.
And
And from
around music.
And from that,
And from that, I'm
around music.
And from that, I'm standing
here
here today
And from that, I'm standing
here today so
here today so proud
And from that, I'm standing
here today so proud of
here today so proud of everyone
that's
that's worked
here today so proud of everyone
that's worked so
that's worked so hard,
here today so proud of everyone
that's worked so hard, and
that's worked so hard, and I
here today so proud of everyone
that's worked so hard, and I am
going
going to
that's worked so hard, and I am
going to introduce
going to introduce you
that's worked so hard, and I am
going to introduce you to
going to introduce you to Apple
Music
Music.
(Applause)
>>
>> Music
>> Music has
>> Music has such
>> Music has such power
>> Music has such power in
>> Music has such power in our
lives.
lives. The
>> Music has such power in our
lives. The way
lives. The way we
>> Music has such power in our
lives. The way we listen
lives. The way we listen to
and
and experience
lives. The way we listen to
and experience music
and experience music is
undergoing
undergoing a
and experience music is
undergoing a profound
undergoing a profound change
these
these day
undergoing a profound change
these days.
these days. To
undergoing a profound change
these days. To have
these days. To have access
undergoing a profound change
these days. To have access to
nearly
nearly all
these days. To have access to
nearly all the
nearly all the music
these days. To have access to
nearly all the music in
nearly all the music in the
world
world at
nearly all the music in the
world at our
world at our fingertips
nearly all the music in the
world at our fingertips and
world at our fingertips and in
our
our pockets
world at our fingertips and in
our pockets is
our pockets is remarkable
world at our fingertips and in
our pockets is remarkable.
our pockets is remarkable. A
world at our fingertips and in
our pockets is remarkable. And
yet
yet there
our pockets is remarkable. And
yet there n
yet there needs
our pockets is remarkable. And
yet there needs to
yet there needs to be
our pockets is remarkable. And
yet there needs to be a
yet there needs to be a place
where
where music
yet there needs to be a place
where music can
where music can be
yet there needs to be a place
where music can be treated
where music can be treated less
like
like digital
where music can be treated less
like digital bits
like digital bits and
where music can be treated less
like digital bits and more
like digital bits and more l
where music can be treated less
like digital bits and more like
the
the art
like digital bits and more like
the art i
the art it
like digital bits and more like
the art it is,
the art it is, w
like digital bits and more like
the art it is, with
the art it is, with a
like digital bits and more like
the art it is, with a sense
the art it is, with a sense of
respect
respect a
the art it is, with a sense of
respect and
respect and discovery.
the art it is, with a sense of
respect and discovery. And
respect and discovery. And if
that
that place
respect and discovery. And if
that place could
that place could actual
respect and discovery. And if
that place could actually
accommodate
accommodate and
that place could actually
accommodate and support
accommodate and support the
artists
artists who
accommodate and support the
artists who make
artists who make the
accommodate and support the
artists who make the m
artists who make the music,
accommodate and support the
artists who make the music, not
just
just the
artists who make the music, not
just the top
just the top-tier
artists who make the music, not
just the top-tier artists
just the top-tier artists,
artists who make the music, not
just the top-tier artists, but
the
the kids
just the top-tier artists, but
the kids in
the kids in their
just the top-tier artists, but
the kids in their bedrooms
the kids in their bedrooms too,
provide
provide them
the kids in their bedrooms too,
provide them all
provide them all with
the kids in their bedrooms too,
provide them all with a
provide them all with a home
and
and a
provide them all with a home
and a way
and a way to
provide them all with a home
and a way to engage
and a way to engage with
provide them all with a home
and a way to engage with their
audiences,
audiences, that
and a way to engage with their
audiences, that would
audiences, that would be
and a way to engage with their
audiences, that would be pretty
great.
great. And
audiences, that would be pretty
great. And that's
great. And that's what
audiences, that would be pretty
great. And that's what we
great. And that's what we set
out
out to
great. And that's what we set
out to do
out to do with
great. And that's what we set
out to do with Apple
out to do with Apple M
great. And that's what we set
out to do with Apple Music
out to do with Apple Music.
(Music)
>>
>> On
>> On Apple
>> On Apple Music,
>> On Apple Music, all
>> On Apple Music, all the
ways
ways you
>> On Apple Music, all the
ways you love
ways you love music
>> On Apple Music, all the
ways you love music can
ways you love music can now
live
live together
ways you love music can now
live together.
live together. Stream
ways you love music can now
live together. Stream from
live together. Stream from the
millions
millions of
live together. Stream from the
millions of songs
millions of songs on
live together. Stream from the
millions of songs on i
millions of songs on iTunes
live together. Stream from the
millions of songs on iTunes any
time
time and
millions of songs on iTunes any
time and on
time and on d
millions of songs on iTunes any
time and on demand,
time and on demand, along
millions of songs on iTunes any
time and on demand, along with
hand-pick
hand-picked
time and on demand, along with
hand-picked playlists,
recommendations
recommendations,
hand-picked playlists,
recommendations, a
recommendations, and
hand-picked playlists,
recommendations, and all
recommendations, and all that's
great
great and
recommendations, and all that's
great and breaking
great and breaking in
recommendations, and all that's
great and breaking in music
right
right now
great and breaking in music
right now.
An
And
right now.
And broadcasting
And broadcasting every
right now.
And broadcasting every day
And broadcasting every day is
Apple's
Apple's first
And broadcasting every day is
Apple's first 24
Apple's first 24/7
And broadcasting every day is
Apple's first 24/7 worldwide
radio
radio s
Apple's first 24/7 worldwide
radio station,
radio station, live
Apple's first 24/7 worldwide
radio station, live i
radio station, live in
Apple's first 24/7 worldwide
radio station, live in over
radio station, live in over 100
countries,
countries, Beats
radio station, live in over 100
countries, Beats 1
countries, Beats 1 i
radio station, live in over 100
countries, Beats 1 is
countries, Beats 1 is anchors
by
by Zane
countries, Beats 1 is anchors
by Zane Lowe.
by Zane Lowe. Ero
countries, Beats 1 is anchors
by Zane Lowe. Ero Dodd
by Zane Lowe. Ero Dodden
countries, Beats 1 is anchors
by Zane Lowe. Ero Dodden in
New
New York
by Zane Lowe. Ero Dodden in
New York.
>>
>> New
New York.
>> New York
>> New York City
New York.
>> New York City worldwide,
this
this is
>> New York City worldwide,
this is Beats
this is Beats 1
>> New York City worldwide,
this is Beats 1.
>>
>> And
this is Beats 1.
>> And me,
>> And me, J
this is Beats 1.
>> And me, Julie
>> And me, Julie out
this is Beats 1.
>> And me, Julie out of
>> And me, Julie out of Lo
London.
>>
>> We
London.
>> We cannot
>> We cannot wait
London.
>> We cannot wait to
>> We cannot wait to play
London.
>> We cannot wait to play you
guys
guys music
>> We cannot wait to play you
guys music we've
guys music we've g
>> We cannot wait to play you
guys music we've got
guys music we've got lined
>> We cannot wait to play you
guys music we've got lined u
guys music we've got lined up.
>>
>> And
>> And at
>> And at the
>> And at the heart
>> And at the heart of
>> And at the heart of Apple
Music
Music,
>> And at the heart of Apple
Music, there's
Music, there's C
>> And at the heart of Apple
Music, there's Connect,
Music, there's Connect, where
artists
artists can
Music, there's Connect, where
artists can share
artists can share with
Music, there's Connect, where
artists can share with fan
artists can share with fans
like
like never
artists can share with fans
like never before
like never before.
artists can share with fans
like never before. Songs,
re
remixes,
like never before. Songs,
remixes, demos
remixes, demos,
like never before. Songs,
remixes, demos, p
remixes, demos, photos
like never before. Songs,
remixes, demos, photos,
remixes, demos, photos, videos
like never before. Songs,
remixes, demos, photos, videos,
lyrics
lyrics,
remixes, demos, photos, videos,
lyrics, sound
lyrics, sound bites
remixes, demos, photos, videos,
lyrics, sound bites.
lyrics, sound bites. Really,
any
any way
lyrics, sound bites. Really,
any way an
any way an art
lyrics, sound bites. Really,
any way an artis
any way an artist
lyrics, sound bites. Really,
any way an artist chooses
any way an artist chooses to
express
express t
any way an artist chooses to
express themselves.
>>
>> TRENT
express themselves.
>> TRENT REZNOR:
>> TRENT REZNOR: For
express themselves.
>> TRENT REZNOR: For fans
>> TRENT REZNOR: For fans,
express themselves.
>> TRENT REZNOR: For fans, we
tried
tried to
>> TRENT REZNOR: For fans, we
tried to create
tried to create a
>> TRENT REZNOR: For fans, we
tried to create a complete
experience,
experience, by
tried to create a complete
experience, by combining
experience, by combining the
catalog
catalog of
experience, by combining the
catalog of the
catalog of the world
experience, by combining the
catalog of the world's
catalog of the world's music
with
with the
catalog of the world's music
with the music
with the music t
catalog of the world's music
with the music that's
with the music that's not
catalog of the world's music
with the music that's not in
that
that catalog
with the music that's not in
that catalog yet
that catalog yet,
with the music that's not in
that catalog yet, direct
that catalog yet, direct from
the
the artist
that catalog yet, direct from
the artist to
the artist to you
that catalog yet, direct from
the artist to you in
the artist to you in a
that catalog yet, direct from
the artist to you in a shared
experience
experience with
the artist to you in a shared
experience with Beats
experience with Beats 1.
the artist to you in a shared
experience with Beats 1. For
the
the art
experience with Beats 1. For
the artists
the artists,
experience with Beats 1. For
the artists, we've
the artists, we've built
experience with Beats 1. For
the artists, we've built an
ecosystem
ecosystem we
the artists, we've built an
ecosystem we hope
ecosystem we hope can
the artists, we've built an
ecosystem we hope can start
ecosystem we hope can start to
provide
provide t
ecosystem we hope can start to
provide the
provide the tools
ecosystem we hope can start to
provide the tools to
provide the tools to grow,
ecosystem we hope can start to
nurture,
provide the tools to grow,
nurture, a
nurture, and
provide the tools to grow,
nurture, and sustain
nurture, and sustain careers.
One
One place,
nurture, and sustain careers.
One place, one
One place, one complete
nurture, and sustain careers.
One place, one complete thought
around
around music.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
around music.
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> JIMMY
(Cheers and applause)
>> JIMMY IOVINE:
>> JIMMY IOVINE: Thank
(Cheers and applause)
>> JIMMY IOVINE: Thank you
>> JIMMY IOVINE: Thank you.
That's
That's Apple
>> JIMMY IOVINE: Thank you.
That's Apple music
That's Apple music and
>> JIMMY IOVINE: Thank you.
That's Apple music and t
That's Apple music and the
great
great Trent
That's Apple music and the
great Trent Reznor.
great Trent Reznor. It's
That's Apple music and the
great Trent Reznor. It's all
the
the w
great Trent Reznor. It's all
the ways
the ways you
great Trent Reznor. It's all
the ways you love
the ways you love m
great Trent Reznor. It's all
the ways you love music
the ways you love music all
great Trent Reznor. It's all
the ways you love music all in
one
one p
the ways you love music all in
one place.
one place. And
the ways you love music all in
one place. And that
one place. And that place
the ways you love music all in
one place. And that place is
almost
almost in
one place. And that place is
almost in a
almost in a billion
one place. And that place is
almost in a billion hands
around
around the
almost in a billion hands
around the w
around the world
almost in a billion hands
around the world already.
around the world already. One
app,
app, one
around the world already. One
app, one sing
app, one single
around the world already. One
app, one single app
app, one single app on
around the world already. One
app, one single app on your
iPhone
iPhone.
Apple
Apple Music
iPhone.
Apple Music is
Apple Music is three
iPhone.
Apple Music is three things.
It's
It's a
Apple Music is three things.
It's a revolutionary
It's a revolutionary music
service
service.
Oh.
A
A revolutionary
Oh.
A revolutionary music
A revolutionary music s
Oh.
A revolutionary music service
curated
curated by
A revolutionary music service
curated by the
curated by the leading
A revolutionary music service
curated by the leading m
curated by the leading music
experts
experts who
curated by the leading music
experts who we
experts who we helped
curated by the leading music
experts who we helped hand
experts who we helped h
hand-pick.
hand-pick. These
experts who we helped h
hand-pick. These people
hand-pick. These people are
going
going to
hand-pick. These people are
going to help
going to help y
hand-pick. These people are
going to help you
going to help you with
hand-pick. These people are
going to help you with the
going to help you with the most
difficult
difficult question
going to help you with the most
difficult question in
difficult question in music
going to help you with the most
difficult question in music.
When
When you
difficult question in music.
When you are
When you are listening
difficult question in music.
When you are listening to
When you are listening to a
playlist
playlist,
When you are listening to a
playlist, what
playlist, what song
When you are listening to a
playlist, what song comes
playlist, what song comes n
When you are listening to a
playlist, what song comes next?
The
The only
playlist, what song comes next?
The only song
The only song that's
playlist, what song comes next?
The only song that's a
The only song that's as
playlist, what song comes next?
important
The only song that's as
important as
important as the
The only song that's as
important as the one
important as the one you
The only song that's as
important as the one you are
listening
listening to
important as the one you are
listening to at
listening to at that
important as the one you are
listening to at that moment
listening to at that moment is
the
the o
listening to at that moment is
the one
the one that
listening to at that moment is
the one that follows
the one that follows it
listening to at that moment is
the one that follows it.
Now,
Now, picture
the one that follows it.
Now, picture this
Now, picture this.
the one that follows it.
Now, picture this. You
Now, picture this. You are
the one that follows it.
Now, picture this. You are in
a
a s
Now, picture this. You are in
a special
a special moment.
Now, picture this. You are in
a special moment. Y
a special moment. You're
exercising
exercising or
a special moment. You're
exercising or some
exercising or some o
a special moment. You're
exercising or some other
special
special moment.
(Laughter)
Right
Right,
(Laughter)
Right, Dre?
Right, Dre? He
(Laughter)
Right, Dre? He exercises
Right, Dre? He exercises a
lot
lot.
And
And your
lot.
And your heart's
And your heart's p
lot.
And your heart's pumping
And your heart's pumping.
lot.
And your heart's pumping. And
you
you are
And your heart's pumping. And
you are about
you are about to
And your heart's pumping. And
you are about to turn
you are about to turn up
And your heart's pumping. And
you are about to turn up the
reps
reps.
you are about to turn up the
reps. And
reps. And the
you are about to turn up the
reps. And the next
reps. And the next song
you are about to turn up the
reps. And the next song comes
on
on,
reps. And the next song comes
on, e
on, ehhh!
reps. And the next song comes
on, ehhh! Buzz
on, ehhh! Buzz kill
reps. And the next song comes
on, ehhh! Buzz kill.
on, ehhh! Buzz kill. You
reps. And the next song comes
on, ehhh! Buzz kill. You may
ask
ask why
on, ehhh! Buzz kill. You may
ask why that
ask why that happened.
on, ehhh! Buzz kill. You may
ask why that happened. It
happened
happened because
ask why that happened. It
happened because i
happened because it
ask why that happened. It
happened because it was
probably
probably programmed
happened because it was
probably programmed by
probably programmed by an
algorithm
algorithm a
probably programmed by an
algorithm alone
algorithm alone.
probably programmed by an
algorithm alone. Algorithms
alone
alone can't
algorithm alone. Algorithms
alone can't d
alone can't do
algorithm alone. Algorithms
alone can't do that
alone can't do that emotional
task
task.
alone can't do that emotional
task. You
task. You n
alone can't do that emotional
task. You need
task. You need a
alone can't do that emotional
task. You need a human
task. You need a human touch,
and
and that's
task. You need a human touch,
and that's why
and that's why at
task. You need a human touch,
and that's why at Apple
and that's why at Apple Music
task. You need a human touch,
and that's why at Apple Music,
we
we want
and that's why at Apple Music,
we want to
we want to give
and that's why at Apple Music,
we want to give you
we want to give you the
and that's why at Apple Music,
we want to give you the right
song,
song, the
we want to give you the right
song, the right
song, the right p
we want to give you the right
song, the right playlist
song, the right playlist at
we want to give you the right
song, the right playlist at the
right
right moment,
song, the right playlist at the
right moment, a
right moment, all
song, the right playlist at the
right moment, all on
right moment, all on demand
song, the right playlist at the
right moment, all on demand.
Now,
Now, the
right moment, all on demand.
Now, the f
Now, the first
right moment, all on demand.
Now, the first-ever
Now, the first-ever l
right moment, all on demand.
Now, the first-ever live
Now, the first-ever live 24
right moment, all on demand.
Now, the first-ever live
24-hour
24-hour w
Now, the first-ever live
24-hour world
24-hour worldwide
Now, the first-ever live
24-hour worldwide radio
station,
station, so
24-hour worldwide radio
station, so Trent
station, so Trent Reznor
24-hour worldwide radio
station, so Trent Reznor calls
me
me up
station, so Trent Reznor calls
me up and
me up and says
station, so Trent Reznor calls
me up and says I
me up and says I got
station, so Trent Reznor calls
me up and says I got it.
me up and says I got it. This
is
is what
me up and says I got it. This
is what we're
is what we're going
me up and says I got it. This
is what we're going to
is what we're going to do.
Let's
Let's b
is what we're going to do.
Let's build
Let's build the
is what we're going to do.
Let's build the f
Let's build the first-ever
worldwide
worldwide live
Let's build the first-ever
worldwide live radio
worldwide live radio station
broadcast
broadcast f
worldwide live radio station
broadcast from
broadcast from t
worldwide live radio station
broadcast from three
broadcast from three cities
that
that play
broadcast from three cities
that plays
that plays m
broadcast from three cities
that plays music
that plays music not
broadcast from three cities
that plays music not b
that plays music not based
broadcast from three cities
that plays music not based o
that plays music not based on
research,
research, n
that plays music not based on
research, not
research, not based
that plays music not based on
research, not based on
research, not based on genre,
not
not base
research, not based on genre,
not based
not based on
research, not based on genre,
not based on drum
not based on drum beats
research, not based on genre,
not based on drum beats,
not based on drum beats, only
music
music that
not based on drum beats, only
music that is
music that is g
not based on drum beats, only
music that is great
music that is great and
not based on drum beats, only
music that is great and feels
great.
A
A s
great.
A station
A station that
great.
A station that has
A station that has only
great.
A station that has only one
mast
master,
A station that has only one
master, m
master, music
A station that has only one
master, music it
master, music itse
A station that has only one
master, music itself
master, music itself.
So
So I
master, music itself.
So I said
So I said why
master, music itself.
So I said why do
So I said why do artists
always
always have
So I said why do artists
always have t
always have the
So I said why do artists
always have the great
always have the greates
So I said why do artists
always have the greatest
always have the greatest ideas
that
that are
always have the greatest ideas
that are practically
that are practically impossible
to
to e
that are practically impossible
to execute
to execute?
So
So I
to execute?
So I said,
So I said, well
to execute?
So I said, well,
So I said, well, wait
to execute?
So I said, well, wait a
second.
second. That's
So I said, well, wait a
second. That's why
second. That's why we
So I said, well, wait a
second. That's why we are
second. That's why we are at
Apple
Apple.
second. That's why we are at
Apple. We
Apple. We are
second. That's why we are at
Apple. We are a
Apple. We are at
second. That's why we are at
Apple. We are at Apple
Apple. We are at Apple to
second. That's why we are at
Apple. We are at Apple to help
art
artists'
Apple. We are at Apple to help
artists' dreams
artists' dreams be
Apple. We are at Apple to help
artists' dreams be realize
artists' dreams be realized
Apple. We are at Apple to help
artists' dreams be realized.
So
So we
artists' dreams be realized.
So we built
So we built the
artists' dreams be realized.
So we built the sta
So we built the station
artists' dreams be realized.
So we built the station,
So we built the station, and
it's
it's a
So we built the station, and
it's a music
it's a music lover's
So we built the station, and
it's a music lover's d
it's a music lover's dream.
So we built the station, and
it's a music lover's dream. I
it's a music lover's dream. If
you
you love
it's a music lover's dream. If
you love great
you love great music
it's a music lover's dream. If
you love great music without
any
any restrictions
you love great music without
any restrictions,
any restrictions, you
you love great music without
any restrictions, you are
any restrictions, you are going
to
to love
any restrictions, you are going
to love Apple
to love Apple Music
any restrictions, you are going
to love Apple Music's
to love Apple Music's Beats
any restrictions, you are going
to love Apple Music's Beats 1.
Final
Finally
Finally,
Finally, Connect,
Finally, Connect, a
Finally, Connect, a fantastic
way
way for
Finally, Connect, a fantastic
way for established
way for established and
Finally, Connect, a fantastic
way for established and new
way for established and new and
even
even unsigned
way for established and new and
even unsigned artists
even unsigned artists to
connect
connect direct
even unsigned artists to
connect directly
connect directly with
even unsigned artists to
connect directly with music
lovers
lovers any
connect directly with music
lovers anywh
lovers anywhere.
connect directly with music
lovers anywhere. This
lovers anywhere. This is
connect directly with music
lovers anywhere. This is g
lovers anywhere. This is going
to
to be
lovers anywhere. This is going
to be very
to be very powerful
lovers anywhere. This is going
to be very powerful for
musicians
musicians.
Ca
Can
musicians.
Can you
Can you imagine
musicians.
Can you imagine being
Can you imagine being an
up-and-coming
up-and-coming artist
Can you imagine being an
up-and-coming artist and
up-and-coming artist and being
able
able to
up-and-coming artist and being
able to share
able to share your
up-and-coming artist and being
able to share your music
able to share your music on
up-and-coming artist and being
able to share your music on t
able to share your music on the
biggest
biggest m
able to share your music on the
biggest music
biggest music platform
able to share your music on the
biggest music platform on
biggest music platform on t
able to share your music on the
biggest music platform on the
world
world that
biggest music platform on the
world that p
world that people
biggest music platform on the
world that people already
world that people already have
biggest music platform on the
world that people already have,
Apple
Apple Music
world that people already have,
Apple Music?
Apple Music? Remember
world that people already have,
Apple Music? Remember,
Apple Music? Remember, this
world that people already have,
Apple Music? Remember, this is
an
an ecosystem
Apple Music? Remember, this is
an ecosystem.
an ecosystem. It's
Apple Music? Remember, this is
an ecosystem. It's built
an ecosystem. It's built to
fit
fit together.
an ecosystem. It's built to
fit together. It
fit together. It feeds
an ecosystem. It's built to
fit together. It feeds off
each
each other.
fit together. It feeds off
each other. When
each other. When y
fit together. It feeds off
each other. When you
each other. When you upload
your
your m
each other. When you upload
your music
your music t
each other. When you upload
your music to
your music to Apple
each other. When you upload
your music to Apple Music
your music to Apple Music,
anything
anything c
your music to Apple Music,
anything can
anything can happen
your music to Apple Music,
anything can happen.
So
So n
anything can happen.
So now
So now let
anything can happen.
So now let me
So now let me leave
anything can happen.
So now let me leave the
So now let me leave the real
anything can happen.
heavy
So now let me leave the real
heavy lifting
heavy lifting to
So now let me leave the real
heavy lifting to my
heavy lifting to my great
friend
friend,
heavy lifting to my great
friend, Eddy
friend, Eddy Cue,
heavy lifting to my great
friend, Eddy Cue, and
friend, Eddy Cue, and tell
heavy lifting to my great
friend, Eddy Cue, and tell you
how
how this
friend, Eddy Cue, and tell you
how this all
how this all works
friend, Eddy Cue, and tell you
how this all works together
how this all works together.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
how this all works together.
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> EDDY
>> EDDY CUE:
>> EDDY CUE: Thank
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you,
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you, Jimmy
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you, Jimmy.
It's
It's great
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you, Jimmy.
It's great to
It's great to be
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you, Jimmy.
It's great to be h
It's great to be here
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you, Jimmy.
It's great to be here this
morning
morning w
It's great to be here this
morning with
morning with you
It's great to be here this
morning with you.
So
So Apple
morning with you.
So Apple Music
So Apple Music,
morning with you.
So Apple Music, it's
So Apple Music, it's a
revolutionary
revolutionary music
So Apple Music, it's a
revolutionary music service
revolutionary music service,
and
and i
revolutionary music service,
and it
and it s
revolutionary music service,
and it starts
and it starts with
revolutionary music service,
and it starts with M
and it starts with My
revolutionary music service,
and it starts with My Music.
We've
We've add
and it starts with My Music.
We've added
We've added some
and it starts with My Music.
We've added some great
We've added some great new
features
features from
We've added some great new
features from iTunes
features from iTunes like
We've added some great new
features from iTunes like the
Up
Up Next
features from iTunes like the
Up Next queue,
Up Next queue, and
features from iTunes like the
Up Next queue, and also
Up Next queue, and also your
recently
recently add
Up Next queue, and also your
recently added
recently added albums
Up Next queue, and also your
recently added albums and
recently added albums and songs
right
right across
recently added albums and songs
right across the
right across the top.
recently added albums and songs
right across the top. A
right across the top. And
recently added albums and songs
right across the top. And all
of
of the
right across the top. And all
of the music
of the music you've
right across the top. And all
of the music you've purchased
of the music you've purchased,
along
along with
of the music you've purchased,
along with the
along with the playlists
of the music you've purchased,
along with the playlists you've
created
created on
along with the playlists you've
created on your
created on your Mac
along with the playlists you've
created on your Mac or
created on your Mac or your
iPhone,
iPhone, are
created on your Mac or your
iPhone, are right
iPhone, are right here.
Now
Now,
iPhone, are right here.
Now, of
Now, of course,
iPhone, are right here.
Now, of course, y
Now, of course, you
iPhone, are right here.
Now, of course, you can
Now, of course, you can search
your
your music
Now, of course, you can search
your music library,
your music library, but
Now, of course, you can search
your music library, but now
your music library, but now you
can
can search
your music library, but now you
can search a
can search and
your music library, but now you
can search and s
can search and stream
your music library, but now you
can search and stream the
millions
millions and
can search and stream the
millions and millions
millions and millions of
can search and stream the
millions and millions of songs
that
that we
millions and millions of songs
that we h
that we have
millions and millions of songs
that we have on
that we have on iTunes.
Now
Now,
that we have on iTunes.
Now, in
Now, in addition
that we have on iTunes.
Now, in addition to
Now, in addition to My
that we have on iTunes.
Now, in addition to My Music
Now, in addition to My Music,
when
when you
Now, in addition to My Music,
when you can
when you can stream
Now, in addition to My Music,
when you can stream and
when you can stream and listen
to
to any
when you can stream and listen
to any song
to any song you
when you can stream and listen
to any song you want,
to any song you want, you
when you can stream and listen
to any song you want, you need
a
a great
to any song you want, you need
a great place
a great place to
to any song you want, you need
a great place to start,
a great place to start, and
that's
that's why
a great place to start, and
that's why we've
that's why we've created
a great place to start, and
that's why we've created F
that's why we've created For
You
You.
that's why we've created For
You. For
You. For You
that's why we've created For
You. For You r
You. For You recommends
playlists
playlists and
You. For You recommends
playlists and albums
playlists and albums that
You. For You recommends
playlists and albums that we
think
think you
playlists and albums that we
think you are
think you are going
playlists and albums that we
think you are going to
think you are going to love.
They
They are
think you are going to love.
They are personal
They are personaliz
think you are going to love.
They are personalized
They are personalized to
think you are going to love.
They are personalized to your
taste
taste base
They are personalized to your
taste based
taste based on
They are personalized to your
taste based on the
taste based on the music
They are personalized to your
taste based on the music you
list
listen
taste based on the music you
listen to,
listen to, the
taste based on the music you
listen to, the art
listen to, the artis
taste based on the music you
listen to, the artists
listen to, the artists you
love.
love. And
listen to, the artists you
love. And it
love. And it isn't
listen to, the artists you
love. And it isn't just
algorithms
algorithms.
love. And it isn't just
algorithms. It's
recommendations
recommendations m
algorithms. It's
recommendations made
recommendations made by
algorithms. It's
recommendations made by real
people
people who
recommendations made by real
people who love
people who love music
recommendations made by real
people who love mu
people who love music,
recommendations made by real
people who love music, a
people who love music, and
recommendations made by real
people who love music, and they
are
are our
people who love music, and they
are our t
are our team
people who love music, and they
are our team of
are our team of experts.
Now
Now,
are our team of experts.
Now, let's
Now, let's take
are our team of experts.
Now, let's take a
Now, let's take a l
are our team of experts.
Now, let's take a look
Now, let's take a look at
are our team of experts.
Now, let's take a look at New.
H
Here
Now, let's take a look at New.
Here you
Here you will
Now, let's take a look at New.
Here you will discover
Here you will discover new
artists
artists and
Here you will discover new
artists and albums
artists and albums every
Here you will discover new
artists and albums every week,
along
along w
artists and albums every week,
along with
along with the
artists and albums every week,
along with the top
along with the top charts,
artists and albums every week,
along with the top charts, and
every
every one
along with the top charts, and
every one of
every one of o
along with the top charts, and
every one of our
every one of our playlist
along with the top charts, and
every one of our playlists
every one of our playlists,
along with the top charts, and
every one of our playlists, all
human
human c
every one of our playlists, all
human curated
human curated,
every one of our playlists, all
human curated, available
human curated, available by
genre
genre or
human curated, available by
genre or by
genre or by activity
human curated, available by
genre or by activity.
So
So when
genre or by activity.
So when you
So when you think
genre or by activity.
So when you think of
So when you think of A
genre or by activity.
So when you think of Apple
Music
Music,
So when you think of Apple
Music, it's
Music, it's M
So when you think of Apple
Music, it's My
Music, it's My Music
So when you think of Apple
Music, it's My Music,
Music, it's My Music, for
So when you think of Apple
Music, it's My Music, for you
and
and new.
Music, it's My Music, for you
and new. It
and new. It m
Music, it's My Music, for you
and new. It makes
and new. It makes it
Music, it's My Music, for you
and new. It makes it fun
and new. It makes it fun and
easy
easy to
and new. It makes it fun and
easy to experience
easy to experience the
and new. It makes it fun and
easy to experience the catalog
of
of the
easy to experience the catalog
of the world
of the world's
easy to experience the catalog
of the world's music
of the world's music.
easy to experience the catalog
of the world's music. And
of the world's music. And t
easy to experience the catalog
of the world's music. And that
is
is the
of the world's music. And that
is the revolutionary
is the revolutionary music
service.
No
Now
service.
Now let's
Now let's talk
service.
Now let's talk about
Now let's talk about radio.
The
The truth
Now let's talk about radio.
The truth is
The truth is Internet
Now let's talk about radio.
The truth is Internet r
The truth is Internet radio
isn't
isn't really
The truth is Internet radio
isn't really r
isn't really radio.
The truth is Internet radio
isn't really radio. I
isn't really radio. It's
The truth is Internet radio
isn't really radio. It's just
a
a playlist
isn't really radio. It's just
a playlist o
a playlist of
isn't really radio. It's just
a playlist of songs
a playlist of songs.
isn't really radio. It's just
a playlist of songs. And
a playlist of songs. And so
isn't really radio. It's just
a playlist of songs. And so we
wanted
wanted to
a playlist of songs. And so we
wanted to do
wanted to do something
a playlist of songs. And so we
wanted to do something really
big.
big. W
wanted to do something really
big. We
big. We want
wanted to do something really
big. We wanted
big. We wanted to
wanted to do something really
big. We wanted to create
big. We wanted to create a
worldwide
worldwide live
big. We wanted to create a
worldwide live radio
worldwide live radio station
broadcasting
broadcasting around
worldwide live radio station
broadcasting around the
broadcasting around the globe,
and
and we've
broadcasting around the globe,
and we've done
and we've done that
broadcasting around the globe,
and we've done that with
and we've done that with Beats
1.
1. It's
and we've done that with Beats
1. It's the
1. It's the world
and we've done that with Beats
1. It's the world's
1. It's the world's best
and we've done that with Beats
1. It's the world's best radio
station
station now
1. It's the world's best radio
station now meets
station now meets the
1. It's the world's best radio
station now meets the w
station now meets the world's
best
best voice,
station now meets the world's
best voice, and
best voice, and that's
station now meets the world's
best voice, and that's why
we've
we've h
best voice, and that's why
we've hired
we've hired Zane
best voice, and that's why
we've hired Zane Lowe.
we've hired Zane Lowe. Zane
best voice, and that's why
we've hired Zane Lowe. Zane is
a
a mast
we've hired Zane Lowe. Zane is
a masterful
a masterful interviewer
we've hired Zane Lowe. Zane is
a masterful interviewer and
a masterful interviewer and an
influential
influential m
a masterful interviewer and an
influential music
influential music figure
a masterful interviewer and an
influential music figure in
influential music figure in his
own
own right,
influential music figure in his
own right, a
own right, and
influential music figure in his
own right, and to
own right, and to tell
influential music figure in his
own right, and to tell y
own right, and to tell you
influential music figure in his
own right, and to tell you more
about
about it,
own right, and to tell you more
about it, h
about it, here
own right, and to tell you more
about it, here is
about it, here is Zane
own right, and to tell you more
about it, here is Zane.
>>
>> ZANE
>> ZANE LOWE:
>> ZANE LOWE: I
>> ZANE LOWE: I am
>> ZANE LOWE: I am a
>> ZANE LOWE: I am a music
>> ZANE LOWE: I am a music f
fan.
fan. I
>> ZANE LOWE: I am a music f
fan. I play
fan. I play records
>> ZANE LOWE: I am a music f
fan. I play records.
fan. I play records. What
>> ZANE LOWE: I am a music f
fan. I play records. What I
love
love is
fan. I play records. What I
love is watching
love is watching a
fan. I play records. What I
love is watching a group
love is watching a group of
people
people react
love is watching a group of
people react to
people react to a
love is watching a group of
people react to a gre
people react to a great
love is watching a group of
people react to a great record
for
for the
people react to a great record
for the first
for the first time
people react to a great record
for the first time.
for the first time. When
people react to a great record
for the first time. When I
play
play t
for the first time. When I
play that
play that record
for the first time. When I
play that record on
play that record on the
for the first time. When I
play that record on the radio,
the
the audience
play that record on the radio,
the audience tell
the audience tell me
play that record on the radio,
the audience tell me,
the audience tell me, the
play that record on the radio,
the audience tell me, the time
lines
lines light
the audience tell me, the time
lines light up
lines light up,
the audience tell me, the time
lines light up, my
lines light up, my friends
the audience tell me, the time
lines light up, my friends tell
me,
me, my
lines light up, my friends tell
me, my phone
me, my phone lights
lines light up, my friends tell
me, my phone lights up
me, my phone lights up.
lines light up, my friends tell
me, my phone lights up. They
love
love it
me, my phone lights up. They
love it or
love it or t
me, my phone lights up. They
love it or they
love it or they hate
me, my phone lights up. They
love it or they hate it
love it or they hate it.
me, my phone lights up. They
love it or they hate it. But
it
it c
love it or they hate it. But
it creates
it creates a
love it or they hate it. But
it creates a debate.
it creates a debate. That's
what
what good
it creates a debate. That's
what good music
what good music on
it creates a debate. That's
what good music on the
what good music on the radio
does
does.
When
When Apple
does.
When Apple first
When Apple first asked
does.
When Apple first asked me
When Apple first asked me to
be
be involved
When Apple first asked me to
be involved in
be involved in this
When Apple first asked me to
be involved in this,
be involved in this, they
When Apple first asked me to
be involved in this, they told
us
us to
be involved in this, they told
us to put
us to put t
be involved in this, they told
us to put the
us to put the great
be involved in this, they told
us to put the great music
us to put the great music in
front
front of
us to put the great music in
front of the
front of the average
us to put the great music in
front of the average,
front of the average, the
unexpected
unexpected,
front of the average, the
unexpected, the
unexpected, the undiscovered,
the
the anticipated,
unexpected, the undiscovered,
the anticipated, the
the anticipated, the u
unexpected, the undiscovered,
the anticipated, the underrate
the anticipated, the unde
underrated.
underrated. Their
the anticipated, the unde
underrated. Their words:
underrated. Their words: Move
the
the n
underrated. Their words: Move
the needle.
the needle. And
underrated. Their words: Move
the needle. And that's
the needle. And that's what
underrated. Their words: Move
the needle. And that's what we
are
are doing
the needle. And that's what we
are doing.
are doing. We
the needle. And that's what we
are doing. We h
are doing. We have
the needle. And that's what we
are doing. We have real
are doing. We have real music
fans
fans running
are doing. We have real music
fans running this
fans running this p
are doing. We have real music
fans running this place.
fans running this place. We
have
have great
fans running this place. We
have great music
have great music D
fans running this place. We
have great music DJs
have great music DJs and
incredible
incredible artist
have great music DJs and
incredible artist who
incredible artist who is
have great music DJs and
incredible artist who is are
incredible artist who is are in
the
the studio
incredible artist who is are in
the studio right
the studio right now
incredible artist who is are in
the studio right now b
the studio right now building
real
real radio
the studio right now building
real radio shows
real radio shows that
the studio right now building
real radio shows that are
real radio shows that are going
to
to blow
real radio shows that are going
to blow your
to blow your mind.
real radio shows that are going
to blow your mind. And
to blow your mind. And the
only
only place
to blow your mind. And the
only place that
only place that can
to blow your mind. And the
only place that can pull
only place that can pull off
to blow your mind. And the
only place that can pull off a
only place that can pull off an
imaginative
imaginative idea
only place that can pull off an
imaginative idea as
imaginative idea as big
only place that can pull off an
imaginative idea as big as
imaginative idea as big as this
--
-- Apple
imaginative idea as big as this
-- Apple.
We
We are
-- Apple.
We are called
We are called Beats
-- Apple.
We are called Beats 1.
We are called Beats 1. We
-- Apple.
We are called Beats 1. We are
always
always on
We are called Beats 1. We are
always on,
always on, playing
We are called Beats 1. We are
always on, playing the
always on, playing the m
We are called Beats 1. We are
always on, playing the music
that
that we
always on, playing the music
that we love
(Applause)
>>
>> EDDY
>> EDDY CUE:
>> EDDY CUE: So
>> EDDY CUE: So Beats
>> EDDY CUE: So Beats 1.
>> EDDY CUE: So Beats 1. It
is
is worldwide
>> EDDY CUE: So Beats 1. It
is worldwide,
is worldwide, live
>> EDDY CUE: So Beats 1. It
is worldwide, live,
broadcasting
broadcasting 24
is worldwide, live,
broadcasting 24 by
broadcasting 24 by 7,
is worldwide, live,
broadcasting 24 by 7, and
broadcasting 24 by 7, and it
is worldwide, live,
broadcasting 24 by 7, and it is
coming
coming from
broadcasting 24 by 7, and it is
coming from New
coming from New York,
broadcasting 24 by 7, and it is
coming from New York, LA,
coming from New York, LA, and
Lon
L
coming from New York, LA, and
an
and
coming from New York, LA, and
and London
and London,
coming from New York, LA, and
and London, and
and London, and that
coming from New York, LA, and
and London, and that is
and London, and that is Radio.
Ne
Next
Next,
Next, we
Next, we wanted
Next, we wanted to
Next, we wanted to find
Next, we wanted to find a
Next, we wanted to find a way
to
to b
Next, we wanted to find a way
to bring
to bring fans
Next, we wanted to find a way
to bring fans close
to bring fans closer
Next, we wanted to find a way
to bring fans closer to
to bring fans closer to the
artists
artists t
to bring fans closer to the
artists they
artists they love,
to bring fans closer to the
artists they love, a
artists they love, and
to bring fans closer to the
artists they love, and we
artists they love, and we call
it
it Connect.
artists they love, and we call
it Connect. It's
it Connect. It's a
artists they love, and we call
it Connect. It's a place
it Connect. It's a place whe
artists they love, and we call
it Connect. It's a place where
art
artis
it Connect. It's a place where
artists
artists are
it Connect. It's a place where
artists are free
artists are free to
it Connect. It's a place where
artists are free to upload
their
their m
artists are free to upload
their music,
their music, their
artists are free to upload
their music, their video
their music, their videos
artists are free to upload
their music, their videos,
their
their photos,
their music, their videos,
their photos, all
their photos, all directly
their music, their videos,
their photos, all directly to
their photos, all directly to a
fan.
Let's
Let's take
fan.
Let's take Pharrell,
Let's take Pharrell, a
favorite
favorite musician
Let's take Pharrell, a
favorite musician and
favorite musician and song
Let's take Pharrell, a
favorite musician and songwrite
favorite musician and song
songwriter
songwriter of
favorite musician and song
songwriter of mine
songwriter of mine.
favorite musician and song
songwriter of mine. He
songwriter of mine. He is
prolific
prolific,
songwriter of mine. He is
prolific, and
prolific, and he
songwriter of mine. He is
prolific, and he does
prolific, and he does a
songwriter of mine. He is
prolific, and he does a lot
prolific, and he does a lot.
Let
Let me
prolific, and he does a lot.
Let me show
Let me show you
prolific, and he does a lot.
Let me show you how
Let me show you how it
prolific, and he does a lot.
Let me show you how it works
with
with Connect.
He
He takes
with Connect.
He takes a
He takes a lot
with Connect.
He takes a lot of
He takes a lot of photos.
with Connect.
He takes a lot of photos. He
writes
writes a
He takes a lot of photos. He
writes a lot
writes a lot of
He takes a lot of photos. He
writes a lot of lyrics
writes a lot of lyrics.
He takes a lot of photos. He
writes a lot of lyrics. He's
experiment
experimenting
writes a lot of lyrics. He's
experimenting and
experimenting and m
writes a lot of lyrics. He's
experimenting and mixing
experimenting and mixing songs
all
all the
experimenting and mixing songs
all the t
all the time
experimenting and mixing songs
all the time.
all the time. Or
experimenting and mixing songs
all the time. Or he
all the time. Or he just
experimenting and mixing songs
all the time. Or he just has
something
something new
all the time. Or he just has
something new and
something new and interesting
to
to say
something new and interesting
to say.
to say. All
something new and interesting
to say. All of
to say. All of this
something new and interesting
to say. All of this lives
right
right in
to say. All of this lives
right in Connect.
right in Connect. Artists
to say. All of this lives
right in Connect. Artists can
post
post a
right in Connect. Artists can
post and
post and publish
right in Connect. Artists can
post and publish and
post and publish and upload
anything,
anything, i
post and publish and upload
anything, including
anything, including directly
post and publish and upload
anything, including directly to
Facebook
Facebook,
anything, including directly to
Facebook, T
Facebook, Twitter,
anything, including directly to
Facebook, Twitter, and
Facebook, Twitter, and their
own
own website
Facebook, Twitter, and their
own website,
own website, an
Facebook, Twitter, and their
own website, and
own website, and fans
Facebook, Twitter, and their
own website, and fans can
own website, and fans can like
and
and comment
own website, and fans can like
and comment on
and comment on those
own website, and fans can like
and comment on those p
and comment on those posts.
And
And it's
and comment on those posts.
And it's not
And it's not just
and comment on those posts.
And it's not just for
And it's not just for one
and comment on those posts.
And it's not just for one a
artist,
artist, but
And it's not just for one a
artist, but it's
artist, but it's for
And it's not just for one a
artist, but it's for all
artist, but it's for all of
And it's not just for one a
artist, but it's for all of the
artists
artists that
artist, but it's for all of the
artists that you
artists that you love.
artist, but it's for all of the
artists that you love. And
artists that you love. And to
give
give you
artists that you love. And to
give you a
give you a little
artists that you love. And to
give you a little s
give you a little sense
artists that you love. And to
give you a little sense of
give you a little sense of what
it's
it's l
give you a little sense of what
it's like
it's like to
give you a little sense of what
it's like to be
it's like to be a
give you a little sense of what
it's like to be an
it's like to be an artist
give you a little sense of what
it's like to be an artist on
Connect,
Connect, I'd
it's like to be an artist on
Connect, I'd l
Connect, I'd like
it's like to be an artist on
Connect, I'd like to
Connect, I'd like to invite
it's like to be an artist on
Connect, I'd like to invite up
a
a friend
Connect, I'd like to invite up
a friend,
a friend, Drake
Connect, I'd like to invite up
a friend, Drake.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
a friend, Drake.
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> DRAKE:
>> DRAKE: Thank
>> DRAKE: Thank you
>> DRAKE: Thank you.
>> DRAKE: Thank you. I
>> DRAKE: Thank you. I want
to
to say
>> DRAKE: Thank you. I want
to say,
to say, honestly
>> DRAKE: Thank you. I want
to say, honestly,
to say, honestly, what
>> DRAKE: Thank you. I want
to say, honestly, what an
to say, honestly, what an honor
it
it is
to say, honestly, what an honor
it is to
it is to be
to say, honestly, what an honor
it is to be i
it is to be in
to say, honestly, what an honor
it is to be in this
it is to be in this room
to say, honestly, what an honor
it is to be in this room with
so
so many
it is to be in this room with
so many individuals
so many individuals that
it is to be in this room with
so many individuals that have
change
changed
so many individuals that have
changed the
changed the way
so many individuals that have
changed the way in
changed the way in which
so many individuals that have
changed the way in which t
changed the way in which the
world
world relates
changed the way in which the
world relates to
world relates to technology,
changed the way in which the
world relates to technology, so
give
give yourselves
world relates to technology, so
give yourselves a
give yourselves a round
world relates to technology, so
give yourselves a round of
applause,
applause, please.
(Applause)
For
For example
(Applause)
For example,
For example, I
(Applause)
For example, I bought
For example, I bought this
vintage
vintage Apple
For example, I bought this
vintage Apple employee's
vintage Apple employee's jacket
using
using a
vintage Apple employee's jacket
using a tool
using a tool known
vintage Apple employee's jacket
using a tool known in
using a tool known in the
vintage Apple employee's jacket
using a tool known in the rap
world
world as
using a tool known in the rap
world as the
world as the Internet.
using a tool known in the rap
world as the Internet. It's
going
going to
world as the Internet. It's
going to be
going to be huge
world as the Internet. It's
going to be huge this
going to be huge this year.
It's
It's out
going to be huge this year.
It's out of
It's out of this
going to be huge this year.
It's out of this world.
It's out of this world. He
going to be huge this year.
It's out of this world. He is
excited
excited,
It's out of this world. He is
excited, he
excited, he knows
It's out of this world. He is
excited, he knows about
excited, he knows about it
It's out of this world. He is
excited, he knows about it,
that
that guy
excited, he knows about it,
that guy right
that guy right there.
(Laughter)
Honestly,
Honestly, in
(Laughter)
Honestly, in all
Honestly, in all seriousness,
I
I came
Honestly, in all seriousness,
I came here
I came here today
Honestly, in all seriousness,
I came here today to
I came here today to share
Honestly, in all seriousness,
I came here today to share my
story,
story, the
I came here today to share my
story, the way
story, the way technology
changed
changed what
story, the way technology
changed what I
changed what I do
story, the way technology
changed what I do for
changed what I do for a
story, the way technology
changed what I do for a living.
I
I am
I am from
I am from Toronto,
I am from Toronto, Canada.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
I am from Toronto, Canada.
(Cheers and applause)
(Laughter)
(Laughter).
You
You know,
(Laughter).
You know, as
You know, as a
(Laughter).
You know, as a kid
You know, as a kid growing
(Laughter).
You know, as a kid growing up,
I
I always
You know, as a kid growing up,
I always wondered
I always wondered if
You know, as a kid growing up,
I always wondered if my
I always wondered if my city
You know, as a kid growing up,
I always wondered if my city or
even
even my
I always wondered if my city or
even my country
even my country would
I always wondered if my city or
even my country would have
somebody
somebody break
even my country would have
somebody break into
somebody break into the
even my country would have
somebody break into the global
music
music scene
somebody break into the global
music scene as
music scene as a
somebody break into the global
music scene as a true
superstar.
superstar. You
music scene as a true
superstar. You know
superstar. You know,
music scene as a true
superstar. You know, the
superstar. You know, the dream
seemed
seemed unattainable
superstar. You know, the dream
seemed unattainable at
seemed unattainable at the
time.
time. Even
seemed unattainable at the
time. Even myself,
time. Even myself, I
seemed unattainable at the
time. Even myself, I tried
time. Even myself, I tried to
do
do it
time. Even myself, I tried to
do it the
do it the traditional
time. Even myself, I tried to
do it the traditional way
do it the traditional way,
time. Even myself, I tried to
do it the traditional way, the
towering
towering New
do it the traditional way, the
towering New York
towering New York label
buildings,
buildings, the
towering New York label
buildings, the lobby
buildings, the lobby littered
with
with other
buildings, the lobby littered
with other people
with other people's
accomplishments.
accomplishments. It's
improbable
improbable to
accomplishments. It's
improbable to think
improbable to think that
accomplishments. It's
improbable to think that every
talent
talented
improbable to think that every
talented art
talented artist
improbable to think that every
talented artist is
talented artist is going
improbable to think that every
talented artist is going to
talented artist is going to get
a
a shot
talented artist is going to get
a shot to
a shot to have
talented artist is going to get
a shot to have their
a shot to have their vision
validated
validated.
And
And then
validated.
And then that's
And then that's when
validated.
And then that's when the
And then that's when the game
change
changed
And then that's when the game
changed.
changed. And
And then that's when the game
changed. And we
changed. And we had
And then that's when the game
changed. And we had to
changed. And we had to change
it.
it. Myself
changed. And we had to change
it. Myself and
it. Myself and my
changed. And we had to change
it. Myself and my team
it. Myself and my team brought
our
our vision
it. Myself and my team brought
our vision and
our vision and our
it. Myself and my team brought
our vision and our music
our vision and our music di
directly
directly to
our vision and our music di
directly to the
directly to the people
our vision and our music di
directly to the people.
And
And that
directly to the people.
And that was
And that was kind
directly to the people.
And that was kind of
And that was kind of the
directly to the people.
And that was kind of the first
time
time that
And that was kind of the first
time that we
time that we really
And that was kind of the first
time that we really got
time that we really got noticed
And that was kind of the first
time that we really got not
noticed.
noticed. The
time that we really got not
noticed. The dream
noticed. The dream of
time that we really got not
noticed. The dream of being
noticed. The dream of being a
new
new art
noticed. The dream of being a
new artist
new artist like
noticed. The dream of being a
new artist like myself
new artist like myself five
years
years ago
new artist like myself five
years ago and
years ago and connecting
new artist like myself five
years ago and connecting di
directly
directly with
years ago and connecting di
directly with an
directly with an audience
years ago and connecting di
directly with an audience has
never
never been
directly with an audience has
never been more
never been more close
directly with an audience has
never been more close and
reachable
reachable than
never been more close and
reachable than right
reachable than right now
never been more close and
reachable than right now.
See
See,
reachable than right now.
See, now
See, now we
reachable than right now.
See, now we encourage
See, now we encourage you
reachable than right now.
See, now we encourage you to
spend
spend the
See, now we encourage you to
spend the time
spend the time on
See, now we encourage you to
spend the time on your
spend the time on your body
See, now we encourage you to
spend the time on your body of
work,
work, spend
spend the time on your body of
work, spend the
work, spend the time
spend the time on your body of
work, spend the time on
work, spend the time on your
craft,
craft, assemble
work, spend the time on your
craft, assemble the
craft, assemble the right
work, spend the time on your
craft, assemble the right body
of
of work,
craft, assemble the right body
of work, and
of work, and instead
craft, assemble the right body
of work, and instead of
of work, and instead of having
to
to post
of work, and instead of having
to post your
to post your stuff
of work, and instead of having
to post your stuff on
to post your stuff on all
of work, and instead of having
to post your stuff on all these
different
different and
to post your stuff on all these
different and sometimes
confusing
confusing place
different and sometimes
confusing places
confusing places,
different and sometimes
confusing places, it
confusing places, it all
different and sometimes
confusing places, it all lives
in
in one
confusing places, it all lives
in one very
in one very simple,
confusing places, it all lives
in one very simple, very
in one very simple, very easy
place,
place, and
in one very simple, very easy
place, and that
place, and that is
in one very simple, very easy
place, and that is Connect.
It's
It's right
place, and that is Connect.
It's right from
It's right from where
place, and that is Connect.
It's right from where you
It's right from where you are
in
in your
It's right from where you are
in your city
in your city in
It's right from where you are
in your city in front
in your city in front of
It's right from where you are
in your city in front of your
computer
computer.
in your city in front of your
computer. And
computer. And this
in your city in front of your
computer. And this approach
computer. And this approach is
how
how we
computer. And this approach is
how we broke
how we broke in
computer. And this approach is
how we broke in 2008,
how we broke in 2008, and
computer. And this approach is
how we broke in 2008, and it
has
has been
how we broke in 2008, and it
has been perfected
has been perfected and
simplified
simplified,
has been perfected and
simplified, of
simplified, of course,
has been perfected and
simplified, of course, by
simplified, of course, by the
great
great people
simplified, of course, by the
great people at
great people at Apple
simplified, of course, by the
great people at Apple.
So
So you
great people at Apple.
So you know
So you know,
great people at Apple.
So you know, as
So you know, as I'm
great people at Apple.
So you know, as I'm working
tireless
tirelessly
So you know, as I'm working
tirelessly on
tirelessly on this
So you know, as I'm working
tirelessly on this next
tirelessly on this next album,
this
this comes
tirelessly on this next album,
this comes at
this comes at the
tirelessly on this next album,
this comes at the perfect
this comes at the perfect time
for
for me.
this comes at the perfect time
for me. Given
for me. Given the
this comes at the perfect time
for me. Given the great
success
success of
for me. Given the great
success of my
success of my last
for me. Given the great
success of my last mix
success of my last mix tape
that
that went
success of my last mix tape
that went directly
that went directly to
success of my last mix tape
that went directly to iTunes,
this
this really
that went directly to iTunes,
this really --
this really -- I
that went directly to iTunes,
this really -- I can't
this really -- I can't wait
that went directly to iTunes,
this really -- I can't wait to
incorporate
incorporate Apple
this really -- I can't wait to
incorporate Apple Music
incorporate Apple Music and
especially
especially Connect
incorporate Apple Music and
especially Connect into
especially Connect into what
incorporate Apple Music and
especially Connect into what I
am
am doing
especially Connect into what I
am doing next
am doing next.
especially Connect into what I
am doing next. I
am doing next. I am
especially Connect into what I
am doing next. I am really
excited
excited about
am doing next. I am really
excited about what
excited about what I
am doing next. I am really
excited about what I am
excited about what I am working
on
on.
excited about what I am working
on. And
on. And as
excited about what I am working
on. And as an
on. And as an artist,
excited about what I am working
on. And as an artist, I
on. And as an artist, I can
say
say for
on. And as an artist, I can
say for all
say for all those
on. And as an artist, I can
say for all those kids
say for all those kids sitting
at
at home,
say for all those kids sitting
at home, it's
at home, it's truly
say for all those kids sitting
at home, it's truly amazing
at home, it's truly amazing to
be
be part
at home, it's truly amazing to
be part of
be part of something
at home, it's truly amazing to
be part of something that
be part of something that I
believe
believe in
be part of something that I
believe in,
believe in, and
be part of something that I
believe in, and this
believe in, and this is
something
something that
believe in, and this is
something that simplifies
everything
everything for
something that simplifies
everything for the
everything for the modern
musician
musician like
everything for the modern
musician like myself
musician like myself and
everything for the modern
musician like myself and the
modern
modern music
musician like myself and the
modern music consumer
modern music consumer like
musician like myself and the
modern music consumer like you
modern music consumer like you.
So
So I
So I hope
So I hope you
So I hope you enjoy
So I hope you enjoy Apple
Music.
Music. I
So I hope you enjoy Apple
Music. I hope
Music. I hope you
So I hope you enjoy Apple
Music. I hope you enjoy
Connect
Connect.
Music. I hope you enjoy
Connect. My
Connect. My name
Music. I hope you enjoy
Connect. My name is
Connect. My name is Drake,
Music. I hope you enjoy
Connect. My name is Drake, and
thank
thank you
Connect. My name is Drake, and
thank you for
thank you for your
Connect. My name is Drake, and
thank you for your time.
Appreciate
Appreciate it.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
Appreciate it.
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> EDDY
>> EDDY CUE:
>> EDDY CUE: Thank
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you,
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you, Drake
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you, Drake.
And
And that
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you, Drake.
And that is
And that is Connect
>> EDDY CUE: Thank you, Drake.
And that is Connect.
Now,
Now, I'd
And that is Connect.
Now, I'd love
Now, I'd love to
And that is Connect.
Now, I'd love to give
Now, I'd love to give you
And that is Connect.
Now, I'd love to give you a
demo
demo of
Now, I'd love to give you a
demo of Apple
demo of Apple Music
Now, I'd love to give you a
demo of Apple Music,
demo of Apple Music, but
Now, I'd love to give you a
demo of Apple Music, but before
I
I start,
demo of Apple Music, but before
I start, I
I start, I do
demo of Apple Music, but before
I start, I do want
I start, I do want to
demo of Apple Music, but before
I start, I do want to wish
I start, I do want to wish Phil
Schiller
Schiller a
I start, I do want to wish Phil
Schiller a happy
Schiller a happy birthday
I start, I do want to wish Phil
Schiller a happy birthday.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
Schiller a happy birthday.
(Cheers and applause)
So
So let's
(Cheers and applause)
So let's go
So let's go ahead
(Cheers and applause)
So let's go ahead and
So let's go ahead and launch
our
our new
So let's go ahead and launch
our new Music
our new Music app.
So let's go ahead and launch
our new Music app. You
our new Music app. You will
notice
notice right
our new Music app. You will
notice right away
notice right away it's
our new Music app. You will
notice right away it's got
notice right away it's got a
grand-new
grand-new UI,
notice right away it's got a
grand-new UI, much
grand-new UI, much simpler
notice right away it's got a
grand-new UI, much simpler to
use.
use. Your
grand-new UI, much simpler to
use. Your recent
use. Your recently
grand-new UI, much simpler to
use. Your recently added
albums
albums and
use. Your recently added
albums and songs
albums and songs across
use. Your recently added
albums and songs across the
albums and songs across the top
use. Your recently added
albums and songs across the t
top.
top. Let's
albums and songs across the t
top. Let's play
top. Let's play this
albums and songs across the t
top. Let's play this new
top. Let's play this new album
from
from Spoon
top. Let's play this new album
from Spoon I
from Spoon I added.
(Music)
One
One of
One of the
One of the things
One of the things you
One of the things you will
notice,
notice, we
One of the things you will
notice, we have
notice, we have a
One of the things you will
notice, we have a new
notice, we have a new mini
player
player a
notice, we have a new mini
player across
player across the
notice, we have a new mini
player across the bottom
player across the bottom that
always
always shows
player across the bottom that
always shows you
always shows you w
player across the bottom that
always shows you what's
always shows you what's pla
playing.
playing. If
always shows you what's pla
playing. If I
playing. If I tap
always shows you what's pla
playing. If I tap on
playing. If I tap on it
always shows you what's pla
playing. If I tap on it,
playing. If I tap on it, I
always shows you what's pla
playing. If I tap on it, I get
full
full s
playing. If I tap on it, I get
full screen,
full screen, and
playing. If I tap on it, I get
full screen, and I
full screen, and I can
playing. If I tap on it, I get
full screen, and I can see
full screen, and I can see the
beautiful
beautiful artwork
full screen, and I can see the
beautiful artwork,
beautiful artwork, all
full screen, and I can see the
beautiful artwork, all the
beautiful artwork, all the play
full screen, and I can see the
beautiful artwork, all the p
playback
playback controls.
beautiful artwork, all the p
playback controls. I
playback controls. I can
beautiful artwork, all the p
playback controls. I can just
swipe
swipe down
playback controls. I can just
swipe down,
swipe down, and
playback controls. I can just
swipe down, and it
swipe down, and it d
playback controls. I can just
swipe down, and it disappears
swipe down, and it disappears.
Now,
Now, I
Now, I like
Now, I like looking
Now, I like looking a
Now, I like looking at
Now, I like looking at my
music
music by
Now, I like looking at my
music by art
music by artis
Now, I like looking at my
music by artist.
music by artist. It's
Now, I like looking at my
music by artist. It's really
easy
easy t
music by artist. It's really
easy to
easy to do
music by artist. It's really
easy to do that
easy to do that too
music by artist. It's really
easy to do that too.
easy to do that too. I
music by artist. It's really
easy to do that too. I will
just
just tap
easy to do that too. I will
just tap on
just tap on Albums
easy to do that too. I will
just tap on Albums,
just tap on Albums, s
easy to do that too. I will
just tap on Albums, switch
just tap on Albums, switch to
Art
Artists,
just tap on Albums, switch to
Artists, and
Artists, and let's
just tap on Albums, switch to
Artists, and let's take
Artists, and let's take a
just tap on Albums, switch to
Artists, and let's take a look
at
at Aretha
Artists, and let's take a look
at Aretha Franklin
at Aretha Franklin.
Artists, and let's take a look
at Aretha Franklin. The
at Aretha Franklin. The first
thing
thing you
at Aretha Franklin. The first
thing you will
thing you will n
at Aretha Franklin. The first
thing you will notice
thing you will notice is
at Aretha Franklin. The first
thing you will notice is we
thing you will notice is we add
beautiful
beautiful artwork
thing you will notice is we add
beautiful artwork to
beautiful artwork to all
thing you will notice is we add
beautiful artwork to all the
artist
artist pages.
beautiful artwork to all the
artist pages. Notice
artist pages. Notice as
beautiful artwork to all the
artist pages. Notice as I
swipe
swipe up
artist pages. Notice as I
swipe up,
swipe up, it
artist pages. Notice as I
swipe up, it goes
swipe up, it goes a
artist pages. Notice as I
swipe up, it goes away,
swipe up, it goes away, and
artist pages. Notice as I
swipe up, it goes away, and you
see
see A
swipe up, it goes away, and you
see Aretha
see Aretha at
swipe up, it goes away, and you
see Aretha at the
see Aretha at the top.
swipe up, it goes away, and you
see Aretha at the top. No
see Aretha at the top. No demo
goes
goes complete
see Aretha at the top. No demo
goes complete without
goes complete without playing
this
this song
goes complete without playing
this song.
(Music)
Now
Now,
Now, you
Now, you not
Now, you not only
Now, you not only get
Now, you not only get all
Now, you not only get all of
your
your Aretha
Now, you not only get all of
your Aretha Franklin
your Aretha Franklin songs
Now, you not only get all of
your Aretha Franklin songs in
your
your music
your Aretha Franklin songs in
your music library,
your music library, but
your Aretha Franklin songs in
your music library, but you
your music library, but you can
also
also tap
your music library, but you can
also tap on
also tap on All,
your music library, but you can
also tap on All, and
also tap on All, and now
your music library, but you can
also tap on All, and now you
can
can s
also tap on All, and now you
can see
can see all
also tap on All, and now you
can see all of
can see all of the
also tap on All, and now you
can see all of the songs
can see all of the songs on
Apple
Apple Music
can see all of the songs on
Apple Music,
Apple Music, including
can see all of the songs on
Apple Music, including the
latest
latest release,
Apple Music, including the
latest release, what
latest release, what the
Apple Music, including the
latest release, what the top
song
song is,
latest release, what the top
song is, what
song is, what the
latest release, what the top
song is, what the t
song is, what the top
latest release, what the top
song is, what the top album
song is, what the top album is
latest release, what the top
song is, what the top album is.
Now
Now,
Now, it
Now, it is
Now, it is hard
Now, it is hard to
Now, it is hard to stop
Now, it is hard to stop this
song,
song, but
Now, it is hard to stop this
song, but I
song, but I want
Now, it is hard to stop this
song, but I want to
song, but I want to keep
Now, it is hard to stop this
song, but I want to keep going
song, but I want to keep going.
Now
Now let's
Now let's go
Now let's go back
Now let's go back t
Now let's go back to
Now let's go back to my
library,
library, and
Now let's go back to my
library, and let's
library, and let's take
Now let's go back to my
library, and let's take a
library, and let's take a look
at
at my
library, and let's take a look
at my playlists
at my playlists.
library, and let's take a look
at my playlists. Now,
at my playlists. Now, despite
the
the game
at my playlists. Now, despite
the game last
the game last night
at my playlists. Now, despite
the game last night,
the game last night, I
at my playlists. Now, despite
the game last night, I am
getting
getting ready
the game last night, I am
getting ready f
getting ready for
the game last night, I am
getting ready for t
getting ready for tomorrow
night
night,
getting ready for tomorrow
night, and
night, and I
getting ready for tomorrow
night, and I have
night, and I have already
getting ready for tomorrow
night, and I have already st
started
started creating
night, and I have already st
started creating my
started creating my playlist.
One
One of
started creating my playlist.
One of the
One of the first
started creating my playlist.
One of the first things
One of the first things you
will
will notice
One of the first things you
will notice is
will notice is you
One of the first things you
will notice is you can
will notice is you can add
One of the first things you
will notice is you can add your
own
own artwork
will notice is you can add your
own artwork to
own artwork to your
will notice is you can add your
own artwork to your playlist
own artwork to your playlist.
I
I am
own artwork to your playlist.
I am going
I am going to
own artwork to your playlist.
I am going to be
I am going to be doing
own artwork to your playlist.
I am going to be doing t
I am going to be doing this
tonight
tonight,
I am going to be doing this
tonight, getting
tonight, getting the
I am going to be doing this
tonight, getting the Warriors
ready
ready,
tonight, getting the Warriors
ready, but
ready, but let's
tonight, getting the Warriors
ready, but let's go
ready, but let's go back.
tonight, getting the Warriors
ready, but let's go back. It
is
is karaoke
ready, but let's go back. It
is karaoke night
is karaoke night,
ready, but let's go back. It
is karaoke night, and
is karaoke night, and these
ready, but let's go back. It
is karaoke night, and these are
some
some of
is karaoke night, and these are
some of the
some of the songs
is karaoke night, and these are
some of the songs that
some of the songs that our
is karaoke night, and these are
some of the songs that our team
has
has to
some of the songs that our team
has to l
has to look
some of the songs that our team
has to look forward
has to look forward to
some of the songs that our team
has to look forward to tonight.
Let's
Let's go
has to look forward to tonight.
Let's go ahead
Let's go ahead a
has to look forward to tonight.
Let's go ahead and
Let's go ahead and play
has to look forward to tonight.
Let's go ahead and play that.
(Music)
Just
Just imagine.
(Music)
Now
Now,
Now, if
Now, if I
Now, if I tap
Now, if I tap on
Now, if I tap on the
Now, if I tap on the mini
player,
player, I
Now, if I tap on the mini
player, I can
player, I can see
Now, if I tap on the mini
player, I can see the
player, I can see the full
screen
screen.
player, I can see the full
screen. I
screen. If
player, I can see the full
screen. If I
screen. If I t
player, I can see the full
screen. If I tap
screen. If I tap on
player, I can see the full
screen. If I tap on the
right-hand
right-hand side
screen. If I tap on the
right-hand side next
right-hand side next to
screen. If I tap on the
right-hand side next to the
play
playback
right-hand side next to the
playback con
playback controls,
right-hand side next to the
playback controls, I
playback controls, I can
right-hand side next to the
playback controls, I can see
the
the complete
playback controls, I can see
the complete playlist,
the complete playlist, and
playback controls, I can see
the complete playlist, and it's
very
very easy
the complete playlist, and it's
very easy for
very easy for me
the complete playlist, and it's
very easy for me t
very easy for me to
the complete playlist, and it's
very easy for me to reorganize
it.
it. Let's
very easy for me to reorganize
it. Let's say
it. Let's say I
very easy for me to reorganize
it. Let's say I want
it. Let's say I want t
very easy for me to reorganize
it. Let's say I want to
it. Let's say I want to move
Jealous
Jealous back
it. Let's say I want to move
Jealous back u
Jealous back up,
it. Let's say I want to move
Jealous back up, and
Jealous back up, and n
it. Let's say I want to move
Jealous back up, and now
Jealous back up, and now that
will
will be
Jealous back up, and now that
will be the
will be the next
Jealous back up, and now that
will be the next song
will be the next song that
plays
plays.
will be the next song that
plays. It's
plays. It's that
will be the next song that
plays. It's that simple
plays. It's that simple.
(Applause)
Now
Now,
(Applause)
Now, that's
Now, that's great.
(Applause)
Now, that's great. The
Now, that's great. The first
time
time w
Now, that's great. The first
time we
time we go
Now, that's great. The first
time we go to
time we go to For
Now, that's great. The first
time we go to For You
time we go to For You,
Now, that's great. The first
time we go to For You, w
time we go to For You, we
Now, that's great. The first
time we go to For You, we want
to
to find
time we go to For You, we want
to find out
to find out a
time we go to For You, we want
to find out a little
to find out a little bit
time we go to For You, we want
to find out a little bit about
your
your musical
to find out a little bit about
your musical tastes
your musical tastes,
to find out a little bit about
your musical tastes, so
your musical tastes, so we
to find out a little bit about
your musical tastes, so we are
going
going to
your musical tastes, so we are
going to ask
going to ask y
your musical tastes, so we are
going to ask you
going to ask you what
your musical tastes, so we are
going to ask you what genres
you
you like.
going to ask you what genres
you like. I
you like. I am
going to ask you what genres
you like. I am a
you like. I am a b
going to ask you what genres
you like. I am a big
you like. I am a big fan
going to ask you what genres
you like. I am a big fan of
rock
rock,
you like. I am a big fan of
rock, pop
rock, pop,
you like. I am a big fan of
rock, pop, hip
rock, pop, hip hop
you like. I am a big fan of
rock, pop, hip hop,
rock, pop, hip hop, and
alternative.
And
And now
alternative.
And now it
And now it will
alternative.
And now it will ask
And now it will ask me
alternative.
And now it will ask me for
some
some artists
And now it will ask me for
some artists that
some artists that I
And now it will ask me for
some artists that I like.
Well,
Well, I
some artists that I like.
Well, I love
Well, I love B
some artists that I like.
Well, I love Bruce
Well, I love Bruce Springsteen
some artists that I like.
Well, I love Bruce Springsteen,
so
so I
Well, I love Bruce Springsteen,
so I am
so I am going
Well, I love Bruce Springsteen,
so I am going to
so I am going to t
Well, I love Bruce Springsteen,
so I am going to tap
so I am going to tap twice.
Well, I love Bruce Springsteen,
so I am going to tap twice. I
like
like Lor
so I am going to tap twice. I
like Lord
like Lord,
so I am going to tap twice. I
like Lord, like
like Lord, like Alabama
so I am going to tap twice. I
like Lord, like Alabama Shakes.
Now
Now we
like Lord, like Alabama Shakes.
Now we are
Now we are going
like Lord, like Alabama Shakes.
Now we are going to
Now we are going to take
like Lord, like Alabama Shakes.
Now we are going to take all
of
of this
Now we are going to take all
of this information
of this information you've
provide
provided,
of this information you've
provided, a
provided, along
of this information you've
provided, along with
provided, along with all
of this information you've
provided, along with all of
your
your playlists
provided, along with all of
your playlists a
your playlists and
provided, along with all of
your playlists and the
your playlists and the s
provided, along with all of
your playlists and the songs
that
that you've
your playlists and the songs
that you've purchased
that you've purchased on
iTunes,
iTunes, a
that you've purchased on
iTunes, and
iTunes, and we
that you've purchased on
iTunes, and we are
iTunes, and we are going
that you've purchased on
iTunes, and we are going t
iTunes, and we are going to
make
make recommendations
iTunes, and we are going to
make recommendations just
make recommendations just for
you
you.
So
So here
you.
So here is
So here is one
you.
So here is one inspired
So here is one inspired by
Bruce
Bruce Springsteen
So here is one inspired by
Bruce Springsteen.
Bruce Springsteen. Here
So here is one inspired by
Bruce Springsteen. Here's
Bruce Springsteen. Here's one
called
called Bring
Bruce Springsteen. Here's one
called Bring the
called Bring the Big
Bruce Springsteen. Here's one
called Bring the Big Rock
called Bring the Big Rock.
Let's
Let's play
called Bring the Big Rock.
Let's play that
Let's play that.
(Music)
That's
That's a
That's a great
That's a great song.
That's a great song. I
That's a great song. I can
just
just tap
That's a great song. I can
just tap and
just tap and see
That's a great song. I can
just tap and see the
just tap and see the rest
That's a great song. I can
just tap and see the rest of
the
the songs.
just tap and see the rest of
the songs. Definitely
the songs. Definitely going
just tap and see the rest of
the songs. Definitely going t
the songs. Definitely going to
like
like this
the songs. Definitely going to
like this playlist
like this playlist.
the songs. Definitely going to
Now
like this playlist.
Now,
Now, here
like this playlist.
Now, here's
Now, here's another
like this playlist.
Now, here's another one
Now, here's another one from
Pharrell.
Pharrell. I
Now, here's another one from
Pharrell. I also
Pharrell. I also get
Now, here's another one from
Pharrell. I also get new
albums
albums that
Pharrell. I also get new
albums that are
albums that are available
Pharrell. I also get new
albums that are available to
me,
me, and
albums that are available to
me, and even
me, and even some
albums that are available to
me, and even some c
me, and even some classic
albums
albums that
me, and even some classic
albums that I
albums that I s
me, and even some classic
albums that I should
albums that I should be
listening
listening to
albums that I should be
listening to.
And
And so
listening to.
And so here
And so here are
listening to.
And so here are some
And so here are some brand
listening to.
And so here are some brand-new
albums
albums from
And so here are some brand-new
albums from the
albums from the artists
And so here are some brand-new
albums from the artists t
albums from the artists that
And so here are some brand-new
albums from the artists that I
really
really l
albums from the artists that I
really love.
Now
Now,
really love.
Now, here
Now, here is
really love.
Now, here is an
Now, here is an i
really love.
Now, here is an interesting
one
one,
Now, here is an interesting
one, a
one, a Cuban
Now, here is an interesting
one, a Cuban playlist
one, a Cuban playlist.
Now, here is an interesting
one, a Cuban playlist. You
might
might be
one, a Cuban playlist. You
might be wondering
might be wondering how
one, a Cuban playlist. You
might be wondering how did
might be wondering how did that
get
get in
might be wondering how did that
get in there?
get in there? Well
might be wondering how did that
get in there? Well,
get in there? Well, I
might be wondering how did that
get in there? Well, I like
get in there? Well, I like a
lot
lot o
get in there? Well, I like a
lot of
lot of Latin
get in there? Well, I like a
lot of Latin music
lot of Latin music,
get in there? Well, I like a
lot of Latin music, so
lot of Latin music, so Apple
Music
Music knows
lot of Latin music, so Apple
Music knows that
Music knows that and
lot of Latin music, so Apple
Music knows that and is
recommending
recommending t
Music knows that and is
recommending this
recommending this playlist
Music knows that and is
recommending this playlist to
me.
me. Let's
recommending this playlist to
me. Let's take
me. Let's take a
recommending this playlist to
me. Let's take a look
me. Let's take a look at
recommending this playlist to
me. Let's take a look at it
me. Let's take a look at it.
(Music)
Definitely
Definitely gets
(Music)
Definitely gets m
Definitely gets my
(Music)
Definitely gets my Cuban
Definitely gets my Cuban blood
going
going.
(Music)
Now,
Now, this
Now, this is
Now, this is a
Now, this is a playlist
Now, this is a playlist I
definitely
definitely want
Now, this is a playlist I
definitely want to
definitely want to keep
Now, this is a playlist I
definitely want to keep,
definitely want to keep, so
Now, this is a playlist I
definitely want to keep, so I
am
am going
definitely want to keep, so I
am going to
am going to tap
definitely want to keep, so I
am going to tap on
am going to tap on the
definitely want to keep, so I
am going to tap on the plus
sign,
sign, and
am going to tap on the plus
sign, and I've
sign, and I've added
am going to tap on the plus
sign, and I've added that
sign, and I've added that now
to
to m
sign, and I've added that now
to my
to my playlist
sign, and I've added that now
to my playlist.
Now,
Now, let's
to my playlist.
Now, let's take
Now, let's take a
to my playlist.
Now, let's take a l
Now, let's take a look
to my playlist.
Now, let's take a look at
what's
what's new
Now, let's take a look at
what's new.
what's new. You
Now, let's take a look at
what's new. You can
what's new. You can see
Now, let's take a look at
what's new. You can see new
albums
albums a
what's new. You can see new
albums across
albums across t
what's new. You can see new
albums across the
albums across the top
what's new. You can see new
albums across the top.
albums across the top. More
here,
here, and
albums across the top. More
here, and even
here, and even the
albums across the top. More
here, and even the hot
here, and even the hot sing
albums across the top. More
here, and even the hot singles
that
that are
here, and even the hot singles
that are out.
that are out. L
here, and even the hot singles
that are out. Let's
that are out. Let's play
here, and even the hot singles
that are out. Let's play t
that are out. Let's play this
one
one from
that are out. Let's play this
one from Florence
one from Florence and
that are out. Let's play this
one from Florence and the
Machine
Machine.
(Music)
I
I can
(Music)
I can k
I can keep
(Music)
I can keep scrolling
I can keep scrolling and
(Music)
I can keep scrolling and see
some
some recent
I can keep scrolling and see
some recent releases
some recent releases.
I can keep scrolling and see
some recent releases. B
some recent releases. But
I can keep scrolling and see
some recent releases. But of
course
course,
some recent releases. But of
course, everyone
course, everyone loves
some recent releases. But of
course, everyone loves t
course, everyone loves the
charts
charts,
course, everyone loves the
charts, so
charts, so let's
course, everyone loves the
charts, so let's go
charts, so let's go ahead
course, everyone loves the
charts, so let's go ahead and
take
take a
charts, so let's go ahead and
take a look
take a look at
charts, so let's go ahead and
take a look at the
take a look at the charts,
charts, so let's go ahead and
take a look at the charts, see
the
the top
take a look at the charts, see
the top s
the top songs.
take a look at the charts, see
the top songs. The
the top songs. The top
take a look at the charts, see
the top songs. The top albums.
And
And even
the top songs. The top albums.
And even t
And even the
the top songs. The top albums.
And even the top
And even the top m
the top songs. The top albums.
And even the top music
And even the top music videos.
We
We h
And even the top music videos.
We have
We have tens
And even the top music videos.
We have tens of
We have tens of thousands
And even the top music videos.
We have tens of thousands of
music
music videos
We have tens of thousands of
music videos in
music videos in H
We have tens of thousands of
music videos in HD,
music videos in HD, all
We have tens of thousands of
music videos in HD, all ad
music videos in HD, all ad free
We have tens of thousands of
music videos in HD, all ad f
free.
Let's
Let's take
free.
Let's take a
Let's take a look
free.
Let's take a look at
Let's take a look at this
free.
Let's take a look at this one
from
from Mark
Let's take a look at this one
from Mark R
from Mark Ronson.
(Music)
I've
I've got
I've got to
I've got to work
I've got to work on
I've got to work on some
I've got to work on some of
those
those moves
I've got to work on some of
those moves for
those moves for next
I've got to work on some of
those moves for next year.
(Laughter)
Now,
Now, sometimes
(Laughter)
Now, sometimes you
Now, sometimes you just
(Laughter)
Now, sometimes you just want
to
to sit
Now, sometimes you just want
to sit back
to sit back and
Now, sometimes you just want
to sit back and let
to sit back and let someone
else
else b
to sit back and let someone
else be
else be your
to sit back and let someone
else be your DJ,
else be your DJ, s
to sit back and let someone
else be your DJ, so
else be your DJ, so let's
to sit back and let someone
else be your DJ, so let's go
else be your DJ, so let's go to
Radio.
Radio. And
else be your DJ, so let's go to
Radio. And t
Radio. And to
else be your DJ, so let's go to
Radio. And to give
Radio. And to give you
else be your DJ, so let's go to
Radio. And to give you a
little
little taste
Radio. And to give you a
little taste of
little taste of what
Radio. And to give you a
little taste of what Beats
little taste of what Beats 1
Radio. And to give you a
little taste of what Beats 1 is
going
going to
little taste of what Beats 1 is
going to sound
going to sound l
little taste of what Beats 1 is
going to sound like
going to sound like ...
>>
>> Beats
>> Beats 1.
>> Beats 1. Welcome
>> Beats 1. Welcome our
special
special guest,
>> Beats 1. Welcome our
special guest, Florence
special guest, Florence from
>> Beats 1. Welcome our
Florence
special guest, Florence from
Florence and
Florence and the
special guest, Florence from
Florence and the Machine.
>>
>> On
Florence and the Machine.
>> On paper,
>> On paper, it
Florence and the Machine.
>> On paper, it sounds
>> On paper, it sounds like
super,
super, not
>> On paper, it sounds like
super, not how
super, not how you
>> On paper, it sounds like
super, not how you think
super, not how you think a
>> On paper, it sounds like
super, not how you think a rock
and
and roll
super, not how you think a rock
and roll album
and roll album would
super, not how you think a rock
and roll album would be
and roll album would be made
super, not how you think a rock
and roll album would be made.
>>
>> Was
and roll album would be made.
>> Was that
>> Was that you
and roll album would be made.
>> Was that you in
>> Was that you in your
and roll album would be made.
>> Was that you in your sw
sweatpants?
>>
>> That
sweatpants?
>> That was
>> That was me
sweatpants?
>> That was me cycling
>> That was me cycling to
sweatpants?
>> That was me cycling to the
studio.
>>
>> We
studio.
>> We are
>> We are looking
studio.
>> We are looking for
>> We are looking for the
studio.
>> We are looking for the most
exciting
exciting music
>> We are looking for the most
exciting music and
exciting music and people
>> We are looking for the most
exciting music and people that
love
love it
exciting music and people that
love it in
love it in all
exciting music and people that
love it in all corners
love it in all corners of
exciting music and people that
love it in all corners of the
globe
globe,
love it in all corners of the
globe, broadcasting
globe, broadcasting to
love it in all corners of the
globe, broadcasting to 1
globe, broadcasting to 100
countries
countries.
globe, broadcasting to 100
countries. That
countries. That shared
experience
experience just
countries. That shared
experience just got
experience just got so
countries. That shared
experience just got so much
better
better.
>>
>> LA.
>> New
>> New York
>> LA.
>> New York City.
>>
>> London.
>> EDDY
>> EDDY CUE:
>> London.
>> EDDY CUE: That's
>> EDDY CUE: That's really
awesome
awesome.
>> EDDY CUE: That's really
awesome. Let's
awesome. Let's take
>> EDDY CUE: That's really
awesome. Let's take a
awesome. Let's take a look
>> EDDY CUE: That's really
awesome. Let's take a look at
Connect
Connect and
awesome. Let's take a look at
Connect and see
Connect and see what
awesome. Let's take a look at
Connect and see what my
favorite
favorite art
Connect and see what my
favorite artis
favorite artists
Connect and see what my
favorite artists are
favorite artists are up
Connect and see what my
favorite artists are up to.
Here
Here's
favorite artists are up to.
Here's Pharrell
Here's Pharrell and
favorite artists are up to.
Here's Pharrell and some
behind-the
behind-the-s
Here's Pharrell and some
behind-the-scenes
behind-the-scenes footage
Here's Pharrell and some
behind-the-scenes footage.
Here
Here is
behind-the-scenes footage.
Here is Chris
Here is Chris Cornell
behind-the-scenes footage.
Here is Chris Cornell.
Here is Chris Cornell. This
behind-the-scenes footage.
Here is Chris Cornell. This is
an
an interesting
Here is Chris Cornell. This is
an interesting o
an interesting one.
Here is Chris Cornell. This is
an interesting one. He
an interesting one. He has
posted
posted lyrics
an interesting one. He has
posted lyrics of
posted lyrics of a
an interesting one. He has
posted lyrics of a new
posted lyrics of a new song
that's
that's coming
posted lyrics of a new song
that's coming out
that's coming out before
posted lyrics of a new song
that's coming out before,
obviously
obviously,
that's coming out before,
obviously, he's
obviously, he's even
that's coming out before,
obviously, he's even recorded
it
it.
Here's
Here's Bastille.
it.
Here's Bastille. They
Here's Bastille. They are
working
working on
Here's Bastille. They are
working on their
working on their n
Here's Bastille. They are
working on their next
working on their next album
Here's Bastille. They are
working on their next album.
Let's
Let's see
working on their next album.
Let's see what
Let's see what they
working on their next album.
Let's see what they have
Let's see what they have to
working on their next album.
Let's see what they have to say
Let's see what they have to s
say.
>>
>> Mark
say.
>> Mark is
>> Mark is just
say.
>> Mark is just through
>> Mark is just through here,
and
and we
>> Mark is just through here,
and we are
and we are working
>> Mark is just through here,
and we are working on
and we are working on a
>> Mark is just through here,
and we are working on a song
called
called Blame
and we are working on a song
called Blame,
called Blame, which
and we are working on a song
called Blame, which some
called Blame, which some of
and we are working on a song
called Blame, which some of you
might
might have
called Blame, which some of you
might have heard
might have heard at
called Blame, which some of you
might have heard at festivals
or
or gig
might have heard at festivals
or gigs
or gigs before
might have heard at festivals
or gigs before,
or gigs before, but
might have heard at festivals
or gigs before, but we're
really
really excited
or gigs before, but we're
really excited to
really excited to have
or gigs before, but we're
really excited to have finally
recorded
recorded it
really excited to have finally
recorded it.
recorded it. It's
really excited to have finally
recorded it. It's a
recorded it. It's a song
really excited to have finally
recorded it. It's a song about
gangsters
gangsters.
recorded it. It's a song about
gangsters. And
gangsters. And yeah,
recorded it. It's a song about
gangsters. And yeah, this
gangsters. And yeah, this is
the
the riff
gangsters. And yeah, this is
the riff,
the riff, which
gangsters. And yeah, this is
the riff, which w
the riff, which we
gangsters. And yeah, this is
the riff, which we already
the riff, which we already have
sounding
sounding g
the riff, which we already have
sounding great
sounding great.
(Music)
>>
>> EDDY
>> EDDY CUE:
>> EDDY CUE: It's
>> EDDY CUE: It's great
>> EDDY CUE: It's great to
>> EDDY CUE: It's great to be
able
able to
>> EDDY CUE: It's great to be
able to get
able to get behind
>> EDDY CUE: It's great to be
able to get behind the
able to get behind the scenes
and
and see
able to get behind the scenes
and see what
and see what the
able to get behind the scenes
and see what the process
and see what the process that
an
an art
and see what the process that
an artist
an artist uses
and see what the process that
an artist uses t
an artist uses to
and see what the process that
an artist uses to create
an artist uses to create a
song.
As
As we
song.
As we k
As we keep
song.
As we keep going
As we keep going down,
song.
As we keep going down, here's
a
a shot
As we keep going down, here's
a shot from
a shot from A
As we keep going down, here's
a shot from Alabama
a shot from Alabama Shakes
As we keep going down, here's
a shot from Alabama Shakes a
couple
couple nights
a shot from Alabama Shakes a
couple nights ago.
And
And here
couple nights ago.
And here is
And here is a
couple nights ago.
And here is a studio
And here is a studio session,
actually,
actually, at
And here is a studio session,
actually, at Capital
actually, at Capital S
And here is a studio session,
actually, at Capital Studio
actually, at Capital Studio A
And here is a studio session,
actually, at Capital Studio A.
Those
Those o
actually, at Capital Studio A.
Those of
Those of you
actually, at Capital Studio A.
Those of you who
Those of you who know
actually, at Capital Studio A.
Those of you who know,
Those of you who know, C
actually, at Capital Studio A.
Those of you who know, Capitol
Studio
Studio i
Those of you who know, Capitol
Studio is
Studio is one
Those of you who know, Capitol
Studio is one of
Studio is one of the
Those of you who know, Capitol
Studio is one of the premier
studios
studios,
Studio is one of the premier
studios, historic
studios, historical,
Studio is one of the premier
studios, historical, and
Alabama
Alabama Shakes
studios, historical, and
Alabama Shakes was
Alabama Shakes was just
studios, historical, and
Alabama Shakes was just there
Alabama Shakes was just there a
couple
couple nights
Alabama Shakes was just there a
couple nights ago.
(Music)
>>
>> EDDY
>> EDDY CUE:
>> EDDY CUE: Again
>> EDDY CUE: Again,
>> EDDY CUE: Again, be
>> EDDY CUE: Again, be able
>> EDDY CUE: Again, be able to
see
see things
>> EDDY CUE: Again, be able to
see things you've
see things you've never
>> EDDY CUE: Again, be able to
see things you've never been
able
able to
see things you've never been
able to hear
able to hear or
see things you've never been
able to hear or see
able to hear or see.
Loren
Loren Kramar,
able to hear or see.
Loren Kramar, you
Loren Kramar, you probably
have
have never
Loren Kramar, you probably
have never heard
have never heard of
Loren Kramar, you probably
have never heard of him.
have never heard of him. He
Loren Kramar, you probably
have never heard of him. He is
an
an unsigned
have never heard of him. He is
an unsigned artist,
an unsigned artist, I
have never heard of him. He is
an unsigned artist, I just
started
started following
an unsigned artist, I just
started following him.
started following him. He
an unsigned artist, I just
started following him. He has
posted
posted a
started following him. He has
posted a new
posted a new song
started following him. He has
posted a new song right
posted a new song right u
started following him. He has
posted a new song right up
posted a new song right up on
Connect,
Connect, I
posted a new song right up on
Connect, I would
Connect, I would like
posted a new song right up on
Connect, I would like to
Connect, I would like to play
it
it now.
Connect, I would like to play
it now. First
it now. First time
Connect, I would like to play
it now. First time anyone's
heard
heard it
it now. First time anyone's
heard it.
(Music)
Just
Just imagine
Just imagine you
Just imagine you are
Just imagine you are a
Just imagine you are a new
Just imagine you are a new a
artist,
artist, and
Just imagine you are a new a
artist, and look
artist, and look at
Just imagine you are a new a
artist, and look at all
artist, and look at all the
people
people who
artist, and look at all the
people who have
people who have been
artist, and look at all the
people who have been able
people who have been able to
hear
hear this
people who have been able to
hear this song
hear this song right
people who have been able to
hear this song right now
hear this song right now thanks
to
to Connect
hear this song right now thanks
to Connect.
(Music)
So
So Loren
(Music)
So Loren Kramar.
So Loren Kramar. Remember
(Music)
So Loren Kramar. Remember that
name.
name. We
So Loren Kramar. Remember that
name. We think
name. We think he
So Loren Kramar. Remember that
name. We think he is
name. We think he is going
So Loren Kramar. Remember that
name. We think he is going to
be
be really
name. We think he is going to
be really,
be really, really
name. We think he is going to
be really, really huge.
Now,
Now, of
be really, really huge.
Now, of c
Now, of course,
be really, really huge.
Now, of course, you
Now, of course, you can
be really, really huge.
Now, of course, you can always
search
search for
Now, of course, you can always
search for music
search for music a
Now, of course, you can always
search for music across
search for music across all
Now, of course, you can always
search for music across all o
search for music across all of
our
our m
search for music across all of
our millions
our millions and
search for music across all of
our millions and millions
our millions and millions of
songs.
songs. I
our millions and millions of
songs. I like
songs. I like to
our millions and millions of
songs. I like to do
songs. I like to do a
our millions and millions of
songs. I like to do a little
bit
bit of
songs. I like to do a little
bit of stuff
bit of stuff with
songs. I like to do a little
bit of stuff with Siri
bit of stuff with Siri because
Siri
Siri h
bit of stuff with Siri because
Siri has
Siri has been
bit of stuff with Siri because
Siri has been learning
Siri has been learning a
bit of stuff with Siri because
Siri has been learning a lot
more
more about
Siri has been learning a lot
more about m
more about music
Siri has been learning a lot
more about music.
Play
Play born
more about music.
Play born t
Play born to
more about music.
Play born to r
Play born to run
more about music.
Play born to run.
(Music)
It's
It's one
(Music)
It's one of
It's one of my
(Music)
It's one of my favorite
It's one of my favorite songs
of
of all
It's one of my favorite songs
of all time.
of all time. Let's
It's one of my favorite songs
of all time. Let's get
of all time. Let's get a
little
little more
of all time. Let's get a
little more specif
little more specific
of all time. Let's get a
little more specific.
Play
Play t
little more specific.
Play the
Play the top
little more specific.
Play the top ten
Play the top ten songs
little more specific.
Play the top ten songs i
Play the top ten songs in
little more specific.
alternative
Play the top ten songs in
alternative.
(Music)
If
If I
(Music)
If I tap
If I tap on
(Music)
If I tap on the
If I tap on the next
(Music)
If I tap on the next view,
If I tap on the next view, I
can
can see
If I tap on the next view, I
can see all
can see all of
If I tap on the next view, I
can see all of the
can see all of the t
If I tap on the next view, I
can see all of the top
can see all of the top ten
songs
songs and
can see all of the top ten
songs and what's
songs and what's next
can see all of the top ten
songs and what's next.
Now,
Now, I
songs and what's next.
Now, I feel
Now, I feel l
songs and what's next.
Now, I feel like
Now, I feel like reminiscing
songs and what's next.
Now, I feel like reminiscing a
little,
little, and
Now, I feel like reminiscing a
little, and let's
little, and let's go
Now, I feel like reminiscing a
little, and let's go back
little, and let's go back to
Now, I feel like reminiscing a
little, and let's go back to my
high
high school
little, and let's go back to my
high school days
high school days when
little, and let's go back to my
high school days when I
graduate
graduated
high school days when I
graduated.
graduated. Play
high school days when I
graduated. Play t
graduated. Play the
high school days when I
graduated. Play the t
graduated. Play the top
high school days when I
graduated. Play the top song
from
from M
graduated. Play the top song
from May
from May 198
graduated. Play the top song
from May 1982
from May 1982.
graduated. Play the top song
(Music)
(Cheers
(Cheers and
(Music)
(Cheers and applause)
Now,
Now, that
Now, that brings
Now, that brings back
Now, that brings back some
memory
memories,
Now, that brings back some
memories, but
memories, but we
Now, that brings back some
memories, but we will
memories, but we will leave
that
that for
memories, but we will leave
that for another
that for another time
memories, but we will leave
that for another time.
Have
Have you
that for another time.
Have you ev
Have you ever
that for another time.
Have you ever gone
Have you ever gone to
that for another time.
Have you ever gone to a
Have you ever gone to a movie
and
and you
Have you ever gone to a movie
and you love
and you love the
Have you ever gone to a movie
and you love the sound
and you love the sound track
Have you ever gone to a movie
and you love the sound track or
the
the song
and you love the sound track or
the song that
the song that was
and you love the sound track or
the song that was on
the song that was on there,
and you love the sound track or
the song that was on there, but
you
you don't
the song that was on there, but
you don't know
you don't know the
the song that was on there, but
you don't know the name
you don't know the name or
the song that was on there, but
you don't know the name or you
have
have forgotten
you don't know the name or you
have forgotten about
have forgotten about it
you don't know the name or you
have forgotten about it later?
Well,
Well, it's
have forgotten about it later?
Well, it's really
Well, it's really easy
have forgotten about it later?
Well, it's really easy with
Siri
Siri.
Play
Play t
Siri.
Play the
Play the song
Siri.
Play the song from
Play the song from Selma.
(Music)
Let's
Let's do
Let's do that
Let's do that again
Let's do that again.
Play
Play the
Let's do that again.
Play the song
Play the song from
Let's do that again.
Play the song from Selma
Play the song from Selma.
(Music)
And
And that
And that is
And that is Siri
And that is Siri,
And that is Siri, and
And that is Siri, and that
And that is Siri, and that is
Apple
Apple Music
And that is Siri, and that is
Apple Music.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
Apple Music.
(Cheers and applause)
It
It is
(Cheers and applause)
It is a
It is a revolutionary
(Cheers and applause)
It is a revolutionary music
service
service with
It is a revolutionary music
service with recommendations
just
just for
service with recommendations
just for you,
just for you, a
service with recommendations
just for you, a worldwide
just for you, a worldwide live
radio
radio station
just for you, a worldwide live
radio station with
radio station with the
just for you, a worldwide live
radio station with the world'S
best
best DJs
radio station with the world'S
best DJs,
best DJs, an
radio station with the world'S
best DJs, an exciting
best DJs, an exciting way
radio station with the world'S
best DJs, an exciting way for
fans
fans to
best DJs, an exciting way for
fans to connect
fans to connect with
best DJs, an exciting way for
fans to connect with artists
fans to connect with artists,
and
and of
fans to connect with artists,
and of course,
and of course, this
fans to connect with artists,
and of course, this is
and of course, this is joined
by
by the
and of course, this is joined
by the i
by the iTunes
and of course, this is joined
by the iTunes Musicstore,
by the iTunes Musicstore, the
best
best p
by the iTunes Musicstore, the
best play
best play to
by the iTunes Musicstore, the
best play to buy
best play to buy music
by the iTunes Musicstore, the
best play to buy music.
best play to buy music. A
by the iTunes Musicstore, the
best play to buy music. Apple
Music
Music is
best play to buy music. Apple
Music is al
Music is all
best play to buy music. Apple
Music is all of
Music is all of the
best play to buy music. Apple
Music is all of the w
Music is all of the ways
best play to buy music. Apple
Music is all of the ways you
love
love music
Music is all of the ways you
love music a
love music all
Music is all of the ways you
love music all in
love music all in one
Music is all of the ways you
love music all in one place.
We
We are
love music all in one place.
We are launching
We are launching in
love music all in one place.
We are launching in over
We are launching in over a
hundred
hundred c
We are launching in over a
hundred countries
hundred countries l
We are launching in over a
hundred countries late
hundred countries later
We are launching in over a
hundred countries later this
month
month with
hundred countries later this
month with iOS
month with iOS 8
hundred countries later this
month with iOS 8.4
month with iOS 8.4 for
hundred countries later this
month with iOS 8.4 for your
iPhone
iPhone,
month with iOS 8.4 for your
iPhone, i
iPhone, iPOD
month with iOS 8.4 for your
iPhone, iPOD touch
iPhone, iPOD touch a
month with iOS 8.4 for your
iPhone, iPOD touch and
iPhone, iPOD touch and iPad,
month with iOS 8.4 for your
iPhone, iPOD touch and iPad, as
well
well as
iPhone, iPOD touch and iPad, as
well as a
well as a new
iPhone, iPOD touch and iPad, as
well as a new version
well as a new version of
iPhone, iPOD touch and iPad, as
well as a new version of iTunes
for
for the
well as a new version of iTunes
for the Mac,
for the Mac, a
well as a new version of iTunes
for the Mac, a new
for the Mac, a new version
well as a new version of iTunes
for the Mac, a new version of
iTunes
iTunes f
for the Mac, a new version of
iTunes for
iTunes for Windows
for the Mac, a new version of
iTunes for Windows,
iTunes for Windows, and
for the Mac, a new version of
iTunes for Windows, and Android
is
is coming
iTunes for Windows, and Android
is coming this
is coming this fall.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
is coming this fall.
(Cheers and applause)
Apple
Apple M
(Cheers and applause)
Apple Music
Apple Music will
(Cheers and applause)
Apple Music will be
Apple Music will be j
(Cheers and applause)
Apple Music will be just
Apple Music will be just 9.9
(Cheers and applause)
Apple Music will be just 9.99
a
a month,
Apple Music will be just 9.99
a month, the
a month, the c
Apple Music will be just 9.99
a month, the cost
a month, the cost of
Apple Music will be just 9.99
a month, the cost of an
a month, the cost of an a
Apple Music will be just 9.99
a month, the cost of an album.
We
We want
a month, the cost of an album.
We want everyone
We want everyone to
a month, the cost of an album.
We want everyone to try
We want everyone to try it,
a month, the cost of an album.
We want everyone to try it, so
we
we are
We want everyone to try it, so
we are making
we are making the
We want everyone to try it, so
we are making the first
we are making the first three
months
months free
we are making the first three
months free.
(Applause)
Now
Now,
(Applause)
Now, we
Now, we w
(Applause)
Now, we want
Now, we want to
(Applause)
Now, we want to do
Now, we want to do something
really
really great
Now, we want to do something
really great for
really great for families
Now, we want to do something
really great for families.
Today
Today you
really great for families.
Today you have
Today you have to
really great for families.
Today you have to buy
Today you have to buy a
really great for families.
Today you have to buy a music
subscription
subscription for
Today you have to buy a music
subscription for each
subscription for each and
Today you have to buy a music
subscription for each and e
subscription for each and every
person.
person. Or
subscription for each and every
person. Or you
person. Or you share
subscription for each and every
person. Or you share an
account
account even
person. Or you share an
account even though
account even though you
person. Or you share an
account even though you are
account even though you are not
suppose
supposed
account even though you are not
supposed to.
supposed to. And
account even though you are not
supposed to. And now
supposed to. And now all
account even though you are not
supposed to. And now all of
you
you can't
supposed to. And now all of
you can't play
you can't play at
supposed to. And now all of
you can't play at the
you can't play at the same
time,
time, and
you can't play at the same
time, and your
time, and your playlist
you can't play at the same
time, and your playlist and
recommendation
recommendations
time, and your playlist and
recommendations get
recommendations get all
time, and your playlist and
recommendations get all messed
up
up.
Well,
Well, with
up.
Well, with Apple
Well, with Apple music
up.
Well, with Apple music Music
Well, with Apple music Music,
for
for j
Well, with Apple music Music,
for just
for just $14
Well, with Apple music Music,
for just $14.9
for just $14.99
Well, with Apple music Music,
for just $14.99,
for just $14.99, you
Well, with Apple music Music,
for just $14.99, you can
for just $14.99, you can have
up
up to
for just $14.99, you can have
up to six
up to six family
for just $14.99, you can have
up to six family members
up to six family members.
for just $14.99, you can have
(Applause)
Everyone
Everyone gets
(Applause)
Everyone gets their
Everyone gets their own
account,
account, their
Everyone gets their own
account, their own
account, their own library
Everyone gets their own
account, their own library,
their
their own
account, their own library,
their own recommendations
their own recommendations.
It's
It's an
their own recommendations.
It's an incredible
It's an incredible v
their own recommendations.
It's an incredible value.
And
And that
It's an incredible value.
And that is
And that is Apple
It's an incredible value.
And that is Apple Music.
Thank
Thank you
And that is Apple Music.
Thank you.
Thank you. T
And that is Apple Music.
Thank you. Turn
Thank you. Turn it
And that is Apple Music.
Thank you. Turn it b
Thank you. Turn it back
And that is Apple Music.
Thank you. Turn it back to
Thank you. Turn it back to Tim
And that is Apple Music.
Thank you. Turn it back to T
Tim.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
Tim.
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> TIM
>> TIM COOK:
>> TIM COOK: Thanks,
>> TIM COOK: Thanks, Eddy.
Isn't
Isn't that
>> TIM COOK: Thanks, Eddy.
Isn't that amazing
Isn't that amazing?
We
We really
Isn't that amazing?
We really lo
We really love
Isn't that amazing?
We really love A
We really love Apple
Isn't that amazing?
We really love Apple Music
We really love Apple Music,
and
and we
We really love Apple Music,
and we hope
and we hope that
We really love Apple Music,
and we hope that you
and we hope that you do
We really love Apple Music,
and we hope that you do too.
And
And we
and we hope that you do too.
And we are
And we are so
and we hope that you do too.
And we are so excited
And we are so excited about
and we hope that you do too.
And we are so excited about it,
and
and with
And we are so excited about it,
and with all
and with all the
And we are so excited about it,
and with all the c
and with all the countries
And we are so excited about it,
and with all the countries we
are
are rolling
and with all the countries we
are rolling out
are rolling out to,
and with all the countries we
are rolling out to, w
are rolling out to, we
and with all the countries we
are rolling out to, we made
are rolling out to, we made a
great
great ad
are rolling out to, we made a
great ad to
great ad to tell
are rolling out to, we made a
great ad to tell t
great ad to tell the
are rolling out to, we made a
great ad to tell the world
about
about it.
great ad to tell the world
about it. And
about it. And I'd
great ad to tell the world
about it. And I'd love
about it. And I'd love to
great ad to tell the world
about it. And I'd love to run
it
it f
about it. And I'd love to run
it for
it for you
about it. And I'd love to run
it for you now
it for you now.
about it. And I'd love to run
>>
>> This
>> This is
>> This is Zane
>> This is Zane Lowe
>> This is Zane Lowe of
>> This is Zane Lowe of beats
1.
1. We've
>> This is Zane Lowe of beats
1. We've got
1. We've got the
>> This is Zane Lowe of beats
1. We've got the w
1. We've got the whole
>> This is Zane Lowe of beats
1. We've got the whole world
locked
locked in
1. We've got the whole world
locked in for
locked in for this
1. We've got the whole world
locked in for this one
locked in for this one.
1. We've got the whole world
locked in for this one. Brand
locked in for this one. Br
Brand-new
Brand-new Pharrell
locked in for this one. Br
Brand-new Pharrell.
(Music)
(Cheers
(Cheers and
(Cheers and applause)
Now,
Now, music
(Cheers and applause)
Now, music connects
Now, music connects with
(Cheers and applause)
Now, music connects with us
all
all at
Now, music connects with us
all at such
all at such a
Now, music connects with us
all at such a deep
all at such a deep,
Now, music connects with us
all at such a deep, emotion
all at such a deep, emotional
level.
level. We
all at such a deep, emotional
level. We couldn't
level. We couldn't be
all at such a deep, emotional
level. We couldn't be happier
to
to launch
level. We couldn't be happier
to launch Apple
to launch Apple Music
level. We couldn't be happier
to launch Apple Music,
to launch Apple Music, and
level. We couldn't be happier
to launch Apple Music, and we
can't
can't wait
to launch Apple Music, and we
can't wait till
can't wait till you
to launch Apple Music, and we
can't wait till you start
listening
listening to
can't wait till you start
listening to it
listening to it at
can't wait till you start
listening to it at the
listening to it at the end
can't wait till you start
listening to it at the end of
the
the month.
This
This has
the month.
This has been
This has been a
the month.
This has been a jam
This has been a jam-packed
morning
morning.
This has been a jam-packed
morning. I
morning. I hope
This has been a jam-packed
morning. I hope you've
morning. I hope you've enjoy
This has been a jam-packed
morning. I hope you've enjoyed
it
it as
morning. I hope you've enjoyed
it as much
it as much as
morning. I hope you've enjoyed
it as much as we
it as much as we have.
morning. I hope you've enjoyed
it as much as we have. We
it as much as we have. We want
to
to thank
it as much as we have. We want
to thank everybody
to thank everybody for
it as much as we have. We want
to thank everybody for joining
us
us,
to thank everybody for joining
us, especially
us, especially the
to thank everybody for joining
us, especially the develop
us, especially the developers,
and
and I'd
us, especially the developers,
and I'd like
and I'd like to
us, especially the developers,
and I'd like to recognize
and I'd like to recognize all
of
of the
and I'd like to recognize all
of the people
of the people in
and I'd like to recognize all
of the people in Apple,
of the people in Apple, all
and I'd like to recognize all
of the people in Apple, all of
our
our team
of the people in Apple, all of
our team that
our team that have
of the people in Apple, all of
our team that have worked
our team that have worked so
hard
hard on
our team that have worked so
hard on making
hard on making and
our team that have worked so
hard on making and creating
hard on making and creating all
of
of these
hard on making and creating all
of these products
of these products you've
hard on making and creating all
of these products you've seen
this
this morning
of these products you've seen
this morning.
this morning. Thank
of these products you've seen
this morning. Thank you,
this morning. Thank you, guys.
(Applause)
It
It is
(Applause)
It is an
It is an incredible
(Applause)
It is an incredible privilege
of
of a
It is an incredible privilege
of a life
of a lifetime
It is an incredible privilege
of a lifetime to
of a lifetime to work
It is an incredible privilege
of a lifetime to work with
them.
Now,
Now, I've
them.
Now, I've got
Now, I've got one
them.
Now, I've got one last
Now, I've got one last thing.
Before
Before we
Now, I've got one last thing.
Before we go,
Before we go, it's
Now, I've got one last thing.
Before we go, it's only
Before we go, it's only fitting
to
to celebrate
Before we go, it's only fitting
to celebrate the
to celebrate the launch
Before we go, it's only fitting
to celebrate the launch of
Apple
Apple Music
to celebrate the launch of
Apple Music with
Apple Music with an
to celebrate the launch of
Apple Music with an incredible
music
music performance
Apple Music with an incredible
music performance by
music performance by one
Apple Music with an incredible
music performance by one of
music performance by one of the
hottest
hottest new
music performance by one of the
hottest new artists
hottest new artists in
music performance by one of the
hottest new artists in music
today,
today, and
hottest new artists in music
today, and it's
today, and it's not
hottest new artists in music
today, and it's not only
today, and it's not only a
hottest new artists in music
today, and it's not only a hot
new
new artist,
today, and it's not only a hot
new artist, but
new artist, but he's
today, and it's not only a hot
new artist, but he's going
new artist, but he's going to
do
do a
new artist, but he's going to
do a worldwide
do a worldwide premiere
new artist, but he's going to
do a worldwide premiere of
do a worldwide premiere of his
new
newest
do a worldwide premiere of his
newest song
newest song this
do a worldwide premiere of his
newest song this morning
newest song this morning.
Please
Please give
newest song this morning.
Please give it
Please give it up
newest song this morning.
Please give it up for
Please give it up for The
Weeknd
Weeknd.
(Cheers
(Cheers and
Weeknd.
(Cheers and applause)
(Music)
(Cheers
(Cheers and
(Cheers and applause)
>>
>> TIM
(Cheers and applause)
>> TIM COOK:
>> TIM COOK: Ladies
(Cheers and applause)
>> TIM COOK: Ladies and
gentlemen,
gentlemen, The
>> TIM COOK: Ladies and
gentlemen, The Weeknd
gentlemen, The Weeknd!
>> TIM COOK: Ladies and
gentlemen, The Weeknd! (Cheers
and
and applause)
Everybody
Everybody have
Everybody have a
Everybody have a great
Everybody have a great week!
It's
It's great
Everybody have a great week!
It's great to
It's great to be
Everybody have a great week!
It's great to be together
It's great to be together!
(Cheers
(Cheers and
It's great to be together!
(Cheers and applause)