[ Silence ]
>> Good morning.
My name is Gregory Hughes and
I'm the engineering manager
for accessibility on OS X.
I'm really excited to be able
to have the opportunity to speak
to you this morning about some
of the great new accessibility
features in OS X Mavericks.
Here at Apple, we care very
deeply about accessibility
and we work really
hard to deliver a lot
of great accessibility features.
We work on all sorts of
products, like VoiceOver
and closed captioning,
Zoom and Guided Access.
And if I were to
summarize what our does,
I would say that we solve
problems and remove barriers
for users with disabilities.
The two big problems
that we look
at everyday are how can we
deliver an outstanding operating
system that's fully usable
by all users regardless
of their abilities
or disabilities?
The second problem we look
at is how can we provide you,
the developers, with outstanding
API and developer support
to help you do the same thing,
to help you deliver applications
that are accessible and
usable by everybody?
So to start off, I want to
talk that first problem.
What features do we deliver as
part of the operating system
to help users with disabilities,
because you're maybe aware one
of the flagship products
is called VoiceOver.
VoiceOver is a screen
reader which is a piece
of software designed
for users who are blind.
A screen reader converts all
the graphical user inter--
graphical user information--
sorry, screen reader converts
the graphical user interface
into a spoken interface so
that somebody who's blind can
navigate OS X and get
all the same information
that you would get, sighted,
looking at the screen.
VoiceOver also has
the capability
of outputting to Braille.
And now, this is
really important,
both of these features
within VoiceOver.
Because what this means
is someone who is blind
and deaf can use
all of the features
and all the functionality of
OS X to its fullest potential.
And because VoiceOver ships
with the operating system,
this means that the computer's
operable right out of the box
for this class of users.
Now, VoiceOver shipping as part
of the OS also has a
really significant impact
across the board.
Now, gone are the days where
student who's blind has to work
in a separate room, work
on a separate computer
with assistive technology,
because VoiceOver ships standard
with OS X, a blind student
can use the same computer
as everybody else.
They just need to
turn on VoiceOver.
The same is true
in the workplace.
Corporations no longer need to
buy expensive assistive pieces
of technology and colleagues
no longer have difficulty
collaborating because
VoiceOver is standard in OS X.
Furthermore, because
VoiceOver is standard in OS X,
you have a world class
screen reader built right
in to help test your
applications.
So, it's incredibly powerful
and incredibly enabling
for both users with
disabilities and developers
who are developing to help
these users with disabilities.
So that's a brief
introduction about VoiceOver.
We also look at a lot
of other disabilities.
We work really hard across
the board to deliver closed--
an outstanding closed
captioned experience.
There are really great
closed captions in iTunes,
on iOS and even the
iPod Classic.
So whenever you open
up your media
that has closed caption content,
you can enable a closed caption
track right on the device.
But we've gone above and
beyond that in OS X Mavericks.
We're happy to introduce some
great new closed caption support
for users who are deaf.
In the Accessibility
Preference pane,
you'll now notice
the Captioning tab.
One feature that I'd like
to draw your attention
to is this checkbox
here that says
"prefer closed captioning
in SDH."
If you're unaware, SDH
stands for "Subtitles
for the deaf and
hard-of-hearing".
What this checkbox does is it
provides a single global place
for user who's deaf to
basically tell the OS
that they want captions
whenever possible.
Now, under the hood, it's
actually pretty complex.
In every application
across the system,
whenever media is played,
we're going to look
and find the best
caption track we can.
We're going to cascade
through some complex rules,
try to find a closed captioning
track, try to find the subtitles
for deaf and hard-of-heard
track, and leaving cascade
down to just a regular
subtitle track based
on the system locale.
So, this is really,
really helpful
because now a user doesn't
have to dig through settings
in each application
to try to find how
to enable closed captioning.
They don't have to dig
through a track list of 10
to 15 text tracks to figure
out which one is best for them.
Users now just have to check
one checkbox and we're going
to do all the work
under the hood.
Users can still override
our choice if they want to.
But we found that generally
that's not necessary.
As you'll notice here too,
we have closed captions
with captioning styles.
By default, we're going to ship
the system with three styles
that our [inaudible]
team has designed
and they look really great.
We have the default
style, the classic style
and the large text style.
So just like that checkbox,
these are going to apply
across the system to all the
applications that adopt this API
that are displaying captioning.
So now, it's really
simple to create--
to select the style
that suits your needs.
You're sitting across
the room from your iMac,
it might be easier to
use large text style.
If you're watching a movie on
an airplane on your laptop,
you might prefer default style.
And, for users with needs to
aren't suited by these styles,
with-- for users with needs
that aren't met by these styles,
rather, you can create
your own style.
And this is really
great, for example,
for a user with a vision
impairment that prefers a font
that has all capital letters.
You can also customize
the color, the opacity,
and really create a great closed
caption experience regardless
of your needs.
And as I said, this is
where it all applies
across the system whether you're
in iTunes, in QuickTime and even
on appropriately tagged
webpages, so really,
really powerful and really
enabling for these users.
Now, we're not going to have
time today to go into the nuts
and bolts specifically
of closed captioning.
There's a whole talk
tomorrow on preparing
and presenting media
for accessibility.
They're going to talk
a lot about the APIs
and preparing media to be
displayed in your application.
So if you have an
application that displays a lot
of video content, I
strongly encourage you
to attend this talk
tomorrow morning at 10:15.
Or otherwise, the video,
just like all videos
will be available.
So the last topic that I
want to talk about are users
with mobility impairments.
So, we've delivered a lot of
really great features for users
with mobility impairments.
We have things like Sticky Keys
and Slow Keys which help user
that have difficulty typing.
We have Mouse Keys
which help users
who don't have the physical
dexterity to use a mouse.
And in OS X Mavericks,
we're really happy
to introduce a great
new feature for users
with severely limited mobility.
This class of users
that we're talking
about quite literally
only have the capability
to operate a single button.
In some cases, this maybe a
button mounted on the side
of a wheelchair that these
will activate with their head.
It could be also called
"sip-and-puff straw"
that these will activate
by blowing air into
or sucking air out of a straw.
Some buttons even
manifests themselves
as a small sensor
they might place
in their cheek that's activated
by clinching their jaw.
But in all of these cases,
the common denominator is
that the user has
some physical mobility
to operate a single button.
And we thought about this
problem and the more we thought
about it, the more we realized,
this is a really hard problem.
How do we take all
of the power of OS X
and fit it in one button?
How do you use an
entire operating system,
all the functionality and
features with just one button?
And the problem really boils
down to the standard
user interface,
the standard input
available to a user.
The average user has a
keyboard with 78 keys,
a Trackpad with two
dimensions of movement.
It also has acceleration
between one and five buttons
and scrolling capabilities.
The case with the Trackpad, you
also have Multi-Touch gestures.
How do you take all of this
input and fit it in one button.
All right, it's not
an easy task.
So after much deliberation and
much kind of intense iteration
on how to fit all of the
functionality of OS X
into a single button,
we're really happy
to introduce Switch
software for OS X.
What does this software
does, it enables a user
who can only operate one button
to use all the functionality
in OS X.
When you turn on Switch Control,
it appears there's a small menu
on the top right of your screen.
This menu here that you see
is what we call the Home Menu.
And now, with only one button,
you don't have the option
to select Next, Previous,
Up or Down.
So, we're going to stand
through the interface
for the user automatically
and the user can set the rate
of scanning speed
that they desire.
So as we scan through
the interface,
you notice each button
gets highlighted on screen.
You need to press your Switch
when the appropriate
button is highlighted.
In this case, if we want
to open up keyboard,
we press the Switch, the
keyboard would appear.
Now, as you can imagine,
navigating through
your keyboard button
by button would take
a really long time.
So, we grouped each row.
So, we navigate down,
grouping rows.
And then each row has groups
and you press your
button to drill in.
And eventually, really
intuitively,
get to the single letter
that you want to type.
As you'll notice up at the top,
we also offer spelling
suggestions.
That gets populated with
the next most likely letter
and next mostly like word
that you're trying to type.
And we use the incredibly
powerful spelling
and spell checking engine
built right into OS X
to help provide us some great
spelling suggestions here.
So now, I'm sure you're
thinking to yourself
that there's lot more to
OS X than just a keyboard.
Now, we do have access to the
other keyboard keys, of course,
like the media keys and
even the hardware buttons
that might appear
on your monitor
like the brightness controls.
But going beyond that, we have
full functionality of the mouse.
And this problem
alone is really hard.
How do you take a trackpad, a
mouse with that two dimensions
of movement, and boil it
down into a single button.
Well, I'm fortunate enough
to be able to work with some
of the brightest
people on the planet.
And they've came up-- they came
up with a really great solution.
When you want to move the mouse,
you'd select Move
from this menu here.
And if we take an
example of Calculator,
if we want to move the mouse
to select the Five button,
we're first going to scan the
x-axis and the user is going
to press their Switch when the
appropriate region is selected.
You then press your Switch
again to select the point
within that region and we repeat
the process on the y-axis.
So, really, really
simple and fast.
Just using one button,
we're able to move the mouse
anywhere on the screen.
So this is incredibly powerful
because now that we have access
to the keyboard and mouse,
the full functionality
of OS X is usable with
just a single switch.
At this point, you may note,
a user could do a left click,
a right click, they can
even do click and hold
to do Drag and Drop operations.
So, really powerful and all
the functionality is available
to the user right with
their single switch.
So, these are just some
of the build-in features
of Switch Control in OS X.
And we've gone above
and beyond that.
Switch Control and these
panels are also fully editable
by the user.
We have a fully functional
Panel Editor for users
to create their own
panels, to create panels
of their own shortcuts.
And this is incredibly critical
for this class of users.
As you may imagine, it can
be a little bit tedious
to navigate an entire
OS with just one button.
And just like you or I might
create keyboard shortcuts,
especially in tools like
Xcode or professional tools
like Final Cut, Switch
users need to be able
to create their own
shortcuts, their own panels.
We've seen a lot of users--
a lot Switch users
do video editing
and really enjoy video editing.
And this class of users
really like creating panels
that have commonly used
functionality come in macros,
things like insert a Crossfade,
insert a Fade to Black,
or trim this Clip
by Five Seconds.
So with this tool,
users have the ability
to create their own panels,
create their own shortcuts,
and really design an interface
that works for their workflow.
Now, one another that I didn't
get into with Switch Control is,
just like on iOS, Switch
Control has the ability
to navigate the user interface.
And to do this, it uses
the Accessibility API just
like VoiceOver.
So now, more than ever,
it's absolutely critical
that your application implements
the Accessibility API.
And as I started out this talk,
I said that we solve
two problems,
and the first problem is
we try to deliver some
of the best features
within the operating system
for users with disabilities.
But the truth of the matter is
no matter how great our features
are, no matter how many
weekends we spend in the office,
no matter how many late
nights we spend in toiling
over these interfaces,
users don't buy our products
because of the features
we build into the OS.
Users buy our products because
of the great applications
you make.
Users buy our products because
of the extended functionality
and integration that
your apps provide.
So now, more than ever,
it's absolutely critical
for your applications to be
accessible and work correctly
with the Accessibility API.
To help show you
a little bit more
about making your application
accessible, I'd like to bring
up my colleague,
Patti Hoa [phonetic].
[applause]
[ Background Noise ]
>> Okay, my name is Patti Hoa.
I'm a software engineer
on the accessibility team.
Today, I'm going to help
you guide you through some
of the basics of accessibility
technology on OS X.
And then I'm going to
present to you some
of the UI challenges
we have and some
of the new APIs we've introduced
to solve some of those problems.
And last, I'm going to
also talk about some
of the security improvements
we've made.
So, let's first talk
about accessibility
technology on OS X.
First, there is your application
that presents lots of pretty UIs
and fancy cool features.
And then there's a few
software, what we call,
"assistive software" that
uses Accessibility APIs
to obtain informations
from other applications.
Some examples of
those are VoiceOver
and the Switch software
that Greg just talked about.
So the way it works is the
assistive software will request
accessibility information
from your app
and the application vents
those accessibility information
back out.
To use a specific
example, VoiceOver here
as the assistive software and
then just a generic application
that perhaps just has a
Play button in the window.
So the way they communicate
with each other is through,
what we call, the
NSAccessibility Protocol.
And the way it works is that
every UI, like this Play button,
is conveying its accessibility
information through attributes.
So, VoiceOver can simply
ask for a specific attribute
and get some information back.
In this case, VoiceOver to
ask for role description
and get the type
of UI information
back which is button.
Or, it could ask
for AX description
which describes what kind of
function this UI presents.
In this case, you could
return the string Play.
So, VoiceOver could
then take these two keys
of attribute information
and either speak or output
to Braille the words
Play button.
So let's take a quick look at
the NSAccessibility Protocol.
There's methods to determine
if any particular
element is ignored
in accessibility hierarchies.
And then there's methods
to get attributes in such.
And there are methods to
perform actions [inaudible] UIs
that you could interact with.
And then there's
hit-testings and focused testing
that you could do
with accessibility.
And last but not
least, you could do--
you could post notification
when things change.
I'm not going to go into details
about how this protocol works.
If you're new to the
NSAccessibility Protocol,
I encourage to you look at the
previous WWDC videos or look
at our documentation online.
What I do want to do right now
is to show you a tool we have
on OS X to help you
going at information
about any particular
piece of UI.
[ Background Noise ]
So this tool is called
Accessibility Inspector
and the good thing is, now,
it's a bundled with Xcode.
So you could simply go to Xcode,
open Developer Tool
and launch the app.
[ Background Noise ]
And Xcode won't hide.
There you go.
So the way Inspector works
is it does hit-testing.
So whenever UI you're
pointing under mouse,
it's going to display
it in the Inspector.
So I'm going to use this app
I have called Accessibility
UI examples.
If you came here last year, you
know that we used this demo app.
So you've seen some of
the examples we had.
This is a great app to
use to determine how
to accessorize various
type of UI.
So this year, we added four
more examples for you here.
Now, what I want to do is use
Inspector, take my mouse over,
say, for example,
this Recycle icon.
I'm going to lock the screen
so that way I could continue
to move my mouse while we're
inspecting the content.
So this icon has its AX image.
This shows you the
hierarchy of this image
and then underneath all the
attributes that it supports.
For example, here it tells
you, it has a role of AX image,
a role description of image,
description of recycle,
et cetera.
I encourage you to take
a look at this Inspector
and use it while you're
implementing your accessibility
to support for your app.
[ Background Noise ]
So now, I'm going to tell you
about all the exciting
new APIs we have coming
up in OS X Maverick.
So we came up with
a few UI challenges
that we're trying to solve.
So in OS 10.9, we
introduced some new APIs
to solve those UI problems.
So I'm going to talk about some
of the new subroles
we've introduced, some--
a new set a of APIs to support--
excuse me, set of new APIs
to support Transient UIs
and also notification
support to--
for accessibility announcement.
So let's first take a look at
some of the UI challenges we had
or some of the new
behavior we've noticed.
So, traditionally,
NSSegmentedControl,
you can only select
one segment at a time.
But we noticed that developer
have altered the behavior
so that you could select
multiple segments at a time,
like the Xcode for View
Controller in this example.
So to solve that problem,
we introduced a new
subrole several called the
Toggle Subrole.
Similarly, we also
noticed that a lot
of developers are creating
UIs that look like a switch
to do a function that
where, traditionally,
they might have used a checkbox,
like in a time machine perhaps
where you could use
a switch looking UI
to turn something on and off.
And to support that,
we introduced a new subrole
called the Switch Subrole.
In the Accessibility UI example
demo app, there's example
of the Switch, you could
take a look at that
and see how that's accessorized.
Next, I want to talk about
UIs that appears and disappear
as a result of user actions.
And the most common one we're
seeing are mouse hovering.
So the example I have up
here is the Reminders app.
When you take your mouse
over of the Reminder item,
the Information button appears.
And similarly, if you
take your mouse away,
the Information button
disappears.
So this is a mouse-only
function that, you know,
if you're not a mouse-user
like VoiceOver user,
then there's no way to bring
up that Information button.
We could tell you to add
keyboard support like we've done
for many years, but we know
that's not always possible.
And even if you did add
the keyboard support,
shortcut support, it
may not be discoverable.
So in 10.9, we introduced new
APIs to solve this problem.
All you have to do
are two things.
First, when VoiceOver
wants to show or hide UIs,
you simply need to implement
the Show Alternate UI action
or the Show Default UI action.
And when VoiceOver wants to know
when UI changes on the screen,
you simply need to post
the notification layout,
change notification.
This notification takes a user
information dictionary, a key--
UI elements key that takes in
a rate of changed elements.
So if you've ever implemented
or posted accessibility
notification,
you may be wondering
right now, "How do I pass
in this user information key?"
Guess what.
In 10.9, we introduced a new
API for you to do just that.
This post notification
was user info.
API takes in additional
parameter
which is the User
Information Dictionary.
So to see how this all works,
I'm going to go ahead
and demo it to you.
[ Background Noise ]
So in this app here, the
Accessibility UI examples,
there's the Transient
UI example.
So note that as I take my
mouse over here, the Previous
and Next buttons appear.
And you could click on
this to change the page.
And if you take your mouse away
from this, the UIs disappear.
So obviously, this
is not possible
for a VoiceOver user
to use currently.
So let's see how you can add
those API support to solve that.
I have the Accessibility
UI example project.
In that Transient UI folder,
there's a Transient
UI Trigger view
which is just a subclass
of the NSView.
This is the view that
holds the two buttons.
So what I want to do is add
the NSAccessibility Protocol
for this view.
So I created a category
for that.
So the first thing I
want to do is make sure
that this view is exposed
through the Accessibility
hierarchy.
NSViews, by default, will not
exposed through accessibility.
So I have to explicitly return
No for Accessibility is Ignored.
So once this element is
exposed through the hierarchy,
the next you want
to do is, well,
define what type of UI this is.
So in the accessibility
attribute value,
this is when you
ask for the role,
I'll just return the group role
since the only function this
view does is hold other UIs.
For any attributes that you
don't explicitly support,
call Super because [inaudible]
underneath will do all the work
for you.
So now, we're ready to
add some of the new APIs.
The first thing is
the new actions.
Depending on if those
buttons are visible or not,
you can support the
Show Default UI action
or the Show Alternate UI action.
Then when you're asked
to perform those actions,
you could go ahead and
make those buttons appear
or disappear.
Every time those UI appear or
disappear, you want to remember
to post the notification.
And this is where we
can use that new API,
the post notification
with user info API,
pass in the Layout
Change notification,
and the User Information
Dictionary
with those changed elements.
So with that, I want to show you
how this works with VoiceOver.
You can launch VoiceOver
with command F5
and the very first
time you launch that,
it's going to ask you if you
want to run through a tutorial.
If you never used VoiceOver,
I really encourage you
to try it out, the tutorial.
For now, I'm going to skip that.
>> Welcome to VoiceOver.
VoiceOver speaks descriptions
of items on the screen
and can be used to control
the computer using only
your keyboard.
If you already know how to use
VoiceOver, press the V key now.
If you want to learn
how to use VoiceOver,
press the Space Bar now.
>> Okay, so I'm going
to go and continue.
>> VoiceOver Accessibility
UI examples,
Accessibility UI examples
window, table, Transient UI,
selected has keyboard focus.
>> Okay, so the way it works
is there's a VoiceOver cursor
which is the black box
around the UI I'm focused on.
And I can simply use
VoiceOver key commands
to move that cursor around.
>> This is page 3 of 10.
Has Alternate UI action.
>> So, it tells me this one
has Alternate UI action.
So now, I could use
another key command to bring
up the VoiceOver Action Menu.
>> Actions Menu, one item.
Show Alternate UI.
>> I'll go ahead
and select that.
>> Two items available
in the Update Items Menu.
>> And note that
now I could bring
up the Previous and
Next buttons.
So let's jump there.
>> This, stop inter-- Previous
button displaying Alternate UI,
Next button displaying
Alternative UI.
>> And I could interact with it.
>> Press Next button.
Press Next button.
>> Okay. And we could
do the same thing
to hide these buttons.
>> Previous button.
This is page 5 of 10
displaying Alternative UI.
Actions Menu one item,
Show Default UI, Table,
Transient UI selected.
VoiceOver off.
>> Okay, with the
few lines of code,
now you're giving VoiceOver
the same experience to be able
to access those buttons.
[ Background Noise ]
The next thing I want to talk
about is Accessibility
Announcement.
In your app, there may
be times where you want
to convey some status
to the user.
And the example I have here
of the Keyboard Preference
where when a user assigns
a key that conflicts
with the existing key, Keyboard
Prefs will display a little
status text at the
bottom of the screen.
Now, this is a-- what I
call, a "visual announcement"
which works great
if you're sighted.
But if you're not,
this is useless.
So to help you make
the experience the same
for every user, we've introduced
a new notification called
Announcement Requested
Notification.
It takes an Announcement key
so you could pass on a string
of what you want the
assistive software to announce.
So with that information,
once we post that,
VoiceOver can then either
determine to speak it,
output to Braille, or
do something about it.
Now, not every announcement
has the same priority,
so we also have a new priority
key that you could pass
in to determine the priority.
We've predefined some priorities
for you, Low, Medium and High.
So, so far, I've talked
about APIs that help
to solve UI challenges.
Next, I want to talk about some
of the security improvements
we've made.
Two things, specifically, one
is the text content protection
and the other one is
a more secure usage
of Accessibility API.
So let's first talk
about content protection.
If you run apps such
as the eBook
that display copyrighted
content like a book,
or if you have a medical app
that display valuable
sensitive patient informations,
what I'm going to
say next is for you.
If you have not made
your app accessible
because of text content
protection concern,
we now have one more reason for
you to make your app accessible.
We've heard your feedback
and now we're introducing
a new attribute
that you could implement to
make your content more secure.
So this attribute is called
the Contents Protected
Content Attribute.
If you pass in Yes for this,
then your text content string
will no longer be viewable
by other applications.
There is one exception
and those are the system--
system assistive software apps
such as VoiceOver
for obvious reasons.
To use this new attribute, you
will also need to make API call.
This is called the Set Make
Contents Protected Content API.
So to see how these works,
I'm going to go ahead
and demo to you.
[ Background Noise ]
So in the Accessibility
UI example,
there's the protected text.
And I simply have a view that
display a paragraph of text.
And for demo purpose, I
also included a checkbox
so we could toggle the
protection on and off.
Now, let's take a look at
this using the Inspector.
So I'm going to lock this thing.
[ Background Noise ]
What I want you to look
at specifically is this
AX Value attribute.
Note that, right now, you
could see their entire string
of that content.
So if I go and check this
Protect Content checkbox
and refresh the Inspector,
note that you can no longer
see the string anymore.
And we can do the same thing
with VoiceOver and
see what happens.
>> VoiceOver Accessibility
UI-- Apple designs Macs,
the best personal computers
in the world along with OS X,
iLife, iWork, and
professional software.
Apple leads the digital music
revolution with its iPods
and iTunes online store.
VoiceOver off.
>> Great. So, it allows
assistive software to continue
to use and see the content
but it doesn't allow other
apps to see the content.
So let's see how that
works in the code.
The example is under the
Protected Text folder.
In there, I just have a
subclass of the NSTextField,
so that displayed the content.
And so, I want to override some
of the Accessibility APIs here.
So since what I'm doing here is
dynamically toggling the text
content protection on and
off, I'll make the API call
in a place where I'm setting
the protection turning--
toggling that protection.
So I could just call
NSAccessibility Set Make
Contents Protected
Content, turn it yes or no.
In your app, you probably
want the protection
to last throughout the
lifespan of your app.
So, you could power it like
in the app launch time.
Next, I want to add
this new attribute,
so in Accessibility
Attribute Names.
In addition to all
the attributes
that app already supports
for the text field cell,
we're also going to add
this new Contents Protected
Content attribute.
And then when you're being
asked for this attribute,
this is where you return
yes or no if you want to--
if you want that protection.
So that's all you have to
do to protect a content.
[ Pause ]
So, so far, I've been
talking about your app
and how events various
accessibility information
to enhance the user experience.
Now, I want to switch gear
and talk about some changes
that affect assistive software.
At Apple, we really care about
protecting end-user's privacy,
basically, all of
their information.
So in OS X, if any
application that wants
to use the end-user's
location information
or context information will have
to get the users permission.
We're taking that
great mechanism
to accessibility too in 10.9.
So in 10.9, any application that
wants to use Accessibility API
to obtain information
about other applications
will also need gain the
user's permission.
So the very first time the app
uses the Accessibility API,
the system will prompt
the end-user
for permission on your behalf.
And until your app is
on the approved list,
the APIs would be disabled.
So if you're an app that heavily
depends on the use of the API,
you will probably want to
remind the end-user more often.
So we created an API
for you to do just that.
It's called the AX is Trusted,
Process Trusted with Options
that takes in a dictionary.
So in your app launch
time, you could simply pass
in the Trusted Check Option
prompt, it has Boolean for the--
Boolean true for that into
the dictionary and set
that as the argument
for your API.
And when that happens, then
every time your app launch,
it'll prompt the user
for permission again.
So if you want more
information, there's e-mail list
for you to join or a contact.
And if you miss the
accessibility
in iOS session earlier today
in this room, you can watch it
on video once it's available.
And if you want to hear more
about the close captioning stuff
that Greg talked about, tomorrow
morning in Uphill [phonetic],
you can listen to that.
So to recap, Apple is
really committed to ensure
that every user have equal
access to the rich experience
of using all of our
Apple products.
On our end, we work
really hard to continue
to improve our existing products
like VoiceOver and new products
like the Switch software,
and to continue
to enhance our existing
set of APIs.
However, all of that are
just tools to help the user
to use your application.
So, your application
is the important thing
in this equation.
I'm hoping that I've given you
some basic information on how
to use the Accessibility
APIs and the tool
to make your application
accessible.
If you have further questions,
contact us, watch videos,
previous WWDC videos, or look
online for documentations.
Today, I have also
presented some UI challenges
and how we have new APIs to
help solve those problems.
If, in your application,
you have any of those UIs
that I presented, I
really encourage you
to implement those new APIs.
As you've see in the demo,
they're really easy
to implement.
And I've also talked about some
of the security improvements
too.
So, I'm hoping that you go
away with this and start
to make your application
accessible.
If you have further
question, again,
come to our lab this
afternoon at 12:45.
And if I don't see you at
the lab, have a great day.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]