[ Silence ]
>> Good afternoon.
How are you doing?
Welcome to Session 301:
Extending your Apps
for Enterprise and
Education Use.
My name is Dave Rahardja and I'm
up here with Victor Alexander.
So as you know, the use of iOS
in the enterprise is
growing at a phenomenal rate.
There's great momentum in the
enterprise to adopt the devices
that people love so much
and that allows them to do
so many things that
they couldn't do before.
From everything, from retail
to corporations, to medical,
to education, even
inside airline cockpits,
iOS devices are everywhere
you go.
A large part of the
success is of course due
to the elegant design
of iOS devices,
the great management
capabilities of iOS itself,
data security that's built
into the device and a host,
a lot of things that people
love about the device carry
over into the enterprise use.
But much of the success is
thanks to developers like you
that develop apps that allow
the enterprise to do things
that they couldn't before.
Apps in the App Store,
in the custom B2B store
and in-house apps
that are developed
by the enterprise themselves.
So during this hour,
I'd like to talk to you
about how you can make
your apps more attractive
to the enterprise so
you can take advantage
of the growth in this industry.
And I'm going to do that by
highlighting four major areas
that you can implement
in your apps to do this.
They are: authentication,
networking,
data security, and management.
And, of course, this is an
incomplete list of making an app
that would be attractive
to the enterprise.
Of course, your apps have
to provide a solution
that they're looking for.
Of course, your apps have to
have a great user experience
and those things are a given.
But these are the things
that we're going to focus
on that will let you add
that little bit of extra
so that your apps stand
out from the crowd
in the enterprise market.
So, let's start up
with authentication.
Authentication is, of course,
very important in
the enterprise.
When someone logs into
your app, you have to know
that this person is
who they say they are.
So, iOS has built an, of course,
a great authentication tool
if you are an in-house developer
or if you're an App
Store developer
that has developed
a suite of apps
and we call that
shared keychain.
Now, that way shared
keychain works is
that if you're a developer
and you have multiple titles
or multiple apps that are
deployed on a single device,
those apps share the keychain
or could share the keychain.
This allows you to sign into
one app and reuse the sign-in
in a second app and
it's very convenient
because users don't
have to keep signing
in every time they
switch their apps.
And for in-house developers,
this is a great solution
because all your in-house
apps can be signed
with the same shared
keychain with the same ID
and you can implement
this in your own Apps.
But what happens if you
want to mix and match?
So, if you're an
enterprise and you say, "Hey,
that's a great App Store app."
You want to pull it in,
it supports my authentication
model,
but you can't really
share the keychain.
So now, you end up having
to log in twice depending
on which app you have.
So, new in iOS 7, we are
introducing Single Sign-On.
[ Applause ]
Single Sign-On takes the
burden of authentication
and places it inside iOS.
So, let's take a
closer look at this.
In iOS 7, Single Sign On is
built on top of Kerberos.
This is a very popular
authentication scheme
as you know inside
the enterprise.
You can grant access to
your Single Sign On accounts
to specific apps only.
And of course, the passwords
are never stored inside the Apps
but they are managed by iOS.
As an app developer, this
is what you have to do.
Oh and by the way, for every
one of the topics that I'm going
to talk about, I'm
going to talk about it
from three different
perspectives.
I'm going to present to you
what iOS brings to the table.
And then, I'm going to talk
like I do here about what you
as the app developer can do to
take advantage of the service.
And then, I'm also
going to talk about it
from the IT integrator's
point of view
to tell you what you need
to be aware of when you want
to deploy this feature in your
enterprise and what to look
for when you are trying to find
the next great app to deploy
in your enterprise, what kind
of features you're
going to look for.
So keep that in mind.
So Single Sign On.
As an app developer, I
have great news for you.
You have no co-changes required
if you use NSURLConnection.
If you don't use
NSURLConnection,
the way you take advantage
of Single Sign On is
to use NSURLConnection.
So that's-- so we built this
into the NSURLConnection
mechanism.
You can also use NSURLSession
which is the great new API
that we're introducing in iOS 7.
So, the only change that you
will see as a developer is
when you access a resource
that has been configured it
to be managed-- to use Single
Sign On authentication,
you will not receive
this callback:
the willSendRequestFor
AuthenticationChallenge
callback.
So, what you'll do is
you'll make a request,
you will not see
an authentication,
iOS will prompt the user
to enter their credentials.
If it's successful, your
request will just complete,
it will just succeed.
If not, then it'll just fail.
So, your app probably already
works with Single Sign On.
For IT integrators, the way
you configure Single Sign-On is
using a configuration profile.
So as you know, configuration
profiles is the--
is the way that we manage
settings and accounts on iOS.
Inside the configuration
profile,
you can define a
Single Sign-On payload,
define the account,
you know, the realm.
And define the app bundle IDs
that you are going to allow
into this system, into the
Single Sign On account,
you can also define
URL prefixes.
So, when you go to Safari
and you hit the URL prefix,
it will trigger Single Sign On.
So, that's what new
in Single Sign On
and authentication on iOS.
Next, we're going to
talk about networking.
So the networking environment
in an enterprise is
maybe a little different
from the environment at home.
Generally, iOS has great support
for enterprise networking.
It has great SSL and TLS or
TLS Support and we, of course,
allow MDM to install
certificates, certificate chains
and such if you have
you have your own
self-signed certificates.
Then, we also have proxy support
both per SSID and Global Proxy,
and we support enterprise
Wi-Fi 802.1X, WPA, WPA2,
and we support virtual
private networks.
And VPN tunnels the
traffic from your iOS device
into the enterprise,
into the intranet.
All right, something
new in iOS 7,
we're introducing per-app VPN.
So, what's this?
Here is what this conceptual--
a conceptual model of
what per-app VPN does.
So, let's say you have two apps
that the enterprise has
installed: app one and two,
and you have an app
that the user installed
on their own device.
Let's say this is a "bring
your own device" scenario,
the user installs
their own device--
their own app on the App Store.
Per-app VPN allows you to
specify that apps one and two go
to the VPN into the corporate
intranet and not app three.
App three that the user
installed does not get access
to the intranet.
So that's what it
is conceptually.
This limits VPN access
to only the apps
that the enterprise has
installed, specific Apps.
It enhances both
security and privacy.
So, security because you are not
exposing your intranet to apps
that the user may have installed
from the App Store on their own.
That's better than
system wide VPN.
And privacy, because your
user's personal traffic
to the internet does not go
through your enterprise
network, all right?
I knew you'd like that.
All right, so per-app VPN for
app developers, what do you have
to do to take advantage
of this great feature?
Nothing, your app already works.
It works transparently, you
don't have to change a thing,
this is my favorite
slide, it's great.
For IT integrators, what do you
have to do to install this--
to configure this feature?
You need support from
your VPN plug-in.
Now, these are the
same VPN plug-ins
that you probably already use
from your third party
VPN vendors.
They need to have a plug-in
that supports the
notion of per-app VPN.
Once that plug-in is installed,
you then configure
the VPN account
with a configuration profile
through MDM and then you use MDM
to tag which apps are allowed
to use that VPN connection.
More things about networking?
If you are developing
without using NSURLConnection,
you'll see a pattern
here by the way.
If you don't use NSURLConnection
or NSUrlSession, you must--
you need to be aware
of the presence
of proxies inside
the enterprise.
If you are using NSURLConnection
or the new NSURLSession,
we take care of that
for you, you have to--
don't have to worry about it.
But if you're using
say, CFSocketStream
or UNIX level sockets, you
need to be aware of that.
Read the API, you probably need
to move some data structures
around to take care
of the presence
of proxies in your path.
And as a final note and this
is not just for enterprise,
this is just good practice
for an app developer.
Be conscious of your
app's cellular data usage.
In iOS 7, we've enhanced
multi-tasking
so that your app can be woken
up at particular intervals
or when a push notification
comes in.
This is great for you to
update the status of your app
but you need to ask
the question,
"Should I be doing
this over cellular?"
If you're going to update
a large amount of data,
maybe you should defer it to
when the user brings the app
to UI foreground or
when you are in Wi-Fi.
So, in an enterprise, it
is especially attractive
if your app knows
how to behave itself
and limit the consumption
of cellular data.
And the way you do that is
you tag your URL request
with this property,
allowsCellularAccess equals no
and that-- really, that's it
and that request will not go
out over cellular, very simple.
So, that's a short session on
networking in the enterprise.
Next stop, data security.
So, data security is very
important in the enterprise.
One of the things that you'll
notice when you develop apps
for the enterprise is
the enterprise is really,
really concerned
about the security
and privacy of their data.
And here are some
things that are available
to you in iOS already.
So, built into iOS, we have a
great data protection model.
There are three main
data protection classes
in iOS, just to review.
There are some subtle variations
on these, but basically,
there are three classes
that you can choose from.
These classes can be applied to
files that you write to flash.
So you have none which is none,
they're not data protected.
You have complete
with authentication
which protects the data
in an encrypted fashion
until the user enters
their passcode
for the first time
after a restart.
And complete, which will
protect your data as long
as the phone is locked.
So when the user locks the
phone again, it gets protected.
Let me illustrate that.
So, after the device has
restarted, none is readable,
the others are encrypted,
unreadable by your apps.
When the user enters
their passcode,
then all the classes
become available
for reading and writing.
When the user locks
the device again,
that complete class gets
locked while the others
remain unencrypted.
So, keep that in mind, this is
the model that you can choose
from and you can start to
see that this is a good way
of binning your data
to see which kind
of sensitivity does
the enterprise have
about that particular
file and for you to choose
which class you want
to choose from.
So, but there's one
thing new in iOS 7
that we're really proud of.
We are improving the data
security of all apps in iOS 7
across the board,
even App Store apps.
All App Store apps
and enterprise apps
that are installed in iOS
7 automatically receive the
complete until first
authentication class,
the second class.
What this means is that
for the enterprise,
for the IT integrators
of the enterprise,
you can now feel confident
that when you install an app
from the App Store even,
that that data has some--
has a greater level
of protection
in iOS 7 than it did in iOS 6.
And we do this across the board
and there's no change
required for most of the apps.
Also, you may be aware or
not that starting from iOS 6,
we have FIPS 140-2
certification.
This is a government
certification
that certifies the
integrity of our crypto,
CoreCrypto algorithms and
we're really proud of this.
So, for app developers,
what do you have to--
what can you do to
enhance your data security?
Well, use the protection
complete class when appropriate.
Ask yourself the question,
if somebody were to be able
to read this file off a disk--
off the disk, will that make
my enterprise customer happy
or not?
And if the answer is no,
then please consider using the
File Protection Complete Class.
There is a small wrinkle
when you do that, of course,
when the device is locked
and your App gets woken
up by multi-tasking, you can't
actually write to your database
because it's unreadable
and unwritable.
And as I said, there are
some variations to this theme
but in general you will be woken
up and then you'll discover
that you can't write to the
files that you need to write.
So, at this time, consider
what your options are.
First of all, you can always
write down the fact or write
to disk the fact that
there is an update
and the next time the
user launches the app
in UI foreground, device is
unlocked, go fetch the update.
Or you can create
a side buffer file
of maybe the second
protection class, you know,
complete until first
user authentication
to buffer your data.
And then, write that over
to the protected data base
when your App goes
to foreground.
But of course, the
question you ask there is,
should I be doing
that with this data?
And if the answer is no,
then just write the fact
that you are-- that you
need to do an update
when the app comes back
to foreground and do it
when the app starts back up.
The keychain has an additional
attribute that you can place
on the data security
of each item.
You can assign an app--
a data security attribute
per keychain item by the way,
the same classes that
you have up there
with an additional
feature in there.
If you'll notice, the
attribute here says accessible
after first unlock this
device only in the end.
This helps you to secure
credentials, private keys,
passwords or whatever from
getting backed up off the device
and restored to another device.
Right? The fact that your
keychain items are backed up
and restored as a great
convenience for end-users
because you don't
have to log in again.
But for the enterprise, you
should ask the question,
if a user logs into this
device which may be managed
by the enterprise, is it
appropriate for that login
to transfer to another
device that the user owns
that may not be managed, right?
So in many cases, the
answer is no, and you need
to put this attribute on the
keychain items to prevent backup
and restore from taking that
credential out of that device.
And finally, iCloud
Document Sync.
Now, iCloud Document Sync is
another feature that users love
but this becomes a
problem for enterprise data
because sensitive enterprise
data may leak out into the cloud
and into other unmanaged
and unprotected devices.
So, the enterprise
does have a restriction
to disable iCloud document
sync across the whole device.
And it would be better
if there was a way
to disable iCloud Document
sync in your app only
so that the user doesn't have
to turn off document
sync across the board.
So, consider adding a--
the capability of
storing your documents
in your local documents
folder instead
of the iCloud document folder
when your app is configured
for enterprise use.
But, how do you configure
your app for enterprise use?
You certainly don't
want to put a UI switch
to let users turn
off this feature.
Well, there's a great way
of doing that and I'll talk
about it a few slides
down so hang in there.
So, there's data security.
Let's talk about management.
When we talk about management
on iOS, we generally talk
about mobile device
management protocol.
This is a very powerful protocol
that allows an enterprise
to manage and administer
thousands
of iOS devices over the air.
And some of the things MDM
can do, it can set passcode
and security policies,
like you'd have
to have a certain
number of letters
in your passcode
and stuff like that.
It can install accounts
including email, calendar, VPN,
you know, Wi-Fi accounts,
any-- all kinds of accounts.
It can remotely erase your
device and it can, of course,
great news for you, install
and remove apps over the air.
Now, the accounts and
apps that are installed
by MDM are called Managed
Apps, Accounts and Apps.
So things that are
installed with MDM are Managed
and the things that
users install
in the device are
called Unmanaged.
So, Managed Apps and Accounts.
So in iOS 7, we're
introducing another great way
to manage the data inside your
managed apps and accounts,
we call it Managed Open In.
Managed Open In prevents the
unintentional data movement
between managed and
unmanaged apps and accounts.
Managed apps-- managed data stay
inside managed apps and accounts
and they don't leak out
to the unmanaged ones.
So, to show you a demo of
this, I'm going to call Victor
to show you a little
demo of Managed Open In.
>> Great.
[ Applause ]
Thanks Dave.
All right.
So here, we have an iOS
device which is running iOS 7
and it's being managed by the
enterprise via an MDM server.
You notice we have number
of applications installed
on this device.
But specifically of
note that the top of row
of applications were
ones that were installed
by the enterprise via
MDM, and the second row
of applications were
installed by the user,
so we have a bit of a mix here.
So normally, when the user might
say or do something like open
up mail, tap on a message and
view an attachment and want
to send that attachment
to another application.
If we tap the share sheet,
you'll notice that the list
of applications here is the same
as what we saw in
the Home screen.
Long list, we've got drop box
present, a long list of apps
and that might-- that might not
be desirable in the enterprise.
So, since this email account
is a managed Exchange account,
we have the ability to
enable Managed Open In.
So, I'm going to go ahead
and push that change
down to the device,
we'll give it a moment
to actually take effect.
And now, when the user goes
back to the share sheet,
what you'll notice is that
there's a much shorter list
of applications present,
it's only those applications
that were installed
by the enterprise.
Thus, limiting the
user's ability to--
thus limiting the user's ability
to try and send that attachment
to a non enterprise-installed
application
and that is Managed Open In.
Back to you Dave.
>> Thanks Victor.
So, Managed Open In works
with both apps and accounts.
So, when you tap an
attachment and there's an--
there's a mail action that
you can tap on, when you tap
on that mail action,
if the attachment came
from a managed account,
the email accounts
that you can choose to send
it from are also filtered
down to the managed accounts.
So, that's a-- that's a very
cool feature, and it works
with all kinds of
accounts including mail
and calendar attachment.
So that's Managed Open In.
Next up, a great new feature
in iOS 7 called App
Configuration and Feedback.
So, what is this?
This is a way to reduce your
support calls, IT integrators,
by configuring apps
that you install.
And the way to do this is an
MDM server can send a dictionary
into a managed app
to configure it.
Now, the dictionary that
you push down appears
in the NSUserDefaults of that
app, it's very convenient.
And the feedback part of this
allows an app to write something
into the NSUserDefaults that
can be read by the MDM Server
to report-- to report back
a status out of band, right?
It's very simple.
As an app developer here's--
here is all you need now.
This is very similar
to what happens
if you use a settings bundle.
So, if you already
have a settings bundle
that allows the user
to go to Settings
and configure your apps, this
is very, very similar to that.
Excuse me.
Your app needs to
read the dictionary
from a particular magic key:
com.apple.configuration.managed,
that's where the dictionary
will appear that's pushed
down by the enterprise.
When you write your feedback
out, write it to com--
NSUserDefaults key
com.apple.feedback.managed.
And when the MDM
Server queries your app,
it will find your
dictionary there.
Listen to this notification, the
defaults did change notification
to be aware that the
configuration has changed
or that the server
has read your feedback
and erased it to make it nil.
You can be aware of that
by listening to this.
And your app may not be
running, of course, when you--
when the configuration changes
or when the feedback
is retrieved and erased
from your NSUserDefaults.
So, read the configuration
every time your app starts up.
Again, the same things
that you've already done
for Settings bundles,
basically, the same idea.
So, in order to show
you how this works,
I'm going to ask Victor
to come back up here
to give you a little demo.
>> Thanks Dave.
So here, we have a
sample application
that was developed using app
configuration and feedback
and you'll notice at the top
here, we've got a URL bar,
we've got a success and failure
values that were tracking.
And in the center,
we've got a UIWebView.
And also at the bottom
here, take note,
we have a Cloud document
sync switch.
Maybe not something you
might want to add to the UI
of your app but for the
purposes of our sample demo,
I think it's appropriate to use.
So, you might notice at
the top of the application,
we have URL that might
not work correctly.
Let's start tap the go button
here and see what happens.
Our app is not quite
working correctly,
we got a failure
there, no web page loads
in the center, we've
got a problem.
This might be something
your user hits if they want
to load their login information
for their enterprise app
or help documentation and
if we try and connect,
we just keep hitting errors.
Wouldn't it be nice
if we had a mechanism
through which we could update
that, reset it, correct it
and get this app back
into a working state?
So since the URL
value is something
that I configured using app
configuration, I could push
down the change to that app
to update the URL and see
if we can get things working.
So, I'm going to go ahead
and push down that change,
give it a moment for the
device to receive it.
You noticed almost immediately,
the URL bar updates,
you noticed almost immediately
the URL string updates
with a much more valid
looking URL and also note
that the UI Switch
is now disabled.
So, we've done a couple of
really powerful things here
to get this app into a
better state and let's see
as a test here, I will tap,
go and our webpage loads
in the UIWebView as expected
which is-- which is excellent.
Now, we have these-- so
that's the configuration side
of things, what about the
feedback side of things?
We've hit, you know,
three errors on this app.
It might be useful for the
enterprise to find that out
if users are having problems or
issues and we can have the MDM
to sort of pull that information
from the apps and collect it
and work with that data.
Now, if I place a command to
this app from the MDM Server
to fetch that error information.
What we'll see here is
that not only the failures
but the success values
were pulled out of the app,
sent back to the MDM Server
for evaluation by the IT Staff.
But also, the values
were set back to zero
so that any future polls for
that information can be clean
and updated and evaluated
between the last two times
the information was pulled.
And that is app configuration
and feedback.
Back to you Dave.
>> Thank you Victor.
So app configuration
and feedback,
very simple feature,
very powerful.
For IT integrators,
this is invaluable
to configure the apps
in your enterprise.
You need to look for
apps that support this.
Now normally, you would
send out apps to your users
and then send them a email
or something that says, "Hey,
tap this, tap that,
type this in, type that"
and you get you know--
and you get support calls.
With app configuration, you
can prepare the dictionary
for that app and
send it to the users
without their intervention.
The first time they launch that
app, it's already configured.
Let's take a closer look at
what's going on under the--
under the covers here.
So, I added this notification
observer in viewDidLoad.
You could add this view
will appear or, you know,
in your apps delegate or
wherever it's appropriate
for you handle the event.
So, the first thing you
notice is I added an observer
for NSUseDefaultsDidChange,
always add the notification
observer before reading the
values, so that you
don't miss an update.
And when that notification
fires,
what this app will do
is it will call this
readDefaultsValues method.
And once that's done, I actually
call the read defaults values
method to read it at least once.
The readDefaultValues method
does what you probably will do
if you are using a
settings bundle is to read
that magic key, magic
dictionary column.apple.
configuration.managed, and
then it picks apart the keys
and the values from
that dictionary.
Notice that I validate
the values here so I pick
out the value under
the key serverURL,
make sure it's a string first.
This is not a very
string validation
but it's some kind validation
before accepting the URL.
If a URL is not found
in the dictionary,
make sure you provide
a default value
that is sensible
even if it's nil.
So, if that's not
available, set it to something
that is reasonable default.
So, for the feedback
part, what I've--
what we've done here is to have
a little feedback-writing piece
of code inside the increment
success and failures.
So, every time the success and
failure count is incremented,
we create-- we try to read
the feedback dictionary
that already exists.
If one doesn't exist, we create
one, a mutable dictionary
under that magic key
com.apple.feedback.managed.
We then write the value of the
success count as a key under--
into this dictionary
under a well-known key.
In this case, successCount,
and that's it.
We just write it back
to NSUserDefaults
and it just sits there until
the MDM Server picks it up.
It's really simple.
So, what can you use
app configuration for?
Well, settings and
preferences of course.
You can set your app UI settings
from here, the same kind
of things that you would
set in your settings bundle
but very useful thing
to setup here: URLs.
URLs are very, very
powerful things to configure
with the server and
you can bootstrap a lot
of things using URLs.
And here is where you put
the disable iCloud document
sync switch.
So, this allows you to
disable iCloud document sync
in an enterprise
deployment situation
without exposing
a user facing UI.
Some things to note about this
configuration, it is stored
as file protection
none just as the rest
of your NSUserDefaults are.
So, no passwords or
private keys please.
You need to document your
dictionary keys, of course,
so that the enterprise
can configure your app.
And specify what
kind of data types
and the valid value
ranges that you accept.
And validate all the types
and values that you get.
From your app's perspective,
the enterprise server is
an unknown third party.
They are giving you
a dictionary that--
that your app is
supposed to ingest,
make sure you validate
the content.
And of course, keep it small,
as anything that you put
in your NSUserDefaults.
You're going to read your user
defaults every time your app
starts up and every time it
changes so keep it small.
No documents or images or little
sound files or things like that
in there, put the URLs in
there and read the assets
when your app starts up.
Once again, a reminder,
your app may not be running
so read this every time.
For feedback, what's
useful to put in there?
As you saw, errors and user
statistics are very useful.
Again, if your app can't talk
to the server, they can't report
that they can't talk with the
server so this is a good place
to put that information in.
So I, you know, I can't reach
that URL, here is an error.
Aggregate your reports.
Do not log, because it will
grow without bound and again,
this belongs in your
NSUserDefaults
and it needs to be small.
Document your dictionary keys so
that the enterprise knows what
to look for and keep it small.
It goes into the same
place that your--
all the rest of your defaults
go in your NSUserDefaults.
Your app might not be running
when the feedback is retrieved
and very importantly,
respect your user's privacy.
Before you send
up any personally
identifiable information,
things like location,
things like that,
be sure that you are legally
allowed to do this and,
of course, respect what the
user expects your app to report
and preserve the user privacy.
Your users will thank
you for that.
For IT Integrators,
app configuration
and feedback amounts to a
couple of new MDM commands
so what you need to do
is to use these commands
to configure your user's
devices as early as possible.
So, there is an extension
to the app install command
that allows you to add a
configuration dictionary inside
the app installation request.
So, do that if possible so that
the first time the user taps
on the app, it's
already preconfigured.
You can, of course,
refresh the configuration
as on an ongoing basis.
And use the feedback service
to detect configuration errors.
All right, so that's app
configuration and feedback.
Next, fonts.
We can now install
fonts in iOS 7,
they are installed using
configuration profiles.
So as an app developer,
this means that the
font list may change
as your app is running
and you need to listen
to this notification
to detect that event.
And of course, this also means
that your app may have to deal
with missing fonts, et cetera,
all that fun stuff that comes
with a system that
has installable fonts.
One of the things about
fonts in the enterprise is
that you are very likely
to encounter custom fonts
in an enterprise because an
enterprise will probably have a
corporate identity
font of some sort
that they will install
in every device.
So, your app needs to
be able to adopt to that
and at least use the fonts
that are installed to--
in your documents and et cetera.
So, that's fonts.
Next, I want to highlight a
feature that is very popular
in certain industries
in the enterprise
and that's single app mode.
So, you may not know this, but
MDM can put certain devices
into Single App Mode which means
that the device will run
one app and one app only.
This mode is very resilient
you can restart the device
and it would launch that app.
The app can crash and it
will just keep launching
and just keep launching
and crash again
which is a good thing.
You want this behavior
because this makes it perfect
for Kiosks, for point of sale
like this, for exam taking,
for example, or a whole host
of different applications.
So, this already an
iOS but new in iOS 7,
were adding an app-requested
single app mode.
So, what's this?
Some of you already
know what this is.
So, app-requested single app
mode allows an MDM Server
to pre-authorize a
set of app bundle IDs
to go into single app mode.
So-- and all the app has
to do is to call this API,
so that first one
you see up there,
UI accessibility request
guided access session
that there is the parameter
you can put in there to say yes
or no and enter a
session or exit a session.
If successful, your
app will be locked
into a single app
mode, all right?
And when your app
is done with it,
they can call the same API
again to get out with the--
with the Boolean false.
This is great for,
for example, exams.
So, you have an exam
app, examination starts,
the new student logs
in, you got locked in,
and the exam is over,
it locks out.
You can use the second API up
there, is guided access enabled,
to detect whether your
app is in this mode.
And you can use a notification
to detect transitions
between states.
So again, this state is very
resilient, your app will get--
the device will only run
your app until you exit.
So, make sure you have
an escape strategy
in case your app crashes or
the user powers down the device
and starts back up again.
Try not to lock the user
into your app forever,
but exit gracefully.
OK. So, that's single app mode.
Next up, app revocation.
In iOS 7 and OS X Mavericks,
we are supporting a new model
of volume purchasing
based on app assignment.
If you're not aware of this,
it allows an enterprise
to purchase an app
license essentially,
assign it to a user's device
or a user on a iOS device
and then later, revoke
that license from that--
from that user and assign
it to some other user.
So, what happens is your
app may be installed
on some user's device and
then, the right to run
that app may be revoked
from that device.
So, what happens then?
When that happens, your app
license "is going to expire."
The iOS-- iOS will run the app.
Well, first of all,
iOS will tell the user
that that app has been revoked
and give them the opportunity
to buy the app from
the app store.
And it will continue to
run that app for 30 days.
At the end of the 30 days, iOS
will no longer launch your app
but instead, will launch
an alert or show an alert
that says you got
to buy this app
from the App Store
to continue using it.
The reason we give the
grace period there is
so that the user
doesn't lose their data
and to give them an opportunity
to buy from the app store.
If you're checking for receipts
already, the expiry date is
on the receipt, so you might
want to check with that too.
There is the session on
the receipt checking,
I recommend it-- I
recommended you go to that one
and we'll cite that at the
end of the presentation.
So, that's management.
So, as you can see, iOS 7
brings a lot to the table in all
of these fields and there's
a lot that you can do,
with very little
effort in some cases,
to extend you app just
a little bit more,
to make it very attractive
to the enterprise.
Now, I want to talk a bit about
the philosophy that we have
on iOS about enterprise apps.
There are many cases where
an app developer who wants
to put their app into
the enterprise just wants
to tag something on in the end.
I'm just going to wrap
my app in something,
I'm going to add some
library to it and it's going
to make it all better.
It's going to make it
secure and stuff like that.
And we don't-- we encourage
you to do something different,
we encourage you to
build the next generation
of enterprise apps, right?
And what that means is we
would like you to build this--
the iOS features into your app.
The iOS 7 features,
they are like, you know,
a Single Sign On, data
protection, Managed Open In,
configuration or feedback for
app developers, of course.
Build this right into your
app so that as iOS grows
and additional features are
added, your app is ready to go
into the enterprise,
to grow along with it.
IT Integrators, I encourage
you to look for apps
that actually support these
iOS 7 features inside their app
natively and not just
tacked on at the end.
These are the apps
that are going
to serve your enterprise very
well into the next decade.
So, to sum up, if you
ask me, you know Dave,
as an app developer, what three
things can I add or do to my app
to make it that much more
attractive to the enterprise.
I will say these three things.
First, support app
configuration and feedback.
It's a very light-weight
extension to your app
that will greatly help
the IT Integrators
to deploy your app correctly
and to save them a
lot of support calls.
Next, use NSURLConnection
and NSURLSession.
These are your best bets to
get an app into the enterprise
and have it work correctly
the first time, all right?
I know in some cases, you can't,
but if you can, please
do use that.
And finally, build in data
protection and security
into your app, don't leave
it as an afterthought.
When you write files to
disk, consider what kind
of data protection
you're going to use.
When you write items
into the keychain,
think about what the use cases
might be in the enterprise.
All right, so for
more information,
our evangelist is Paul Marcos
and here are two great pages
on our Apple website
for you to get started.
So, if you're new to this
enterprise app development
world, there are some
great articles and guides
in both the business
and educational sites.
And, of course, the developer
forums are a great help.
There are some related sessions
that you are probably going
to be interested in because
they are prevalent here.
The first is already
gone passed 11:30 AM,
Managing Apple Devices.
If you haven't seen this
session, this session covers all
of the new features in
mobile device management
that we've added into
iOS 7 and OS X Mavericks.
So, please go view
that video if you can.
And the second one
is equally important,
it's how to use your--
how to check your receipts
to protect your apps.
So, thank you very much
and see you at the labs.
[Applause]