[ Silence ]
[ Applause ]
>> Good afternoon.
My name is Doug Gregor and I'm
here today to talk today to you
about Advances in Objective-C.
Objective-C is a great language
with the vibrant user community.
If you're here last year,
you saw that we are really,
really excited that
we could see this here
in the TIOBE Programming
Community Index.
This is from May 2012.
And we see that Objective-C
had moved all the way
up to fourth place
in the rankings.
Just pretty amazing.
Well in just the last
year, Objective-C has moved
up even further displacing
the vulnerable C++
for the number three spot.
Whoo!
[ Applause ]
So how do we evolve
the Objective-C?
Well, there are some
things that we focus on.
The two things in general that
we really do want to focus
on are developer
productivity, that's your time,
and software quality,
that's the quality that goes
into your applications.
And we can improve
both of these things
through evolving the language
and the tools that support it.
So in the realm of developer
productivity, we can do things
like find places where
there's boilerplate,
you're writing the same thing
over and over and over again,
at synthesize, at synthesize,
at synthesize, and eliminate
that from the language by
getting the right defaults.
Second, we can find other
operations that you do day in
and day out throughout many,
many different code bases
and simplify them, bring the
syntax into the language,
make them easier to use, faster
to write, faster to read.
And finally, we can
provide great tools
because you use tools to
write codes in Objective-C.
And part of this is developing
the tools themselves and part
of this is making sure that
the language itself is amenable
to building great tools.
We'll actually get back to that
with our first major feature.
The other area is
software quality
and how can we help there
through the language.
So, couple of areas.
We can try to catch
more bugs earlier.
You can do this through stronger
and better static type safety
so the compiler can reason
about the type in your program
and warn when something
is going wrong.
Next, we can find error
prone tasks, for example,
writing retain and release
everywhere, automate those away
within the compiler to eliminate
huge classes of problems.
And finally, Objective-C is a
language with a rich history.
We have a large developer
community
that has established
best practices for how
to use this language well.
And we can bring those
into the language
to help you build
better software.
Today, we're going to talk
about a couple of things.
We're going to talk about a new
Objective-C language feature
called Modules.
We're also going to talk
about better productivity
in the use of Objective-C.
And finally, some improvements
to Automatic Reference
Counting or ARC.
Modules. So, the idea behind
Modules is that if you look
at applications built
for iOS and OS X,
at the core of these
applications is the use of a ton
of really great systems
frameworks.
This is how you integrate
with services
like iCloud or with Game Center.
Maybe it's using
iAd to introduce ads
into your application or
core location services
so that you give your
user relevant content
where they at right now.
And so, this is sort of
the foundational layer
on which you build all of the
magic of your applications.
So we looked at the
process of how is it
that you use a framework.
Well, first, you go into Xcode.
You go into your coding window.
You write the #import for
the framework you want.
In this case, we're going
to pull in iAd and use
that as our demonstration.
And the name is really
important, so you see iAd twice
when you import iAd/iAd.h.
That's fine.
You start writing your
code to the iAd framework,
use some tutorial
samples and so on.
You hit Build and you get
the dreaded link error.
If this is the first time you've
seen this, this is horrifying
and you have to search to
see what actually went wrong.
But of course seasoned
developers know.
Fine, there's several
ways to fix this.
You can go edit the project,
just go over to the build
phases, just close the triangle,
hit the Plus, go find
the framework again.
We said iAd three times
now if you're counting.
Hit Add and we can actually
build our application,
not exactly wonderful.
And both of these steps
are very disjointed.
We have the #import which is
what you write in your code
and then we have the
addition of the library
which is something you
do in Xcode, elsewhere.
And so, let's go back to
the #import side of things
because #import is a
teeny tiny innovation
over the basic #include
that's been in C for three,
four decades based
on the preprocessor.
And so, we're going to look a
little bit at how the #import
and #include actually work.
So you have your application,
some .m file from it.
And what it does is it
#imports iAd.h. Fine,
what does that actually do?
Well, it resolves iAd.h and
the compiler goes and hunts
for the next thing
that iAd included
and the next thing
that that included.
Eventually, we get back to
UIKit and all of its headers
and all the things
that that brings in.
And so, really, the
dependency that you have
from your data .m is
out to a whole bunch
of different header
files within the SDK.
How does this actually
work as the language model?
Well, again, this is the C
model of the preprocessor.
It's essentially
textual inclusion
or a fancy form of
cut and paste.
So, here we have, you know,
simple .m for an app delegate.
It imports iAd.h.
What's that do?
First thing compiler does,
go find what is iAd/iAd.h
actually refers to and it comes
up with a file on disk.
Fine, it copies that
file, preprocess it,
and pastes the results
into our .m at the end.
Okay. And then what do we have?
More imports.
So we go hunt for the next file.
Take its text, copy it,
preprocess it, paste it in,
and the .m gets as
little longer.
And we go hunt for more files
and we copy and paste those in.
And once you get at the
end is one big long .m
which is what the
compiler actually sees
for each .m file in
your application.
This model has been
working for decades,
so what's wrong with it?
Well, it has two problems.
The first problem
we're going to talk
about is it's a very
fragile model.
So I'm going to do
something here
that may make a few
of you cringe.
I'm going to define a
constant read-only to 0x01
because that makes sense for
my .m, for my application code.
And I happen to do that
before #importing iAd.h. See,
preprocessor does
what its design to do.
It goes and hunts down
these files, copies them,
preprocess them,
paste the result,
and we end up with
this file up here
which is the .m the
compiler sees.
The compiler is not going to
like this .m and it's going
to complain, 0x01 is not a
valid property attribute,
it is very correct.
The really unfortunate
thing here is that the error
that you get is in
the system headers.
That's not code you wrote and
yet somehow you accidentally
broke it just by doing something
where you defined the local
constant in your header file.
And now, you can blame
me for doing this.
I'm the one that write--
wrote this code in this slide.
Clearly, it's my fault because
what I should have done is used
a prefixed very long
uppercase name for my constant
because that's what
we do with macros.
It's the convention
that we've established
within the C programming
world to cope
with this fragility problem.
And so, this doesn't
happen often
that you hit these problems.
But we do hit them
in programming.
And usually, they
come in as some sort
of header include-dependency.
Someone's header over here
didn't follow the rules.
He didn't get the memo.
And it stomps on
another header over here.
And if you include them in
one order, things work fine,
or with one version of some
framework, it works fine.
You migrate to another
version and, suddenly,
there's a conflict
that you get to debug.
If you're lucky, it manifests
an error that's fairly easy
to track down.
If you're not so lucky, it could
actually be a runtime that's
really hard to track down
for something that ends
up being just flipping
to include.
So this is a problem that we
deal with but we've been working
through it through
our conventions.
It's fine.
The real issue here, however,
is that this whole model
is inherently not scalable.
And so, to see this, we took
all of the .m files in iOS Mail
and we plot them according
to their size on disk.
So it's got, you know,
about 250 .ms here
and you can see they range
from half a kilobyte up to
about 200 kilobytes in
size with a very large skew
with really tiny files.
And we see this across the
numerous projects that you tend
to have many, many
small .m files.
Now, we've added iAd.h,
an import of iAd.h
into a fairly central header.
So what that really means
is for all these .m files,
we're not just parsing
what's in the .m file,
we're also parsing
everything that's in iAd.
iAd is a fairly small
framework and the headers come
in about 25 kilobytes.
So, for many of these
files, just the size
of iAd works the size
of the actual code
that you wrote in your .m file.
Of course, iAd isn't standalone
and everyone needs
UIKit everywhere
and UIKit is more
like 400 kilobytes.
Okay. So now, our tiny
little files which is most
of what's here are actually
going through 425 kilobytes
of header files pulling
all those
in from disk parsing
them just to get
at your tiny little bit of code.
And if you think this is bad,
this is iOS where UIKit
is actually fairly small.
So, on OS X, the Cocoa framework
that you pull in everywhere,
it's about 29 times
larger than UIKit.
So you can't even see the
.m files, your own code
in this kind of chart.
So what this presents is
inherent scalability problem.
You can't scale with
a system like this
because you have
your M source files
and you have the N headers.
That's the storage
on disk, M plus N.
But the time to compile
is M times N
because you're reparsing
every one of those headers
for all of your .m files.
And of course, both
M and N are growing
as you build your applications
and add more code to them
and as the system adds more
frameworks and APIs to them.
So clearly, it can't be this
horrible or I'll be screaming
at us to fix the
compile time issue.
And so, one of that features
that we've had for a long time
to try to solve this
is precompiled headers.
And so, precompiled headers
actually do help a lot.
The idea is fairly simple.
You take some subset of
headers that's common
across your entire project,
like maybe all of UIKit.
And you compile it once
into some efficient
on disk representation.
And then whenever
you build a .m file,
you load that representation
first,
that binary representation
that's fast,
no parsing, and start
from there.
Now, this is great
because you don't have
to parse UIKit or Cocoa.
And in fact, when you started
with your project with Xcode,
you got a precompiled
header for UIKit or Cocoa
for free as you started.
But anything else that you've
added later on, when you add
that #import of iAd.h
is still being parsed
over and over again.
You could fix this if
you really wanted to.
You could extend your
precompiled header
to include iAd.h. And now,
you're no longer
parsing this every time.
What we've seen, however,
is that developers don't
generally maintain their
precompiled headers.
A few people do and
they see more benefits
out of precompiled headers.
But most don't, partly because
they don't know about it,
partly because they don't want
to be optimizing for our tools.
But also, there's another
reason you might want to this
and that's using
precompiled headers introduces
namespace pollution.
You may not want to have iAd in
every part of your application.
It maybe fairly centralized
but putting it
into your precompiled header
makes it available everywhere.
So they're always showing
up in code completion
results, for example.
It's always available.
And so, there's principle
reasons for not wanting
to use precompiled
headers anywhere.
So Modules are designed to
solve these two problems,
the problem of the inherent
scalability problem of headers
and also the fragility
problem of headers.
So what are these Modules?
So think of them
as an encapsulation
of what a framework is.
It's API and its
corresponding implementation.
A Module is something that's
separately compiled all
the time.
So, it's compiled once and
set aside so that later
on your application
can import that Module,
get access to the API, get
access to the implementation
without having the go
through and parse the headers.
Now in support of Modules,
we introduced one
little bit of syntax.
It's the @import declaration.
What @import does is it pulls in
the API for a particular Module
which corresponds
to the framework.
So here, we're importing
the iAd frameworks API
into our application.
Now this is what we
call a Semantic Import
and it's very different from the
textual inclusion that you get
with headers 'cause
semantic import, of course,
it doesn't parse the headers
but it also doesn't let
the API that's exposed
by @import be changed by
any of your local context.
So if I do this horrible
thing that I did earlier,
# defining read-only to
0x01, it's perfectly fine.
That doesn't change or break
the API of iAd in any way.
The API you get out of the iAd
Module is exactly as the authors
of iAd intended you to get.
You can't make mistake here.
Now, Modules can be thought
of as monolithic things,
like we often think
of frameworks
as a monolithic thing.
I want to get all of the API of
iAd, but you don't have to think
about frameworks this way.
And therefore, you don't have
to think about Modules this way.
And so, we can think of Modules
as being a larger structure,
so here we have the iAd Module
and their smaller pieces
which we call submodules.
So here, we have the
ADInterstitialAd,
the ADBannerView as submodules
within the iAd module itself.
We can import just
part of a framework
by writing @import of iAd.
and then one of the
submodule names.
In this case, it's ADBannerView.
And what that does is it gives
us just the API corresponding
to ADBannerView within iAd.
So from an API perspective,
this is giving you exactly the
same thing that you would get
out of #import of
iAd/ADBannerView.h. And in fact,
the frameworks and the sub--
the framework headers and the
submodules match up exactly.
It's something you can see if
you look at code completion
for example after @import iAd.
is the submodule structure here
to get at exactly what you want
and this match up exactly what
the file names that are there.
Now, once you've used @import,
you get the API of a framework.
You also get the implementation
for free via the
Autolinking feature.
And so, once you've
switch over to Modules
and you're importing
a particular Module,
the compiler is just
going to record
in the object files it
create what Modules you used
so that we'll automatically
link against these things
and you never have
to go in-- thank you.
[ Applause ]
Right. So you should not have
to go in and then link binary
with libraries anymore.
So what does it takes
to use Modules?
We've shown the new
syntax, the @import syntax.
So Modules are an
opting feature.
So you can opt in via
build setting and I'll show
in just a few moments.
And of course, once you've
opted in, you have access
to the @import syntax.
Now, you probably have
a couple of #imports
and maybe some #includes
in your code,
maybe a handful,
hundreds, thousands.
We don't actually want you to
have to go and rewrite those,
not even automatically.
Of course, we could
migrate them.
What we really want is you
to be able to turn on Modules
and go use the feature
immediately.
And so, the way we deal
with this is we actually
automatically remapped the
#includes and the #includes
in your source code.
When those refer to a
header that we know is part
of a Module, we just treat it
as if you had written
@import all along.
And the great thing
here is you don't have
to change your source
code to use Modules.
You just need to opt in
via the build settings.
The Modules, the @import
provides the exact same API
that you got before just
through a different mechanism
that is safer and
more efficient.
Now, all of the system
frameworks in iOS 7
and OS X Mavericks are
available as Modules.
And so, when you opt in to
Modules, anything you're using
from the system, any of those
system frameworks automatically
goes through this more
efficient, safer path.
You may be wondering, how
does this actually work
under the hood?
Well, let's take a quick look.
So, the basic idea is we have
this notion of Module Maps.
And a Module Map establishes a
relationship between the headers
that are part of the framework
and have always been there,
and the actual logical
Module structure.
So here's a fragment
of a Module Map.
It defines the UIKit Module
based on the UIKit framework.
It says that to actually get
the contents of the UIKit model,
you parse the umbrella
header UIKit.h
which UIKit.h is what
you generally import.
So this is the same
API description.
And that anything that UIKit.h
itself imports becomes a
submodule within UIKit.
This is what reflects
the header structure
within the logical
Module structure.
And finally, you can
see Autolinking here
through the link framework
line here that says
when you actually use the
UIKit Module, you should link
against the UIKit framework.
Now, these Module Maps
are actually very crucial
because in our SDKs, we
don't ship Module binaries.
Instead, we ship headers
like we always have.
And when the compiler asks
for a Module, when you ask
to @import UIKit, the compiler
will find the Module Map,
it tells it how to build UIKit
and effectively spawn a
separate compilation process
to go separately compile
UIkit.h into the UIKit Module
which is then cached in
Xcode's derived data.
So the next time you come
through and ask to import UIKit,
it's already there and
it's instantaneous to load.
So this is what breaks the M
times N scalability problem
down to actually
efficient compilation model.
So let's take a quick look at
what this does to build times?
So build times, of course, build
time for an entire project.
And so, we'll talk about
a couple of projects
at different scales and with
different levels of utilization
of the precompiled
headers feature.
So Xcode is a very, very
large Objective-C project,
a lot going on in the build.
And in fact, they've been
tuning their precompiled headers
for years.
And so, what we see when
we turn on Modules is
that they don't have to change
their source code at all.
It's just a build setting.
And they get a smallish win,
a couple of percent
win in the build time.
Since they had optimized
precompiled headers,
this isn't a huge surprise.
Preview on the Mac is
actually a much smaller project
as you might expect.
Also, has fairly decent
precompiled header.
And so, you get a small
win [inaudible] larger win
out of using Modules.
Again, no source code-- yeah--
source code changes required,
so it's essentially a
free performance here.
And finally, the Mail
Application on iOS didn't have
such great use
of the precompiled headers
'cause they hadn't been actively
maintained, like most
of all operators don't actively
maintained their precompiled
headers and it's a huge
40 percent speed up just
from flipping the
switch, turning on Modules
and not doing anything
else, all right.
This is the elimination
of repeated header
processing really helping.
So now, build times or
overall project build times,
they're a little
bit messy in a sense
that we're not really
just measuring what the
compiler does.
There's a whole lot of
other things going on.
So, let's go to something
a little bit more heavy
on the parsing and
that is indexing.
When an Xcode is
indexing your project,
it's parsing all the sources
in your project so it can build
that rich cross reference
to give you more information
at your fingertips
within the IDE.
And so if we take these
same projects, indexing time
for Xcode got a bit faster,
we're in the seven
percent range or so.
Preview on the other hand got
pretty significantly faster,
so 32 percent faster
indexing time just
from switching to Modules.
And iOS Mail, as you may have
seen earlier this morning,
got 2.3 times faster
indexing just
from doing the switch
to Modules.
Hopefully, at this
point, I've convinced you,
you should at least try out
Modules, fairly easy to do.
So if you start a new
project in Xcode 5,
Modules are enabled by default.
We really thinking this is the
way forward for Objective-C
to get access to
system frameworks.
If you have an existing
project, to covert it Modules,
just go into your Build Settings
and find the Module Setting,
change it to Yes
and then Rebuild.
Nothing else is needed.
Now, if you're doing some
fancy linking tricks,
you may actually want to turn
off the Autolinking feature
in which case there is
a separate option here
where you can turn off
the Autolinking feature.
Most users shouldn't
actually need to do this.
As you may expect, there's
a couple of caveats.
So, first caveat, you
need to be using the iOS 7
or OS X Mavericks SDK.
Only those SDKs have
support for Modules.
Now, of course, you
can deploy backward
because you can use the new
SDK and deploy backward.
Modules don't change how
your code is actually built.
They don't change
for your source code.
They don't change how
your code is built.
You just need to move to
the newer SDK to get those--
essentially the Module Maps
that tell the Module
system how to work.
Second point is that
Modules aren't available C++.
Now, it's perfectly fine to
enable Modules in a C++ project.
Essentially, the fact that you
requested Modules will just be
ignored for the C++ sources,
you'll still get the benefits
of Modules for your
Objective-C sources.
The only downside here is you
can't use the fancy new @import
syntax in something
that's shared
between C++ and non-C++ code.
And finally, while Modules
are available for all
of the system frameworks,
on iOS and the Mac,
they're not available
for user frameworks.
So, let's wrap up here.
We talked about this
new feature, Modules.
The idea behind Modules is to
simplify the user frameworks
so you can just get the nice
semantic import behavior
which is much harder to break
than the textual inclusion
behavior that would, so--
and this means we've essentially
eliminated all of the problems
with strange header
order dependencies
between system frameworks
and user code,
and we've eliminated the
separate link with library step
through the Autolinking
feature of Modules.
Now, Modules are
actually a lot more
than just a user convenience.
We're actually fundamentally
changing the underlying model
and how we can access
to APIs in a way
that can significantly improve
the performance of source tools.
And the very nice thing here is
that improvement
essentially comes for free.
You no longer have to tweak
your precompiled header
to get the build times.
Just use Modules and forget
about the precompiled header,
Modules will do the right thing.
And finally, you can enable
this feature without any changes
to your source code, whatsoever.
It's changing your Build Setting
and rebuilding your application.
The application doesn't change.
Your source code doesn't change.
So with that, I'd like to
turn you over to my colleague,
Dave Zarzycki to talk about
advances in Objective-C.
[applause]
>> All right.
Thanks, Doug.
So I'm going to be talking
to you about more advances
in Objective-C, some
recent, some new.
So, I'm going to be
starting off talking
about better productivity.
We're going to be
talking about tool support
for modernizing your code.
We'll be talking about
improvements in the SDK
and how they make your life
better and more productive
and generate better code.
And we'll be talking
about block return safety
and catching some common errors.
And then we'll be talking
about the runtime in your code.
And then, for the rest of
the talk, we'll be talking
about Automatic Reference
Counting.
We'll be talking about
updates we've made to it
and we've been talking--
we'll talk about improvements
in generating better warnings
that help you generate
more correct code.
So with that, let's
jump in and talk
about Tools Support
for Modernization.
Something we did recently
was adding a Refactoring Tool
to modernize your code.
It's found right
here in the Edit Menu
under the Refactoring
Submenu and you just convert
to the Modern Objective-C
Syntax.
So what does this do?
Well, it reduces a ton of
boilerplate in your code.
We have object-- more object
literals, container literals.
We have improved subscripting.
And this is covered in-depth
at last year's version
of this talk.
So let's look at
the example of this.
Here is an example of one of
my favorite jazz musicians.
Now, we do have literals.
We have string literals.
We have a lot of other things.
We need to remember how
to create a dictionary.
What factory method to call?
We need to remember the order
of the keys and the objects.
We need to remember that
they have to be objects.
And we have to remember to
nil-terminate this list.
And similarly for NSArray,
we have to remember the
right factory method to call.
And like NSDictionary, we need
to remember the nil-terminate
it.
Similarly, NSNumber
has the same problem.
We need to remember the
right factory method to call.
Is that an end?
Is it a long?
Is it a short?
We need to remember
the right one for Bool.
There's a lot of opportunity
here to reduce boilerplate.
Well, with the Refactoring Tool,
you can adopt the modern syntax.
Dictionary literals just
become @, curly brace.
Array literals become
@ square bracket.
The compiler helps you remember
keys and values and the fact
that they have to be objects.
You don't need to worry about
nil terminating the list.
And similarly, for NSNumber,
you don't need to worry
about what type it is anymore.
You can just say @
number or @ yes or @ no.
So this is a huge simplification
and we have tools to help you
about the syntax so you can
focus on writing great code
and sweeping away the details.
Similarly, we can consider
containers before the
modern syntax.
Throughout your code, you work
with containers and you have
to write this code repeatedly.
You have to remember
if in the case--
whether the key comes first
or the object comes first,
it's just a lot of boilerplate
that could be simplified.
Well, with modern
syntax, you can do that.
You can use common subscripting
syntax that's available
in a variety of languages
to access containers
in the modern SDK and
the modern syntax.
Now, there's a ton more to
modern syntax that I'm not going
to cover here and
I strongly suggest
that you watch last year's talk.
We have boxed expressions
via @ parenthesis.
We have the full intersection
with C types if you want
to understand how they work,
like shorts and chars and longs
and unsigned behavior.
We have-- we teach you how
to implement subscripting
for your own classes and you can
see this on last year's version
of this talk, number
four or five.
So with that, I'd like to
jump into SDK improvements
and how they will
improve your productivity.
So the SDK is constantly
leveraging the compiler.
It's adopting new features.
It's helping you write more
correct code, safer code,
and get better compiled time
error detection and problems
that you might be running into.
And specifically, I'd like
to call out two features
that the new SDKs have adopted
that will affect
potentially your experience
and help you write better code.
And specifically, where there--
instancetype keyword and
explicitly-typed enums.
So let's jump in and
consider with that is.
Now, some of you probably
can look at this code
and already see the bug.
We're taking an NSArray
and we're assigning it
to an NSDictionary variable.
That's terrible.
But, copy and paste
errors are easy.
Refactoring are easy.
And in fact, now with the
SDKs worshipping this,
you will actually get a warning
pointing out the problem.
So how is it that the compiler
knows if we have a problem?
When previous versions
of the SDK,
array and many similar
APIs returned IDE.
The problem is that IDE
implicitly converts to anything,
so the compiler didn't
historically know
that there was a problem here.
In the new SDK, array
returns instancetype.
This is a contextual keyword.
It's only for return types.
And subclasses don't need
to redeclare array here
to expose the fact that
they're returning an instance
of their subclass.
And finally, the compiler
contextually matches the return
type to that other receiver.
Okay, well what does that mean?
Let's consider our
subclassing NSArray.
And let's say we create
a class name Foobar.
We don't do anything more.
We just put in @end.
And what happens in this code
now that we're taking a Foobar
and calling array and this
signage NSDictionary variable?
Well, the compiler would still
print out the warning, great.
But I'd like to point out is
that the compiler is
contextually taking the receive
type Foobar and printing
out the warning pointing
out that the return
value is also a Foobar,
and that's the source
of the problem.
So that's the instancetype
keyword.
Next up, I'd like to talk
about explicitly-typed enum.
Another feature that the SDK
has adopted that will show
up in your code and help
you detect more errors
and be more productive.
So let's look at this code.
Some of you that have experience
with URLs may already
see the bug.
These are not the same enum.
We have an NSURLHandleStatus
on the left.
We have an NSURLSessionTaskState
on the right.
Whoops. Well, again, copy
and paste errors are easy
and refactoring errors
are really easy.
And the reason this is used
to compile in the past is
that enums are essentially
just global integers.
So, we're just assigning
one number to another.
Well now, with the SDKs, you
will get a warning pointing
out that these are
of different types
which is exactly what you want.
So how does the compiler know?
In the past, we declared
enums like this.
In one line, we would declare
the enum and enumerate,
you know, ABC, JKL, XYZ.
And the next line, we
declare a typedef where we say
that what the storage is
and then give it a name.
Well, this is where the
first line is just mint.
We haven't actually bound the
two pieces of information here.
And how we fixed this in the SDK
and with the compiler is the
compiler supports a new feature
for explicitly-typed enums.
What you can see here
on the first line is we've
actually moved the storage up
and now the enum knows
what its storage type is
and then now it's no longer
an int, it's an NSUInteger.
Now in the next line,
we actually bind or enum
to a type available for use.
This is all covered last year
in-depth and this version--
in this talk last year.
Now, the Cocoa team have
provided convenient macros
that exposed this feature.
We have NS Enum for a
traditional enumerations,
like we just demonstrated.
You know, ABC, JKL, XYZ.
And they also have a
convenient macro for NS Options.
So, a bit wise operations,
like, you know, different flags.
So I recommend the use of these
macros and you'll see them
in the system frameworks.
But we don't stop
with just warnings.
We also improved code
completion with NS Enum
and explicitly-typed enums.
So before NS Enum, if you tried
to code complete our
example enumeration here
and you typed X, you would see
a bunch of XPC-related APIs
and you wouldn't see your enum.
That's not fun.
Well, if we just switch to
the NS Enum macro and then get
up the compiler feature,
Code Completion gives
us exactly what we want
and we see our enumeration
available
in Code Completion
which is great.
But it just doesn't--
it doesn't stop there.
The power of explicitly-typed
enums manifest in multiple ways.
So in this particular
case, we have an NSArray
that we're trying to
sort using a comparator.
And we do some logic
and then we decide
to return ascending
or descending.
Now if you look closely,
we actually haven't specified
the return type of this block
between the caret and
the opening parenthesis.
And the compiler would actually
give us an error saying that,
"Well, we infer the type of
this block as returning int
but the API actually takes
NS-- comparison result."
All right.
Well, how do we fix this?
Before explicitly-typed
enums, we have the Cast, thus,
assigning the correct type.
And yes, this would
make the warning go away
but now we have this lingering
cast in our code that, you know,
could create future problems.
Because the explicitly-typed
enums allow us to fix this
and make the enum how
many explicit-type,
we can help you avoid casting
and in fact you can now go
and delete these
casts and go back
to the natural looking
code you wanted to have
in the first place and
write it as intended.
Digging deeper on what
NS Enum can do for you,
let's consider the fact
of how implicitly-typed enums
can manifest in different ways.
Again, before explicitly-typed
enums,
these two URL-related enums
that are actually different
were just ints as far
as the compiler was concerned.
And this manifested as a
silent bug in your code.
Now with NS Enum, you get
the warning that you want
and now you have to
decide how to fix the code.
Now, here, this is pointing
out a design problem
so that there is
no quick solution.
You'd have to think about
it and actually figure
out what you originally
intended.
So with that, now
I'd like to move
on to the Objective-C
Runtime and you.
The Objective-C Runtime is
the core of the language.
It enables a ton of
dynamic behavior.
We have, you know, of course,
dynamic method dispatch.
We have object introspection.
We have object proxies.
And we have dynamic
class construction,
even a dynamic method
replacement.
The runtime enables a ton of
innovation in the language.
We've added many
features over the years
and it's really the heart
of all these features.
So to give you an example, we've
added a new key-value observing,
associated objects, we've added
@synchronized to do locking,
we've added weak references,
we've added tagged pointers,
and the list go on, on and on.
I'd like to actually call
out tagged pointers though
because we have some new
warnings to enable innovation.
So, let's first dive deep
and ask the question,
what are tagged pointers?
They were added in 64-bit Cocoa
for a small value-like objects.
And examples of a
value-like objects are
like NSNumber, NSDate,
just values.
What we're doing is we're
actually storing the object
in the pointer itself,
so we don't actually need
to call malloc or free.
And when you don't call
malloc or free, you could've--
code gets a ton faster and
it's more space efficient.
It's three times more
space efficient and it's
over 100 times faster
to allocate
and deallocate these
small value-like objects.
Okay, it's great in theory
but I'm a visual person.
Show me how this actually works.
In a normal pointer,
we're actually only
using the top 60 bits.
The bottom four bits of
a pointer are always zero
because objects are
always 16-byte aligned.
We can take advantage
of this fact
to implement what we call tagged
pointers where we actually store
in the bottom bit discriminators
and when it's one,
we can actually store a ton of
data in the rest of the bits.
And this is in fact what we do.
Having said all this, this
is an implementation detail.
Some of you have
discovered this feature
and we need you to
undiscover it.
[laughter] The runtime
details are private.
And in fact, what
remaining little tidbits
of data structures you're
finding that are still public
in the data structures
are becoming private.
Most URI-- applications
are well behaved
and we thank you for that.
Use APIs to instropect things
and this lets us
innovate considerably
as we've already described.
But we've added some new
warnings to detect the use
of tagged pointers and a related
problem of Raw 'isa' access.
So, you might have code
like this in your program
where you're testing the tag bit
and then you are like, "Great,
I have discovered the tag bit
isn't set, I'm just going to run
in there and just access
the isa directly and--
because I'm think I'm
optimizing, this is fun."
But in the case when
the tag bit is set,
you actually called
the correct API.
Well now, you're going to get a
warning for that tag bit check.
And you're actually
going to get an error
for the direct usage of the isa.
Well how do you fix this?
You delete the testing of that
bit and direct that access
to the isa and you actually call
like it isKindOfClass
or object getClass.
We really need you to do this
so we can unlock the
next level of innovation.
And failure to do so, might
break your code in the future.
So please, heed these warnings
and errors in your code
and do the right thing.
Thank you.
Finally on the runtime part
of this talk, I'd like to talk
about Garbage Collection.
GC only exists on the Mac.
We have replaced it with ARC
and in fact we deprecated
Garbage Collection as of 10.8.
We're very serious about this.
We're not supporting Garbage
Collection in new frameworks,
things like AVKit or Accounts
or GameController or GameKit,
et cetera, et cetera, we're not
supporting Garbage Collection.
We really need you to
use the ARC Migrator
to transition off GC.
So with that, let's talk about
Automatic Reference Counting
and tell you about updates we've
been doing and some improvements
to help you write better code.
Let's start with the updates.
Cocoa is designed with reference
counting semantics in mind.
This is great.
Being able to deterministically
know
when an object is
destroyed allows you
to better reason
about your code.
It allows you to
better schedule things.
It allows you to better design.
And it's also just
great for debugging.
ARC also helps you
write great code.
It allows you to focus on what
matters and not the minutia
of details of when things
need to be released.
The majority of new App Store
submissions are using ARC.
So a lot of you also agree that
this is a really great tool
for focusing on what matters.
Specific-- another great
example of ARC is Xcode 5.0.
This used to be a GC app.
It was a large app.
Nevertheless, we were
able to convert it
to Automatic Reference Counting
and we're thrilled
with the results.
We're thrilled with
the better determinism.
We love the better debugging.
We love that we're able to offer
tons of better performance.
And we hope that you'll
find the same experience.
Speaking of performance,
we are continuing
to improve the performance
of ARC.
Weak references are
now about twice as fast
and this year's version
of our operating system
iOS 7 and 10.9 for the Mac.
And we're also improving the
debug experience as well.
We have more predictable memory
usage under debug builds.
Specifically, the lifetime
of autoreleased objects is
much more like released builds.
Now when you autorelease
an object,
you don't necessarily
know when it goes away.
And in fact, ARC
optimizations could kick in
and change that timing.
We've improved the compilers
so the debug builds now
release the object much more
like when released builds and
we hope you appreciate that.
[applause] So this is our
great [inaudible] ARC.
Well, we have Migrator.
It does all the heavy
lifting for you.
It removes retain,
release, autorelease.
It deletes empty dealloc methods
if all your dealloc method
was doing was calling release,
release, release.
It converts NSAutoreleasePool
to @autoreleasepool
in the modern syntax.
But you have to do the rest.
You need to reason about some
rare things like id in structs.
Usually the easiest thing to
do is convert these to classes
and then, you know,
your code looks prettier
in the end anyway.
You also need to reason
about some atypical uses
of memory management APIs.
This was covered
in depth last year
in the Automatic
Reference Counting talk
and you can get all
the details there.
But if you don't have time
to jump back to the video,
here's what you need to do.
Just like with modern syntax,
you can go to the Edit Menu,
go to the Refracturing Submenu,
and you can convert to ARC
and let the tools help
you along the way.
So ARC and your app, we really
want you to switch to ARC
by default and focus on what
matters which is your app
and writing great code.
You can always opt out specific
files if you run into problems.
So you can just go to the
Profile Build Settings
and select the Compiler
Flag for turning off ARC.
And I'd also like to point
out that the ARC Migrator
supports both manual reference
counting code and
garbage-collected code
and it helps you migrate both
easily and straight forward.
Now for an update on
new things we've added
that we think you will love.
Let's talk about some new memory
management warnings we have
added to help you better
reason about life under ARC.
So, there are three things
I'm going to be talking about
and we're going to be talking
about the implicit referencing
of self and retain
cycles with blocks.
We're going to be talking about
repeated use of a weak variable
and what does that even mean.
And then thirdly, we'll be
talking about sending messages
to weak and had a better reason
about the behavior thereof.
So let's jump in first and
talk about retain cycles.
As a brief refresher,
let's imagine your app is
just referencing an object.
The reference count of this
object will start out is one.
And similarly, if that object
references another object,
that will be one.
But, if we actually
have a reference back
to the original object, its
reference count would be two.
And if our app lets go of
the object, we have a leak
because now these two
objects are holding references
on to each other and
keeping the object alive.
So with that in mind,
let's look at some code.
Let's say in a method you
have two instance variables.
And one of the instance
variables holds the block
and the other one
is just an object.
It doesn't really
matter what kind.
In the block we use ivar2,
and then we assign
the block to ivar1.
Well what's actually
going on under the covers
and how the compiler reasons
about this is we have
implicit use of self
in both of these cases.
And those are the actual
objects in question
that we need to think about.
So let's delete that and then
see what warning the compiler
can now print out.
So I've enabled this warning,
the compiler will print out,
they were capturing self
strongly in the ivar2 case,
and then it points
out the related case
where it believes
the cycle began.
Well, again, I'm
a visual person,
but show what this
looks like in practice.
So we have an instance of
our class and we have ivar2.
Again, ivar2 can be any
object, string, whatever.
And now we're creating
this block.
Now when we wrote the code,
it may look like this.
It may look like we're just
assigning the block to ivar1
and we're using ivar2.
What's the problem?
I don't see any cycle.
Well because there is
an implicit use of self,
the block is actually
retaining self.
And now we have a cycle and now
it's indirectly accessing ivar2.
And again, we'll
get the same leak
that we demonstrated earlier
if we let go of the instance
of our class, the
block will be keeping
that instance alive
and we have a leak.
So let's go back to the
code and the warning.
How do we fix this?
Well we make some room and
we add a weak variable.
So what we do is we create
a weak variable on the stack
and assign self to it.
And this variable is an instance
of the same type of our class.
And then what we do is we use
this weak variable in our block.
And if we do that,
the warning goes away.
So what's going on here?
Weak variables do not extend
the lifetime on objects.
They are-- and therefore,
they don't implicitly
create retain cycles.
And the great thing about weak
variables is they safely become
nil when the reference count
of the object they're
referring to drops to zero.
Now in this particular
case, they are tied together
so we don't have a problem.
But it allows us
to break the cycle
and actually get
the paper we want
when we release the
instance of our class.
So building on this, let's talk
about weak variables in general.
Consider this simple method
where we're logging the
description of a weak ivar.
Does this method
even called call?
What happens if the weak is nil?
You know, what actually
happens here?
How do we reason
about this at all?
Well, now the compiler
can warn about this saying
that we're using weak variable
and it may unpredictably be nil.
Well what do we do about this?
Well, it's actually
worst than that.
It can get-- we can have a
weak variable and use it twice.
Does this get called
zero, one or two times?
You know, how do we
reason about this?
Well there's actually a
solution for both of these
and I'd like to-- oh, sorry.
In the repeated use case, we
now have a specific warning
for that too pointing
out that, you know,
you can't actually reason about
the zero, one or two case.
[ Pause ]
So let's go back to the original
code and the original warning
and look at how we fix this.
Let's make some room and
do as the compiler advices
and put a local strong
variable on the stack,
assign our weak variable
into it.
And once we've done that,
that strong variable is
either nil or not nil.
It's not going to
change magically
out from underneath us.
And because we know that,
we can now test for it.
And if it's not nil, we can now
safely print the description.
And if we do that, of
course, the warning goes away.
So this is great.
We now can reason about the
lifetime of this variable.
And the great thing too is
handling the nil case becomes
very obvious.
We just add the else block
and do the right thing.
Next up in the Automatic
Reference Counting Improvements,
I'd like to talk
about the relationship
between ARC and CoreFoundation.
If you've already
been using ARC,
you may have been writing a code
like this every time you
interact with CoreFoundation.
You have a CFDictionary,
getting some value out of it.
And in order to help ARC reason
about the object lifetime,
we use a bridge cast saying
that there's no net change
in the reference count here.
This is required because
anytime we come in and out
of the ARC system, we
need the ARC compiler
to actually be tracking
the reference count
so that way objects live
only as long as they need to,
and no longer and no shorter.
We have a +1-- you can express
+1 to ARC via CFBridgingRetain.
You can express a decrement
of the reference count
via CFBridgingRelease.
And you can express a no
net change via bridge cast.
Well, you know, it's
great that we're using ARC
and we've been able
to make our CF code
and our Foundation
code work together,
but can we improve
this situation?
Well, CoreFoundation
actually has some really
strong conventions.
Create and copy methods
return +1
and everything else returns +0.
And in fact, we already have
some compiler attributes
for the exceptions,
like CF RETUNS RETAINED
and CF RETURNS NOT RETAINED and
CF releases argument for APIs
that consume their argument.
And these are there to
help the static analyzer
and you may have already
seen this kick in,
in your use of the
static analyzer.
Well, what if we can just
use these conventions
to make this bridge
cast go away?
In fact, we've formalized
the everything else cast now.
The common CF APIs you use
now allow implicit bridging
as opposed to this
explicit bridging.
[ Applause ]
There are new macros
available for use too.
And with that, I'd like to
show you how this works.
So, how do we enable
implicit bridging?
Let's imagine we're wrapping
a CoreFoundation Array
and we have our example
Foo that--
we have just bunch of
wrappers around the array.
Well the first API we
have here is great.
It follows the convention
as copying the name.
We don't need to do anything.
The second API is also great.
We don't need to anything
because it follows
the convention.
It returns +1.
It doesn't consume
any arguments.
But our third API, we don't
know what we were thinking.
We decided that we're going
to return retained and--
but we're following
the convention.
Well, what we need to do is put
a CF RETURNS RETAINED attribute
there via macro and let the
compiler know what's going on.
Even if we just stop
here and do this,
we've already help the static
analyzer reason about our code.
But once we're done auditing,
what we can do is
add these macros,
CF IMPLICIT BRIDGING ENABLED and
CF IMPLICIT BRIDGING DISABLED
to tell the compiler
that we've audited code.
Now, this must be
after all #includes.
Obviously, you're not
auditing somebody else's code.
You're auditing your code.
And you don't have to
do it around everything.
If there's code you don't
want to think about right now,
you could have the explicitly
bridge code remain outside
of the macros they are using.
And that is implicit bridging
and this is all the
common CF plist types
or have been auditing and you
can go remove this bridge cast
from your code if you're
using the new SDKs.
So to wrap up, we have Modules.
This is really great for finally
fixing the textual inclusion
problem and all the
associated bugs.
It also adds great performance
for compilation time
and indexing.
And it's just a much more
pleasurable experience
with features like Autolinking.
We also have improved
productivity
with better compiler warnings
throughout the SDK adoption
of these compiler warnings to
help you catch errors early
and write more productive code.
And with ARC, we've made
it better and faster
by allowing you to better
reason about simple retain cycle
and weak reference bugs,
and also easier in the fact
that you no longer need
to write bridge cast
for common CF plist types.
For more information,
I'd like to point you
at Dave DeLong, our evangelist.
We also have tons
of documentation
on the developer website and
of course the Developer Forums.
We have two labs,
one tomorrow morning
and one Thursday afternoon.
Oh sorry, related sessions.
We have What's New
in LLVM Compiler,
it happened earlier today, you
have to catch them on video.
But tomorrow, we have
Optimize Your Code Using LLVM
in Nob Hill at 3:30.
So, thanks for coming.
[ Applause ]