[ Silence ]
>> Sal Soghoian: Welcome to
WWDC and especially welcome
to the first session
on automation today.
We have two.
This one's an overview of
all the new different things
in automation, and there's
a lot to talk about today.
I'll be joined in this
presentation by Chris Nebel.
He's the Senior Automation
Engineer and, when he comes back
from being wired up,
he'll stand over here
and do some of the demos.
But, like I said, we
have a lot to talk about.
There's been a lot of
work and a lot of changes,
and I think you're going to
enjoy some of these things.
So let's begin.
So what's new in the
world of automation?
Well, without actually just
bullet pointing the whole list,
we're going to be talking about
Automator and AppleScript.
Especially we're going to
introduce some new features.
They're very powerful.
Some of them are
pretty dramatic.
I think you're going to find
that they become your
favorite things to work with.
And we're going to look at
multiple computer file access.
We'll be looking at some
security transparency issues,
some new OS X integration
that we've created,
and getting your
computer to pay attention
to what you want
it to do for you.
So those are my mystery
topics here, and we'll begin
with the simplest
multicomputer file integration
which is iCloud support,
specifically documents
in the Cloud.
Now, you're all familiar
with how this works.
You can create a
document on one computer.
You store it in the Cloud, and
it automatically gets pushed
to another computer using
your same iCloud account.
Now, through the magic of
automation and iCloud support,
we've incorporated this into the
AppleScript Editor, and it works
in the same way that
you're used to working
with other applications
that have document
in the Cloud support.
You can drag your favorite
scripts and applets right
into the iCloud window.
They'll automatically load
and go up to the server.
And then you can search based
upon tags that you've applied:
key words, names,
those kind of things.
And, in addition, you can
use some of the resources
of the iCloud viewer to sort
and organize your scripts
and to be able to use the
shared menu to send them,
share them over iDrop,
AirDrop or iMessage
or something like that.
So here's an AirDrop example
where you're taking something
from your Cloud and
you're sharing it across.
Hello there.
And we've incorporated this,
too, for Automator as well.
So not overly dramatic,
but you know what?
Being a script hoarder like
me, I'm actually starting
to like having one
place that I can go
to where I know I'll
find what I'm looking for
and copy it to the machine.
It's been very, very useful.
I think you're going
to find it useful too;
and you'll soon make
this just part
of your normal everyday
life with the editors.
Next we're going to look at
automation applets and security.
So the other day I get
an email from a friend
of mine, Trudy Anchover.
She's head of the --
she's Director for the
Bay Area Forest Scouts,
and she was at a
conference with me.
She saw me demonstrate
this little photo droplet.
And she asked me in
an email, you know,
Can you share that with me?
It would really help me out.
So I didn't think
twice about it.
I just, you know, instantly
replied in an email message
to her, addressed
the email message.
I found the droplet, added it
to the email message,
and sent it to her.
I didn't think twice about this.
And then I send it to Trudy.
So when Trudy gets it on her
machine, she takes the droplet
from mail, drags
it to the desktop,
and is ready to use the droplet.
She selects an image and drags
it on top of the droplet.
And, instead of getting
processing,
she gets this dialog saying
that this droplet can't be run
because it's from an
unidentified developer
and that her settings
for security are set
to only use apple --
applets from the Apple Store
or from known developers.
Now, that's because,
in the Security
and Privacy Control Panel, she's
using a default setting which is
for Mac App Store and
identified developers.
Trudy's not a particularly
sophisticated user,
and so she doesn't know how
to bypass this or anything.
It just -- to her,
it's just broken.
And it's really my fault because
I forgot a very important thing
is that Automator and
AppleScript droplets
and applets are applications.
And, because they are
applications, they're subject
to the same level
of security scrutiny
as any other application
on the OS.
So, in order for them
to function correctly,
they really do need to be signed
to be Gatekeeper approved.
And you can try doing
that with the Terminal
and some magic commands,
if you like;
but now in Mavericks we are
introducing code signing support
built into our editing apps.
[ Applause ]
Yeah. Really nice.
And it requires that you have,
you know, your developer ID,
which you do, and that you
have the Xcode installed
with the command line tools.
And, since we're
all developers here,
you're used to this concept
because you've been preparing
your apps for the Store anyway.
So you're used to
sending out signed copies.
And you already have
your developer ID
and certificates
installed into the keychain.
So, once you do, then you
can use this new feature.
And let me show you
what it looks like.
Here, in the AppleScript Editor,
I'm going to export
the droplet for Trudy.
And so I go to the File
menu and choose Export.
And when I do, I get
the dropdown sheet.
You'll notice that there's a
new pop-up menu at the bottom
of the Save sheet and
it says code sign.
It's for code signing
and, by default,
it's set to don't code sign.
But if you do click
that pop-up menu,
all of your developer
identities that are installed
on that computer will
appear in this list.
It's just simply a
matter at that point
of choosing the identity
that you want
and then clicking the Save
button, and it will save a copy
of that droplet or applet
signed ready to deliver.
So, if I had done this for
Trudy, she wouldn't have had any
of the problems that
she came across.
For Automator, it's
a similar process.
So here I have a workflow
open in Automator.
This is one I use for
video editing quite a bit
and creating a compressed
video version from raw source.
And so, to do the same export,
I just go to the File
menu, choose Export.
I get the Save sheet
in Automator.
And at the bottom
of the Save sheet
in Automator is also a
code sign pop-up menu.
Again, I can select from that
menu the developer identity
that I'm looking for, pick
that, and then just click Save.
The applet will be saved
to wherever I indicated,
and it's signed and
ready to be distributed.
It's really that
easy to use these.
And, to show you that, I'm going
to turn to my friend Chris Nebel
and have Chris demonstrate.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
>> Chris Nebel: Thank you, Sal.
So let's take a look at how
Maverick makes it easier
to code sign your workflows,
applets, applications
so you can distribute
them to other users.
So I've got an applet
I've been working on here.
Notice getting this
out of iCloud.
It's working on another machine.
And I worked long and
hard on this applet.
I'm very proud of it.
I'm ready to send
it out to the world.
And, historically, what I
would do is I'd just, you know,
stick this in an email
message, send it off,
and the other person
would grab it from there.
So I have an applet
that simulates uploading
and downloading it, so it will
pop up in the Downloads folder.
And, if I open this now, I get
this dialog, and it's saying
that it can't open
this because it's
from an unidentified developer.
This is the default Gatekeeper
policy on everyone's system.
And OK here doesn't mean
"okay, go ahead and run it".
It means "okay, we're done".
There's nothing to do here.
This applet simply won't run.
And there is a workaround.
You can Control click on the
applet, open the long way
and you'll get a
different dialog.
But, for most users, as far
as they're concerned,
it's busted, right?
All they can really do
is throw it in the trash.
So how do I -- how do I make
life easier on my users here
and not have them think
I'm a complete idiot
for sending them broken applets?
So, in Mountain Lion, we
added an Export command
to Script Editor.
The whole point of Export is
to save the script
for distribution.
In Mountain Lion, the main thing
that it did was it allows you
to save the script as run only,
taking that out of the Save
As dialog because who here has
accidentally saved a run-only
copy of their script
over their real one?
Uh-huh. I thought so.
So Export makes that
a little harder to do.
And now, in Mavericks,
here's run only
but here also is code sign.
So last year we showed you
how to do this in Terminal,
but now it's built right
into Script Editor
and into Automator.
And so, if I pick my --
my developer ID here,
I will save that to the desktop.
Yes, I want to allow this.
So now I have my
code-signed version.
If I up and download
that and run it,
now I get a different dialog.
It says this is downloaded
from the Internet.
Gatekeeper is still not too
sure about this Internet thing.
Kind of new.
But now it's Cancel
and it's Open.
So, if I open, it goes
ahead and run -- and runs.
[ Applause ]
So that is how -- so code
signing will make your
life easier.
Mavericks makes your life
easier code signing your applets
because it's now built right
into the editor you're
already using.
And it makes life easier on your
user because they don't have
to worry about long
hand waves of dealing
with nonsigned applets.
Sal, back to you.
>> Sal Soghoian: Thank you.
So it works with Automator
and AppleScript applets
and droplets.
They're applications.
You have to remember
that, if you're going
to distribute them now that
we have Gatekeeper, it --
its default settings,
you might want
to just quickly do an export.
Code signing will even
save it as run only
if you like to as well.
And this has all
been integrated.
You can see it's a
very simple process.
Take advantage of it.
Next we're going to talk
about extending the
power of AppleScript.
And we're going to be doing that
with something that's brand new,
and it's called AppleScript
libraries.
Now, why libraries?
Well, I assume that
many of you are like me.
You're the kind of person
has hundreds and hundreds
of your favorite routines that
you've written over and over
and over for lots of different
situations and scenarios,
and you want to be able to
use those in multiple scripts.
So I have four or five things if
I have a script that's dealing
with text I'm going
to be pasting these
in the bottom part of my script.
Now, if you also are the
type of person that relies
on third-party scripting
additions
to provide a missing command
like especially something
with text handling, you're
going to like libraries.
And if you just want to
simplify your scripts,
you're going to like libraries.
Now, it started for me by having
a routine that I like to use,
and then I started using
it in multiple scripts.
And it was quite useful.
I would just copy this
thing from, like a clipping.
I would paste in.
Then I found another
routine that I used,
and then I would paste that into
some of the scripts that I had.
But then I started changing
some of the routines
and then I added new ones and
then it just became this thing
of I couldn't keep track of all
the different stuff that I had.
So new in Mavericks we're
introducing AppleScript
libraries that will
help address this issue.
And what they are is a
new plug-in architecture
for AppleScript that allows you
to create your own libraries
of commands and gives you
quick and easy access to them
without having to go
through a bunch of --
of hoo-ha to get
to your handlers.
Now, they're different
than scripting editions
in a couple ways.
First of all, you can
write them in AppleScript.
You don't have to write
these in C or C++.
You can write them
in AppleScript.
And they're controlled by the
script that's calling them,
so that manages your
script libraries.
It means that the
library is only loaded
and it's only available when
your script tells it to load.
And it helps avoid
terminology conflicts that way.
It helps deal with resources.
And the script library
commands are run
by the process that's
executing the script.
So it's a lot smoother
to deal with.
In addition, these
libraries can take advantage
of AppleScript Objective-C,
so the wealth
of the Cocoa frameworks
and all of those classes
and methods now come into
play in the libraries
that you write yourself.
You can use some AppleScript
Objective-C and talk
to the NS string class and use
some of its methods as well.
In addition, your libraries can
contain their own terminology.
They can publish
their own terminology.
So you can make custom terms
that represent the
complex handlers
that are parts of your library.
Yes. It's really, really nice.
So, instead of remembering a
handler name, I can just put
in some terminology and
it will work perfectly.
Now, in support of that, we've
created two new constructs.
The first is something
that we're calling a
script library reference.
And what it does is it
does a couple of functions.
It locates the script
library for you automatically
and prepares it for loading
and use in your script.
The second is something
brand new.
It's called a use clause,
and it is really a command
for importing terminology
and making it globally
available in your script.
Very powerful.
A lot of fun to use.
Let's take a look at this.
So, in its simplest
form, simplest form,
an AppleScript library can
just be in AppleScript routine
that you have like this
simple routine here
for converting the
case of some text
from uppercase to lowercase.
You can have this very
simple AppleScript handler
that you've created.
You take that, you
place it into a script.
Then you compile it.
You save it.
And, in this case, you just
save it as a script file.
Next, in your home
library folder,
you create a new folder
called script libraries
and then drag your script file,
your new script library,
into that folder.
Now you've installed it
into the script library,
AppleScript library system.
That's all you have to do.
So, to use it, it's just a
matter of typing the word
"script" followed by the
name of your library.
And you don't have to
use .scbt or anything,
just the name of your library.
And, when you compile this,
it becomes a script
library identifier.
That is now a representation
of your script library.
The AppleScript architecture
automatically located it
in the script libraries folder.
It's prepared it,
ready for load.
And now that it's an identifier,
you can target it using a
tell verb or a tell block
like this example where
I will be calling one
of the subroutines or
one of the handlers
within that library
script, pass it some text --
how now brown cow -- and
use a numeric indicator
to indicate I want uppercase.
So when this gets run,
the library is loaded,
the information is passed,
and the results come back
to you automatically.
Very simple way to
make a library.
Just very functional
but easy to do,
easy to install,
and easy to use.
Now, in its more advanced forms,
a library can have
its own terminology.
And here is the dictionary
window
for an AppleScript library.
It has a single suite, and the
suite is called AppleScript
Text Utilities.
This suite has two commands
in it: one for changing,
transforming text; one
for replacing text.
It has a definition for the
suite and shows the definition
for each one of the
individual commands.
So in an advanced
form of a library,
you can have this
terminology available for you
and for your customers and
for everybody else to use.
So no longer are you calling
a handler name or having
to remember a handler name.
Instead, you can now use
terminology like transform text,
how now brown cow to uppercase.
And this will function
exactly the same way
as a library did before.
Now, that's in the
more advanced format.
So here's an example
script talking
to the Finder application,
and this contains a
tell block addressing an
AppleScript library.
You can see it right
there where it's going
to basically take the name
of some selected folders
in the Finder, and it's
going to iterate all
of these folders getting
their lowercase names
and converting them
to uppercase names.
So that's the purpose
of the script.
Now, you'll notice that, by
having an individual tell block
for every time I want to talk to
this library, in a small script
like that, I can
get away with it.
But, in a larger script where
you repeatedly might go back
and refer to this library,
that's a little clunky
to deal with.
In addition, there's
another issue going on here.
You'll notice that there
is a variable called
"adjusted name" that's
actually going
to store the transformation
result, hold it for a second
because it was within a tell
block, and then use it later
on in the script for the
Finder to assign the name
of the selected item to
that transformed name.
So you're doing this
little dance
because of this tell block.
And, again, this makes
it a little clunkier.
It works, but it's
not smooth syntax.
So we've come up with
something to address this issue.
And I'm just going to make
a little room at the top
of the script, and were going
to insert something new.
It's called a use clause.
And this use clause is
an importing command
that says "Use this library."
There's a script
library identifier.
And that means it will take it,
load it, and make its resources
and handlers available
for the script globally.
So, because I have a use
clause here, I don't need
to have the tell block around my
statement that calls my library.
I can remove that.
And I can also deal with
that little back and forth
about having you create a
variable to store the contents
of the command and then reapply
it and instead put everything
on one line so that the
Finder can say "Set the name
of the selected file to the
results of this transformation."
And then it just becomes one
seamless, transparent line.
So we can go from
this little clunkiness
to a very smooth example with
this new use clause ability.
And it works the same
way as anything else.
It works totally smooth.
It's transparent.
Now, let's talk about the
use clause for just a second.
It's about importing
terminology, and it allows you
to import the terminology
of script libraries
and applications.
So the importing commands,
when you import an
applications terminology
or a script libraries
terminology,
they are available
globally through the script.
You no longer have to address
that application
or that library.
It's not necessary.
And you can also use this use
-- use clause to specify the use
of a particular version
of AppleScript
or a particular version
of an application
or even a particular
version of a script library.
And it sure does make --
streamline the script
syntax that you have.
It makes things easier to
see, conceive, and use.
So here to show you the
use clause is my friend,
Chris Nebel.
>> Chris Nebel: Okay.
I personally am really
excited about this feature.
This is, like, my favorite
AppleScript feature
in a long time.
It's one of those ones
that makes you wonder why
it didn't always work this
way [laughter].
So let's see how it
affects an actual script.
So I am the team mom --
that's the actual job title --
for my neighborhood soccer team.
Basically, it's handle all
the administrative stuff
so the coach doesn't have to.
And part of the job is
forwarding email around.
Someone -- someone on the
team sends me an email.
I have to send it out to
the rest of the group.
But the rules are
a little tricky.
I want to send it to everyone
else in the group except
for the original sender.
Them, I want to Cc.
And mail can almost
do this but not quite.
If you put an address book or
contacts group in the To field,
it can expand it out
to all the people.
But then it's up to me to
actually find the right person
and pull them over
to the Cc group.
It gets a bit out of -- it
gets a bit messy after a while,
especially when you have
to do ten of these a day.
So -- but, automation, one
of the things it's for is
for filling in the gaps when the
system almost does what you want
but not quite.
So here's the script that I
wrote to handle this for me.
So we tell application mail get
the current selected message;
forward that message.
It creates a new forwarding
message ready to be filled in.
And then we flip
over to Contacts.
I have a group defined
Neighborhood Team so --
with every person in that group,
filled out an email address
for them, and then we flip
back to application mail.
And, if the sender of the
original message contains
that name, then we want to
add them as a Cc recipient;
otherwise, it's a To recipient.
And this works well enough.
Let's see it in action.
And the message was
originally from John.
He's been Cc'd.
Everyone else, it goes "To."
So, obviously, the script works.
But you notice the sort
of back and forth tell --
tell this, tell this, tell
that, tell this, tell that.
And that's very typical of
any script when you're talking
to more than one application.
You have to flip back and
forth between them a lot.
So wouldn't it be nice if the --
if AppleScript could figure
out which application you're
actually talking to just
by the terms that you're using.
Well, that's pretty
much what use does.
Let's look at how
the script changes.
So two use statements
at the top.
The first one is
application mail,
and I'm also defining
a shorthand name
for it that I can use later.
It's essentially a property
whose value is application mail.
I'm also going to use
application contacts.
The first line is
pretty much the same.
Get the selection of mail.
I have to specify that
it's mail selection
because contacts
has a selection to.
So got to be explicit there.
But then we can forward
the message.
And notice there's
no tell block here.
The compiler knows that,
forward, mail is the only thing
that defined forward; so
it will send that to mail.
And then we repeat with
every person in a group.
No tell blocks again
because it knows that person
in group are defined by
contacts and not by mail.
You're building up the
mail address if the sender
of the original message were
actually getting this straight
from mail instead
of prefetching it,
and this actually
comes from contacts.
We're mixing two applications
in the same statement making you
to Cc or To recipient.
And, again, there's no
tell blocks anywhere here.
And, yet, it works
exactly the same.
[ Pause ]
So, essentially, what use
does is it lets you get rid
of all the bookkeeping that
the computer really ought
to be able to do for you.
Notice that this script, this
new script, is much narrower
than the original one.
It gets rid of all
the tell blocks
so you can concentrate just
on your application logic
and not have to worry
so much about exactly
which application
you're telling to do what
because AppleScript should
be able to do that for you.
Now it can.
[ Applause ]
>> Sal Soghoian: Yeah.
It's going to take me
a while to wrap my head
around all the different places
I can use the use clause,
but I'm very excited by
it because I've been able
to do some really
interesting things
in a single line statement
that it would usually
take me multiple lines
and multiple tell blocks to do.
It's a very powerful
construct and especially
when it's used with libraries.
It's great.
So, AppleScript libraries, they
are a new plug-in architecture
that allows you to get at
your favorite handlers.
You can create these yourself.
They're different than
scripting additions
because you can write
them in AppleScript
and that the script
manages their use
and use of resources as well.
They can also have access
to AppleScript Objective-C,
so that means the
world of Cocoa, methods
and classes are at
your disposal.
And you can publish your own
terminology for them as well.
In support, we've added the new
script library reference and,
as we just demonstrated,
the new use clause
to help automatically
find, locate,
and load these things
globally for you.
Now, we have a session this
afternoon on just libraries
where we get into
detail and show you how
to construct a library, not
only a simple one but one
in AppleScript Objective-C, one
that actually has a terminology.
And, for the first time
anywhere in the world,
we will show you how to write
a scripting dictionary file
or an sdef [laughter].
[ Applause ]
It is sick, sick, sick.
You can't miss it.
So that's this afternoon.
It's right in this same room.
It session 416 at 3:15 pm.
If this is interesting you, I
suggest please come to this.
When you're done, you'll
really understand them
and be able to start
using these.
They're very powerful.
Next we're going to talk
about notifications.
Informing the user
of what's going on.
So the other day I
was reading this blog
about how they got
it right in OS X
with the Notification Center.
And the guy says, "Yeah, man.
You know, they -- they're
located in a central location.
They're organized
by application.
And they disappear quickly
so that there is no
clutter on your screen.
It's really nice
that they're there.
And it can even provide a
mechanism for you to respond.
And, in the new version
that you've seen,
you can even have replies
and stuff like that.
And, you know, they're
designed not
to annoy you or get in the way.
[Laughter] And they should
never, ever leap, jump,
or hop and definitely
not bounce."
So I'm showing you this
because, for many, many years,
this is the way that scripts
tried to notify you until now.
So we've added notifications
support
in Automator and AppleScript.
And we've integrated
it [applause] -- yes.
And we've integrated it in
both applications and --
so that there's no more need
for these mobile dialogs
that just kind of hang around,
and you can now create
your automations
that are 100 percent
bounce-free [laughter].
So let's take a look
at how this works.
There's a Notifications Control
-- System Preference pane,
right, in the Master
Preference pane.
If you open that in Mavericks,
you'll see that your favorite,
you know, automation applets
and droplets appear in the list
of applications like
everything else.
And you can select them
and set their preferences.
For example, I can select my
photo droplet, and I can choose
that it will display
as an alert.
Or I can even say, No; I
don't want any display.
Just use the sound.
Or, if I have something
that I use quite a lot
and doesn't require
a notification,
then I can just turn
it off and take it
out of the Notification system
by just clicking that checkbox.
So, when it comes to Automator,
many people don't know that,
when you run an Automator
workflow or applet,
it does provide some feedback.
And you'll notice
at the very top
of your menu bar there's a gear.
And, if you've ever seen that
or even caught your eye with it,
if you click on that, it will
show you every workflow that's
running and generally
give you an idea
about where the workflow is.
But you have to hold
the cursor down.
And, if you're still holding,
you might get this notice
that says the workflow ended.
But most people don't know
about that and so, generally,
the way that you know
that a workflow is --
is finished is nothing.
There's nothing there
to show you.
Now, with the Automator
in Mavericks,
we've introduced a new
notification action,
and this will cause a
notification to occur.
And you can insert
it more than once
in your workflow if you want.
You could put it into the start.
You could put it in key
points in the workflow.
You could just put
it at the end.
Whatever works for you.
And, in addition, it provides
various options for which one
of the fields you want to do,
and it also supports Automator
variables, workflow variables.
So we can have dynamic
information
in that dialog related to
the workflow that was run.
Now, why would you need this
kind of thing in a workflow?
Well, here's a workflow that
I use myself for home movies,
and it's a video
compressing workflow.
Anytime I shoot a bunch of
stuff on my iPhone or a camera,
I take the raw files and I
run it through this droplet.
And let me just walk you
through it real quick.
So it's an applet,
so you can see
at the top it says it receives
whatever you drop onto it.
And then the first
action, I have a find --
filter finder items, so it
looks just for movie files.
In case something else
gets accidentally dropped
on it, it ignores it.
Then, the next action is
creating a workflow variable
that stores the references
to the raw movie files.
Then I proceed to do the first
encoding at a lower thing
of 480p to a certain
location on my drive.
Next, I append a -480p
to the end of the name
of all the created
video files so I know
which ones are the
lower resolution.
Then I use a workflow variable.
I call back that
workflow variable.
I get the original list
of source references.
I perform another encoding pass
using 720p or 1080p depending
on where I'm going to,
to a certain location.
And then again I append
to the end of the name.
So this workflow can take
quite a while to run.
If you drag four or five
10GB files onto this,
it can go on for quite a while,
and you have no idea of knowing
where you are in this process.
So this is an example of a
workflow that you would want
to add a notification to.
And to do that it's pretty easy.
You just open up
your library view.
You search in the Search
field for notification.
And you'll see that
it appears in the list
of available Automator actions.
Hit the Return key;
it becomes selected.
You can see the display
of information
about the new notification
action.
Hit the Return key again and it
will automatically inserted it
into the bottom of my workflow.
Then it's just a
matter of me filling
out the fields the
way I want, saving it.
So now I drag my video
file on top of that.
And I hit the gear, but
after a period of time,
the first encoding thing
appears on my desktop.
Then some more time goes by,
and the second encoded
file appears along
with a notification.
So now I know what's
been processed.
If I come back from eating my
doughnut or lunch, whatever,
and I just look at the
machine, I can say, "Oh, great.
The encoding went fine.
Okay. I'm ready to do the
next batch or something."
And because the parameters
are settable
in the System Preference
pane, I can choose to have
that be an alert that demands
that I close that alert so just
as a confirmation as well.
Now, for AppleScript, what we
did is we added a new command
that's part of the
standard editions,
and it's called Display
Notification, of course.
And here's the verb.
There's an optional
parameter with title.
There's another optional
parameter here for subtitle.
And you can put the
name of the sound file
that you want to have play.
Now, all those are
optional parameters,
but you have to use one of them.
And it creates a notification.
So, in that example
I sent to Trudy,
this is basically
the repeat routine.
I would just open some
space here after the repeat,
insert that into there so now
there's display notification.
And I can add custom data
like the number of items
that were processed into
the final message so that,
when I drag a bunch of images
onto the photo droplet,
it processes.
And, then, after a while, it
will display the notification
with the custom information.
It's that simple to use.
So here to show you
notifications
in action is Chris Nebel.
Thank you.
>> Chris Nebel: Thank you, Sal.
[ Applause ]
Okay. So I've got Sal's
encoding workflow here.
Let me get that started.
And, like he said, you
can see that it's running
from the spinning gear menu.
But, when it's done, all you
get is just the gear disappears.
You'd like some better
notification of this.
And in the past you'd use
a modal dialog to do this,
but that's really the
wrong interaction method
because a modal dialog
is an alert.
It is saying, "Oh, oh, here.
Sir, sir, sir.
You've got to see this.
You've got to do
something about this.
It's right here.
Are you even paying
attention to this?"
Whereas a notification
is much more passive.
It says, "Oh, hi.
So, yeah. This thing
happened and, yeah.
If you want I can hook you
up with, you know, a guy.
But, you know, if
you don't, it's cool.
See you [laughter]."
And that's what we just got
if you weren't paying
attention as it flowed by.
Our notification showed up and,
if we look in Notification
Center, it's still there
if we happen to be away at
a coffee break or something.
So let's see how we did that.
I have it open in
Automator over here.
So the basic workflow Sal
explained to you already,
filter out the movies, encode
them, encode them, add the name,
encode then again, add
the different name.
And, at the end, we have display
notification, finished encoding.
So this is nice, but we
can do a little better.
We'd like to get a notification
about what items
just got encoded
because we might have several
of these in flight at once.
Now, we happen to already
have the input file stored
in a variable.
We had to save them
because we were going to --
we have to feed them into two
different encode media actions.
So we can just take
that variable and put it
into the message here because
all these fields support --
support variables.
Save that.
And now, if we do
our workflow again --
I'm using a shorter
movie this time
so it won't take quite as long.
There's one file;
there's the next
and says finished
encoding, menomena.
[ Pause ]
So let's try something now
a little more complicated
and a lot more geeky.
So there are lots
of system services,
low-level system services
that tell you what they're doing
simply by writing out to a file.
They write out to a system log.
And, you know, that's
okay as far as it goes.
But, you know, here's
an example.
I have a machine that
other people log into.
And, you know, they
are nice enough folks,
but they get a little, shall
we say, overenthusiastic
about using Pseudo, and I
like to keep an eye on them.
Now, Pseudo is one of
the system services.
It writes into a log.
So anytime something
goes on, you know,
we can keep an eye
on that using Syslog.
So this just writes
out a message anytime
Pseudo logs a message.
And I'm going to pipe this
through sed to clean it
up a little bit so I just
get a simplified version.
And, if I come over here
and say Pseudo-something,
there's my message popping out.
So this is nice as
far as it goes.
But, you know, I've got lots
of Terminal windows
blabbing text at me all day.
Odds are good I'm
going to miss this one.
You know, it might
get covered up.
I'm not necessarily
looking at Terminal.
But, you know, hey.
Notifications.
Let's see what we
can do with that.
So I have a script
that I wrote here.
If you don't know
Perl, don't be afraid.
This is just what I'm
more comfortable with.
So what this does is
it's going to just sit
in the loop reading lines
of text as they come in.
And, for every line of test,
it's going to run the
rest of the script.
So this little hunk of line
noise breaks up the input line
into three chunks,
breaking on colons.
So we wind up with three
pieces: dollar one,
dollar two, dollar three.
And then we'll use those
to build up the parameters
for a display notification
command.
That's how you do
notification from AppleScript.
And then we're going to run
that assembled script
using osascript.
Osascript is how you run
a script from Terminal.
So, if we run that -- and if
I can spell it correctly --
we can give it some
text, break up by colons,
and watch the corner
of the screen there.
We get our little notification.
So now let's take the
previous command we had,
the Syslog command, and pipe
it through notification filter.
So, now, this will
just sit here running.
I can minimize this
window or whatever.
But someone comes
along and does Pseudo;
I get an actual notification
that shows up wherever I am.
[ Applause ]
And that is just a few ways
you can use notifications
to improve the awareness
of your workflows
that are running
on your machine.
Sal?
>> Sal Soghoian: Very cool.
I like to know everything
that's going on in my house
on every computer everywhere.
I want total awareness
through notifications.
So notification support in
Automator and AppleScript,
it's been integrated right
into the editing applications,
that you have resources
for Automator to do it,
for AppleScript to
do it as well.
This means you don't have
to create these modal
confirmation dialogs,
and now you can be 100
percent bounce free.
So that's notification support.
Next I'd like to talk about
accessibility integration.
Now, some of you might be
familiar with Speakable Items.
How many people in here
have used Speakable Items?
Quite a few.
And it's an architecture
built into OS X
in the accessibility frameworks
and allows you to speak commands
to your computer and have
them perform them for you.
And it has a lot of integration.
There is a lot of
customization built
into the standard
set of commands.
For example, you can
say, Mail this to mom,
and it will understand
who mom is.
You could say meet with
Karl Whelan [phonetic],
and it will look up Karl
Whelan in your address book
and then create a new
meeting for you in Calendar.
It has a lot of other commands
that are just basically,
you know, work things
like open iPhoto,
bring this window forward,
that kind of stuff.
But it's very useful.
So a lot of people use
this who are not involved
in accessibility issues.
It's just a nice
power feature to have.
So what we've done in Mavericks
is we've created a new entity
called Speakable Workflows.
It's a way of saving
your workflows
into the Speakable Items'
architecture and have it work
for you automatically.
So you can extend a set of
commands that are available
by voice using Automator.
And this is how it works.
So, to turn on Speakable Items,
you just go to the
Accessibility Preference pane.
At the bottom of the list
of different accessibility
features is Speakable Items.
You select that and then
just click the radio button
to turn it on.
As confirmation, you'll see
this floating round window.
That's the Speech
Feedback window.
When that's available,
the computer is ready
to respond to your commands.
And, by default, you just
press down the Escape key
and say your command and it
will start working for you.
Now, in Automator, if you want
to create a Speakable Workflow,
I have an example here.
So I use USB keys all the time.
I have one here.
I call it Digital Briefcase.
And, you know, I'm constantly
plugging them into the computer,
and then I have to
go eject them.
So I have to find some dialog,
whether it's an open dialog
or finder window, find the
stupid little down thing,
click that, and then
wait for the thing
to eject and then grab it.
I would really like to just
be able to tell the computer
"Eject Digital Briefcase"
and, plop,
it will just pull it out for me.
So this is the workflow that
does that, and I'll walk you
through it to show
you how to do this.
So it's an applet by default,
and the first action is a
Find Finder Items action,
and it looks for two parameters.
One, it looks for volume whose
name is Digital Briefcase.
Once it finds that
volume, it will pass
that to the next action which
is just simply Eject Disc,
and it will eject
for us automatically.
Then the next step is to specify
some text I want as a response.
And I type the word Done!
and then have that
spoken by a certain voice.
I've chosen Samantha.
So then I choose to
save this workflow.
This will be my Speakable
Workflow.
And in the Save sheet you'll see
that there is a File Format menu
that says Application.
Well, if I click on that,
there's a new file format.
If you have Speakable Items
architecture turned on
and installed on your machine,
you will see this in Automator
and it's called a
Speakable Item.
So, therefore, I can save
this as a Speakable Item.
You'll notice that
Speakable Item appears
on the File Format menu,
but it also automatically
locates the Speakable Items
folder which is within
your Speech folder which is
within your Home folder.
In other words, that's
the location
that the speech architecture
uses.
So, when you save,
you want to save it
with a name being the
name of the command.
So, in this case, I'm going to
say Eject Digital Briefcase,
and that's what I want to be
able to say to my computer.
I save that.
It will install it into the
Speakable Items architecture
for me automatically.
So the next time my thumb drive
is plugged into the computer
like it is here, if I want to,
no matter what program I'm in,
if I want to eject
it, I just simply --
I just simply say the command -
>> "Eject Digital
Briefcase" [laughter].
>> It does it.
>> "Done!"
>> -- and then says done.
So there's a very simple example
of how you can take workflows
and integrate them in with the
speech recognition architecture
in the operating system
to perform custom actions.
Now, in preparation for release
of Mavericks in the fall,
we'll be posting a new website
called Speakable Workflows.com
that will have hundreds of
examples that you can download.
In addition, they'll be a
feedback mechanism there
that you can send us response
about how you use this,
the kind of things that you're
looking for, that kind of thing.
So we encourage you to give
this a try in Mavericks.
So, in summary, this has been
a great release for automation.
We've had a lot of
new stuff happening.
Specifically, we
added iCloud support
so that you can have your
scripts just distributed
across all the computers
that you use.
We added code signing so that
you can distribute your applets
and droplets to every -- to your
customers or to your friends
without invoking any of
the Gatekeeper responses.
We now have a new construct
for extending the power
of AppleScript through
AppleScript libraries
which you can write yourself in
AppleScript and expose commands
and terminology that you
didn't have available before.
And we now have introduced
the new use clause
that will really streamline
the syntax of your scripts
and add a lot of power
and ability to them.
And we've implemented
notification support in addition
to our new Speakable Workflows.
So that's quite a bit that's
been going on this year.
This is a great release for us.
We're really excited about it.
Now, if you have questions or
more information I'll point
to these four guys that you can
probably beat up with Nerf bats
or something to get
answers out of them.
And, in additional,
remember the session
on AppleScript libraries.
And there's one more
thing: Did you know this?
Some of you might not know
this but this is a special day
for us because, 20
years ago at WWDC,
AppleScript was released
to the world.
[ Applause ]
And it's been a very, very
powerful boon to our customers,
to us, to engineers,
to everybody to use it
to create automations that
really empower and change lives.
It has been a fantastic
language.
It's constantly growing,
expanding.
And, as you can see,
with this release,
there's new things
happening all the time.
So we just want to take
this one opportunity
on the 20th anniversary of this
technology to say thank you
to all the developers who
made their apps scriptable.
We want to say thank you to
all the scripters that wrote
and shared scripts
with the community.
We want to say thank
you to all the customers
that use AppleScript and
rely on it every day.
And to the engineers that
make their apps scriptable
and to the engineers at Apple
that implemented AppleScript,
we want to say thank
you as well.
So have a great conference.
We'll see you later
this afternoon, guys.
[applause] Thank you.
[ Silence ]