[ Silence ]
>> Good afternoon.
How is everybody?
Really? That's exciting.
[applause] Good.
Good. Well, welcome to
the afternoon of day 2
of the Worldwide
Developers Conference.
My name is Brian Tucker and
I am ultimately responsible
for Bluetooth here at Apple and
it's a honor and a privilege
to spend a few minutes
to talk to you guys
about what we're doing
specifically in CoreBluetooth,
but in some sense of what we're
doing in Bluetooth in general.
And in a major way where we
think Bluetooth is going.
Right now, Bluetooth is
just absolutely everywhere.
I'm seeing it-- Well, I went
to a Consumer Electronic
Show this winter
and I literally saw
Bluetooth everywhere.
I saw it in trade
show booths walls.
I saw it in people's shirts.
I saw-- I think I saw a couple
of tattoos on people's arms.
I swear. Bluetooth is
literally everywhere.
So it's super, super
exciting times for us
to talk about this stuff.
So speaking of which, what
are we going to cover?
So we're going to be covering
these particular areas.
I'm going to focus a little bit
on BLE and the State of Union
of where BLE is currently.
We'll get into the evolution
of CoreBluetooth kind
of where we started
to where we are today.
We'll talk about
CoreBluetooth in iOS 7.
Jason is going to take
you through that and some
of the cool new features that I
think you guys are going to dig.
Jason has a demo, a
code demo on that.
He'll go through to the code
tying in to some of the things
that he's talking as
it relates to iOS 7.
And then finally, we have
some tips and best practices
that we've learned by listening
to you guys in the forums
as well as all the phone calls
and visits and conversations
that we've had over the
last year or so on the do's
and don't's around some
of this technology.
So State of the Union,
so where is BLE today?
Well, I think this number
pretty much says it all,
a billion devices.
Right now, we're--
there is estimation
that over a billion Bluetooth--
low energy devices will ship
by the end of this year and
that includes the last couple
of years.
But that's remarkable
considering this technology
really kind of came in to its
own just a couple of years ago.
So it's just crazy to think
that we've reached
this point so quickly.
In fact, if you look
at the projection
over our BLE devices are
going to be in the market just
in the next few years.
It's just up and up and up
and this is conservative
on my opinion.
It's absolutely amazing.
And this kind of ties into those
used cases that I keep talking
to you guys about,
around all the areas,
healthcare for example.
I mean, I was in the lab earlier
today and group after group
after group came up and
talked to me about healthcare
and it's not just
one element of it.
It might be a blood
glucose monitor.
It might be something
that literally controls a
limb attached to your leg
that controls the
robotics that's a part--
I mean it's just crazy where
these products are going to go,
sports and fitness, security,
we talked a little bit
about already, toys.
I hope all of you got to see the
demo and the keynote on Monday
which was awesome, and that was
all Bluetooth LE, pay systems,
time services, proximity.
We have some new stuff in
proximity that we're going
to talk about today and it's
going to come up and more
in a Core Location session
later tomorrow I believe is
when the Core Location
session is.
So without further adieu,
I'd like to invite up Renaud
who is going just to
talk about the evolution
of CoreBluetooth
and get us going.
So, Renaud?
[Applause]
>> Thank you, Brian.
So, we introduced
CoreBluetooth in 2011
and we were the first ones to
support Bluetooth Low Energy,
the mass produced
device in the market.
So if you remember in iOS 5
we introduced two classes,
the CBCentralManager and
CBPeripheral that allowed you
to scan for devices, connect
to them and then exchange it
with them, which allowed
you to do a lot of--
which a lot of applications
already.
In iOS 6, we implemented the
other side of the Java rule
of specification which is they
[inaudible] a peripheral rule
and gets over rule.
And for the CBPeripheralManager,
you were able to implement you
on services and Field
CBCentralRequest.
We also introduced
for the first time
or peripheral database
caching mechanism
which drastically improves
performance especially
on discovery as you may
already use that in your app.
Well, iOS 7 is all
about LE, Evolved.
It's about refining OAPIs
based on new feedback
and because we monitor, first
and foremost the mailing list
and the [inaudible] forums.
We also looked at all your
radars that you sent us.
And we are refining OAPIs and
we're also filling the gaps.
We're also putting the last
remaining pieces of the puzzle
to provide user-based
API, so best
and the simplest
API you can use.
So here's what you're going
to talk, a high level agenda.
We simplified Device
Management in iOS 7.
We got more intelligent
peripherals.
We improved performance again.
And pretty drastically
again, we solved the problem
of application persistence
that some of you may have
and we also did some built-in
services right into the OS.
But before I move
to these points,
I want to have a discussion
with you about the simulator.
In 2011, we had a simulator's
report for all coverage of APIs
because low energy was
an emerging market.
There was almost no
device available.
We were in shipping
iOS devices until late
in the year with iPhone 4S.
And that made development very
difficult for you and for us.
Therefore, we introduced
a simulator.
In 2013, nowadays,
things are very different.
The market is exploding,
like Brian just told you.
There are many, many
LE-compatible devices
on the market including all
our shipping iOS hardware
and most of them are hardware.
And you also have access
to fantastic third-party
development kits running
on less fantastic OSs,
but very fantastic anyway.
And as we move forward and
implement more and more feature
in CoreBluetooth and we're
moving in a breakneck speed.
It gets harder and harder for us
to give the simulator up to par
with what's running
on the hardware.
We cannot continue properly
supporting all the [inaudible]
goals that you guys may be
able to buy from third parties
that you can plug on your Mac.
And run it exactly as it
should on an iOS device.
And for these reasons
we are now seeing
that we're dropping
simulator support.
So best way to test
CoreBluetooth is really
on the iOS hardware itself
with all the behaviors--
specific behaviors to iOS,
because all hardware
has specificities
that a simulator cannot obtain.
So we're dropping
simulator support.
I'm sorry about that.
Let's move on to the good stuff.
So I'm going to go into the
major changes in the API
that we are doing in iOS 7.
There's more, more-- There's
much more that you can see.
I'm going to put that down.
There's much more
in [inaudible].
But I'm going to talk
about the major ones.
So first of all, like I said,
we simplified device management.
And you probably all
know this property.
You probably all hate this
property which is UUID
of CBPeripherals and CBCentrals.
Another time in 2011, we
didn't have UUID class
in the foundation framework.
Therefore, we use a CFUUIDRef.
Since then we now have
the NSUUID and we're going
to deprecate a UUID property
and we have a new one
which is called "IDentifier".
And which is for all intents
and purposes the same value,
but as a convenient NSUUID.
And also these identifiers,
I know because--
are now going to be created
at discovery, because we know
that you had problems
with these being created
at connection time.
So they will always be there.
I guarantee it to be there
and they are much more
convenient to use.
So UUID is deprecated.
And so peripheral retrieval was
also-- was always very wonky.
So UIVs retrievePeripherals
method that you gave an array
of UUID to [inaudible]
peripherals callback comes
to delegate.
Same thing for the
connected peripherals,
we have the same kind of
asynchronous delegate callback.
This was always wonky.
We didn't like it.
You didn't like it.
So we're changing that.
In iOS 7, we're introducing
a new method called
retrievePeripherals
WithIdentifiers.
And whereas before UUIDs are
synchronous callback you had
to wait for, for your objects.
Now, you don't have
to do this anymore.
This is asynchronous method,
it returns to you directly
as the objects you
want to work with.
Same thing for the
connected services,
we also have asynchronous method
for the connected
peripherals, sorry.
And you can also pass an array
service you're interested in--
you are interested in.
So that you don't get just an
anonymous list of peripheral
as you get peripherals that
you are only interested in.
And once you use these methods,
you cans continue using
your CBPeripherals
like you use them before by,
for example, connecting to them.
And so we saw that you
guys, these are a lot
of boilerplate code to find
out whenever a CBPeripheral
was being connected
to it any point in time.
So you had your upper
classes just around that,
just to get this property.
And we have the folders
be simple Boolean
that told you whether a
peripheral was connected or not.
We are deprecating that as well
and we're introducing
a tri-state instead
that tells you whenever a
peripheral is connected--
connected to or simply
connected at any point in time.
Simple change is going to-- we
think is going to simplify a lot
of your code, is
going to be great.
We also improve all
service and validation API.
So for those of you that cared
about that, we had this kind
of bazooka callback that nukes
the world service database
on a peripheral or
when database changed.
And that wasn't really good,
because you had to restart,
rediscover all services
and restart all services
from scratch.
Well, we have a more fine grain
callback that gives you exactly
which services when
validated, and all services
that were not been
validated are still valid
and you can continue using them
without restarting anything.
So again you see all these-- all
these APIs are about refining
and fixing of things we--
that are not proper--
that were not proper previously.
All right.
Anyway, going to now-- that's
finished for the API changes.
I'm going to invite Jason
to the stage to talk more
about new iOS 7 features.
[Applause]
>> Thanks Renaud.
So next I want to talk about
something that's very near
and dear to our heart
here at Apple.
I think it's super important
and that's performance.
So in iOS 7 we've made a ton
if performance improvements.
And don't worry I'm not going
to bore you with the details
of each and everyone
that we've done.
But I am going to talk about
two main areas of improvement
that we're really excited about
and we think you guys
are going to love.
The first of those is caching.
So as Renauld said earlier,
we first implemented the
database caching in iOS 6.
And what caching
does is it allows us
to remember the attributes that
we find on a remote device.
So the next time one
of your application--
wants one of those
attributes, we don't have
to go backout over the air.
And these lets us really
make things go a lot faster
and save a lot of power,
'cause we're cutting back
on the unnecessary conversation.
So in iOS 6, we are currently
caching two attributes,
cache services and
their characteristics.
And this is working really well
because once you do your
initial discovery it--
they're all in the cache
and discovery will fly
the next time around.
In iOS 7, we've taken the
caching that we've done
and we've extended it,
and we've added caching
for characteristic descriptors.
So now, every attribute
that you can discover
in a remote device's database,
services, characteristics
and characteristic descriptors
will be automatically cached
for you by the system.
So we're really excited
about that.
But you might notice there is
one attribute up there that's--
we haven't talked about yet.
That's characteristic values.
And there's a good
reason for it.
So up to this point,
all of the attributes
that we're caching are static.
Their contents never change.
But characteristic
values can be dynamic.
You see what I mean
by that, you--
we can look at the heart rate
measurement characteristic value
as an example.
So right now, if you're to read
that heart rate measurement
characteristic value,
you'd see that it's at
190 beats per minute,
which by no small
coincidence is right
about where my own heart
rate is at the moment.
But later on if you were to read
it perhaps once I got off this
giant stage with this bright
lights in my face, you might see
that it's dropped down
to under 100, good thing.
So how do we cache this?
What do we do?
Well since the system doesn't
know whether a characteristic
value is static or dynamic.
Your application knows,
because you guys are the ones
who were using this service.
So what we are going to do is
when we discover characteristic,
if we've previously read
that characteristic value,
we're going to pre-fill that out
when we send you
the characteristic
up in your discovery call.
So that if you know that you
just discovered a characteristic
that is static, you know it
will never change, you're done.
You don't even have to
issue that we're going
to wait for that response.
There's nothing left
for you to do.
So we're really excited
about this.
We think this is--
this can be great
for a lot of your used cases.
And the best part about
this is you don't have
to do anything to get this.
Just like the caching iOS 6,
it's all handled automatically
for you by the system.
The second performance
improvement that I want to talk
about is something that we've
seen a lot of discussion around,
and that's sending data.
So when we are first
taking a look
at the Bluetooth Low Energy
technology, we're trying
to figure out, OK,
what are people going
to want to do with this?
How are they going to use it?
So we're thinking its
Bluetooth Low Energy,
it's a packet-based protocol.
It's good for sending small
amounts of data back and forth,
but it's not really fast.
So people will send things
like your heart rate.
Or you might send
your GPS location.
And of course there are always
the crazy ones out there.
And they're going to-- they
might send something huge
like all of the information
for one of your contacts.
So maybe a little naive of us.
But to be fair, there
were applications
that sent all of those things.
But then we started seeing apps
that we're sending
a little bit more.
Things like photographs
or they'd be thinking the
week's worth of activity data.
And then we learn that some
of you are successfully,
I might add, using CoreBluetooth
to updates to their devices.
So once we kind of got over the
shock, we took a look, you know,
obviously things are
growing by leaps and bounds.
It's not a single heart rate
value anymore it's entire files.
And we crunch some numbers.
And based on this
current rate of growth,
we're pretty confident
that somewhere out there,
there's a government
contractor who's laboring a way
on an application that's going
to transfer the entire digital
collection of the Library
of Congress when you
walk into the building.
Frankly, it's the--
scares the hell out of us.
But since some of you appear
to have confused Buetooth
low energy with 80211N,
we figure that the least we can
do is take a page from Wi-Fi
and try to make things
go a little faster.
So in iOS 7, we worked on
improving our throughput speeds.
How do we do this?
The primary way we've
done this is
by implementing the
MTU exchange request.
And for those of
you who don't know,
MTU stands for Maximum
Transmission Unit.
And that's the largest
amount of data
that we can send
in a single packet.
Now when we increase this, we
can send more data in one go.
And when we're sending
large amounts of data,
it means we can send
it more efficiently.
It might help to kind of
see exactly what this means
when we're talking
about changing MTU.
So I'm asking you to get
creative with me for a moment
and we're going to imagine
that when you're transferring
data via CoreBluetooth,
you're actually sending
it by Rail.
So you have same data to
send, you package it up,
you take it down to
the train station,
throw it out on the
train, the train leaves.
When you have small
MTU, like what we have
for the default you can
put a very small amount
of data on each train.
So you end up with
a lot little trains,
and there's a reason why you
don't often see a train engine
pulling a single car behind it,
because it would be
incredibly inefficient.
And the same holds through
for our Bluetooth Low Energy.
So when we increase our
MTU, like I said before,
we increase the amount of data
that we can send at once or put
on a train if you will.
So we end up with that same
train engine pulling a lot more
data behind it.
So by doing this we've cut
down on the overhead a ton
and that allows us to
send more data in the
in the same amount of time.
So now in iOS 7 when you make
a connection from your app
to remote peripheral, one of the
first things that we're going
to do once that connection
goes through is try
to negotiate a larger
MTU with that device.
And we did some internal testing
while you're working on this
to try to characterize
the amount
of speed improvement
that we have seen.
So we wrote a test app
that streamed large amounts
of data via notifications,
which is a used case
that we've seen a
lot of you doing.
And we saw up to a
20 percent increase
in throughput speeds there.
And you don't-- this comes
with the standard disclaimer,
this is very used
case dependent.
It's going to depend on a lot
of things you may see
less, you may see more.
Things that could affect us
are your connection interval,
the number of connection events,
what you had for breakfast
that morning, the face of the
moon, you know, you name it.
There's a lot that comes in
the play here, but all of this
to say that it can be a very
nontrivial speed boost for those
of you who are sending
large amounts of data.
And even if you're not you
should still see a bump in kind
of your standard activities
like your discovery,
your reads and your writes.
And again, let's save the
best part of this for last,
because you get this all
for free, you don't have
to make any changes
to your application
to start taking advantage
of this.
So we spend a lot of
time talking about how
to make things faster,
faster, faster, faster.
But for all of you who are
familiar with the story
of the Tortoise and the Hare,
you know that it's not
always the fastest one
that wins the race.
Sometimes it's Raphael the
running Teenage Mutant Ninja
Turtle here.
So for all of your Tortoises
out there, we're going to talk
about how to give you
more staying power.
But first let's take a
look at the current state
of multitasking with
CoreBluetooth.
So today, the user launches
their apps, they work well,
they do everything
they're supposed to,
they look great while doing it,
but at some point despite
your valiant effort
that user is going to want
to do somethings else.
Depressing, I know.
They're going to
background your application.
But that's OK, because
that's why we came
up with these two great
backgrounding modes.
And your peripheral managers can
continue to host their services
in the database and field
request from its remote central.
And this work great.
They allow your application
to continue
to use CoreBluetooth even when
it's not on the foreground.
But as many of you may be
aware, there's a problem.
Because while your application
is running in the background,
the system may terminate it if
it needs to free up more memory
for the foreground application.
So it doesn't take a
computer engineer to see
that there might be a problem
here, because a lot of things
that you guys do
with CoreBluetooth
are really long-term,
some of these used
cases can take hours,
they can even take days.
If you imagine an application,
a home security application
that wants to reconnect to your
Smart Lock when you get home
in the evening, well,
a lot of times
if you've been using you phone
heavily throughout the day,
that application
might not be running
by the time you get back.
So the question is,
"Can we allow the system
to reclaim the memory that
it needs while allowing your
application to continue
to use CoreBluetooth?"
And the answer is no.
So I'd like to thank you all
for coming to our session today
and we'll see you
down at the lab.
No, I'm just kidding, of
course, the answer is yes
or we wouldn't be
here right now.
And not only is it
yes, but we've come
up with a really simple way
that we think you guys
are going to love.
So what are we doing?
Well, the systems going to watch
the state of your application.
It knows when it's running.
It knows when it's
in the background.
And it knows when
it gets terminated.
So when that happens,
when it's gets terminated,
we're going to look at why.
And if it's because the system
needed free up more memory
for the foreground app, and your
application was performing some
long-term action with
CoreBluetooth at the time,
then we're going to step in
on your application's behalf
and take over and we'll
continue to do everything
that it was doing when
it was in the background.
At some point later, when you
need your application again,
it will bring you
back and we're going
to give you back everything, we
bring you right back up to speed
where you were before
you went away.
So we're calling this-- So
we're calling this feature State
Preservations and restoration.
Those of you might be familiar
with the UIKit feature
the same name.
It's pretty similar
conceptually.
So this is an optional feature,
for those of you who don't run
into the background or
who aren't interested
in performing long-term
actions in the background,
there's nothing for
you to do here.
If you do care, you should
know that it's fully supported
by both of our manager
classes, CBCentralManager
and CBPeripheralManager.
And there's not much work that
you need to do to adapt this.
It's pretty simple.
You're going to have to create
a unique restore identifier
when you instantiate
your manager objects.
And you're going to have
to implement a single
new delegate method.
That's it.
So how does this work from
the system perspective?
Well, when your application
is terminated,
right before it goes away,
we're going to take a snap shot
of everything it was doing.
Assuming it was performing
some action with CoreBluetooth.
For things like-- central
manager things this is what you
are discovering, the devices
that you try to connect to
or you had already connected to,
and all of the characteristics
that you were subscribed
to on these devices.
And the peripheral manager side
may keep track of everything
as well, what you're
advertising, all the services
that you'd publish in the
database, and all the centrals
that were subscribed to
your characteristics.
So once we take the snapshot,
your application is
still terminated,
it's no longer running.
But like I said,
we've stepped in
and we're doing everything
on its behalf.
And we said that at some point,
something is going to happen
and we said we'd bring you back.
So any event that the system
either can't handle without you
or that you need to know
about will trigger us
to re-launch your application.
And these are things like
that peripheral you're trying
to connect to finally
completed or someone subscribed
to a characteristic that you're
hosting, or your got an update
to a characteristic that
your were subscribed on.
And at that point we'll
re-launch you back
into the background
where you were.
And allow you to run for
a short period of time.
The application is then going to
reinstantiate all the managers
that I was using
before it went away.
It's going to get that
one delegate callback
where we give you
back all the state
that we're keeping
track of for you.
And then it's kind
of business as usual.
You'll see that power on event
in your didUpdateState callback.
And you're going to get whatever
event triggered us to re-launch
and you'll get that
delegate callback as normal.
So I know it might
seem like there a lot
of moving pieces here,
but I said it was simple
and I'd never lead you astray.
So I'm going to show
you how simple it is
by taking an existing
background capable application
and adding support for state
preservation and restoration.
[ Pause ]
All right, so here is our app
and it's a very simple heart
rate monitor application,
it looks for all the
heart rate monitor devices
that are near you.
It connects to them and
it finds and subscribes
to the heart rate-- at heart
rate measurement characteristics
that we looked at earlier.
It's been pretty
stripped down just
for illustrative
purposes for this demo.
But it should look pretty
familiar for any of you
who have worked with
the CBCentralManager
and CBPeripheral classes before.
So before we get started, I'm
just going to take you in kind
of a quick tour through
the code here
so you can see what
we're working
with before we start
making changes.
So this is a single
view controller.
Like I said very
simple application.
Down here in viewDidLoad
where the magic starts,
you can see that we instantiate
out central manager--
single central manager object.
And this object is going to be
around for the lifetime
of our application.
So as you all know after we
instantiate our manager, we're--
the first thing that we're going
to get is a callback
on didUpdateState.
So in this situation when we see
that the state has been powered
on, we simply begin scanning
for devices that are advertising
the heart rate service.
At this point when
we find the device,
we're going to get a callback
to didDiscoverPeripheral.
And there are a couple of things
that I wanted point out in here.
So the first is that you can
see here, we have a list--
we keep a list of heart
rate monitor devices around.
So when you find a device and
you want to use that device,
you need to keep
a reference to it.
So the system knows, "Hey,
this application is trying
to use this device, we
better keep it around.
So we looked to see if we
have this OS in our list;
and if not, we put it in there.
And at that point we call
connect.net [phonetic].
Hopefully, later on that
connection will complete
and we'll get our
didConnectPeripheral callback.
And at this point we simply set
the delegate and then we move
on to kind of the
service interaction part
of our phase of our application.
The first thing we do is
we simply discover services
and we're only interested
that heart rate service,
pretty straightforward.
Later on when the
command completes,
we'll get our
didDiscoverServices callback.
We're going to look
and see, hey,
were we able to find
the service?
And if so, the next
step we're going to look
for that heart rate
measurement characteristic.
Once that completes, again,
we're going to check to see,
were we able to find it,
and we're simply going
to call set notify value
to subscribe updates on it.
Later on when that
value changes,
the peripheral will send
us the new updated value,
we'll get a didUpdateValue
for characteristic callback.
And since this is
such a simple app,
we're not really doing
anything here other
than logging that information.
OK, so I said this is a
background capable app,
of course it wants to do all
of this in the background.
So we're going to go to
the info.plist here and see
that it is in fact specified
the correct required background
mode, app communicates
using CoreBluetooth,
which as you all know
is the appropriate one.
We're going to be using a
CBCentralManager and you want
to continue using peripherals
while in the background.
So one thing I want to note,
you notice that even though this
application is geared toward
CBCentralManager, everything
that we're going to talk
about here for this preservation
and restoration feature
applies equally
to peripheral manages as well.
So the first thing
that it said before was
that this is an optional
feature, so we need the opt-in.
And we're going to go back
down to this viewDidLoad here
where we instantiate our
central manger object.
And we're going to move
it to a new init method.
It looks pretty much
the same as the old one,
but now we've got this
options dictionary on the end
and we need to provide a
single new option for this
and that's our restore
identifier.
So by providing this
restore identifier key,
we're doing two things.
One, we are telling the
system and the application,
we're giving them a
way to uniquely refer
to this specific manager.
The second thing that we're
doing is telling the system,
"Hey, I want to support
this feature."
So I need to give it a
restore identifier and I
like to just do something
descriptive here,
something like heart
rate central
since this is a central
manager we're using
to find heart rate devices.
You can name it whatever
you want.
The only thing that you
need to be aware of is
that it should be unique
within your application.
If you give two managers
the same restore identifier,
both the system and
your app is--
aren't going to able
to know which is which.
OK, so now, we've opted-in.
And I said, the second thing
that we needed to do was
to implement our
new delegate method.
And that delegate method is
central manager will restore
a state.
When the system is persisting
some sort of long-term action
on your behalf like we
talked about earlier
and something happens
that we decide
to re-launch your application,
this is the very first delegate
method that will be called.
Let me reiterate because
this is important.
This is the very
first delegate method.
No longer is it didUpdateState.
If you are restored, you
will first get a call
to will restore state and
that's your application's chance
to bring itself back up to
speed with what has been going
on in the system because it
has been gone, it doesn't know.
So, we're going to get back
a variety of things in this.
And the first thing that
we'll do in this application,
we're always scanning.
So we are scanning
from the background.
When our application
got terminated,
we are still scanning.
The system stepped in
and continued scanning
in our behalf.
So now, when we're coming back,
that scanning is
still happening.
So, we can see the services
that we're scanning for
and the scan options that we
provided to the scan call.
Again, in the case of this app,
since we're always scanning
and we're always scanning
for the same thing this is
already kind of expected.
We don't really need to
do anything with this.
The next thing that we're
going to back is a list of all
of the devices that we
had tried to connect
to or were connected to.
So, in this situation we
actually do care about these
because in this app once we find
a device we add it to our list
of Heart Rate devices because we
need to keep a reference to it.
So, here we're coming back
starting up with devices
that we may already
be connected to.
So, they again we need to
keep a reference to them
and they're going
to go on our list.
So, we just go through
any peripherals
that were restored
with, go right back
into that Heart Rate Peripheral
list and we set the delegate.
Now, for some of your
applications this might be
enough, really simple we
haven't done a lot here
but there are two
other things that--
and one in particular
that you really should
at least think about.
And the next thing that
I want to take a look
at is our initialization
process for this application
because before we started
supporting this feature,
every time our application
started up we'd be starting
up with a clean slate.
Now that we support restoration,
we might be getting restored
with stuff that's
still happening
on our behalf in this system.
So, we're going to go to a
Data Update State Method here
and pretend that we've
just been restored.
So, we've gotten that call
to Will Restore State.
So, as we saw before
when power goes
on the first we do
is start scanning.
If we've been restored
we're already scanning,
in this situation calling
up one more time isn't really
going to hurt anything.
It'll actually be
optimized a way anyway
because we're providing
the exact same parameters
as we were-- as we're
already scanning with.
So, it's OK to leave
it, we don't need
to get too tricky here.
But the next thing
that we want to do is
because we may have been
restored with those peripherals,
we're going to take
a look and see,
do I already have
connected peripherals.
So, I might not-- like I
said, we might not be starting
with that clean slate anymore.
So, we're going to
look through our list
of Heart Rate peripherals
and see "Am I connected
to this device?"
And now, if we really want
to be robust which I do
because I'm trying to set a good
example here for all of you,
we could've have gone away
at any point during that kind
of initialization
discovery process that we do
when we connect to a device.
So, we need to be
able to handle that
but it's really--
really quite simple.
So, the first thing that we'll
do is we'll look and we're going
to see have we discovered
that Heart Rate Service.
If not, that's our starting
point we just got something go
discover that service
and everything will kind
of fall back through
that state machine.
Next, we're going
to look and see, OK,
have we discovered the Heart
Rate measurement characteristic?
Again, if not, that's where we
know we need to begin by trying
to discover that characteristic.
And finally, we're going to
look and see, are we subscribed
for updates on that
characteristic?
And if we are, we're done.
We don't need to do anything
else, we've done restored,
we're still connected to
that Heart Rate device
and we're still subscribed
in our app as back
up to speed with everything.
It's just got away for updates.
Now, there-- may be one more
thing that you need to consider
for those of you who
have multiple managers
or maybe you have a manager
that isn't always around.
So, you instantiate it sometimes
in your app and get rid of it.
You might be wondering, this
all looks great but if I have
to instantiate my manager
in order to restore it,
how do I know what manager
I need to instantiate?
Very good question.
And the answer to that is in
your application delegate,
in this did finish
launching with options method.
Because when we're
relaunching you,
we will give you
back the list of all
of the identifiers representing
the restored managers
that we've been keeping track
off for you in this system.
So, you can see that you can
retrieve all the identifiers
for the peripheral
managers that you were using
at the time you went away
and the central managers.
In this application,
we don't care again
about peripheral managers
as we're only using
a central manager.
And we're going to go through
and what you need to do
at this point is tell
your application, "Hey,
these are the managers that
I need to reinstantiate.
If you don't reinstantiate a
manager that is being preserved
for you in the system, after
a reasonable amount of time,
the system is going
to assume that, "Hey,
he must not want this
anymore and we're going
to clean it up for you."
So, any long term actions
that was still performing,
those will stop at
that point in time.
In the case of this app, we
have been lucky there's nothing
for us to here because like
I said we have one manager
and it's around for the
lifetime of the application.
So, it's a-- this is pretty
simple, just a recap, we've--
the first thing that we did was
look at our central manager,
we changed the initialization
call
to provide a restore
identifier for it.
We implemented that single new
delegate method will restore
state which gives our
application a chance to kind
of get back into sync with what
has been going on in the system.
And then we took at look
at our initialization
process and did update state.
And we made sure to be able to--
that we're able to
handle possibly starting
up with devices that
we're already connected.
And I also show you guys how
to handle the possibility
where you have multiple--
multiple managers
being restored.
So, that's it, hopefully
you agree
that there's not a whole
lot of code involved here.
This isn't as complicated
as it may have seen.
And, you know, with this
little amount of change
to our application, we
now don't have to worry
about being killed
in the background.
So, I'd like to invite
Renaud back up here.
And he's going to talk to you
about the great new built
in services in iOS 7.
>> So, Bluetooth Low Energy has
been around for a few years now.
Four years if I count correctly.
And as you see you guys come up,
we start our profiles
already for it.
And we feel the technology
is mature enough now
and our stack is mature enough
that we can make this directly
into the system, and that's what
we're going to do with iOS 7.
So, what did we do?
So, first of all we implemented
some services when we act
as a GATT client and
this is basically a HID
Over GATT Profile as we
talked about this morning
in the accessory session.
The HID Over GATT Profile
which is a bad name
implements these free services.
These are the HID service,
the battery service
and the Device Information
service.
What's special about that
and the fact that it's built
into a system is
that it works just
like Bluetooth Classic devices.
So, you will be able to discover
Bluetooth flow energy HID
devices directly from the
Bluetooth settings pane
like a Bluetooth
Classic would be.
And once you are paired with
Bluetooth Energy HID Device,
iOS will automatically manage
the connection and reconnect
to it if the connection goes
away therefore giving this
illusion that it works just
like a normal Bluetooth device
that customers are used to.
So, that's what we use
on the GATT client side.
But we have also interesting
things on the GATT server side.
So, if you connect your
accessory to an iOS device
and you implements
have GATT clients roll.
And you discover services on an
iOS device you will now be able
to see these services
implemented.
And first of all we
have the battery service
which is trivial, I'm not
going to spend much time on it.
We also implemented the
current time service
which is a nifty service if your
accessory requires an accurate
source of time, we provide
accurate time and date
and the time zone information.
So, for example, things
like watches can use that.
But there's one more
thing an iOS dream,
I'm saying that on stage.
And this one more thing
is about Notifications.
We've seen especially
in the last year a lot
of accessories going
on the markets,
the so called "Companion
Devices" that are
for example smart watch that
are all about displaying to you
or relaying notifications
that are happening
on your iOS device.
But they all use methods
to access the notifications
that I'm not very good for
your hockey and all that
and you guys probably know
what I'm talking about.
But these are three
other command solutions
that are being used nowadays.
So, first one is the
Message Access Pro--
or the Message Access Profile
also commonly known as MAP
over Bluetooth Classic.
The problem with MAP is that
it was developed originally
for an automative usage.
It was not meant to be used by a
small smart watch on your wrist.
And it actually doesn't--
it's very constraint,
it only does SMS's, MMS's and
E-mails very well, anything else
that you pass of a MAP is ugly
and it's not going
to go over well.
There is also low energy's
profiles that have come
up from the [inaudible]
for example is the Alert
Notification Service.
The problem with it is that
it is very, very limited,
it's very simple and it's too
simple, it's not good enough.
There's also a full solution
that we've seen a lot
which is you guys developed
a custom application tailored
to your specific accessory.
And those problems
are obvious we've--
did this solution as well which
is that when it's heavyweight,
you have to Run a full
iOS app and any point
on the customer's device
which is not very good.
And your data you
are able to send
through this method is also
limited to what the app
and send both allows and
what the customer allows you
that your app to see which
is not much as you may know.
So, all the solutions are not
very good and that's a state
as it is now but we come
up with all solution
that we think you're
going to love.
And the solution we call it
the Apple Notification Center
Service also known as
ANCS, I may say ANCS
in the next few minutes.
This is also a GATT
server service.
So again, if your accessory
connects to the nearest device
and discover services on it,
it will see this service
implemented on it.
It is Apple's specific uses
on [inaudible] 128 bits UUIDs.
And it basically allows you
to be notified about any kind
of event on your phone.
And that's includes all the
phone functionality events,
for example your incoming
calls and your voice mails.
It notifies you about your IMs
and all the messages you can get
for Facebook or anything else.
It notifies you about calendar.
For example if you are
in 5 minutes it will
be carried over--
this information would be
carried over this service.
And what I'm getting
at basically is
that I need notification
and notification center will
be carried over this service.
There's no preferential
treatment, anything which is
in notification center will
be sent over this service.
You have full access to anything
that's will be notifiable
on iOS by default.
And again, like the HID service
I just talked to you about,
once an accessory has been
recognized as using ANCS,
iOS would automatically
manage a connection
and reconnect for you.
So, your app doesn't
have to do that anymore.
We will do that for you.
So, detailed specification
will be posted
on the developers portal soon.
We still have a few
things to work-out.
But look forward to that and,
well, [inaudible] is going
to be out really soon.
But before I finish that,
I just want to give you
like a sneak peek of the
mechanisms on who it works
and you will see it's really
simple and straightforward.
It's not complex at all.
But it [inaudible]
very powerful.
So, let's take the used case
of an iPhone connected
to a smart watch.
For example, in this case
a very blue smart watch.
And the user just
received a new iMessage.
Well, we will send a
message over ANCS telling you
that the user just received
a so-called new social
notification and we will create
a UUID for this notification
which is going to
[inaudible] a handle
to retrieve more
information about it.
In this case, we just use one.
And the accessory as supposedly
to retrieve more information
about this notification which
is exactly what it does now
where it can go back
and ask for attributes.
In this example, it wants
the title and message.
There's a list of
attribute to provide.
In this case, we just want two.
And iPhone will provide all this
information to your accessory.
In this case it's the title
is actually the sender
of the iMessage and the
message is the body of iMessage
and it's Jason because
Jason is part is looking
to get beers pretty soon.
Of course at this point
your accessory is free
to do whatever it want.
You can blink an LED or you
can displays the entirety
of the message and
a big display.
Whatever you accessory
implements,
it's up to you at this point.
Later on when the
iMessages is read
or the notification is
dismissed on the device,
we will also notify
the accessory
that this notification is
now invalid and you're free
to dismiss the alert
on your device as well.
So, a full synchronization
mechanism
between notification
center and all these events
and your accessory and
as pretty much ANCS
and this was just a sneak
peek, it's capable of much,
much more-- it's very
powerful, very simple as well.
We try to keep it simple
and look forward to that
onto the developer
portals again.
I just want to quickly finish
by some tips and best practices
that I've come up by monitoring
the developer forums and,
you know, and getting
your radars
because radar [inaudible]
is not a black hole as--
I assure you, all the radar you
filed they're going all queue
and we looked at
everyone of them.
So, here are some few tips
and best practices
some common mishaps
and pitfalls you guys
tend to fall in to.
So, I just-- I just want
you to keep track of that.
So, first of all, like we said
before, CoreBluetooth needs
to know if you intend
CBPeripherals.
Please keep a reference to them.
If a CBPeripheral gets locked,
we will assume you are
not interested in it
and the system will take action
in your behalf including
disconnecting the peripheral
implicitly because we do not
want to making that connection
that is not used by
your system at all.
So, keep a reference, it
is something that a lot
of you probably made
the mistake,
it's the first time
you use CoreBluetooth.
Scan request and connection
request never time out
and you needed to
call them once.
So, it's like an
elevator button.
You don't need to press
them multiple times.
It's not going to go any faster.
And actually it might
be detriment
or to the speed of your action.
So, just call it once and
everything will work fine.
We'll take care of
the rest for you.
It wasn't explicit before
but now it's explicit.
CBPeripherals and CBCentrals
conform to NSCopying.
And actually most CB objects can
be used as NS dictionary keys.
We've seen a lot of you
guys using an indirect map
between UUIDs and CB
objects and all of that.
Just use the CB objects
as dictionary keys.
It simplifies a lot
of the codes.
I know I simplify a lot
of my code by doing that.
So, please just use that as
keys and you'll see it's great.
Please, please do not touch
the Client Configuration
Characteristic Descriptor
directly.
This is not going to work
and you guys may
already have tried that.
These are not going to work.
This is going to break the
state in the application.
So, we have an API for that
whether set notify value
for descriptor which--
for characteristic, sorry,
which is much easier
to use and it's going
to work instead of that.
Please, please do not game
the background mechanisms.
We are not stupid.
We know it's the kind of
tricks you guys are using
and if you start using them
or you continue using them,
you're going to get
in trouble eventually.
And we hope that we-- what we
introduce today with iOS 7,
you will have all the
tools and APIs especially
with application restoration,
things that Jason
have told about.
You have all to the
tools for you to not have
to use these nasty
tricks that nobody likes.
We don't like them.
You don't like them.
We know we've provided
you everything.
We hope that that you don't
need to do that anymore.
And that's it for my tips
and best practices session.
And I'm going call back Brian
to have the final words.
>> Pretty amazing stuff, right?
I mean this-- this in my mind
makes CoreBluetooth really the
launching platform for
really major initiates
in Bluetooth Low Energy.
I'm thrilled that we've
finally got this stuff in there.
And with the stuff around
restoration, you know,
preservation and restoration,
it completely opens up markets
that we know that you guys
have tried to participate in.
But now from a consumer's
perspective it should work all
the time.
It should be 100
percent up all the time.
Every time I walk in front of
my home door, it unlocks, right.
Every time that my blood
glucose monitor takes reading,
my phone knows about it.
And it's not going to
work some of the time
and not work the other time.
It's now completely bulletproof,
consumer-ready, you know,
industry leading technology.
And we're super, super
excited to bring it to you.
The other thing around Apple
Notification Center Service,
affectionately called ANCS, is
we feel like that that's going
to make this [inaudible]
products sing and the things
that you guys are going
to be doing with this.
It doesn't matter if it's a
watch like Renaud showed here
or something as simple as
fashion or jewelry that lights
up when you get a text message
from your significant other
or your child, the things
that you guys can make
with these things is
just going to be awesome
and I can't wait to see that.
One thing, I will note on Jason
and Renaud, these guys wrote
in part CoreBluetooth.
So, these, you cannot hear
from anybody more expert
in this particular topics.
And both of them will be
in the lab this afternoon
to answer any questions
you may have.
We also have folks like
Gus [phonetic] is here
who is our senior
engineer for all
of our Bluetooth
server and stack.
Ardy Kumar is here which is
one of our audio experts.
We have you know industry
leading engineering in this area
and they're all here to
answer questions for you.
So, if you do have more
questions definitely come
down into the lab
after this session
and we would love to
help you guys out.
One other question that we get
a lot and I don't have a slide
for it here but I just wanted
to cover it really quick is I
get a lot of people asking me,
"How do I submit apps that
use CoreBluetooth and talk
to Bluetooth Low
Energy hardware?
And so, the App Store
folks have asked me
to just give you a
couple of suggestions.
When you submit an app that's
using a Bluetooth Low Energy
device, send the
device in as well.
And when you send that device
in, the extremely explicit
and exactly what
that device does,
you could provide the
services and characteristics
that device implements.
Give it the-- you know describe
exactly what the device does.
How to use that device?
A lot of times we'll get a
device and it's like a big trunk
of plastic and there're not
buttons and it's like, OK,
that's great, you know.
And it goes on a
shelf somewhere.
So, just be explicit in
providing that information to us
when you send those apps.
And if you have more questions
on this, a lot of guys
from our [inaudible] team
will be in the lab as well
to answer some of those
questions in more detail
as much as they possibly can.
As always our Bluetooth
guidelines document is online.
You can search for this pretty
much anywhere and it's available
if you go in our developer site.
It's absolutely super
easy to find.
We constantly keep this updated
and this is being
updated as we speak.
I don't know if an
update is online yet.
Hopefully, it'll
be very, very soon.
And in addition to that,
for the first time,
we now have a CoreBluetooth
programming guide
or reference manual, finally.
It took us awhile
to get this done.
But we have some awesome writers
working on this and I know
that they have a little bit more
work to do to incorporate some
of the new things that
we've implemented in iOS 7.
But this will be available very,
very soon on the
developer portal as well.
So, definitely check it
out as soon it's there.
It's going to be a
huge, huge reference
of you guys not only the
kind of introduce you the lot
of the key concepts that
we brought up today.
But then it'll go into
lot of the reference
around that the actual code
and implementation details.
So, check it out.
For more information, we
have these people who eat
and breathe this stuff.
Craig and Stephen, both
of them are awesome guys.
They love to answer any
questions you may have
around CoreBluetooth or
Bluetooth in general.
We also have the
developer program, DTS.
It's a little bit more formal.
You're going to get a
guaranteed response with that.
Our developer programs, MFI,
we briefly talk about that
in our session this morning.
You're going to get for-- more
information from those guys
at our MFI web landing
page on the developer site.
In addition of that,
all these other things,
the one thing I want to iterate
right now before we go any
further is right now you guys
having your hands hopefully all
of you have updated
your devices to iOS 7.
You have the new SDK.
You're playing around with
it and you're going to come
to the lab with all
of your code in hand
and work with those on that.
And if you haven't, we're going
to have another lab on Thursday.
So, hopefully that gives you a
couple of more nights to work
through upgrading your code.
But bring that to us,
if for whatever reason
you can't make it,
or even if you can make it
and you find what
you think are bugs,
report those bugs
especially right now.
This is the time to
get those bugs to as
so that we can investigate these
issues and get them resolve
as quickly as possible.
And if by the way send an email
to Craig or Stephen as well just
to let them know, hey, I found
this issue, it's the problem.
The developer forums
are both active,
very active for iOS and Mac.
We have a great community
in that space
that you guys are
helping each other
to solve a lot of
these problems.
We personally cannot respond
to everything that's
going on in those forms.
But rest assured we
read every single post.
I personally read every
single post in those spaces.
I can't always respond but
I love hearing the feedback.
And certainly we take all that
information and internalize it.
As far as what's going
on, with other sessions.
There was a session
this morning--
you cannot go back in time.
If you can, good for you.
But if you can't, you
can watch this later.
The WWDC app is making a lot
of these sessions
available almost instantly.
So, definitely go check it out.
And then we didn't talk a
whole lot about proximity.
Well, because they're talking
about that in Core Location.
We felt like that's a
location services technology
and the Core Location guys
should really go into that.
There is a session on Thursday
that you guys should check out.
So, I want close
was just talking
about these used cases again.
And I want to kind of reiterate
how important we think Bluetooth
Low Energy is to the future
of accessory communications.
I mean all of these used
cases are profoundly important
to the consumer.
And when they have iOS
products in their hand
and it just naturally
communicates
with these devices we really are
starting to realize this concept
of the internet of things.
And it's just incredibly
powerful.
And it's super, super exciting
to be an engineer working
in communications because
of the nature the fact
that we can now truly put a
radio in everything around us
and have it fully integrate
with the consumer's
applications in their devices.
And ultimately it means this
idea of connecting the world
that we can connect
all these devices
in this heterogeneous
ecosystem that's just going
to create incredibly profound
experiences for our customers.
So, with that, I'd like to thank
you for coming for our session.
Enjoy WWDC.
We'll see you guys in the lab.
Thanks. [Applause]