>> Hello everyone.
[ Applause ]
>> So I'm Mike Stern.
I'm a User Experience
Evangelist at Apple,
and thank you all for coming.
And sticking around,
after a really long day
of very technical content.
Now, this presentation is going
to be a bit different, right?
This is about design.
And in particular, it's about
designing intuitive interfaces.
I'd like to start with
a little exercise.
Imagine if you will that
you're at your house,
and you're in your kitchen,
and the phone rings.
And the person on the other end
of the line has some really
exciting news for you.
They tell you that
you've won some money.
Not just a little bit of
money, but like a lot of money.
And they also tell you that
in order to claim your prize,
you need to call a phone number.
And then, they hang
up the phone.
And so you're sitting there
in your kitchen, and you need
to write down this phone number.
And you need to write down
this phone number before you
forget it.
So you're looking around
for something to write with.
Your iPhone is not
around, right?
And you're casting
around, and you're starting
to get a little panicky
because you really want
to remember this number, and
right before you forget it,
you see a pen and a piece
of paper, and you write
down the phone number.
So that's a pretty
simple scenario, right?
That was the end of
the story, by the way.
[Applause] Thank you, thank
you very much [laughter].
So you had this very clear
objective, which was to write
down this phone number, and you
found a pen and a pad of paper
with which to accomplish
that task, and then you wrote
down the phone number.
And that was it.
Well, it's not really
quite that simple.
You were under pressure.
You were stressing
out a little bit,
and when you're stressed out,
that can affect your memory.
And it can affect your ability
to perform basic
cognitive tasks,
such as remembering a phone
number and writing it down.
Or picking out a pen from
a bunch of similar objects,
things that look
just like a pen.
And assuming that you can
remember the phone number,
and find the pen and
paper, and write it down,
you have to also consider,
what are all the skills
that are necessary
for you to write?
For starters, writing
involves a lot
of coordination and dexterity.
Just ask a 3-year-old.
They totally suck at
writing [laughter].
And so did all of you, and so
did I, when we were that age.
We went from writing like
this-- to writing like that.
Or at least something like this.
Writing with a pen takes
years and years of practice,
and there's all of these small
little skills that you need
to learn along the way.
They're so fluid and
natural to you now,
but they weren't always so easy.
You had to gain the eye-hand
coordination to be able to pick
up and manipulate small objects.
And it took years to learn
how to hold a pen properly,
and position your
wrist on the table,
and your arm for stability.
You had to learn how to
draw basic letter forms.
Or write along a straight line.
You needed to learn the
difference between upper case
and lower case letters.
The list goes on.
But you don't think about any of
those things when you're sitting
in your kitchen and writing
down that phone number.
All of those years of writing
with different types of pens
and pencils and markers
and crayons have given
you this tremendous amount
of muscle memory.
And that muscle memory frees you
to remember something
like a phone number.
If you had to consciously
remember all
of those individual skills,
it would be pretty difficult
for you to have accomplished
that task.
In other words, it's easier
for you to have written down
and remembered that phone
number because the act
of writing is so intuitive.
Using software is no different.
The more apps behave
as we expect them to,
the more intuitive
they are to us.
The more intuitive apps are
to us, the easier it is for us
to concentrate on
our true objectives,
whether that's communicating
with friends, capturing memories
of loved ones, checking
the weather,
or exploring the cosmos.
The very best user interfaces
are so intuitive, so natural,
that they just sort of
disappear, and allow us to focus
on what truly matters.
That is what we call intuitive.
So with that in mind, what
makes an app intuitive?
Well, I've put together
a list of what I believe
to be the top five
characteristics
of intuitive user and
interface designs.
And this is not an
exhaustive list.
We could be here for hours
and hours and hours talking
about all of the things that
makes something intuitive.
We would order pizza,
get drinks,
it would be a lot of fun.
But unfortunately, we don't
have the time for that today.
This list of five things
I think are the most basic
and essential characteristics
of what makes an iOS
or Mac app intuitive.
And I also want to point out up
front here that what's intuitive
to one person may not be
so intuitive to others.
I mean, this is intuitive
if you're an airline pilot.
Every button, every switch,
every display is there
for a very good reason.
You know where everything is.
Totally natural.
I'm pretty sure this
doesn't work [laughter].
I also want to point out
that these are the most
fundamental things.
The most basic things.
But design is just like
anything else in life.
I mean, sometimes the most basic
things are the most important.
The most consequential.
I've been designing for many
years, and I've seen time
and time again, even
the most seasoned,
the most experienced designers,
who make poor quality designs
because they've lost
sight of the fundamentals.
Now, in order for a
pen to be intuitive,
it needs to get some
very fundamental
or basic things just right.
It needs to be wide enough to
grip firmly, but not so wide
that it can't be
manipulated easily.
If a pen is too thin, or too
wide, it becomes intuitive
because we become aware of it.
We're trying to think how are
we going to write with this pen?
It doesn't feel quite right.
Or if a pen was too short,
we would not know how
to hold it, right?
We would pick it up with our
fingertips and we'd be writing
with it, it'd be going
all over the place,
and what we write
wouldn't look very good.
We'd be very conscious
of the pen itself.
Or if a pen was too long,
there'd be an opposite problem.
The top of the pen would be
swinging all over the place,
it would feel heavy,
our hands would strain.
Again, we'd be very
conscious of the pen itself.
Designing a pen to have
the right diameter,
or the right length,
seem like pretty basic
and obvious things, right?
Yet, there are countless pen
and app designs that fail
because their designers
have lost sight
of these fundamentals.
And before we dive in, I'll
just say one more thing,
which is that being intuitive
is not very intuitive.
It's actually pretty
difficult to do.
You have to understand the fact
that you're not designing
just for yourself.
You're designing
for other people.
And those people, they don't
know the things that you know.
And they frankly probably
aren't as passionate
about your app as you are.
So they're going to tend
to be a bit impatient,
easily frustrated,
fickle, right?
Designing an intuitive
interface isn't possible
until you can get
out of your own head.
You need to recognize your
own assumptions about things.
About who the people
you're designing for are,
what they're trying
to accomplish.
What they know, what
they don't know.
You need to see clearly, and
you need to hear clearly,
and figure out what it is that
you can do to help them succeed.
If you can do that, you will
have done an amazing thing.
People will appreciate the
fact that you cared enough
to make a great user experience.
So let's dive in, and find
out what the top five
characteristics are,
starting with platform savvy.
Now, let's go back
to pens again.
You see this particular
pen, but you're not going
to have any trouble
writing with it,
because you've used thousands
and thousands of pens before,
and those experiences, writing
with all those different pens,
has given you this
generalized understanding
of how all pens work.
They have shaped your
expectations, and they're going
to influence your behavior.
And when you pick up that
pen, and you write with it,
sure enough, it works
like you expected it to.
And if it didn't, you'd
become frustrated.
When someone uses your
app for the first time,
they do so with all
sorts of expectations
about how it's supposed to work.
Now, these expectations
are formed and affected
by so many different factors,
but the most important
of those is that individual's
experience using other iOS
or Mac apps.
Those could be ones that
were built into their device
when they purchased it, or
they could be ones that many
of you here today
have made for them.
Now, let's just take
a look at an example.
Swiping a table row to
reveal some actions.
In particular, let's look
at swiping a table row
to reveal some kind of Delete
button or Trash button.
Now, we're all really
familiar with this.
And we first encountered it
maybe with Mail, and we thought,
hey, that's kind of neat, right?
I don't have to go open the
E-mail to see the Trash button
so that I can delete it.
I don't have to go into
some kind of edit mode,
I can just use a gesture
to delete it right away.
And after doing this
a couple of times,
well you got into
the habit of it.
You started to learn to expect
this behavior, this interaction.
Now you open Notes for
the very first time.
Never seen this before,
and, you know,
notes looks a little
bit different from Mail,
but not completely different.
There's some similarities.
Like Mail, everything is
arrayed in a scrollable view,
and there's these little gray
lines that separate them,
and you know, you figure
that like E-mail messages,
Notes can be deleted.
So you think to yourself,
well I should be able to swipe
to reveal a Delete button.
You don't even have
to think about it.
In fact, you probably don't.
You try swiping to delete,
because unconsciously you
believe that it should work.
Intuitively, you
think it should work.
And when it does,
you're rewarded
with the outcome
that you expected.
And if it didn't, you
would be frustrated.
You would say "why
did they not do that?"
It makes so much sense, right?
You now have to figure out how
you're going to delete a Note.
Swiping to delete is
a platform convention,
and it's among thousands
and thousands
of different platform
conventions
that iOS users have
come to expect.
And not only do they expect
swipe to delete to work
in whatever situation it would
make sense for it to work,
they expect every aspect
of that interaction
to match their previous
experience.
From the sense of
direct manipulation,
to how far they need to drag
the row to reveal the buttons,
maybe even the color and the
size of the button itself.
Any deviations from these
things, no matter how small
or insignificant, could be
incorrectly perceived by them
as being meaningfully different.
Or maybe they just
get this vague sense
that something's
not quite right.
Being consistent with
platform conventions,
in other words, is
a very good thing.
Gestures like pinch, swipe,
pan, tap, they should work
in very consistent ways, no
matter what type of app we use.
Same is true for controls,
like switches or buttons,
or navigation bars,
tables, and tab bars.
And there are also powerful
conventions about the labels
that we use to convey
certain actions,
or the icons that we use.
Now, this symbol may have
not been immediately familiar
to you the first
time you saw it,
but after you shared
something a couple of times,
you started to get a sense of
what that symbol represents.
You know what kind of
functionality is accessed
by tapping that button.
And these conventions that
exist, at least for iOS and Mac,
are not at all arbitrary.
Swiping to delete
isn't just intuitive
because of the thousands and
thousands of apps that support
that same interaction.
It's consistent, or
sorry, that's a part of it,
but it's not the whole story.
It's intuitive to
us because it's
like the real-world experiences
that we all share together.
It's like crossing something
off of a list, or you know,
being a 2-year-old
and eating food
and swiping it out of your way.
Right? You don't want it
anymore, so you're going
to swipe to get rid of it.
There is countless, countless
conventions that exist
for any platform for
which you're designing,
and it's important to recognize
what those conventions are,
because that's what
people are going to expect.
But sometimes it's necessary
to break those conventions.
Now, this is actually
not that common,
but maybe you're designing an
app that's never existed before.
A new type of experience.
Or you're designing
for a new type of user,
a new type of scenario,
or context?
Maybe you're just trying
to solve a problem that we,
at Apple, or other, you
guys have never tried
to solve before, right?
So there is no precedent
to follow.
Now, if that's the case for
you, you have a responsibility
to tell people, to inform
them that you have decided
to do something different
with your app.
Now, let's take a
look at an example.
This is Leo's Fortune.
We saw that it won
ADA yesterday.
That's Leo, up there,
on the wooden scale.
Now, as you can see,
there's only one button
on the screen, the Pause button.
Everything else is
done through gestures.
And these gestures,
they're intuitive,
but they're not standard.
They're not really obvious.
So the game provides
instruction.
It teaches you about
them one at a time.
You use your left thumb
to move left and right
so that he moves
forward and backwards.
Or you swipe up your
right thumb to inflate Leo
so that he can hop over
obstacles like this ledge.
These are non-standard
interactions and the developers
of this game knew that they had
to educate people about them,
or else players would
be confused,
and they would become
frustrated,
quit and delete the game.
Wouldn't be a very good
experience for them.
Now, that's all I'm going to
say when it comes to onboarding
and help today, because we
have an entire hour dedicated
to this topic.
It's a really great
presentation,
and I encourage everyone
here to go.
It's Thursday, in the Mission.
I'll see you there.
The next characteristic of
intuitive user interfaces is
that they're easy to navigate.
Now, intuitive navigation
systems do three things
really well.
First, they just tell
you where you are.
The clock app, with its tab bar,
does a really good job of that.
Makes it perfectly clear
what your location is.
And I'm sorry it's so low on the
screen, I know everyone is going
to have to crane their
necks in order to see it.
Now apps that use
a Navigation Bar
and have a title also
do a really good job
of telling you where you are.
The title serves that purpose.
The next thing that
they do is they show you
where else you could go.
They show you what
your options are.
So the phone app,
again with a tab bar,
does a very good job of it.
It just means having everything
on screen and visible.
Pretty simple.
And the third thing that they
do is they explain what's there.
Meaning the navigation
system informs you
about what's contained
within each section.
You don't have to go
to every single section
to figure out what's inside.
So let's take a step
back for a second, right?
Why do we need navigation
to begin with?
We need navigation because
there's way too much information
and functionality in
any given app to display
on screen at one point in time.
So we group things together.
Make these categories, or
sections, and these categories
that we come up with, they need
to be understandable and logical
to people who are
using your app.
It shouldn't feel like a mystery
what's behind or what's inside
of each of these
category labels.
So the phone app succeeds
because each of these icons
and labels that's used makes the
content inside self-explanatory.
Meaning, it provides a good
explanation of what types
of key information or
functionality is contained
within each section of the app.
So in other words, intuitive
navigation systems answer three
basic questions.
Where am I?
Where else can I go?
And what will I find
when I get there?
Now, these seem like
really basic things, right?
Everyone here is
kind of smirking,
it's like totally obvious.
But it turns out that
designing a navigation system
that can accomplish these
three things well is pretty
challenging to make.
So with that in mind, I
have a few tips for you
about how you can make
your navigation system
really intuitive.
Starting with progressive
disclosure.
Now, if you're not familiar
with what this term
is, it's pretty simple.
It just means not
showing things to people
until they actually need it.
Now, you do that by kind
of creating a little bit
of a deeper hierarchy, or adding
a few more steps in a process.
Now this seems like it
might take more time to get
to your destination,
or get the outcome
that you're after,
but it's worth it.
Because it makes decision making
simple and un-intimidating
at every stage of the process.
So ultimately, you're
able to get
to your destination more
quickly and more confidently.
Unless, that is, you
use category names
that aren't logical,
or not meaningful.
So in this situation, if
you're reading the slide,
we're picking a mode of
transportation for getting
from one place to another.
And if we're doing
that, the first choice
that we have is do
you want to go by air
or do you want to go by land?
Now, that makes a
lot of sense, right?
Those things are kind of
mutually exclusive choices.
And these labels are pretty good
because if we're going to go
by air, we figure
that one of the items
in that category is going to
be a choice to go by airplane.
Or if we're going by land, we're
going to have the options to go
by car or maybe by rail.
We don't know all of the choices
that are contained inside,
but we get an inkling.
We get an understanding
about what things
are contained within.
Now, if we decide to go by
land, we get the second choice.
This is a disastrous
set of labels for us.
Now, we can go take a mode of
transportation that uses fuel,
or it doesn't use
fuel, but now all
of a sudden we're
thinking about,
well okay a car uses fuel.
But if I want to take a
train, does that use fuel?
I mean, it's like, steam power?
Fuel? Or coal?
Right? What if it's electric?
What if I'm taking
light rail, you know?
Maybe that's no fuel, I
mean it's electricity,
but it could be solar powered,
or wind powered,
or nuclear powered.
Instead of getting to where
I want to go, I'm asking all
of these esoteric questions
about the nature of fuel
and the meaning of
that word, right?
These are not very good labels.
That uncertainty is
causing hesitation,
and it's making me aware
of the interface itself
and trying to decode it.
Again, use progressive
disclosure, but make sure
that it doesn't feel like
you're trying to figure
out what's behind door number 3.
Now, the next tip I have
is about being predictable.
Everyone likes surprises, right?
Except when it comes
to navigation.
With navigation, we
do not like surprises.
When navigation changes on
us unexpectedly and in ways
that we can't explain
or rationalize,
we can get really
confused and tripped up.
So let's take a look
at how this can happen.
So let's say we're making
a banking app, right?
And we have a few
choices to select from.
And then once we
register and then log in,
there's a few other
sections that are added.
So the navigation has changed,
but I guess I can explain
to myself why things changed
in the way that they did.
Or maybe the bank
decides they're going
to add this awesome new feature
of giving away free cash, right?
I want to bank at this bank.
This is a great feature.
So they put it right at the top,
because they think their
customers are really going
to love it.
But then someone comes to
their senses and decides
that they're not going to be
able to give away that feature
of free cash much longer,
so they de-emphasize it
and they reduce its
visibility in the list
by pushing it to the bottom.
So it's changed.
Or let's say we looked at
the analytics of the app,
and we've talked to all the
people who are using it,
and we figured out that
people really want mostly
to find locations or figure
out how to contact the bank,
so we move that stuff
to the top.
Now there's hundreds of reasons
why navigation can change.
Some of them are good, some of
them are bad or just terrible,
but whatever the reason is,
there's always this downside
retraining people on how
to do something that they're
familiar with, takes time,
and it can be really
frustrating for people.
I mean I think we've
all had this experience
where we've been going to
like a website or using an app
for a very long period of time,
and then it was redesigned,
and all of a sudden
we're thrown off.
We have to study the
interface and figure
out where things went to.
We had just been used
to pressing the red
thing over there, right?
We weren't even reading
the label, and now we have
to study it, and figure
out where that went to.
Even the smallest changes
can really trip people up.
So by all means, change your
interface when you need to,
but do it carefully, and
don't do it frequently.
Now, the next point
is really obvious.
But it's worth talking
about anyway,
and that is that selection
needs to be immediately obvious.
On iOS tab bars, for example,
we use color to show selection.
And we also use shape.
So on the left-hand side,
you can see sometimes
icons get filled in,
and on the right
side you can see
that sometimes they get thicker.
Now part of the reason for
this is that it makes it easier
to show the selection color,
to see the selection color,
but there's another reason
for using a thicker
or filled in shape.
So let's take a look
at the clock app again.
Now we can all see, unless
you're sitting in the back,
that the world's
clock is selected.
It's very obvious right?
Well let's say we
didn't have enough time
to design a totally different
set of icons for the active
or selected state, so instead,
we just use the off state,
but we tinted it red, and we
put that into the interface.
Well, right off the
bat, you can see
that selection is
a lot less obvious.
And it's really not obvious
if you're color blind.
Now, just as a common practice,
something to always
remember to do.
Take screen shots of your app,
bring them into the graphic
design tool of your choice,
and desaturate them,
and make sure
that you can still clearly
see state and selection.
This is a really
important thing to do.
With the filled in tab bar icon,
it's still at least possible
to see what selection,
if the color red looks
like gray to you [applause].
See. And even if you
can see every color
of the spectrum just fine,
using a filled-in shape
makes selection more obvious
for all of us.
This is a case of doing the
right thing for accessibility
and improving the
experience for everyone.
Next, navigation systems
that are intuitive
maximize continuity.
Now, in a profession,
in a world of UI Design,
we use this word
flow all the time.
And all it really means is this
is the experience of moving
from one place to another.
One view to the next.
One state to a different state,
or section to a different
section.
And intuitive navigation
system is designed
to minimize disruption,
or maximize continuity,
by keeping people
oriented, as they flow
through the experience.
So let's take an example.
This is the photos app for iOS.
And here we're looking at a
grid of photos, and when we tap
on one of those photos, it
zooms up, fills the screen.
And this is really
important for usability,
because without having
to think about it,
you know that the
photo you tapped
on is the one now
you're looking at.
You get that instantaneous
confirmation, again,
without having to
think about it.
And the animation to go back
is just the opposite, reversed.
And this is also important for
the usability of the photos app,
because now you're back in the
grid view, and you know exactly
which photo you had just been
looking at, so you know how
to proceed forward or backward
from that specific photo.
Now, if this animation
had been done differently,
instead we tapped on the
photo, and the big photo slid
in from the right, we
wouldn't have the benefit
of that continuous experience.
We would have to remember
which, what the photo looked
at that we wanted to look
at, and then compare it
with the image we're
now looking at.
And the same is true
when we go back.
We have to remember what that
photo we were just looking
at looked like, and compare it
to the photos in the grid view.
Now, this is a very simple
UI animation concept.
But it's a powerful one,
and it's used in all sorts
of different iOS
apps that we make,
as well as on the
home screen itself.
And, what's more, is we use
it all over the place on OS X
as well, for the
very same reasons.
Okay. The next tip is
about providing hints.
Provide hints to
people when they seem
to be getting confused.
This is the app, Sky Guide.
Again, also won at
ADA yesterday.
And it provides information
about the entire
universe, right?
You get to see detailed
information about Betelgeuse,
and countless other
solar bodies that exist.
Now, you may think
that the way you get
that information is just
by tapping on a star.
That's pretty logical.
That's pretty intuitive, right?
That's how you get
information about something
in just about any app.
But if you thought that,
you would be 100 percent
completely and totally wrong.
The real way that you get
information about a star is
by pressing the i button
over on the right-hand side
of the screen.
But if that i button was just
sitting there the whole time,
well, you wouldn't know
what it represented.
You might think it's
just general information
about the app itself, or you
know, like the cosmos, right?
So to clarify that for
people, Sky Guide does a couple
of very simple things with
animation to help you out.
When you select a star,
when you select a star,
the i button fades in and
it pulses a little bit,
just draws your attention to it.
And when you de-select the
star, it just fades out.
And that gives you
this understanding
that there is a relationship
between the star
that you have selected
and the info button.
It's very effective.
Very subtle.
I mean you're not necessarily
even thinking about that.
And what's even cooler than
that, is that if you happen
to think that double tapping
a star will also give you
information about
the star, as I did,
then the i button will just
keep pulsing every time you tap
on that star.
So it's elegantly
redirecting your attention back
over to the i button,
because they can infer
by how you're interacting
with the app
that that's what your intention
is, is to get information
about the star, and they're
retraining you, redirecting you.
Okay. And the last and
probably most important tip
that I have is that
less is more.
Picking between a smaller
number of choices is faster,
and easier, than picking from
a larger number of choices.
I told you I would say a lot of
really dumb and obvious things.
Now giving people too many
choices can slow them down,
and it can be intimidating.
You might think that
you're impressing people
who are using your app with
how feature-rich your app is.
But their takeaway
may be very different.
They may think that your app
is too much for their needs,
or just too intimidating.
And when we see a long list like
this, I mean, we all know this.
We start to skim over things.
We don't want to spend hours
and hours looking at this app.
So we're just going to
glance down really quickly.
But when we do that, inevitably,
we wind up skipping over things.
And the things that we skip
over may very well have been the
things that we wanted to select.
Which means that if we're
skipping over the stuff
that we wanted to
select, that the people
who are using your app are
not getting what they want
out of it.
They're not realizing
your app's full potential.
And if you can't limit
the number of choices
that you're offering
to people, again,
use progressive disclosure to
help keep decision making simple
and unintimidating at
every step in the process.
Now, that's a lot
about navigation.
And I promise I'm going to
talk about other things.
But I feel like I
would be remiss
if I didn't use this
opportunity to talk with you
about hamburger menus.
[Laughter & Applause] AKA
Slide out menus, AKA sidebars,
AKA basements, AKA drawers.
Now, these controls
are very common on iOS,
and on other platforms.
And I'm sure many of you here
work on apps that have these.
You guys made the decision
to put it in your app.
And I'm sure that you did
so with the very
best of intentions.
And I will say that these
controls do a couple
of things very well.
For one thing, they save space.
So rather than taking up a
bunch of room at the bottom
of the screen for a tab
bar, you're just taking
up a little bit of area
in the top left corner
for the hamburger menu.
And you practically have the
entire height of the screen
to show options to people,
and if that's not enough,
you're going to cram more
awesomeness into your app,
people can scroll, right.
But --
[ Laughter & Applause ]
this is-- I actually
haven't played
around with the latest version
of Xcode, so I really hope
that they haven't changed this,
I don't believe you'll find a
hamburger menu controller inside
of Xcode [laughter].
Now, typically we don't provide
design advice about the things
that we don't offer to you guys,
but I can't help myself, right?
I've had so many conversations
with people about this control,
spending hours and hours
and hours talking about it,
and you know, I think
it's important
that we talk about
it here today.
And again, I'm not going to
say that there's no place
for these controls
categorically.
I think there are some apps
that could maybe use one.
But I will say that their
value is greatly over-stated,
and they have huge
usability downsides too.
Remember, the three key things
about an intuitive navigation
system is that they tell you
where you are, and they show
you where else you can go.
Hamburger menus are terrible
at both of those things,
because the menu is
not on the screen.
It's not visible.
Only the button to
display the menu is.
And in practice,
talking to developers,
they found this out themselves.
That people who use
their app don't switch
to different sections
very frequently
when they use this menu.
And the reason for that
is because the people
who use their app don't
know where else they can go.
Right? They don't know because
they can't see the options,
or maybe they saw it
at one point in time,
but they have since forgotten.
And if you use this control,
you have to recognize
that the people who use your
app may not realize the full
potential of your app.
Hamburger menus are also
just tedious, right?
If you want to switch
sections from the Accounts tab
to the Transfers tab, all you
need to do is tap the button
and you're there instantly,
and if you want to go back,
you tap the Accounts
button, and you're back
where you started from.
Doing the same thing with the
hamburger menu involves opening
the menu, waiting for
the animation to finish,
re-orienting yourself, finding
the option you're interested in,
tapping that, and then waiting
for the animation to complete,
getting back to where you
were before, and if you want
to go back, you have
to open the menu again,
go through that whole process,
and there you are, again.
It takes at least twice as
many taps to change sections.
Something that should
be very easy
and fluid is made
more difficult.
And the other thing the
hamburger menus quite frankly do
badly is that they don't play
nicely with back buttons.
Right? I've seen this a lot.
Back buttons are supposed to go
in that top left
corner position,
but instead there's this
hamburger menu there,
so people put the back
button right next to it,
but no longer does this look
like a back button anymore,
it just looks like this
arrow which is pointing
to the hamburger menu,
looks ridiculous,
and sometimes people recognize
that it looks ridiculous,
so when you drill down into
the hierarchy of an app,
the hamburger menu goes away.
Now it takes even more steps to
switch to a different section.
You have to go back up enough
times to get to a level
in the hierarchy of an
app to get to a view
that contains the
hamburger menu.
Now, sometimes people
will try to solve this
by putting the menu on
the right-hand side,
but that's not advisable either.
That location is a
really important location.
Usually you can put some kind
of action there, you know,
like a plus sign to add
something, or an edit button.
And finally, the downside
of being able to show a lot
of options is that you
can show a lot of options.
Is that you will show
a lot of options.
The potential for bloat
and misuse is tremendous.
They allow you to add
all sorts of stuff
that your users don't
really care about.
Like information about the app.
Or version history, or credits.
I hate to break it to
you, but no one cares.
[ Laughter & Applause ]
And the other thing is that
people wind up taking ads
and special offers and
making them look just
like regular sections and
putting it in there too.
That sucks.
No one wants that either.
Look, drawers of any kind
have a nasty tendency
to fill with junk.
Okay, let's move on.
[ Applause ]
Thank you.
Okay, the next major
characteristic
of intuitive navigation,
or sorry, we're not talking
about navigation anymore,
intuitive user interfaces,
is that they are clear.
Now, this applies to the
information apps present,
and the functionality
that they present.
Information and functionality
need
to be straightforward
and understandable.
It's easy for people to do
things, so they're not trying
to decode or interpret
what it is they're saying.
And clarity is this very broad,
but very powerful concept.
And just about everything
I've said
about navigation really boils
down to just being clear.
Is it clear where you are?
Is it clear where
else you can go?
Is it clear what
type of information
or functions you'll
find when you get there?
But clarity applies to so much
more than just navigation.
Now, let's start with language.
Now obviously, we rely
heavily upon the written word
to communicate with the
people who use our app.
But how well do they
understand what we're saying?
It turns out that that's a
really hard question for us
to answer, and it's
especially hard to answer
that question before
they've even had a chance
to use the app.
But there are a few
things that you can do
to increase the likelihood
that you're speaking
and communicating as
clearly as possible.
Now, here are six ways that you
can be sure that you're being
as clear as possible, starting
with using simple words.
Now if you're designing an app
for a large number of people,
avoid using big words
that people may have
trouble understanding.
So here's you.
And this red circle, that
represents your vocabulary.
Now, you use words from your
vocabulary to write the text
that you're going to put
in your app's interface,
and that's great while
you're developing it,
but once you shift, along
come some other people.
And their vocabularies are
different than your own.
They may not be native
speakers of your language.
They may have different
educational backgrounds.
Whatever the reason is,
it doesn't really matter.
The bottom line is
that the number
of words you share
in common is limited.
So use simpler words that
most people will understand,
most of the time.
Those words, they may not
be as precise or descriptive
as you would like them to be,
but it's going to make it easier
for more people to
enjoy your app.
The next tip is to avoid jargon.
People shouldn't need
to be computer scientists
to use an app.
So, for example, we
say airplane mode.
We don't say turn off radios.
Now, turn, off, radios,
those are really basic words,
but most people don't
understand what radios mean
in this context.
They just think it's like
the AM/FM radio they have
in their house.
So we use airplane mode.
It's much more effective.
And this isn't just about
computer mumbo-jumbo,
this is kind of about
everything.
So let's just say we're making
an app about renewable energy,
and this app is intended to be
used by people who own houses,
or office buildings or what
have you, and they're interested
in doing the right thing
for the environment
or just saving money.
They're not necessarily
really well informed about all
of the technologies that
they can choose from.
Now, they shouldn't need to know
what a photovoltaic module is.
They're going to say
solar panels, right?
Photovoltaic what now?
Right? A better design is one
that leads with solar panels,
leads with the commonplace term,
and if you want to define it
for people, that's great.
You're educating them, right?
Well, it's kind of synonymous
with photovoltaic modules.
So now, when that individual
goes somewhere else and they see
that term, well they're
going to know what it means.
But there is a bit of
a qualification here.
And that is that it's
critical to know your audience.
So in this scenario, we
were designing an app
which is targeted at a consumer.
That someone is, it's a
large audience of people
who I described, right?
And we don't know
what they know.
And they probably can't
take anything for granted.
So we want to use a
term like solar panels.
But imagine we were designing
an app which was to be used
by the technicians, the people
who install solar
panels in people's homes.
Well, they're probably going
to be a lot better informed
about the technology.
Maybe they intuitively or just
naturally would use the word
photovoltaic modules.
It's more precise.
In fact, they would be
embarrassed to use an app
which says solar panels.
They wouldn't want
to be caught dead--
they'd be laughed at
by their colleagues.
So think about your app.
Now there's a spectrum, and
it's important to consider,
are you're targeting a
consumer or a professional?
Correctly positioning your app
on that spectrum is the key
to making sure that
your app is intuitive
for the audience
who is using it.
Now, the next tip is
about being descriptive.
So sometimes I see this.
There's an option
that says Home.
Well what's on the Home screen?
I have no idea.
Home is very undescriptive.
In fact, it always
suggests to me
that the person designing
the app probably comes
from a web design background.
On iOS, we try to be really
descriptive about what kind
of content or functionality
you would find on that screen.
So use better words that
are more descriptive.
And next, be succinct.
Brevity is a virtue.
Next, avoid truncation
[Applause].
It's really hard to read text
when it's not all visible
on the screen at
one point in time.
Being succinct, and using
shorter words will help.
And finally, you could have the
best copy in the whole world,
I mean, beautiful prose.
But it won't do you much good
if people are having a
hard time reading it.
So use a type face
which is legible.
And make sure that text is
large enough for people to read
at a comfortable
viewing distance.
Not with their face
pressed against the device
or the computer screen.
And if you're making an
iOS app, I highly recommend
that you use dynamic type.
This will pretty much assure
that text will be as legible
as our built-in apps,
and for those people
who have a hard time
reading, have bad eyesight,
well they can adjust font size
to suit their individual needs.
Now, just as important
as speaking clearly
with words is communicating
clearly with visual symbols.
In fact, a well-designed icon
can often communicate a concept
more quickly and more
effectively than any word can.
But icons are really
tricky to get right.
I mean, what does
this icon mean, right?
It means nothing.
I mean, if I just saw this,
I would think maybe it's
like a beach ball floating in
a fish tank, or it's a dish
in a dish rack, or it's like
a super modern door knocker.
Right? Without any context, I
have no idea what this means.
This is a terrible icon.
So what kind of icons
will work well?
Well, there's some icons
which are successful
because they're internationally
recognizable,
such as this information sign.
We've seen information signs in
museums, in malls, and airports,
and we always know
what they mean.
It means getting
information about something.
Next, there's symbols which
are so pervasively used
in so many types of apps,
like this magnifying glass,
that we understand what
it's trying to tell us.
We know that this
relates to searching.
Even if the particular
form of searching may vary.
And next, there's icons
that are successful
because they represent
these real ordinary,
commonplace objects that
we've all used in our lives.
We've all owned an alarm clock,
or we've at least
seen one on TV.
So when we see this icon that
looks like an alarm clock,
we know what it's trying
to communicate to us.
So let's flip this around a bit.
What types of icons
don't work well?
Well if your icon needs a label
in order to be understandable,
that's a really bad sign.
If your icon represents
a commonplace object
that many people have never seen
in their life, that's a problem.
And if you use a
really common icon,
but in a very non-standard,
unconventional way,
then it's time to go back to the
drawing board, and start over.
And also if you ever
catch yourself or someone
around you says, "Well it
may not be perfectly clear,
but people will learn what it
means eventually," then I'd
like all of you people to
meet me over here after,
because I have this
awesome bridge
that I'd very much
like to sell you.
Look, it's not that
icons can't be learned.
It's just that they're
not likely to be learned.
Why would I find out
what an icon does
if I don't know what it means?
Why would I even tap
on it or click it?
Maybe it's going to do
something destructive?
And anyway, that's a really
low bar to set for yourself.
If you want to make a truly
intuitive app, don't settle
for icons that need
to be learned.
And I also want to mention
that icons are often used
because space is limited.
So they wind up being
kind of small.
So let's say we're making
an icon of a coffee cup.
And when we're making it, we're
using like a vector design tool,
and we're zoomed
into 3200 percent,
and we want to really get
creative with this, so yeah,
it's coffee, but you know,
it's hot coffee, so we're going
to add a little bit of steam,
and we want people to know
that if they happen
to tip the coffee cup,
it's going to be okay
because there's a saucer
that will catch all the coffee,
and you know, who likes boring,
blank vanilla coffee
mugs, right?
They often have pictures
and logos on them,
and coffee makes us happy, so
let's put a happy face on it.
But then when you display it
at the correct resolution,
all that detail gets
kind of lost.
Becomes muddy.
So don't add all those details.
It's better to render
the same symbol,
but with less visual detail.
It will be far more
clear when it's downsized
to the correct resolution.
And if that doesn't work,
just try using a
different symbol altogether.
Look, it's not always that easy
to come up with a great icon.
If you can't find a visual
symbol whose meaning is
universally, immediately,
and clearly understood,
then just stick with text.
Now, pictures and words.
These are really key
and important ways
of communicating information.
But there's another tool in the
tool box that I'd like to talk
with you about today,
and that's animation.
Animation can sometimes
communicate things far more
clearly than either
words or pictures.
One of my favorite examples
of this is the focus
and exposure indicator
in the camera app.
This animation of the focus
and exposure indicator says
three really critical things
very well.
First, by first appearing
and then scaling down,
it's drawing your attention
to the object of the part
of the image which is being used
to determine the correct
focus and exposure.
And because it's
getting smaller,
it's giving you this hint
that it's really precise.
Right? It's zeroing in
on a particular area.
And then when it stops getting
smaller, it just pulses twice,
which tells you that focus
and exposure have been locked.
And then, it simply fades
away, which tells you
that the process is
complete, and it's now okay
for you to take your photo.
Ready? Set.
And go. That's a lot of
information contained
in a very quick and
simple animation.
Let's look at another example.
The animation when you key
in the wrong passcode
on your lock screen.
Without saying a single word,
it just shakes its head no,
that's not the right
answer, I'm going to clear
out that gibberish that you just
entered, and let you try again.
Okay. So the second to
last major characteristic
of intuitive user interfaces
is that they are simple.
Now, the common element
of not overwhelming people
with too many options
at any one point
in time are using more basic
language to communicate
with people, or reducing the
extraneous visual ornamentations
from icons, is that
the user interface,
and the user experience,
needs to be simple.
Now, let's go back to that pen
and paper analogy for a second.
Remember, you were
in your kitchen,
and you were frantically hunting
around for a way to write
down that phone number.
And let's just say,
that just like before,
the pen was sitting
there and the pad
of paper was sitting there
on your kitchen table.
But there is also
some pieces of paper.
And there was also some dishes.
And your kids' toys.
That pen could be right
there, but you don't see it
because there are all
these other objects
which are demanding
your attention.
Complex apps are like this.
In order to do the most
basic and simple of things,
you have to wade
through a bunch of things
that you don't care about.
Simple apps take the
80/20 rule to heart.
Now, there's a lot
of definitions
for what the 80/20 rule means,
one of which is that 80 percent
of people are only going to
use 20 percent of features,
or that 80 percent of the
time, people are only going
to use 20 percent
of the capabilities
of any given system.
However you define it,
it's pretty simple.
Most of the time, most
people will use very little
of what you actually make.
And however you define
it, the takeaway is this.
If you show people information
that they don't care about,
or functions that
they don't need,
then all that stuff is just
going to distract them.
It will get in their way
and make it harder for them
to accomplish what it
is they want to do.
Now, I've been showing a
lot of iOS examples here,
and I want to talk
about Mac for a second,
and the context of simplicity.
Now, what does simplicity
mean for a Mac?
I mean Macs are very
different than iOS, right?
I mean for one thing, the
screens are much larger
than an iPad, let alone an
iPhone, so there's a lot of room
to show all sorts of
controls and information.
And a lot of times, that's
what people really want.
I mean, if you're designing
a professional application,
that's a good thing right?
Macs are all about
utility and power.
So Macs that are designed for
professionals take advantage
of this by offering
sophisticated
and advanced work flows,
and people use these apps
for really extended periods
of time, and as they do so,
they become comfortable in
managing all of that complexity.
And when they become
comfortable managing complexity,
other concerns come to the
fore, such as being efficient.
And efficiency is all
about availability,
meaning everything is in
plain sight, or within reach.
Okay. So that's a
good thing, actually.
But still, keep in mind that
if you're not just designing
for professionals, for a wider
range of people, maybe people
who are just wanting
to pick up new skills
and grow into that profession.
Just new users are trying to
learn the system, you don't want
to drop them into something
that looks like this.
Take the time to give them
this, and allow them to graduate
to something that's
more complicated.
Now, finally, the number
one characteristic,
and that's corny, of
intuitive user interfaces,
is that they are focused.
Now, the design of
this pen is successful
because it's perfectly
suited for the context
for which it was made.
It's a general purpose
writing tool that works well
in your home or in your office.
There's nothing about this
pen that's extraneous.
It's not made more
complicated by features
that people don't really
need all that often.
It just serves basic
writing tasks.
There's no ability to
change the color of the pen.
It's not double-sided in
case one side breaks down.
It doesn't have any kind of
laser pointing capability.
All of those features would make
this pen needlessly complicated.
The design of this pen is a very
singular and focused purpose.
Every aspect of this pen's
design serves that goal.
Its form invites us to pick it
up and to hold it comfortably
with a couple of fingers.
It's obvious how to
click open the pen tip,
and click it closed
again by pressing
on the button at the top.
It's obvious how to clip it to a
shirt pocket or a piece of paper
so that it's portable and
we can take it with us.
In other words, it's intuitive,
because of the intense focus
on supporting just a couple
of basic tasks like writing
and drawing, and being portable.
It is uncomplicated.
And therefore, it is made
intuitive to a wide range
of people and a wide
variety of contexts.
But focus can also
mean designing
to support very specialized,
or niche applications.
This calligraphy pen is
intuitive to a calligrapher.
Everything about
it they understand.
It makes total sense to them.
The shape, and the
nib of the pen.
But if you're not
a calligrapher,
and you pick this up, and
you try to write with it
as you would think to
intuitively, as you would write
with a pen, well the results
are going to be pretty ugly.
You're going to have a lot of
slashes and holes in the paper
that you're writing on.
The paintbrush, it's
the same thing.
This is intuitive to a painter.
But if you're not a painter,
you're going to make a mess.
The design of these
tools is optimized
for very specialized
applications,
and just like a pen, adding
any extra stuff would result
in a less successful and
a less intuitive design.
The beauty of iOS is that there
are hundreds of thousands,
I mean 1.2 million
apps, out there.
And many of the most
successful apps are successful
because they do just one or two
things, extraordinarily well.
In other words, they
were designed
around a clear and
singular purpose.
Focus means that your app can
and probably should do less.
If your app does less, you're
going to have more time
to iterate, to prototype, to
implement, polish and test.
If your app does less, you're
going to have less need
for complicated navigation
controls
that are difficult to use.
If your app does less, you can
spend more time crafting just
the right wording, or
picking just the right icons,
and making sure that you have
time to build in animations
that clearly and meaningfully
provide user feedback
and help people to
stay oriented.
Now, some of the best UI Design
advice that I ever received was
that great software
starts small.
You pick something that you're
really passionate about,
and that is important to real
people, and you try to figure
out what it is that you
can do to help make things
in their life better,
easier, faster, more fun.
More delightful.
And then you dive in.
And you make that happen.
And you don't ship
until you have something
that is truly great.
You don't ship until you
have something that you can
and should feel proud of.
If you've accomplished that,
your app will become
indispensable.
People won't delete it, because
the function it provides them
perfectly suits their needs.
It's exactly what they want.
And the form of the app,
how it's been designed,
perfectly matches
the functionality
that it offers to them.
And perhaps most importantly,
people will sense the care,
the attention to detail,
and the love that went
into making a truly great
and truly intuitive app.
Okay. So thank you.
I want to point out
really quickly if you want
to continue this conversation,
here's my Email address.
We also have a lot of really
great design resources
for you available on
developer.apple.com,
including links to the
Human Interface Guideline,
a bunch of videos.
We also have made the iOS Human
Interface Guidelines available
as an iBook, so you can
go out and get that.
And I also want to point
out that this is not the
last session about design.
We have three other really great
sessions for you this year.
I already talked to you about
the last one there on the list.
Go check it out.
If you do internet purchase,
we have a really good session
with tons of great,
wise advice--
content for you to follow,
and then this session
in the middle is awesome.
It's about prototyping,
and how we use it at Apple
to develop ideas, and really
refine them and figure
out what it is we want to do.
Thank you very much for your
time, and have a great evening.
[ Applause ]