>> Hello, everybody.
[ Applause ]
Thank you very much.
So my name is Kevin McLaughlin.
And I am here this afternoon
to tell you about HomeKit.
I know it has been a day
packed full of all kinds
of new information, but I hope
you are very excited to be here
as I am excited to
see everybody here.
So you've heard a little bit
about HomeKit already, I assume.
Let's talk about it just as
we're getting started here.
So HomeKit is a new feature
for iOS that is bringing,
as Craig said very well, some
rationality to home automation.
It provides a great opportunity
for us, you as developers and us
to work together to provide a
much more consistent experience
for our users as they start
to get into home automation.
And we want to bring this
to a much wider audience
than home automation has really
been accessible to in the past.
So let's get started.
So today I will tell you a
little bit about the features
of HomeKit, and we'll go
through the core concepts,
how to use the APIs,
how to get started,
and then a few advanced topics
that are either interesting
to me and hopefully to you, or
I know are interesting to you.
So let's get on with it.
So the first feature I want
to tell you about is something
that is really important
and is core
to delivering a consistency
that I talked about.
So we have a Common Database
that is stored in iOS,
and it contains all of
the home information,
all of the accessory information
that has been configured
and is available to
all of your apps.
Every time a user
uses one of your apps
to configure a new accessory,
to set up their home,
to set up some other operation,
those things are stored
through HomeKit,
through the framework,
in this Common Database.
And then when the user
uses another application
for some other purpose
and they see some
of their home information
in this other application,
they're going to see the same
information that they saw
or that they set up in
their other applications.
And this means to our users, to
your users, everything is going
to look a lot more
connected, and it's going
to make a lot more sense.
This is starting to provide
that consistent experience
that we want to deliver.
Now building on that, as
we mentioned yesterday,
we have a great interface
for users, which is Siri.
So users can use
Siri to interact
with their HomeKit accessories
in a very natural way
by just speaking
commands that make sense.
I'll talk a little bit about
how that's enabled as we go
through the presentation today.
Now in creating HomeKit, we
have put in a lot of effort
to define a common language
for us to use to talk
to accessories, but we can't
define every kind of accessory
that all of our clever accessory
manufacturers are going
to invent.
I've already heard about
dozens of interesting things
that are well beyond
what we're starting with.
So you can see here,
garage door, light bulb,
door lock-these are things
that are common accessories
that we have defined in
HomeKit, and I'll talk some more
about that as well, but
anything else is possible.
We don't want HomeKit to be
restricted and contained.
We want HomeKit to create
innovation and creativity.
And so anything that an
accessory manufacturer can
imagine and can create, they
can define and make available
through HomeKit to
your applications.
And all of that is exciting,
but you want to be able
to use these accessories.
And so HomeKit also
provides access
to your HomeKit accessories
when you are not at home.
This is enabled through
iOS device connectivity.
And there's no special
requirement for your application
or for the accessories
to take advantage
of this great feature
of HomeKit.
But with all of that
connectivity comes something
very important.
It's actually a pair of things
that are very closely coupled.
That's security and privacy.
We take security and
privacy very seriously.
And we have spent a lot of
time and effort, attention,
reviews after reviews,
making sure that we have
a great solution here.
So we have end-to-end encryption
between iOS devices
and accessories.
And this enables
us to have security
so that accessories
can't be misused.
It also enables us to ensure
user privacy is maintained.
We don't think that it's good
enough to be sort of private,
your data stored somewhere else.
We think it's important to
take privacy very seriously
and do the best that
is possible.
In keeping with this paradigm
of ensuring privacy and security
and making sure that our users
have really good, reliable,
understandable experiences
when they start using
your HomeKit applications,
HomeKit APIs can only be used
when your application
is in the foreground.
This ensures that users know
exactly what's going on.
There's nothing for them to
be afraid of when they take
that first step or second step
into using home automation.
OK. So that's enough about
the high-level stuff.
Let's get into some
of the details.
So, to get started with HomeKit,
your entry point is
the Home Manager.
The Home Manager provides your
pointers to the common database,
accessed through the homes.
The Home Manager allows your
application to manage the homes:
which one is primary, adding
or removing homes as necessary,
and will notify you of changes.
Now, for example, somebody
might have, for whatever reason,
multiple homes set up.
Those might change.
This is where you would
get notified about that.
So you can start
updating your application
to match what the
user knows they have.
So the Home Manager
is represented
by the HMHomeManager class.
You simply create an instance of
it, and then you set a delegate
to be your application.
To use the Home Manager,
the most important thing,
the first thing you
want to do is you want
to implement this
delegate callback
homeManagerDidUpdateHomes.
When you get this callback,
that means that the Home
Manager has finished loading
or preparing the home data.
And you can now save a
pointer to the array of homes.
And you can also save
what is currently set
as the primary home.
Now if there aren't any
homes, then you'll need
to create a home for the user.
So you add a home with name.
And that completes with
a completionHandler.
It would only fail likely if
the home had the same name
as another home because homes
need to be uniquely named.
So homes contain all
of the data for a home.
So you have your rooms, you have
your accessories, and so on.
It notifies you of
changes to that home.
And the names of homes
are recognized by Siri
so that users can refer to them
when they are giving commands.
On a home we have the name, we
have an array of all the rooms,
and an array of all
the accessories
that are in that home.
To fill out the concept or the
image or the map of a home,
whatever you want to call it,
you'll need to create rooms.
So on the home you can create
a room or add a room with name,
provide a name for
the room, and, again,
that would only fail
typically if there was a room
that already had the same name.
So, moving on to rooms.
Rooms contain accessories.
A room, again, will
notify you of changes.
And rooms must be uniquely
named within a home.
So a home creates
its own namespace.
Everything within a home
must have a unique name.
Names of rooms are
recognized by Siri.
So users can also
interact with them
to make some nice
natural interactions
with their accessories.
Rooms are represented
by the HMRoom class.
And they have an array
of the accessories
that are in that room.
Let's move on to accessories.
So an accessory corresponds
to a physical device.
Accessories are assigned to
a room, and that can change.
You can assign an accessory
to a different room.
Accessory objects allow you
to access the device state.
Can I talk to this accessory
right now, for example.
It will notify you of
changes to that accessory.
Again, they have to be
uniquely named within a home.
And names of accessories
also are recognized by Siri.
An accessory is the whole object
that the user is referring to.
And I'll talk about
how the details
of that accessory are exposed
and made available after this.
So an accessory has a pointer
back to the room that it's in,
and it has a pointer to
the array of services
that represent the
functionality of that accessory.
An important delegate
callback for you to implement
on accessory is the
DidUpdateReachability callback.
So an accessory at any point
in time may be reachable.
You may be able to
communicate with it
from your application,
or you may not.
It may be off.
You may be far away
from it, in a situation
where you don't have access.
In this case, this callback will
be given to your application
to let you know when that
reachability changes.
So you might start out with an
accessory that is not reachable,
and then if for some reason
it becomes reachable you'll be
notified, and then
you can update the UI
in your application to reflect
that so the user
knows what's going on.
So to describe a little bit
more about how accessories look,
let's talk about services.
So services represent
functionality of accessories.
They contain characteristics.
So you could describe a service
as a grouping of characteristics
where characteristics are
specific parameters you could
interact with, and I'll
talk about those next.
So, services are interesting
in that they may have a name.
And what that means is
there are some services
that really aren't
intended for the user
to directly interact with them.
They're sort of more
of an operational
type of functionality.
So here, for example,
we have a light bulb.
A service that has a light bulb
would typically have a name
because the user is
going to want to name it.
And if that light has
a name, I refer to it.
But a service to update firmware
on an accessory is something
that a user typically would
not need to name and refer
to in many different ways.
It's something that your
application would take care
of for them, present that
in a more user friendly way
than saying "Oh, here's your
firmware update service,
and here's the data
that goes into it."
So in your UI, generally
you will not expose
unnamed services.
So this is a way that some of
the messiness, if you will,
or the, you could look at it
in a different way and some
of the great functionality
of the protocol
and of HomeKit framework don't
need to be exposed to users
who just want to interact
with these accessories
that they've bought.
Names of services must
be unique within a home,
and they are recognized by Siri.
And importantly for services,
we not only recognize names
of services, but also we have
Apple-defined service types.
And Siri understands
those types,
which means that users can refer
to service types using
natural language, and synonyms
and other things like that,
that may not be exactly the
name provided to the service.
Services are represented
in HMService.
We have a name, an array
of characteristics,
the service type of the service,
and a pointer back
to the accessory.
The services are a
collection of characteristics.
A good example, just
as it shows here is,
for a light bulb service,
your main characteristic
is the power state
of that light bulb service,
and so the power state
is a characteristic
that you can directly
interact with.
Characteristics provide some
information, some metadata
about the characteristics.
So they are self-describing.
So you might get a range,
you might get units,
step values, and so on.
So you can display
appropriate controls to a user
when you get a characteristic.
You get the results
through a completion handler
because it may not be immediate.
And characteristics
are recognized
by Siri although they are
not named by the user.
So we've defined a number
of characteristic types,
and Siri can understand
what those mean,
so you just can interact
with those giving
commands through Siri.
The characteristics can
be of a few varieties.
With these main ones,
so some characteristics,
you only read the
values from them.
So you might say, "What is the
current temperature outside
or inside?"
You have a thermostat.
It tells you the
current temperature.
You don't need to write to
the current temperature.
You can't directly,
immediately change
that with a digital command,
but you read from it.
When you want to
change the temperature,
you need to tell your thermostat
that you have a new
target temperature.
So your target temperature is
something that you do write to,
and you may also read from
that because you might say,
"Why is it so hot in here?
What is the current target
temperature of this thermostat?"
So you read that, and then maybe
you write it and change it.
And there are some
few characteristics
that you only write to.
A write-only characteristic
is something,
think about it a little bit,
but where you tell the accessory
to do something, and
it's going to do it,
and it doesn't matter what it
may have to say back to you.
There's no feedback.
It just, the accessory does
it independently on its own.
So an example here,
and an important one,
is the identify characteristic,
which is a special
characteristic
that all accessories
must support,
and it provides an interface
where from your application,
you can let a user say, "Hey,
I'd like you to help me find
out which one of my
accessories this is."
So you send an identify
characteristic right
to that accessory.
And then it will do something
that identifies itself
to the user.
So a light bulb might flash.
A thermostat might blink an LED.
A garage door opener or
an IP camera might beep,
maybe also flash a light.
Whatever it is, this
is accessory specific.
And the purpose is to help the
user know which thing they are
about to interact with.
It's especially useful when
a user, for example, say,
connects several lights.
And they say, "OK.
Now I need to set up my lights.
Which one is this?"
All right.
They all have the same
default information.
I'm not going to go look
them up by serial number.
That's boring.
So just identify that for me.
And you send the identify
characteristic right
to that accessory, it
blinks, the user knows
which one it is,
they can proceed.
So characteristics are
an HMCharacteristic.
You can
readValueWithCompletionHandler
to get the value
of a characteristic
and also
writeValueWithCompletionHandler.
So now we've talked about
these objects, these things.
They correspond to physical
things in the real world.
We need to be able to find
and set up these accessories.
We do that with the
Accessory Browser.
So this tool lets you
and your application find
out if there are any new
accessories available
and then help a user
add those to a home.
So you create an instance
of the Accessory Browser,
set the delegate, and
then, when appropriate,
you start searching
for new accessories.
You'll find some.
You'll remove some.
I'll talk about that next.
And then later when you're done,
you stop searching
for new accessories.
So it's responsible for power
management, to stop searching
for new accessories when it's
no longer necessary to do that.
You've left the view.
You're leaving the application.
You've decided that enough
time has passed and so on.
So while you're searching
for new accessories,
you will get this callback
didFindNewAccessory.
And it will come with a pointer
to the accessory that was found.
And you can now, for
example, add this to a list
of accessories in the UI that
the user can select from for
which ones they want
to configure.
If, when you start searching
there are already some
accessories that have been
found, you can get the list
from the Accessory Browser
of the already found
new accessories.
And then you'll get this
callback every time a new one is
added to that list.
When you have found the new
accessories and the user would
like to set one of them
up, you need to add
that accessory to a home.
And it's important to note
that this method is on HMHome.
It's not on the Accessory
Browser.
So we add the accessory
to a home.
When the accessory is
successfully added to a home,
it's time to name the accessory
and assign it to a room.
Also while you're searching
for new accessories,
you will sometimes
get this callback.
Especially, you will
get this callback
when you add an accessory
to a home.
This is didRemoveNewAccessory.
This allows you in your UI when
you have a list of accessories
that you are showing to the user
which new accessories would you
like to configure, and they do
select one and they do add it
to a home, you'll
get this callback
to tell you it's removed from
the list of new accessories.
In this case, because
it was added to a home,
so you can update your UI to
take that one off the list.
So that's a quick
introduction to how
to get started, basic
functionality.
And maybe, like I
have been recently,
you'd like to get right
into it and write something.
And you wonder, how are
we going to do that?
We don't have any of these
HomeKit accessories yet.
So we thought about that.
We came up with something.
We have a great solution,
which is the HomeKit
Accessory Simulator.
And this is available for you
in Xcode at this location.
And it's a great
tool, and I'm going
to show you how that works.
Beautiful.
So here is our HomeKit
Accessory Simulator.
Now you can see that in this
case, there are a number
of accessories that have already
been created in the simulator,
but I'll walk you through it.
I'm just kind of making
sure it's big enough
for everybody to
see in the back.
Come forward if you
can't see it.
So here on the left we have
the list of accessories
that are created and
Bridges, which I'll talk
about briefly at the end.
Then on the right
there's information
about the accessories.
So what I'm going to
do is I am going to go
down to this Add Accessory
button here on the bottom left
and choose to Add
a New Accessory.
So I'm going to call this
Garage Door Demo 213.
I'm going to add this accessory.
So you'll see now that
I've added a new accessory
to the accessory simulator.
And let me show you what
that looks like in this very,
very simple sample
app that we wrote.
So this is just a tab view.
You can see there are new
accessories on one tab
and configured accessories
on the other.
These other accessories
are already configured.
We see here that we have the
Garage Door Demo accessory
that I've just created
has shown up here
on the New Accessories tab.
But it's not very
interesting yet.
It just has an accessory
information service.
This is created by default
because all accessories
must have an accessory
information service.
So I can go up here to
add another service.
So this is a garage door.
So let's add a garage
door opener service.
We can see that's added with
all of these characteristics.
And now since garage door
openers typically also have a
light, let's add a light.
Now you see we've created our
garage door opener accessory,
and it has the accessory
information service.
It has the garage door opener
service, which corresponds
to the motor that actually opens
and closes the garage door.
And we have a light
bulb service correspond
to the light that's
on that garage door.
So let's go ahead and
configure this accessory.
So when we go to add
an accessory to a home,
the user must enter
a setup code.
This comes from the accessory.
Maybe on the packaging or
on a label or on a screen
or LCD on the accessory.
In the simulator, it's
here right under the name.
I see Setup Code, which
looks like it's 9143.
So let me enter that.
I'll go ahead and set that up.
And you can see now that
disappears from the list
of new accessories because
it was successfully added
to the home.
Now if I jump over here to the
Configured Accessories tab,
I think I saw that I have a-I'm
revealing my practicing-but here
we have the garage door
accessory that I've just added.
And you can see that it has
two services and a Details tab.
The Details tab shows the
accessory information.
This is not something that
we need to interact with,
but it's there for reference.
We can also go in and see
all of the characteristics
for the garage door and all
of the characteristics
for the light.
And just to show that these are
connected, we can see if I click
on the power characteristic
of the light,
the power in the light bulb
service of the garage door goes
on and off along with that.
It's sort of in the
middle up there.
OK. So that shows
you the basic use
of the HomeKit Accessory
Simulator and also showing sort
of the Accessory Browser in
action and adding an accessory
and then showing the
services and characteristics.
But let's come back to
Bridges for a moment.
So Bridges are a
special type of accessory
where you have one accessory
that supports HomeKit Accessory
Protocol that connects with iOS.
And then you have some
other end-point accessories
that are connected to the Bridge
because they can't
communicate directly
with iOS for some reason.
So a typical example
may be a hub
that has some lights behind it
that are using some
other protocol.
So in this case the hub
is the first accessory
that HomeKit connects to.
So I can come down here,
and I can Add a New Bridge.
So let's call this
Demo Bridge 214.
So I've created a Bridge.
Now when a Bridge is created,
you'll see that it is actually
an accessory that's available.
So if I go over to New
Accessories, that has shown up.
I could connect to it right now,
but it's really very
uninteresting.
We need to add some
accessories behind this Bridge.
So I click on Add Accessories.
So let's add a light
behind the Bridge.
Now we see we've added a
light accessory connected
to this Bridge.
While we're here, let's go ahead
and add another light
behind that Bridge.
So now we have two lights.
And you'll see, on the right
we show the accessories
that are connected to
the Bridge on the left.
Below the Bridge we have the
actual light accessories listed
here that would show
the services of those.
Now here, these are created only
with accessory information
to start.
Let's go ahead and
add lights to them.
Now if I go back and
look at the Bridge,
you'll see that we have
a nice view to show you
of the accessories that are
connected behind the Bridge.
And of course we can pair
with the Bridge just the
same way we did before,
and set this up.
8107. So that appears over here.
We can go down to our
Connected Accessories.
And now you're going to
see something interesting.
The Demo Bridges there, and
we can click on that and see
that it just has details,
which show the accessory
information of the Bridge.
But the lights are also here.
So lights that are behind a
Bridge are presented to you
through HomeKit like
separate accessories.
And you can interact directly
with those lights even though
there's something in the middle
and there's always
protocol translation
and other things going on.
You don't have to
worry about that.
You get the accessory, which
is what the user really
cares about.
And so you can then interact
directly with these accessories.
They can be turned
on and off similarly.
OK. So that is the demo.
So let's get back to our slides.
Perfect. So the HomeKit
Accessory Simulator is available
in Xcode 6.
It acts just like
real accessories,
so when you develop your
application using the simulator,
using the HomeKit
Accessory Simulator,
you're doing the real thing.
When you eventually get real
accessories to connect to,
they're going to
work the same way.
They're going to be exposed
to you the same way
through HomeKit.
So this is a great way for you
to get started and a great way
for you to develop and test
your HomeKit applications.
So during this presentation
so far, we've talked
about all the steps at various
points along the way for how
to get the initial
setup of a home
and getting accessories added.
We've talked about this.
And I want to run through it
for you just as a summary.
So first we need
to create a home.
The user provides a
name for the home.
Then we need to add
rooms to the home.
The user provides
names for those rooms.
Again, all these names
will have to be unique.
And then we add accessories.
So we use the Accessory Browser.
We add the accessories
to the home.
The user provides a
name for the accessory.
The user chooses
which room to put
that accessory in for the home.
And after that then the
user can actually go
and continue using their
accessory and can interact
with it through your
applications,
through other applications,
through Siri.
So now let's move on to
some more advanced topics.
So I've talked a lot about
services and characteristics.
And I've talked about
something defined
by Apple and then custom ones.
So here on the left you can see
a list of services that are some
of the services we've defined.
And we can see these services
correspond to, kind of broadly,
accessory types or functional
groupings of characteristics.
Then you see on the
right a sampling of some
of the characteristics
that we've defined,
and there are many
more of these.
And then, as I said earlier, to
encourage innovation, invention,
creativity, we allow definition
of any custom service,
any custom characteristic an
accessory manufacturer wants
to use.
Those are all available
to you through HomeKit.
And all of these services and
characteristics that are defined
by Apple are recognized by
Siri and understood by Siri
so that users can interact
with them in very natural ways.
Turn something on.
Switch something on.
There's some other ways that
users, all of us I guess,
refer to things in our homes.
So groupings of rooms like
upstairs or downstairs
or maybe the bedrooms.
So rooms can be collected
into zones.
It's represented in HMZone
and is an arbitrary
grouping of rooms.
And this is just an association.
It's not an ownership
relationship.
So a room can be in
any number of zones.
Zones also are uniquely named,
and zones are recognized
by Siri.
We have another type of
grouping, which is to help group
and refer to functionality that
is provided by accessories.
We might want to do something
across multiple accessories
where you don't necessarily need
to control everything
on the accessory.
So these are called Service
Groups in HMServiceGroup.
So you can imagine you might
have nightlights in your home
where some of the nightlights
are their own accessory,
but some nightlights are-it's
a light on a coffee machine,
it's a light on a microwave,
it's a light on the
refrigerator.
It's a light on whatever it is.
And so you can grab all
of these light services
that are actually nightlights,
you can group them together
into a Service Group, and
you can easily display
that to the user.
You can easily perform
operations
on all of those nightlights.
Services can be in
any number of groups.
This is just an association.
Service Groups are
also named uniquely
of course within a home.
And names of Service Groups
are also recognized by Siri.
And now getting into
a couple more things
that are quite interesting.
So first are Action Sets.
So this is the HomeKit
implementation behind collecting
accessories into scenes.
So how this works is we take
a bunch of actions or actions
or something you're going
to do to an accessory.
And we group those
together into an Action Set.
So, for example, night.
So we might have a Night
Action Set or a night scene.
And so this Night Action Set
might turn off all your lights,
lock your door, close
your garage,
turn the thermostat down.
That could be grouped
together to be easily referred
to for the user and
easily execute all at once.
And when I say all at once,
I really mean all at once.
The order of execution
is undefined.
So you can't expect that
something is always going
to happen before something
else in an Action Set.
Everything will just be
done at the same time.
It's all going to get done,
best effort to do everything.
Action Sets, again, uniquely
named and recognized by Siri.
So what are these actions?
So actions are
HMCharacteristicWriteAction.
This is a very literal name
because what you're doing
in an action is you're
writing to a characteristic.
So, for example, you may have an
action that is Close the Garage.
It's a single write to a single
characteristic on the garage,
the garage door opener service.
And so that's a single action.
So you would create that action,
add it to the Action Set.
So Action Sets are interesting.
They're starting to allow you
to do something more complex.
We also have Triggers.
So Triggers are HMTimerTrigger.
So a Timer Trigger
is set up to fire
at a specific date and time.
They can repeat.
They are uniquely
named within a home,
but they are not interacted
with through spoken commands.
But they have something
very special about them,
which is they are
actually executed by iOS
in the background at the time
when that Trigger is supposed
to be executed, when it fires.
So a Trigger is set
to run an Action Set.
And that Action Set
can, the executing
of the Action Set can happen
even when no apps are running
or whatever because the
Trigger is managed by iOS.
So you can imagine that
even with just being able
to specify dates and times,
collections of actions
to happen, repeating
Triggers, you can start
to get some pretty
interesting functionality.
So I'd like to give
you a quick demo
of how Action Sets
and Triggers work.
So we have here our
HomeKit Accessory Simulator
still running.
And I have another very
simple sample app to show you.
Nice and large this time.
So here we have in this home
that's in the background,
we have some Action Sets and
some Triggers already defined.
So if we look at
these Action Sets,
we have the Night Action Set,
that example I gave earlier,
and we also have a Lights On
and Lights Off Action Set.
So if you look at
the Night Action Set,
what we've displayed here are
all of the characteristic rights
that are part of
this Action Set.
And if we go and look at,
for example, some things here
so the, thermostat's
target temperature,
let's say that was set at 70.
We can go here and unlock
the door, for example,
and then we can go here in this
Action Set, and you can see
that the door lock is going
to have the lock
characteristic set to Locked.
The thermostat is going to
have the target temperature set
to 68.
So I can execute this
Action Set, and we can see
that the lock has
indeed changed to Locked.
Thermostat target temperature
has changed back to 68.
And these lights are off.
So simple way, once it's all
set up, very simple way to go
and control many
accessories at the same time.
So now let's look
at these other two.
So Lights On.
It simply turns on
all the lights.
And Lights Off obviously, right,
it just turns off the lights.
So these two Action Sets
just give me the opportunity
to show you a very simple
demo of how Triggers work.
So we have here two
Triggers that are created.
One runs the Action
Set Lights On,
and one runs the
Action Set Lights Off.
And we can see that when I've
turned these Triggers on,
I've enabled them, that these
lights just start blinking.
Probably not a commonly used
use case in the real world,
but a great example for a demo.
So let's stop that.
That's Triggers and Action Sets.
Let's go back to the slides.
So using Action Sets
and Triggers together,
you'll be able to
script or allow the user
to script some fairly complex
and interesting interactions
and enable you and your users
to control many accessories
very easily and very quickly.
So one more thing I want
to tell you about HomeKit,
as you're looking through our
documentation, you're going
to see there are a lot
of delegate methods.
And you might ask, "Do I need
all of these delegate methods?
Do I have to implement
every single one?"
And well, yes.
They're there for a reason.
They're there because, if you
remember back at the beginning
of the presentation, we talked
about the shared database.
And because of the
shared database,
we get this great consistency
across the user experience,
different applications that have
different specialized purposes.
The user is going to see
that all these apps are
aware of their home.
They have their home set up.
They have their living room.
They have their kitchen.
They have their ceiling lights.
They're going to see
that in every app.
All right.
It's going to feel great to
a user who is using this.
But you don't want your
app to get out of sync
with what the user knows they
have set up for their home.
And because of this shared
database, it can be updated
in many different ways.
Many of those ways are
not through your app.
Through some other app.
Through some other event.
Accessories are changing.
And so all of these delegate
methods are how we tell you
what's changing.
Someone changed the
name of that room.
That accessory state
has changed.
Someone has added a-I should
be so lucky-added a lake house
to their collection of homes.
And so when these things
happen, you want to be able
to update your app
so that the user sees
that your app is connected,
your app knows what's going on.
Everything is being
communicated.
So these delegate methods
are how you do that.
So that brings us just about
to the end of my presentation.
And if this timer is right,
I've gone quite a bit
faster than I expected.
But that's okay, right?
It's at the end of the day.
I want you to remember this.
So HomeKit is providing
you the opportunity
to deliver a much more
consistent experience
for home automation
through your applications.
The framework has been
designed to be easy to use.
It's simple to create a home.
It's simple to add an accessory.
It's simple to interact with it.
You can easily get the lists of
accessories that are available
and display them to users.
We've also enabled you to get an
early start and also to be able
to very effectively
and easily debug
and test your applications using
the HomeKit Accessory Simulator.
And there's information
available for you
if you're curious about how to
get started, either with HomeKit
or with making a
HomeKit accessory
at developer.apple.com/homekit.
For more information, we have
our great Evangelism Team
who is there for
you to reach out to.
And we have documentation
available
at all the regular places,
including the MFi Program
for accessory manufacturers.
So that finishes for me today.
I want to say thank
you very much.
[ Applause ]
I definitely appreciate the
opportunity to talk to you.
Enjoy the rest of the show.