[ Silence ]
>> Good morning.
[ Applause ]
All right.
You're happy to see me.
That's good.
My name's Will Turner and with
my colleague, Brooke Callahan,
we'll be talking to you
about testing in Xcode 6.
And let's get started.
So we're going to cover
several topics today.
To start off, to just
kind of motivate this.
Think about the benefits
of testing.
Why should we bother
in the first place?
Then we'll get into what it
takes to add test to a project.
Maybe you have old projects
that don't have tests.
And then we'll talk about
some new features in Xcode 6
which allow you to test
asynchronous systems
and then also testing
features that allow you
to catch performance
regressions.
So why should we test?
Obviously, every moment we spend
developing is an investment
of a resource.
Our resource is time
and our colleagues
for maintaining the code
base that we create.
So the obvious thing
about testing is it
helps you find bugs
and there's many classes of
bugs that you find with testing.
They are regressions so cases
where you've shipped your
product, you make a code change,
add a feature and in the
process something breaks
and now your 1.1
or 1.2 has a bug
and your customers are unhappy.
We hate regressions.
Tests are a fantastic way
to ensure your code ships
without regressions.
There's also bugs where
performance changes.
You make a change in your code
and now suddenly something
is taking a lot more time
to execute and maybe that's only
on some devices and not others.
So tests again can
be a great way
to catch performance
regressions.
The other sort of less talked
about and less obvious benefit
of testing is that it
codifies the requirements
of your project.
So especially if you're
sharing code with engineers,
you create classes as classes
have APIs and a lot of times
because Objective-C and
Swift are great languages
for expressing the API,
semantics of the API,
they're self-documenting.
We think, okay, our job is done.
But in truth, they
don't really account
for all the possible
permutations
of inputs to those functions.
So if you write tests,
those tests help codify the
requirements of those APIs.
So another engineer
can come along.
They can make code
changes in that area
and the tests helps them
understand what the expected
behavior is.
So to get started with
tests, you may have a project
that doesn't have test already.
So you want to add
test to that project
and then the obvious
thing to do is make sure
that those tests pass.
Alternatively, you may
start with a new project.
And in that case, you have the
option of a different workflow
where you create tests first.
And then you write code
that passes those tests
and that's sometimes referred
to as test-driven development.
So now you're set up.
You've got your test.
They're passing.
You can go into a workflow
that we talked about.
We consider continuous
integration workflow.
And you start off
in a green state
where everything is working
and you're making code changes.
You're adding features,
fixing bugs.
And at some point, one of these
code changes introduces a bug.
And so now, your
continuous integration
because you've written
tests identifies that bug
and you know right away, right
after that first code change,
you know that the bug
has been introduced.
So then you can take the
necessary steps to fix the bug
and return to a green state.
And what you really
want to think,
s a green state represents
known quality.
And having tests and having
continuous integration ensures
that your projects
remain in a known state
of quality all the time.
So to get started, let's talk
about how testing
works in Xcode.
Xcode ships with a
framework called XCTest
and this is framework
for testing.
It provides a set of APIs
that lets you create tests,
run the tests, express
expectations,
passes and failures.
It all starts with the
base class XCTestCase.
And to create test,
you subclass XCTestCase
and then you add test methods.
And these test methods
follow a naming convention.
They return void.
They're prefixed with the
word, "test" in lowercase
and they take no parameters.
The remainder of the method
name is at your discretion.
It should be sort of a name that
conveys the purpose of the test.
Inside these test methods,
you can use assertion APIs we
provide to report failures.
For example, XCTAssertEqual
compares two scalar values
and if they don't match,
it outputs a string
and reports a failure
to the test harness.
So in Xcode, we manage
a lot of different parts
of our projects through targets.
And we have test targets
for managing tests.
Test targets build bundles
and these bundles contain
the compiled test code
and also resources that you
would want to use in the test.
Maybe you have data files
that drive your tests.
These go in your test bundle
but you don't really want
to ship those with
your application.
You go and ship them with --
though you don't want
to ship them at all.
You want them to be
with your test bundle.
So these are -- test targets
are automatically included
in new projects.
If I go today and I
create a new application,
you'll see there's a test target
and a test class already there
to start me off, get me right
in test from the beginning.
You can also add test
targets to existing projects.
And this may be something
you want to do to a project
that has no test or it
also be a step you take
to help organize your
tests because you can have
as many test targets as you
want and it's useful sometimes
that you will run just this
test target or that test target
or you can run them
all together.
So let's think about a
moment about how tests run.
Because they are bundles,
these are not executables
that can be launched themselves.
So instead, we need to host
them in an executable process.
Generally, we inject
these into your apps.
So your test can be written
against your application
and it can access all the
code in your application,
which means when
we run the test,
we run it in the context
of your application.
Alternatively, you can run them
in a hosting process
that's provided by Xcode.
Resources for tests,
as I mentioned before,
are not in the main bundle.
They're in your test bundle.
So when you go to load them,
don't use NSBundle mainBundle.
This is something
that trips people up.
I think a lot of us just kind
of have NSBundle mainBundle
on autocomplete in our heads.
But instead, we want to
use NSBundle bundleForClass
and pass your test class.
That ensures that you're
going into the test bundle
to locate that resource.
So running tests, Xcode lets you
run tests in a number of ways.
The simplest way is Command-U
and this takes your active
scheme and runs the tests
that are associated
with that scheme.
You also have buttons and the
Source Editor's [Inaudible] next
to the test method that lets you
run just that test or the class
and all of the tests
in that class.
So you have a similar set of
buttons in the Test Navigator.
And you can also run tests using
xcodebuild so if you have a set
of scripts that you've used
to create your own kind
of automation setup,
you can use xcodebuild.
And you pass at the test action
and you pass your project.
Tell it which scheme
-- this is essential
because your project
may have many schemes --
and the destination.
And you can have multiple
destinations so if you want
to run on multiple devices,
you can pass these all
with distinct destination flags
and xcodebuild will run them.
When your tests are done,
where do you see the results?
Again, there's a
number of places
where we display the
results of the tests.
The first is at Test Navigator.
We will see a green checkmark
or red icon indicating failure.
Also in the Issue Navigator.
If you hit a test failure,
you'll see not only the failure
but the reason it failed and so
if you've used our insertion
macros, this is where you'll see
that error string that says, you
know, 50 was not equal to zero
or whatever the assertion
you were testing.
They also show in the
Source Editor's gutter
and then finally, most
useful is the Test Reports
where we show all the tests that
have run and the logs associated
with them and some
additional data that we'll get
to later in the presentation.
So let's get started.
See what it looks like to add
tests to an existing project.
Let's take a look at how
this is put together.
To simplify this for the demo,
I've tweaked it a little bit
from the sample code
that's online.
But basically the guts of this
app is this NSOperation subclass
that parses the XML data.
And NSOperation, as you know, is
designed to provide concurrency
and be run in the background.
This class has a Delegate
that it calls back
with certain events
when parsing is done,
when it's parsed a
certain number of objects
or if it encounters
any kind of error.
So we have this property
here, parsedEarthquakes,
and that's something you can
access safely at any time
to see the array of
parsedEarthquake objects.
So I'd like to write
a test that validates
that this parsed
operation behaves correctly.
So let's start clean.
We have -- not a
clean slate here.
We're going to reset
this a little bit
so you can see what it
looks like to add test
to an existing project.
So we have our project
and at this point,
there's no test target.
So to add a test, I'm going
to go to the file menu
and will select a new target.
I'm going to select under
other CoCotest testing.
And I'm going to
name this target.
I'm going to call it
two just to be safe.
And now we've noticed
a few things.
We see a new group here.
Inside of that, we see
a template test file
and if we look at the
scheme, we'll also notice
that under the test action, we
have this one that I removed
but more importantly,
we have this new one
that just got added.
So there's a few
template methods in here.
I'm just going to remove
these so we can start clean
and build our test out.
So the first thing, to recap,
what I want to do
is write a test
for this operation subclass.
So I'm going to import
the header
so that I can access the APIs.
The next thing to do is I'm
going to add a test method.
And just to reiterate
from earlier,
this method returns void.
It is prefixed with test and
there are no other parameters.
The rest of the name is just
a name that I've come up with
that to me represents
what this test is for.
Now, I like to sometimes
go through
and outline the steps
I'm going to take
as comments before
I write the code.
It helps me organize
my thoughts.
So just hear the summary of
what the test is going to do.
We're going to get a URL to
a resource and that's going
to be a resource of XML
data that's in the bundle.
We're going to load
that into memory.
We're going to create the parse
operation then we'll run the
operation directly.
And finally, we'll check
the number of earthquakes
and see if it's correct.
So if I'm going to get a
resource to the bundle,
I need to add the file.
Well, I've had this file
here that is, let's see,
I'm going to copy this file
into my project as a resource.
I'll copy it in.
And this is just some data
that I downloaded in advance
because I want to take the
network out of the equation
when I write my tests.
There's nothing wrong
with testing the network,
but in general if you keep your
tests simpler, when they fail,
it'll be easier to figure
out why they failed.
So in this test,
I'm not interested
in validating if
the network works.
I'm validating the
parsing works.
So by having this in my bundle,
I eliminate that as a concern.
So to get the URL, I'm
going to go into the bundle
and get a resource URL,
and then the next thing
that I do is just load
that as an NSData.
The next step is to
create the parse operation.
So that is the class that
we are trying to test here.
I'm going to create it with
this data and I'm not going
to set a Delegate because in
this test, I don't need to.
The next thing is to run
the operation directly.
Now, we know that
NSOperation is designed
to be run in the background.
But operations allow you
to invoke them directly
and synchronously by
just calling start.
That means when we call
start, it's going to run
and when we return,
it's finished running.
So at that point, I can
check the results and see
if they are what I expected.
Now, I have zero here.
I actually know that there
is more than zero but I'd
like to run this and let
you see what a failure looks
like before we go any further.
So I'm hitting Command-U
to run the test.
It ran quickly and you can
see here's this message,
parse operation zero failed,
55 is not equal to zero.
Okay, so there are 55
earthquakes in there.
So let's run this again.
And now we've passed our test.
And again you see that
same pass indicator there
in the Test Navigator and we
see it here in the Test Log
that we parsed and succeeded.
So that's what it takes
to add test to a project.
We created a new test
target and then we go in
and we added the test code.
We create test methods
and we used the assertions
to validate the state
that we expect.
So I'm going to switch
back to slides now.
Okay, so let's get on to
what's new in Xcode 6.
We have new APIs and
improvements to our tools.
So the first thing I want
to mention is we've added
some improvements that help
with the compatibility story.
And I'll get into more detail
but this basically means
which versions of our OS
you can target using XCTest.
We've also added instruments
integration for tests
and Brooke will talk to you
more about that later on.
Finally, we've got new APIs
and as I mentioned earlier,
these are both for
asynchronous testing
and for performance testing.
So first, XCTest on
older iOS versions.
Originally XCTest
shipped and it was part
of the iOS release itself.
So it meant when we shipped
it, you could only run it
on versions of iOS that had it.
We've changed now.
Now we're shipping
XCTest with Xcode itself.
So this means that as we
add new features to XCTest,
you don't have to worry about
whether or not they're going
to be available where
you're running your tests
because you're always
going to be testing
with the current version
that's in the Xcode.
And this also means that we can
target older versions of iOS.
So anywhere that Xcode supports,
XCTest will also support.
And this means iOS 6 and later.
[ Applause ]
So that's probably a good
time to just mention OCUnit
which is the legacy technology
that XCTest was derived from.
In Xcode 5.1, we
deprecated OCUnit.
We're not adding
new features to it
and we really think the time
is now to move to XCTest
because we've added new features
to it, integration is better
and OCUnit is no longer where
we're focusing our energies.
If you have existing targets
that you want to switch
from XCTest, we recommend
you use a migrator
in Xcode to do so.
The reason for this
and also to do this,
you just go to the Edit menu
and select Refactor,
Convert to XCTest.
And it will update the
project settings and also all
of your test classes
will get updated.
The reason for this is
some of the build settings
that are associated with
this are not accessible
in the Xcode UI.
So some people in
the past have tried
to do the migration manually
and you know, you end up --
you're not able to
do it 100% by hand.
If you are, if you really
do want to do it yourself,
there's a different way which is
just to create a new test target
which is guaranteed to have
exactly the right settings
and just move your existing
tests into it manually.
So now, let's talk about
Asynchronous Testing,
one of our new APIs in Xcode 6.
So more and more APIs
on our platform themselves
are asynchronous.
They have block invocations
when they're done
that may get run in
different queues.
They have Delegate callbacks
that may be deferred
by the run loop.
They may make network requests,
which we absolutely know should
be handled asynchronously.
Or they're doing
background processing
like our NSOperation here.
So this creates a challenge
because tests themselves
run synchronously.
And so, to help you with
that, we've added APIs
that will allow you to create
asynchronous control flow
that manages asynchronous
activities.
And we do this through what
we call expectation objects,
and these describe events
in your test that you expect
to happen at some
point in the future,
hopefully not too distant.
With these objects, XCTest
has an API that would wait
for them to be fulfilled.
And that takes a timeout
and a completion handler
that's called either
when the timeout hits or when
all the events are fulfilled.
And you can be waiting
on multiple asynchronous
events at the same time.
So let's look at a code example.
UIDocument, as you may know, has
an open with completion handler
that is an asynchronous
opening and that's great
because if a large document
might take a little bit of time
to open and you don't want
to stall the user's interactive
experience while you're waiting
for that.
So let's write a test for that.
The first thing I do is
I create an expectation.
And these expectation
creation methods take a string
which is simply a
description for your benefit.
It tells you if we
had a timeout,
it tells you what
we were waiting for.
And so the more descriptive
you make that,
the easier your life will be.
Then we create a document
which I'm not showing here.
And we call the
openwithCompletionHandler.
And you notice I haven't filled
out the CompletionHandler.
It's just an empty
block at this point.
We'll get back to
it in a moment.
And then finally, I
call waitForExpectations
with a 5-second timeout.
Probably a little on the long
side but just to be safe here.
So what we have now
is a synchronous flow.
We have create expectation,
set up the document,
open it and then wait.
And this is asynchronous
flow within the test.
Asynchronously later, that
block will be called back.
Inside the handler, I'm
going to do two things.
I'm going to use
one of our asserts
to validate this
opening was successful.
On top of that, I'm going
to call expectation fulfill
which will cause the
waitForExpectations to return
because now all
of the expectations I have
created have been fulfilled.
So let's see what that
looks like if we add
that to our seismic XML tests.
Okay, so we go back to our test.
It's right here.
And the first thing we do is I'm
going to just rename this to,
let's say,
ParsingInTheBackground
because that's closer to our
actual real-world usage anyway.
So the first part of
the test stays the same.
We're still going to use
that same resource file,
load it into memory.
Now before we create our parse
operation, we'll need to --
this is where things are
going to change a little bit.
So if you think about
it, we have here,
we're running the parse
operation directly.
Instead of that, let's run
it in an OperationQueue.
So that looks like
create an OperationQueue
and add the operation to it.
And that means the
operation is going
to start running
immediately but it's going
to do so in the background.
Now if I leave the test as is,
because that running is
happening in the background
and our test is just
continuing on,
it's not stopping or waiting.
It's just ready to go.
If we run this test now,
what we're going to see is
that we failed because
at the point
where we're evaluating
this, parsing isn't done.
It's off in the background
somewhere
and we don't know
whether it's finished yet.
So what we want to
do is wait for it
to be finished before we check.
And I'm just using a
2-second timeout here.
These timeouts are
largely at your discretion.
If you make them really, really
small then you may have cases
where something takes
a little longer to run
and you get a failure
that's not really a failure.
So those are just kind
of at your discretion.
So now, we can wait
but before we wait,
we also need an expectation
that describes what
we're waiting for.
So think about the operation.
How do we know it's done?
Well, it has this Delegate
API with callbacks.
So let's look at what
those were like again.
So ParseOperation, the Delegate
callbacks, we have DidParse,
DidFinish, DidFailWithError.
Well, DidFinish looks
like exactly what I want.
So going back into my test, if
I'm going to be the Delegate,
I need my test itself to conform
to the Delegate Protocol.
And then I need to implement
the DidFinish method.
Now inside that, I'm going
to operate on some kind
of expectation and report
that it's fulfilled.
But since we're here and we're
not in the same context here,
we'll need to track that
operation as a property.
So we'll just add an expectation
property to our test.
We'll set it up before we
create the ParseOperation.
So we've created
our expectation.
"Parsing finished" is what
we're calling it here.
And then inside our
operation, we will fulfill it.
So let's just run this.
Now, secret.
This is actually going to fail
because I've left something
out intentionally but I want
you to see what failure looks
like when we hit a timeout.
And asynchronous wait failed.
Exceeded timeout of 2 seconds
with unfulfilled
expectations "parsing finished".
So we never fulfilled
our expectation.
Well, the reason
is pretty simple.
I forgot actually to say that
this object is the delegate.
So once we hook that
up, we run again.
This time, everything passes
because we get the callback,
we fulfill the expectation, we
unwind from the wait and then
when we evaluate the number of
parsed earthquakes, it's 55.
So just walking through this
again, we used an expectation
to describe a future event.
We wait for the expectation
here.
And then when that event
occurs, which in this case is
in a delegate callback that
could be inside a block handler
or some other context,
we fulfill it.
That causes wait to return.
So this allows us to handle
an asynchronous activity
in a synchronous fashion.
It's fine for testing.
I wouldn't recommend you
do this on the main thread
of your application
code [laughter].
Okay, so let's switch back.
So that's what it looks like
to write an asynchronous test
with the new APIs in Xcode 6.
Now, Brooke's going to talk to
you about performance testing.
[ Applause ]
>> Thanks, Will.
So it can be easy to introduce
performance regressions
in your code.
And historically, finding these
issues can be time consuming
and expensive because you need
to manually use your
application to find them.
Now Apple has some great tools
for investigating
performance issues.
And performance testing
is just a way to tell you
when to do that investigation.
So we'll look at some
new APIs that we've added
to help you measure performance
and detect regressions.
We'll also see how
the measurements
that these APIs make are surface
and Xcode's UI including
those test failures due
to regressions.
And now that Xcode is going to
be reporting performance issues
as failures, it ought to
give you an easy way to do
that investigation so you
can now profile your test
with Instruments.
The easiest way to do this is
to use the new measureBlock API.
This takes a block of code
and runs it 10 times measuring
the duration each time
and showing the results
in Xcode.
So for example, I've got a
test here that I'm writing
that I want to measure
the performance
of using a fileHandle.
So I'll call self measureBlock
and then the code
I want to measure.
It's creating a fileHandle,
using it
and then closing the fileHandle.
Now that I've got this test,
I'm going to want to profile it
in the case that Xcode tells
me something went wrong.
And you can do this from Xcode
Source Editor or Test Navigator
from their context menus.
And there's also a Command for
this under the Product menu.
It's important to keep in mind
that when you profile your test,
this uses settings from
the Scheme Profile Action.
The most obvious
difference here is
that when you're just
running your test
that it uses a Debug
configuration by default.
But Profiling will use
a Release configuration
and there may be some
difference in behavior there.
Let's take a look at the demo.
So here, I have a Mac
version of the project
that Will showed you earlier.
And I've already got
a couple of tests
that used the measureBlock API.
I'm just going to
run my test now.
So I don't know if you can see
this, but Xcode is telling me
that this test is doing 4000%
worse than it did before.
So that's not so great.
So how am I going to figure
out what's gone wrong here?
I could look at the test
itself to see, you know,
is there anything obvious
that the test is doing wrong?
Well, it appears to be loading
its file from the test bundle.
Parsing it and then validating
that the earthquakes are right.
I could look and see if
there are any local changes
in my project?
No, there aren't.
I could look and see
how this test compares
to all the other
tests in my project.
And actually, this one's
doing a little bit --
this one's doing bad but
the other one's doing a
little better.
So it looks like I'm just
going to have to profile it.
And I can do that by
right-clicking on this button
in the Source Editor
and selecting Profile,
or I can also do that from the
Test Navigator by right-clicking
on my test and selecting
Profile.
I'll select Time
Profile from Instruments
and I'll click Record.
Now, Instruments has
launched my application
and it's run my tests
and it's done.
So I'll zoom in a bit
so you can see this.
I'm just going to invert the
call tree and expand this.
And from here, I can see
my test is being called.
XCTest is eventually calling
the block that I've given it
and it's calling this
validateProperties
which is calling some
really expensive function.
Well, that's probably
not what I want.
So let's look into that.
I'm going to right-click
on validateProperties
and use Reveal on
Xcode and zoom out.
Yeah, yeah.
It is expensive.
Okay, so let's just
get rid of this.
I'm just going to delete
that and run my test again.
And it passed, great.
So what you've just seen is you
can use a new measureBlock API
to measure performance
and detect regressions.
You can view these results
in the Source Editor
and the Test Report and you
can also Profile your test
with Instruments.
So you've just gotten a taste
of how Performance
Testing works with Xcode.
Now let's go into details.
First of all, setting Baselines.
For XCTest to report a test as
failing due to a regression,
it needs a fixed point
to compare against.
And the Baselines
let us do that.
And the Standard Deviation,
XCTest should only report
a performance regression
when something's
actually gotten worse.
XCTest uses Standard Deviation
to determine the spread
of the measurements, to tell
us how reliable they are.
And finally, measuring
precisely.
We have some additional APIs
that let you be even
more precise
about what you want to measure.
So let's look at the Baselines.
The Baseline is the
Average from a previous run
that you've specifically
selected for comparison.
Once you've set a Baseline,
XCTest will use this
to detect regressions.
It will fail a test if the
new Average has increased
from the Baseline
Average by 10% or more
and it will ignore
regressions of less
than a tenth of a second.
This is to eliminate a
source of false positives.
The Baselines are stored in
source where you commit them
to your repository and show
them on routine numbers.
And they're stored per
device configuration.
So when I run tests on my
iPhone 5S, they're going
to be using the same Baselines
that when Will runs the same
test on his iPhone 5S are used.
But at the same time, if
I were to run these tests
in a simulated iPhone 5S, it
would not use those Baselines
because that would be a
different device configuration.
So let's talk about how you
set the Baselines with Xcode.
The first time I run a test,
I'm going to see an annotation
like this with this gray
diamond with a white dot
on it telling me there's
no Baseline for the test.
And that lets me know that it
didn't do any comparison at all
and it's just showing
me the average
that the time that
the test took.
If I click on that annotation,
I'll get the performance
result to pop over.
And I can get this
from the Source Editor
or from the new Test Report.
From here I can see the
current average from the test,
and I can also see how the
individual measurements
that were taken differ
from that average.
So here I can see
that measurement number
8 was the longest one.
Now when I'm running too,
I can click Set Baseline
and Xcode will use, will
copy the current average
to the Baseline.
And if I need to set this
again, I can click Edit
and either accept the new
current average or type
in whatever I want
as the Baseline
and I can also edit the maximum
Standard Deviation from here.
In order to set the Baseline,
the next time I run my test,
I'll see a different annotation
with this gray diamond
with the checkmark in it.
And it's telling me that
this test is doing 4% worse
than the Baseline that
it's compared against.
If the test were to do a lot
worse, the test would fail
and I'd get an annotation like
this telling me that, you know,
it's 68% worse in this case.
And I can also see these results
from that new Test Report.
Also from the Test Report, I can
get the performance result pop
over by clicking under the time
call on those measurements.
If you want to get at the
raw values that Xcode gets
from XCTest, those are available
on the logs tab of
the Test Report.
So let's talk about how XCTest
uses the Baseline Average.
Here I have a dataset
from one run of a test.
There are 10 measurements for
the 10 indications of the block.
And they're all -- it comes
around that 1-second mark
with a 1-second average.
I'll set the Baseline for my
test, which fixes that in place.
Now the next time I run my
test, if I were to get a dataset
like this, the average would
be 1 second at 1.5 seconds
and the test would fail because
that 1.5 seconds is well outside
the bounds of the
allowed 10% regression.
So XCTest is going
to fail the test
if the new average has increased
from the Baseline by more
than 10% but it's going
to ignore regressions less
than a tenth of a second.
But is the average enough?
Let's look at that
same dataset again.
All the values come through on 1
second with a 1-second average.
If I were to run this test again
and get a dataset like this,
it hasn't really regressed.
The average is still 1 second
but there's some values
over 1.5 seconds and
some under 0.5 second.
So it isn't a true regression
in terms of the average
but something's gotten worse.
There is something that if I
were to get a dataset like this,
I would want to investigate it.
So the average just doesn't
tell the whole story.
And XCTest is going to
use the Standard Deviation
to indicate the spread
of the measurements.
If we look at that first
dataset one more time,
we see that the Standard
Deviation is set
for these numbers tightly
[inaudible] around 1 second
at 6% while the Standard
Deviation
for the much more
spread-out dataset is 40%.
And the way XCTest is
going to use this is
if the Standard Deviation for
the new dataset is more than 10%
of the current average,
which you can adjust
from that popover, it will fail.
But again, just like
the average,
it will ignore Standard
Deviation of less than a tenth
of a second, again, to
avoid false positives.
So what causes excessive
Standard Deviation?
Well, one thing is if the block
that you're measuring is
doing network I/O or file I/O,
that tends to vary
pretty wildly.
Another thing that can cause
high Standard Deviation is
if the block just isn't trying
to do the same work each time.
So for example, if the block
that's being measured does some
-- sets up some expensive global
state the first time through
and then never again or the
block might just be affected
by an uninitialized variables.
And lastly, another thing
that can cause high
Standard Deviation is
if the system is just
busy with other processes
and short-running tests are
especially sensitive to this.
So how does XCTest
detect issues?
First of all, if there's no
Baseline Average, it's done.
It's not going to try and do any
analysis of the measurements.
If there is a Baseline Average,
first it will check to see
if that Standard Deviation is
more than a tenth of a second
and more than 10% of
the current average.
If it is, it'll fail for that.
Otherwise, it'll check to see if
the average is increased by more
than a tenth of a second and
more than 10% of the Baseline.
And if it is, it'll
fail for that.
And otherwise, it'll pass.
So how can we minimize
Standard Deviation?
Well, one way is to only measure
the code that's important
to you.
So let's look at how we can do
that with that previous example.
Here, this test is doing
the work of setting
up a FileHandle using it
and then closing the FileHandle
each time we run the block.
But if I only want
to measure the time
of using the FileHandle, what I
might do is just move the set up
and tear down work
outside of the block.
But what if I can't do that?
Sometimes, the work
that you want
to measure requires some
set of work that needs
to be done each time
before the measurement.
And for that, we have
some additional APIs;
measureMetrics automatically
start measuring with a block.
You can use this to
measure just part
of the block that's
being called.
This API expects an array
of metrics to measure
and currently only
time is supported.
We'll also need two more APIs,
startMeasuring and
stopMeasuring.
You can use these
to isolate what part
of the block you
want to measure.
You can call these once
per block invocation.
And if you're going to
call startMeasuring,
you need to pass NO for
automatically startMeasuring.
So let's see how that would
work with our previous example.
First, we'd change the method
to call it measureMetrics
passing time as the metric
and NO for automatically
startMeasuring.
It calls startMeasuring right
before you use FileHandle
and stopMeasuring
immediately afterwards.
So now this block is
doing the work of setting
up the FileHandle and
turning it down each time
but it's only actually
measuring the duration spent
in UseFileHandle.
So let's look at
this in practice.
So despite the name of this
project, I'm actually thinking
about adding a JSON parser
to it and I've got a test
that I'm running here that's
loading this file from the web
and parsing it with
NSJSONSerialization.
I think I'd actually
like to turn this
into a performance test
just for my own sake.
And I'll do that now
by calling measureBlock
and then pasting in the code.
And I'll click to run my test.
So here we can see that it took,
it says on average 1.91 seconds
with 114% Standard Deviation
and it's telling me there's no
Baseline Average for this test.
Well, that's not bad but I know
that since it's doing
this expensive work
of loading this file
from the web each time,
I actually don't
want to measure that.
I just want to measure the time
spent in NSJSONSerialization.
So what I'll do is
I'll delete this
and call measure
time measureMetrics
which is passing time
as my metric and NO
for automaticallyStartMeasuring.
Then all I need to do is call
startMeasuring right before
NSJSONSerialization
and I can run my test.
Great! So previously, it
was taking 1.91 seconds
and now it appears to be
taking no time at all.
So that's pretty
good [laughter].
I wish all my APIs
were that quick.
But I actually want this to
measure something, you know,
something that Xcode will
report, something significant
so what I'm going
to do is I'm going
to change this to
use a larger file.
So we actually get
some values here.
And this is going to
take a little bit longer
because what it's actually
doing is it's going
to be calling this block
10 times, loading the file
from the web each time
and then parsing it.
So now the test is taking,
it looks like 1.21 seconds
and it's got a very low Standard
Deviation, which is pretty good.
So I'm going to click to
set this as my new Baseline
and since that seemed to take
a little while, I'm just going
to move this out of the block.
Since the data that it's
loading is actually immutable,
I don't need to do
this every time.
So I'm just going
to do that once
when the test initially starts.
I'll click through
on my test again.
And it still got a result
around the same ballpark
and still got a pretty
reasonable Standard Deviation.
Well, now that I'm not
actually doing any work before
startMeasuring, I
don't need all this.
So I'm just going to delete that
and change this back
to call measureBlock.
I'll run it again.
And I should get similar results
and yeah, it looks like I do.
So the last thing I'd
like to do with this is
like Will showed us earlier.
We kind of want our test
to be self-contained.
We don't want it to be
loading files from the network.
So I'm just going to change this
since I've actually
already got a copy
of this file in my project.
I'm going to use
NSBundle bundleForClass
to load this all-month
file from my test project.
I'll run it again.
And here we go.
So now I've got a new
performance test that's
measuring the time that
it takes to run this
and if something were
to change, I'd find out.
The last thing I want to do is
I want to commit my changes.
So here we can see the
changes that I've made so far.
I got rid of that really
expensive function.
I changed my test to
be a performance test
and we can also see the
Baseline that I've added here.
So I don't think you
can tell from this,
but this is actually a file
that's stored inside the project
bundle itself.
So I'll commit that.
And now it's saved there
for the next time I need it,
the next time I need it, okay.
[ Applause ]
So what you've just seen is
that you can use the
new measureBlock APIs
to measure performance
and to detect regressions.
You can tell Xcode
what the Baseline is
to specify what constitutes
a regression for your test.
And it will -- XCTest will use a
Standard Deviation to inform you
of the spread of
the measurements.
And finally, when
something does go wrong,
you can always use Instruments
to profile your test.
Now I'd like to invite
Will back up.
[ Applause ]
>> Okay great.
So just to kind of go back
through everything we've talked
about today, we started off
with thinking about, you know,
why should we test
in the first place?
What are the benefits?
You know, it helps us
identify bugs before we ship.
It also helps us to describe and
really think about the impact
of the APIs we're
presenting in our project.
And then we talked about how
do you add tests and also how
to organize test into targets in
your project, the test methods,
loading resources
from the test bundle
and using the assertions
inside your test.
And then we talked about the
new asynchronous testing API,
which allows you to get a
synchronous control flow
around asynchronous tasks.
And then Brooke took you
through performance testing
and also the instruments
integration
that lets you profile your test.
And that's a really
powerful feature
because your test code is going
to be executing critical paths
in your project and then
to easily be able to hop
in Instruments and
analyze time profiles
or object alloc profiles.
It's a really great
tool for you to have.
And if you have questions,
we encourage you
to contact Dave DeLong,
our Tools Evangelist
and there's a few
related sessions.
You know, early on, I talked
about this continuous
integration workflow
and XCTest combined with the
Xcode server makes that possible
where you can set up a
server that will on commit
or schedules, check out your
code, and run all of your tests
and report the results.
So there's a session on that
later this afternoon right here
in this room.
And that's it.
Thanks a lot, folks.
[ Applause ]