>> Good morning.
And welcome to WWDC
session on iAd Workbench.
I'm Paresh Rajwat and I'm
here with my colleague,
Ravi Chittari, to share with
you how we're evolving the iAd
Workbench platform.
We have some awesome stuff we
are bringing to you this fall,
and I can't wait to
share it with you.
But before we go there, knowing
some of you are probably new
to advertising, and perhaps
hearing the word iAd Workbench
for the first time.
Let's start with two
foundational questions.
Why advertise?
And why iAd?
Let's start with the first
question: why advertise.
Say you developed this app, you
put a lot of time and energy
in it and you put
it on the App Store.
Now two things can happen.
First, users can find
your app, or second,
you can find users for your app.
Users will find your app
if they know about you,
or your app is featured in one
of the categories
in the App Store.
But with thousands
of apps coming
on the App Store every
day, natural discovery
of your app becomes
increasingly difficult
and you don't have
much control on it.
So what can you do
to take more control
of the success of your app?
You can advertise.
When you advertise, you
can find the right users
that will make the difference.
And when it comes to advertising
your apps or your products
to millions of Apple
costumers around the world,
iAd is your best choice.
Why? Because iAd is part of
Apple, and we know Apple users,
all 800 million of them.
We know what apps and other
items content they downloaded
and we know how and
when they use it.
Last June, we introduced
iAd Workbench.
It's self-service mobile
advertising platform
that provides you the simplest
way to promote your product
to millions of Apple
users around the world.
Since we introduced
iAd Workbench,
we have successfully
helped developers,
many of them advertising for the
very first time, drive millions
of visits to their
iTunes product pages.
iAd Workbench is
open to everyone.
And you can promote
anything using iAd Workbench.
You can promote your apps.
You can promote your products,
your brands, your service,
including your iTunes content,
whether it's music,
books or movies.
Last June when we
introduced iAd Workbench,
we started in the U.S.
as the first market.
And then a few months
after that,
we expanded internationally.
iAd Workbench is now
available in 14 countries
and expanding rapidly.
Now creating a campaign using
iAd Workbench is very easy.
You can create one in
just a few minutes.
To demonstrate, why don't I have
Ravi show you how easy it is
to advertise using
iAd Workbench.
>> Thank you, Paresh.
Good morning everyone.
I'm Ravi Chittari from
iAd Engineering team.
I'm here to demo iAd Workbench.
In this demo, you will see how
easy it is to promote an app.
During this demo, you will see
several options, but I'm going
to focus on a few and
will cover more later.
Let's get started.
iAd Workbench is accessible
through iadworkbench.apple.com.
All you need is an
Apple ID to log in.
When you log in, the first page
you go to is the Dashboard.
Dashboard is a summary
of all the campaigns,
and also it gives basic metrics.
To get into the campaign
creation flow,
let's click on Create Campaign.
The first choice you have is
what do you want to promote?
App or a Product?
Let's select App.
Below are the three apps that
are published to the App Store
from my developer account.
iAd Workbench automatically gets
all the apps that you published
to the App Store and
makes it available here
so you can promote
through campaigns.
Let me select Klara.
For a bid type, my goal
is to drive downloads.
I'm going to select
CPC, cost per click.
Let me name my campaign.
Clicking on Next will take
me to step 2, Targeting.
Targeting is all about
finding the right audience
for your campaign.
We have two options,
Auto and Manual.
In case of Auto, iAd finds
the right audience for you.
In case of Manual, you get to
set the targeting preferences.
Let me set up Auto.
Next, country where
your ad is going to run.
I'm going to select
United States.
Next, Ad. Ad is a combination
of Creative and Destination.
I'm going to select
Banner for Creative
and Destination: iTunes.
iTunes destination refers to
the App Store product page
where user can review
the app details
and download the app
right from there.
Next, flight dates.
These are the dates during which
your campaign is going to run.
The default started is today
and ended is a month from now.
Let's leave it as is.
Next, budget.
How much money you are willing
to spend on this campaign?
Let me enter 2,000 dollars.
Daily Spend Goal is
automatically calculated.
CPC Bid: how much you are
willing to pay per click,
the maximum you're
willing to pay per click.
You may enter 50 cents.
Let's leave the CPA
Goal optional.
Clicking on Calculate will
give us the estimated number
of impressions and tabs.
If you want to see more
impressions and tabs,
you can change the combination
of targeting, budget,
and bid, and you'll see more.
Next, let's name our line.
I've used the term "line"
several times in this page.
What is line?
A line is a combination of
targeting, budget, and bid.
You can have several
lines in a campaign.
I'm going to name this
line, My Simple Auto Line.
Clicking on Next will take me
to the Targeting Summary page
where all the lines are listed.
For this campaign, we
have just one line.
You can always add more lines by
clicking on Create Line button.
Clicking on Next will take us to
step 3, which is Creating an Ad.
The first choice we have
is selecting a device
where your ad is going to run.
Klara is a universal app,
so the system detected that
and gave iPhone,
iPad on Universal.
Let's select Universal.
For language, let's
stick with English.
We have more choices
there as well.
Then let's define the creative.
There are two choices, Using a
Template and From My Desktop.
From My Desktop is
upload your own Banner.
But for now, let's
select templates.
We have built several templates
for you to make it easy.
As you can see, there
are different formats
for these templates.
Let me select marigold.
For title, let's give
the name of the app.
And for message, few
words about your app.
And for Call to Action, you
have several predefined ones
or you can always
enter a custom text.
I'm going to select
Download Now.
And here is the preview of
how your Banner is going
to look on the device.
You can click on View All Sizes
to see how we have prepared
this creative for iPhone, iPad,
portrait and landscape.
That's how simple it is.
Let's select their
destination, iTunes.
As you saw, as soon as I
selected the destination,
it's pointing to the
Klara iTunes product page.
For this ad to go live,
we need to associate this
with the line that
we just created.
I'm assigning to the line.
We give that name, Marigold 1.
Clicking on Next will take
us to the Ad Summary page
where you will see all the ads
that are created
for this campaign.
And you can always
create more Ads from here
by clicking on Create Ad.
Clicking on Next will take us
to the Campaign Summary page
where you can review all
the details in one place.
Where you're promoting,
what you're targeting,
what are your ads.
In case you have not
set up the payment yet,
which is a credit card,
you can always click here,
but let's Submit.
When you submit, the
creatives are submitted
for iAd's Certification review.
Once they are approved,
your campaign goes live.
That's how simple it is.
Back to you, Paresh.
>> So next, let's take a deeper
dive at the tools, options,
controls, flexibility you have
in making advertising
work using iAd Workbench.
We'll look at the choices you
have in choosing your audience,
the controls you have in
setting your price, the tools
and options you have to create
an ad that will make an impact,
and finally, the data
and insights you have
to understand your campaign
performance and optimize.
Let's start with
choosing your audience.
Selecting the right audience
for your app or product is key.
With iAd Workbench, we
make it very easy for you
to define your audience.
At the highest level,
you have two options.
Auto and Manual.
Auto targeting, which you saw
in the demo is the simplest
and probably the most powerful
option we have on iAd Workbench.
This is where iAd does all
the heavy lifting for you.
If you want control,
you can choose Manual.
When you choose Manual,
you'll have several options
to define your audience.
On the left side, you see
simple targeting options
like gender, age,
geo, and device.
You can choose, for age, you
can choose specific age groups
that you want to target.
For geo, you can choose
or specify states and DMAs
that you want to
target for your users.
On the right side, there are
some very powerful options.
Starting to the top, iTunes
Preferences is an option
that is exclusive to iAd.
This is where the
power of the App Store
and the iTunes Store
comes together
to help you find
the right audience.
When you make a selection here,
you're basically selecting users
who have actually downloaded
content in that category.
So if you were to promote
a health and fitness app,
wouldn't it be great if you
could choose the audience
who like to download
health and fitness apps,
or who like to download
fitness and workout music.
With iAd Workbench,
you can do that.
It's very powerful.
The next three options
lets you define
where your ad wants-where
you want to show your ad,
which is App Channels.
When you want to show
your ad, that's scheduling
and how often do you want to
show an ad to a particular user,
which is frequency capping.
You can mix and match
any of these options
to define the right
audience for your campaign.
Next, let's look at the
flexibility you have
in setting your price.
With iAd Workbench, you
can choose how you want
to pay for your campaign.
If you want to pay for every
click, you can choose CPC.
If you want to pay for
every thousand impressions,
you can choose CPM.
The bid you enter is the
maximum you're willing to pay
when you win the auction.
iAd Workbench is a
bidded marketplace.
And on this platform, you
have the peace of mind to know
that you only pay a penny more
than the next highest bidder.
Now let's look at the options
you have in creating your ad.
There are a range
of options you have
when it comes to
selecting your ad.
You can have Banner Ads, Video
Ads, which are also known
as pre-roll, and Rich-Media Ads
if you want higher engagement
of the users with your ads.
Banner ads provide a
direct path to action.
Upon tap of a banner, you
can take a user directly
to an iTunes product page
or to a mobile website.
Upon tap of a banner,
you can also take a user
and show them a video and then
take them to iTunes product page
or to a mobile website.
Let's take a look as an example
how a banner ad looks like.
Here's an app, you see the
ad will render at the bottom.
After a few seconds,
the ad will refresh,
the user engages with the ad.
And when the user clicks on it,
the user is taken
to the App Store.
The user can download
the app at this point.
Now once the user
downloads the app,
you don't show the same
download ad again to this user,
which means you don't waste your
money showing your ads to users
who already have your app.
Next is Video ads.
Video ads play automatically
before a video content.
They play directly
in fullscreen mode.
With video ads, you can also
have an optional call to action
which will take the user
to an iTunes product
page or a mobile website.
Here's an example of a video ad.
>> [Background Music]
You can chase light,
or let the light chase you.
Introducing LightRight,
an iOS bookmarking
tool for natural light.
LightRight for iPhone, now
available in the App Store.
>> As you noticed, there
was a Learn More link
at the bottom of that video.
The user clicks on that Learn
More link and the user is taken
to the iTunes product page.
You can also have the user
go to a mobile website.
If you want to create rich-media
ads for more higher engagement,
you can do that using
iAd Workbench as well.
Upon tap of a banner, you
can immerse your users
into a very custom product
or brand experience.
You can choose any combination
of features and any combination
of call to actions to
create a rich-media ad.
I'll show you an example
that the client had actually
used really good features
to create a great experience.
Let's take a look.
Here's the app.
You see the ad being rendered.
The user taps on the ad,
and is taken-is immersed
into a brand experience.
The user can browse through
the pictures gallery.
The user is still
within the app.
You can take the
user to Facebook
so you can have a
Facebook integration.
You can have the user like
your page on Facebook.
You can have the reservations
module within the ad.
And finally, you can even
integrate the app download right
from this place.
So as you see, you
can do a lot of things
when it comes to rich-media ads.
Now that awesome ad was
created using a free tool
that is available to everyone
which is called iAd Producer.
With iAd Producer, you can
create highly interactive
rich-media ads.
They made it so easy for
you that you can just drag
and drop your assets
in a visual layout.
Or you can customize
the visual layout.
We provide you with an extensive
library of over 500 blueprints
which are like templates.
And when you use one
of these blueprints,
they come with built-in
performance and analytics
so you can see how your user
is engaging and interacting
with the rich-media ad.
And finally, with
iAd Producer 4.2
that was introduced
just two weeks ago,
you have integrated iAd Producer
with Workbench, which means,
if you create an ad
using iAd Producer,
you can now upload it
directly on to Workbench.
And when you go to Workbench,
you'll have it available to use.
So once you create
your campaign,
your campaign is
running and you want
to see how the campaign
is performing.
When it comes to
campaign performance,
we provide you rich analytics
that helps you understand
how your campaign is doing
so you can take the
right actions.
We give you data,
performance metrics,
as well as conversion metrics
which includes, you know,
what your spend is,
your capture rate is,
number of impressions you
got, as well as the downloads
that you've received so
you can tune your campaign.
We provide you this
data at every level
at the aggregate
campaign level as well
as at lower line and ad levels.
You can also download this
data as a .CSV file from any
of the analytic screens.
So, at this point, I'll ask
Ravi to walk us through some
of these tools and
options that we talked
about to make your
advertising work.
>> Thank you, Paresh.
In this demo, I'm going
to walk you through some
of the core concepts that
Paresh has mentioned,
touch and targeting, some of
the new ad formats analytics.
Let's get started.
I've been working on a
campaign I'm halfway through it,
let's finish this
campaign together.
I created a campaign and
created just one line
with a manual targeting
and I want
to finish-show you
what targeting I've set
up by editing the
line and later,
we'll add ads to this one.
A targeting option, we're going
to select as Manual and this-and
for the country, let's
leave it as United States.
And these are the
different targeting options
that we have available.
You can see all the options
on the left-hand side.
On the right, you will see the
options that we have selected.
By default, it's All.
Next, I'm going to target
few of the app references.
I'm going to select Lifestyle,
Photo and Video and Travel.
Then for App Channels, I
want to do similar thing.
I'm going to do Lifestyle,
I'm going to do Photo
and Video and Travel.
You can always select
more based upon,
you know, how it's performing.
For app type, last time we
did for creative: banner.
This time we're going to
do video as a creative
to a website as a destination.
My goal here is to drive
traffic to the website.
And for flight dates,
let's leave it as a default
and I've given some
spend, budget and bid here.
Let's go to the next step
where we can create an ad.
Here we have two choices,
a banner or a video.
Let's select video.
And where your ad-you want
your ad to run for devices
for maximum reach,
let's pick Universal.
For language, let's
keep it at English.
And here we are at a step where
we need to upload a video file.
iAd Workbench supports
two formats
for the video file,
.M4V and .MOV.
There are few more
specs here right here.
We encourage you to follow
the specs so you don't trip
on any validation errors.
Let's upload.
The file is being
uploaded from my laptop
to the Workbench
servers right now.
Once the file reaches
the servers,
the file will be transcoded
to multiple formats
to suit the devices
and resolutions
like iPhone high res, low res,
iPad high res and low res.
It's uploading right now.
Let it take its time.
I guess everybody is using
the network bandwidth I guess.
So, right now it seems like
the file has reached the server
as you saw the status
changed to Formatting.
This is when the video
transcoding is happening.
It's actually transforming the
video to suit the other devices.
Let's take a quick review.
>> [Background Music]
You can chase light
or let the light chase you.
Introducing LightRight,
an iOS bookmarking
tool for natural light.
LightRight for iPhone, now
available from the App Store.
>> That was a cool video.
I just want to highlight
one thing here.
For you as an advertiser,
prepare one file
to one technical
specification and be assured
that your ad-video ad is going
to run on all the Apple devices
in the best way possible,
so, that's how simple it is
to create a video ad here.
Use this ad format, we encourage
you to take advantage of it.
Let's select the destination.
As I said I'm going
to the website.
You can view the URL right here.
And then it will ask you for
the destination, for the name.
I like the name LightRight
website here.
So I'm going to leave it as is.
For this app to go live, you
need to assign to the line.
I'm going to assign to the video
line that I created earlier.
Let's name the ad.
I'm going to name it
as My Awesome Video.
Clicking on Next will take
us to the Ad Summary page.
So, that's the demo of the
powerful ad format video ad.
So far in my two
demos, we mainly focused
on creating a campaign,
on editing a campaign,
focused on a little bit on
targeting and ad formats.
Once a campaign is
created, the next thing
to focus is monitoring the
performance of the campaign
to ensure that it is going
towards the goal you have set
out for.
In order to monitor the
performance of the campaign,
we have some analytics.
So, next, I want you to
take-I want to take you
to the analytics pages.
I have these two campaigns
that have been running
for the last 6 months.
I want to show the
performance of these campaigns.
As you see the Dashboard
used the basic metrics spend,
impressions, TTR
and conversions.
You can click on any of these
metrics and go into the details.
By default, it gives
Since Campaign Start
and you have different custom
data groups you can select
that we have prepared for you.
Let me select last 30 days.
That's the spend for the last
30 days for this campaign.
Seems like we are spending
more in the weekends
and spend is coming down
during the weekdays.
You have different
metrics that you can view.
I've listed here.
And you can overlay any
metric on top of it.
Or if you want to compare
how you've been spending,
compare to the previous period,
you can always select
Compare with Previous Period.
That gives you how the last 30
days is performing as opposed
to the previous 30 days.
Overlay is a pretty neat feature
where you can overlay any metric
here and compare to the spend.
I ordered average CPA metric.
It seems like we are doing less
than 2 dollars for
download here.
Let's go into the lines.
By default, it gives you
the cumulative number.
You can always select
Time, Time Series graph
to see how the lines
are performing.
It seems like we are spending
more on this line than this one.
And you can do similar
analysis on ad side as well.
By default, it gives you
the spend for cumulative.
You can always change
the metrics and change
to the time series graph.
We're pretty close on
these two ads here.
Let me go back to
the summary and find
out a couple of things here.
You can easily toggle between
a graph and a table view
if you choose to do so.
Or if you can scroll down and
you can click on Download CSV
to get a file onto your
desktop and do offline analysis.
And Download CSV is available
across the board on Dashboard
on every analytic
space that we have.
So, that's a quick
overview of, you know,
how to measure the
performance of your campaign.
All the data that I've been
showing in last 5 minutes,
that data is available
through the API.
So, next, I'm going to drop you
through the complete overview
of iAd Workbench API that
we have released this year.
So, your-you are an advertiser.
You have created
multiple campaigns
and managing all
those campaigns.
And you want to scale
beyond the web interface.
API is for you.
Say you're an advertiser who
wanted to get the metrics
and incorporate it to
your own dashboards.
API is for you.
Let's get into the-more details.
You can also use it
for bulk operations.
API has two broad categories.
Reporting, where you can get the
metrics and perform the offline
and real-time analysis.
What do I mean by
real-time analysis here?
You can write a program for
example that runs at the top
of every hour, get some
metrics, analyze the data
and modify your campaign data.
You can trace the bid, start
and stop a campaign ad.
That's what I'm talking
about real-time analysis.
For offline analysis, you
can do your own dashboards.
And campaign management, you
can get the campaign details,
update the critical
campaign data and start
and stop campaign lines or ads.
Let's get into some very basics.
We're talking about API here.
For communication, API
uses JSON or HTTPS.
We want to keep the data
protocol pretty simple
so it's easy to understand
and it's easy to test.
We use JSON for data protocol
and secure HTTPS for security.
The next: authentication, we use
client certificates, private key
and access token as a
combination for authentication,
making it a very
strong authentication.
And for key management, we want
to make it as easy as possible
so you can be having
web interface
for that on Workbench app.
So, how do you initiate
this API?
We have three basic
steps: download keys,
verify keys and integrate.
Go to Workbench,
go to the API page,
click on the Download
link to download the keys.
When you download the keys,
we give you a .zip file
that has keys and
sample programs.
And sample programs are
already embedded with your keys.
Run those sample programs
and verify the keys.
And then download the
API programming guide,
write your own programs,
deploy them on your servers
and integrate, that's
how simple it is.
Let me quickly walk you through
some of the core methods here.
We have InitSession for session
initialization, which is key
because you need to pass the
sessionId for every method
that you are going to call
in your program for API.
Campaign method-metadata methods
to get the campaign details,
reporting API to
get the metrics.
And campaign management
API to update the details
as well as start and stop.
Now, I'm going to
walk you through some
of the sample program that
I've already done using the
highlighted methods
here, InitSession,
GetCampaignDetails
and UpdateLine.
So, here is a sample program,
sample method where I'm trying
to pass access token,
prepare the request tab,
post it to the server
then get the response back
and read the session from that,
sessionId from the response.
Once I get the sessionId,
I pass the sessionId
to getCampaignDetails method,
get the campaign IDs and filter
by running state, post
that to the server,
get the response back.
Next, for the campaign details
I got, I'm passing the LineId
for which I want to
increase the bid.
So I gave the line-SessionId,
LineId and the CPMBid,
post to server, and
get the response back.
That's how simple it is
to write the programs
to communicate with the API.
Powerful, secure and easy
to use, go try it out.
With this, I'm going to
pass on to Paresh to walk us
through what's coming next.
There you go Paresh.
>> Thank you, Ravi.
It's fascinating what
you can do with the APIs
and how you can make bulk
changes to your campaigns
from your own user interface.
So, what's coming this fall?
So far, we've talked about
how iAd Workbench can help you
acquire new customers.
But that's just half the battle.
For you to grow your business,
you also need to re-engage
with your existing customers
and have them do more
of what you want, whether it's
spending more time in your app,
buying more of your products,
or even trying your new apps.
I came across a study
recently on the web
by a mobile analytics
firm, Localytics,
which said 22 percent
of the apps
that were downloaded were used
only once and over 60 percent
of them were used
less than 10 times.
Now, you want users
to frequently engage
with your app or your website.
Let's take a few examples
how engaged-re-engaging
with your customers can
help you grow your business.
First example is
about a game app.
So you came up with a new iPad
version of your iPhone game.
Now, who will be the best
customers for this new app?
Of course, the users who
use that game on the iPhone.
What if you had a way to
connect with these customers
and inform them about
your new game?
And what if you could inform
them about this new game
when they are on their iPad?
Or, say you enhanced your app
and you added more
levels more game levels
or you have more things that
you want to sell in your app.
What if you had a way to
re-engage with the users
and show or promote these
levels only to users
who have reached certain
levels in your game
or show this merchandise
only to users
who actually buy
merchandise like this?
And what about all those
users who downloaded your app
but haven't used it
in the last two weeks?
What if you had a way
to reconnect with them
and motivate them to try-come
back and try your app again?
And what if you could
connect with them
when they're not in your app?
Let's take another example.
A retail app.
Say you have a retail app.
Now, you have users who browse
through your product catalog
and add things to
the shopping basket.
Many of these users exit the
app before they actually make
a purchase.
What if you had a way to find
these users and bring them back
to finish the purchase and what
if you could bring them
back exactly at the point
where they had left
in the shopping basket
so they can finish the
transaction in next step.
And if you want to send offers
to your loyal customers,
what if you could
show these offers
to your loyal customers
irrespective
of what iOS device they are on?
And for users and your
customers who have items
in their wish list, what if
you could reconnect with these
and inform them when the items
on the wish list are on sale?
Now, in each of these
examples that we talked about,
we talked about reconnecting
with a specific group
of audience.
Whether it's all the customers
who have downloaded your app
or the dormant users who
haven't used your app,
or the loyal users who do
purchases for you, or the users
who have an abandoned cart
on your shopping-on your app.
We call this group of
audiences as "segments".
Now there are probably
a million ways you could
segment audiences.
You know your business and
your app, and your users best.
So you will segment your
users the way you want it.
And for you to easily
create segments,
we're introducing a new
functionality this fall
with iOS 8 which we call
Audience Segmentation.
Building segments using Audience
Segmentation is very easy.
You can do it in just two steps.
The first one is you get
segment IDs from iAd Workbench.
Now, every segment is unique
so it has a unique segment ID.
You can download the segment
IDs from iAd Workbench.
Once you get the segment IDs,
you then integrate those
segment IDs in your app.
You map the user behavior of
the functionality you have
in the app with these
segment IDs.
And when the user demonstrates
a particular user behavior
or reaches a functionality,
say reaches a particular level,
you instrument it in a way
that you automatically make API
call using the new iOS 8 SDK,
and pass that segment
ID onto Workbench.
Now when you do that,
your segments will automatically
start getting populated
on iAd Workbench.
Here's an example where
segmentation was done based
on time spent in an app.
To avail your segments, users
who have spent less than 1 hour
in the app, 1 to 10 hours, 10 to
20 and 20 plus hours in the app.
Now, if you were to reconnect
or re-engage with these users,
you would probably have a very
different strategy when it comes
to reengaging you with users
who have spent less than an hour
in your app compared to who
have spent more than 20 hours.
Here's another example
where segmentation is
based on levels of use.
Whenever a user reaches
a particular level,
they go from level 1 to level 2.
The API call that I talked
about is automatically made
from the client side
from your app
and the right segment
ID is passed
and the user gets added
to this new segment.
So once you do segmentation
this way using iOS 8,
we can unlock some amazing
things which brings us
to the second thing that
we're introducing this fall,
we call it Audience Insights.
When your segments reach a
particular threshold of users,
we will show you unique audience
insights into your segments,
all for free at no charge.
These insights are
based on iTunes data.
So we'll show you how the
distribution is of the users
in your segment, the
demographic distribution.
How age, gender, household
income distribution is
for these users.
We'll show you the top regions,
the top countries, top states,
DMAs these users come from, the
top languages these users have
on their devices as well
as the top iTunes
preferences of these users.
So you know what are the things
they really like to download.
Now once you have
these unique insights,
you can take some
very tangible actions.
If you know the demographics of
your audience in the segment,
you can fine tune your app to
suit more of the demographics.
If you know the top regions and
the languages of your audience,
you might want to consider
localizing your app.
If you have an English
app and you know
that the top region
is Asia Pacific
and the top language is
Japanese, you might want
to make a Japanese app.
If you created a segment
of all your loyal users,
now you understand
the characteristics
of those audience.
And then using Workbench
targeting, you can find more
of the same and you can
build your audience pool.
And finally, with
audience segmentation
and audience targeting together,
we can bring you
another big thing
which we are also
introducing this fall
and we call it Audience
Retargeting.
Audience retargeting lets you
re-engage with every segment
that you have in
a customized way
so you can give a
custom experience
through each of your segments.
So now when you have
those dormant users
who didn't use your
app, you can re-engage
with those users
with that segment.
Show them a custom message,
motivate them to come back
and try your app again.
And when you have users who
have reached a certain level
and you want to push
them to the next level,
you can create a
segment of the users
who have reached say level 2.
Show them a custom
message about level 3.
When they engage with
that, take them to level 3,
not open the app, deep link
them directly to level 3.
And those users who
had an abundant cart
in your retail app,
you can now re-engage
or retarget those
users irrespective
of what device they are on and
bring them back to your app.
And not only bring them
back, deep link them directly
to the shopping basket,
so in the next step they
can finish the purchase.
So really anything is possible.
For each of your segments, you
can create that awesome message
and take the user to
wherever you want in the app
or even to any website.
Now that's not it.
With audience retargeting,
we'll actually find those users
for you on any iOS device.
So now when you had that example
but you introduce your iPad app,
a new app, now you can
find you iPhone app users
when they're on the iPad.
So what we are introducing
here is a cross-app,
cross-device retargeting.
That is huge.
What else is unique about this?
The first thing is
automation that comes with it.
When you build segments
using iOS 8,
your segments are automatically
updated in real-time.
No more of manually harvesting
idea phase, sharing them
with your network partners.
Your data is most secure
when it's in one place.
And there's no better
place than Apple iAd.
When you create segments this
way, segmentation is automated,
audience insights run
based on segmentation,
that's real-time updated as well
as the audience retargeting
is updated in real-time.
The next thing is Privacy.
Audience retargeting and this
entire solution we talked
about is deeply integrated
with iOS.
So you get all the benefits
of the built-in privacy
controls that come with it.
The solution complies with
the Limit Ad Tracking.
So now if you have a user
who has Limit Ad Tracking on,
that user is removed
automatically from the segments.
So the user is not retargeted.
Everything is automated.
You have nothing to worry about.
So with Audience
Segmentation, Audience Insights,
and Audience Retargeting,
iAd becomes-iAd Workbench
becomes a complete solution.
You can, not only acquire
new users and new customers,
you can now understand your
existing users and re-engage
with them to grow your business.
What else is coming?
We'll be introducing two
new ad formats this fall.
Interstitial ads which are also
called as fullscreen banners
and Medium Rectangle
also call as MREC.
Both these ad formats
will be available
on iPad as well as on iPhone.
So with that, you will have
four ad formats to choose:
the banner ads, video ads,
interstitials and MREC.
The next is we're going
to continue enhancing
the iAd Workbench APIs.
We'll introduce iAd
Workbench API 2.0
which will give you a
full read-write campaign
creation capability.
So if you work with a
Demand Side Partner,
also called as DSP, you
can now have your DSP plug
into iAd Workbench and
create and manage campaigns
on your behalf from their
own UI ad interface.
That's a move towards
programmatic buying,
automated way of
booking campaigns
and managing them
from your own UI.
We'll also provide you APIs
for segmentation that we talked
about just in-a little bit ago.
And finally, we'll continue
with the geo expansion.
We'll go in more countries
and there is bunch more things
that we have in plans for you.
So to summarize, as
you saw in the demos
and throughout the talk, iAd
Workbench is the simplest way
for you to reach Apple users.
It's very powerful and
it's open to everyone.
So if you haven't tried
iAd Workbench yet,
go to iadworkbench.apple.com and
log in with just your Apple ID.
Make sure you take advantage of
the APIs that we reviewed today.
And the new ad formats
that are available now
and coming in fall.
And finally, the key thing,
make sure you enable your app
for segmentation so you
can get those free insights
that we just talked about
and you can also re-engage
with your current customers.
If you have more
questions, please reach
out to our evangelist,
Mark Malone.
We have lots of documentation
on iAd Online Workbench Help.
And you can also find us in
the Apple Developer Forum.
There was a session which
is very related to some
of the things that we
talked about today.
It was yesterday.
In case you missed it, make
sure you watch it later on.
In that session,
we talked about how
to use the API for segmentation.
So if you're interested in that,
make sure you take
a look at that.
That's it.
Thank you and have a great WWDC.