>> Welcome.
[ Applause ]
So welcome to "Ingredients
of Great Games".
What we're going to talk
about today is some things
that you can do in your game to
make it really, really great.
Because having a fun game
is simply not enough.
There are things
that great games do.
What I mean is, games that are
recognized as industry leading
in the games industry.
Things that they do
that you should be doing
or what you really need to be
doing to make your game great.
And there's a massive
opportunity.
As Tim talked about yesterday,
there's 75 billion
downloads of applications.
And as everyone in
this room knows,
a huge portion of
those are games.
Game Center also reinforces this
with 130 million monthly
active users last month.
That is a huge audience that
you can tap into for your game.
But, and to do that, you need
to start with a great idea,
obviously put in hard work, and
you need to follow some really,
really important key tips
to make your game great.
So over the last couple days,
yesterday and this morning,
we've been talking
about technology.
And so technology like OpenGL
ES 3.0, which was introduced
since WWDC last year, and is
the most advanced OpenGL ES
out there.
We also have Metal, our low
level highly optimized GPU API.
We have Game Center,
which provides
that social connection
for your players.
SpriteKit and SceneKit.
You know, let us do the
heavy lifting for you.
If you don't need to go
right to OpenGL or Metal,
you can use SpriteKit
and SceneKit.
It'll allow you to do less
programming and let us build
out efficient API
underneath your game.
And Game Controllers: open your
game up to many forms of input.
Of course, there's also Xcode
6 with Swift and Playground.
We have tools like the
Metal or OpenGL Debuggers.
We have SceneKit and
SpriteKit editors.
And, also this week,
we have a mass amount
of sessions about games.
We have three on Metal, two
on SceneKit, two on SpriteKit.
We have labs on all of
these technologies all week,
and we have sessions
about developer tools.
But technology alone
is not enough.
You can't just take the
technology, build a game on top
of it, and expect
it to be successful.
You have to go about the games
business and the business
of building a game with the
same passion that you would go
about your game design
or choosing your technology
or your graphics API.
If you look at the winners
from the Apple Design Awards
last night, like "Threes",
"Leo's Fortune", "DEVICE 6",
"Blek", or "Monument Valley",
they have some common
traits that attract,
engage and retain their players.
And this engagement
is key to success.
So what we find are there are
some common threads among these
successful games.
Things like, make it easy
to buy and play your game
by reducing the friction.
Or refresh your content to
continually be able to retain
and engage those players.
As I said, engagement
is really key.
We've identified these and
other traits among these games.
And I'd like to invite Allan
Schaffer up on stage to talk
about these key ingredients
for great games.
>> Thank you, sir.
Hello, everyone.
Welcome to WWDC 2014 and games.
So my name is Allan Schaffer.
I'm the Game Technologies
Evangelist at Apple.
And, as Geoff said, I'm here
to talk to you about some
of the things we see in some
of the best games on iOS.
Now, there's a lot
of things that go
into making a great game.
And a lot of different ways to
describe that process, right?
But to echo back to what he was
saying, when we look at games
and we think about the
Apple Design Award winners
over the years, we start to
see common threads and the kind
of key ingredients that all
of these games get right.
And that's what I want to
talk to you about today.
So I'm going to go through a
list of some of these things
that just really
stand out to me.
There is a lot more than
what I'm going to go through,
but here is the first
thing on my list: Okay,
is to remove friction.
So I'm talking here about
making a great first impression
and a really frictionless first
time experience in the game,
really streamlining
everything that gets in the way
of the player getting into
the game as they start.
So what do I really
mean by friction here?
So here's our imaginary
game, "Paddle Mania 3000".
It is awesome, by the way.
But it has some of the
problems with friction
that I'm thinking of here.
So let me show you first
the start up experience
of this game: Player comes in?
Loading. So, yeah,
still loading.
And it's going to take
it about a minute to load
because that's how
long it will take me
to get through the slide.
So, you know, the problem
that I have or that I see here
with a number of games is
that they really take kind
of a monolithic approach
to loading their assets.
And they preload everything
up front instead of, you know,
trying to just do what they
need just to get started.
So your goal should
be to get interactive
as quickly as you can.
Load just enough of your
assets so that you can get up
and running to your
first interactive screen.
And then use technologies
like Grand Central Dispatch,
and so on, to move work off
of your main thread and so,
and let that continue
asynchronously.
Then, also, use the Time
Profiler to really take a look
at your loading performance.
And it will show you in a lot
of detail exactly what work the
app is doing during that time.
But even before you get into
the Time Profiler, I don't want
to just punt to the Time
Profiler as my advice.
You have to really think
about it first, right?
Why are so many things
being loaded up front?
And isn't there something
that could be deferred
and loaded asynchronously
a little bit later?
So, okay. So it's done loading.
And now let's go on to now
we're downloading some assets.
Okay. So, you know, a lot of
you guys do this in the game.
And it's fine.
In many cases, it's
a good thing.
But it doesn't have
to be something
where it makes the player wait.
So later in the talk I'm going
to go through a couple of things
that you can do to move
this off to the side
so the user doesn't
even have to notice it.
Okay, next: registration.
Would I like a "Paddle
Mania" account?
No, I would like to
play "Paddle Mania".
So, you know, when you think
about the registration,
there's a couple of
possibilities here.
You know, maybe, actually
that registration is needed.
Maybe you have a game
that is server backed,
and you need some way to
uniquely identify this player.
If that's the case,
then actually you could just use
the Vendor ID that we provide
to the game as the unique
identifier for that player.
And get it so that it's
out of the player's way.
Handle it automatically.
But maybe the case isn't that
you have a server backed game.
Maybe you're just asking the
user to sign up for an account
because you want to give
them news or special offers
or just whatever
the reason may be.
Well, the first-time experience
in the game is not the right
time to ask for this yet.
They don't who, you know,
why you might be asking.
So, of course, you would
need to clearly explain it.
Like, is it needed?
Or is it just kind of extra?
And if it's not really needed,
then defer it until later.
So I want to play, I'm
going to say, no thanks.
Next, configure my paddle.
It's "Paddle Mania".
But, so, let me be clear:
If this is my first
time playing the game,
then I don't know the
implications of any
of these choices,
right, to go and play.
So if they matter, then
now is not the time
to ask me because I don't know.
And if they don't matter,
then don't put them in the way
of user getting onboard
into the game.
And, you know, not knowing
either way sort of conveys
to the players that it's not
really-the experience here
hadn't really been
thought through.
And so there's some real trouble
with "Paddle Mania", actually.
And then, yeah, there we go.
The last one here:
please leave a rating.
You know, this is fine, right,
we talk about this all the time.
But, you know, at
this point, actually,
I haven't even played
the game yet.
So, you know, now is not
the best time to come
and ask me about rating it.
But, you know, I think, you
guys are getting it here, right.
So let me give you the
takeaways of this first section:
So you've got to get the
player into the game.
Reduce the load time
and any blocking updates
to get the game interactive
as quickly as possible.
Then streamline the
registration, right.
Provide an escape from
tutorials and long intros
and all those things that
might get in the way.
And then don't force
decisions about something
that the player can't
possibly know about yet.
And be patient, you
know, show some restraint
when you're asking for feedback.
So that's number
one: remove friction
from the first time experience.
Okay, here's number
two: be a good teacher.
So being a good teacher is
really all about thinking
through that onboarding
experience
and really kind of
making it fun.
Because if you can help
your players get started,
it's more likely that they'll
become more deeply engaged
into the game.
And, you know, it's
almost easier to think
of it on the other side.
If you just leave it
to the player to figure
out your game themselves,
then you run a lot of risks.
You risk people just
failing a couple of times
and getting frustrated
and leaving the game.
Or maybe they'll miss something
that was really important
to the gameplay and would
have captured their interest,
but they just didn't see it.
They didn't know to
go down that path.
So yesterday during the
design award ceremony,
John was up here.
He talked about "Leo's
Fortune" as his example.
I'm going to use a
different example:
Apple Design Award Winner from
2011, and that's "Cut the Rope".
So this was an awesome
puzzle game.
And it's kind of the
perfect example here to use
as an onboarding case study.
So right away what you see here
is they're using coaching tips
to explain the goal,
which is to deliver candy
to Om Nom, the little character.
And then they start to
tell you about things
like the primary interaction.
In "Cut the Rope", you swipe
with your finger
to cut the rope.
Now you might be looking at
this kind of going like, well,
that's totally obvious.
But, no, it's only because
you've seen this picture.
And so the, you know what
people would do without this,
they would tap the candy,
they would tap Om Nom trying
to get him to jump
up and eat the candy.
They don't know what to do.
And those aren't the
right interactions, right?
The correct one is to
swipe, cut the rope.
So then once the
player has that down,
then they start introducing new
interactions one at that time.
So each time there's
another coaching tip.
So here you cut the rope,
the candy flows down,
it goes into the bubble,
and then the bubble will
start to lift it up.
And then there's another tip
put right in context once
that happens telling the
player to pop the bubble
with their finger and
that will release it
and it will come down to Om Nom.
Okay. And then more really
sort of subtle thing is
that a big part of the
gameplay in Cut the Rope comes
from trying to get the candy
to touch all the stars before
it gets down to Om Nom and kind
of routing around that way.
And to be successful at that
usually takes some trial
and error on every level
when you're actually
playing the game.
So it's actually really
important to the Core Loop
of this game to show players
how they can try again, right.
So in their onboarding, they
call that out specifically.
And you would think oh,
that's just, you know,
okay fine they're showing
me around the buttons.
But, no, if they had left
that to the player to discover
on their own, some people
might not have played
around with all the buttons and
the menus to go and play again.
But really this is
core to the gameplay
so that's why they show it.
But, okay, so to summarize now:
So start by bringing the
player right into the game
and show them how
to get started.
And then introduce more complex
interactions one at that time.
Provide tips and
context as you go along
and then help them discover the
things that will be important
in the game as they
play through it.
So that's number two:
be a good teacher.
Now, I want to mention, also,
we're having a related session.
It's going to be on
Thursday, very aptly named,
"Making a Great First Impression
with Strong Onboarding Design".
We'll spend a whole hour
going through some examples
that really get this right.
So be sure to catch
that on Thursday.
All right, now I want to turn
focus to the gameplay itself.
So number three is to really
tune and perfect your Core Loop.
You know, I talk to
people all the time.
And people will ask me to
take a look at their game,
give them some feedback, you
know stuff under development.
And a lot of times what I'm
looking at is something,
you know, they're saying, I just
it doesn't really feel fun yet.
And what that really comes
down to is the Core Loop.
So Core Loop is the
term that wraps up how
to describe the game mechanic
in terms of, you know,
the actions the player
takes in the game;
the reward that they
receive, you know,
as they're pursuing a goal;
and the resulting expansion
of the game or the growth of the
character that motivated them
to pursue that reward.
And just in games that
aren't quite right,
what I often find is that
there's some disconnect
in this cycle or some
mismatch between the parts
so they don't really
line up well.
But, so let me just
illustrate this
by showing you some typical
examples from different genres,
just to set the stage.
So, you know, here is a
fantasy role playing game.
I explore the dungeon.
I fight enemies.
Defeating the enemies gets
me treasure and experience.
And then I use that
treasure and experience
to level up and to buy things.
And then that lets
me go and fight more
and more powerful enemies, okay?
Very clear.
Or a platformer, you know, the
basic idea in a platformer is
to run and jump, okay,
that's the player action.
But their goal is really to
complete the level itself
and avoid all the
obstacles and the bad guys
and collect the stars
or power ups
or whatever is happening
on that level.
But then if you're
successful the expansion is
to unlock the next stage,
literally expand the universe,
the game universe,
for that game.
And where then you then go
and find new things to run
and jump over, new
obstacles, and so on.
But, okay.
So now to get a little
deeper, you know,
it's really worth
noting that some
of the most compelling
games are the ones
with more than one Core Loop.
And I'm showing these
side by side.
But really they're
meant to be overlapping.
So you're fighting monsters,
you gain experience,
you're leveling up.
But, at the same time,
you're collecting clues.
You're using the clues
to solve a puzzle.
The puzzle lets you
unlock a door.
Behind the door there's more
monsters and more clues.
And these are overlaid in the
experience on top of each other.
But, okay.
So let me give you some
more concrete advice here.
So, you know, what
really is the bottom line?
So the best games, first,
are the ones that really,
clearly understand their
target audience and are able
to put center excuse
me, put the centerpoint
of the Core Loop right
on top of that audience.
And it's important that the Core
Loop be easy to express and kind
of easy to understand.
That's kind of, when
I find games
that are have these little
mismatches, usually it's a case
where it's difficult
for the developer
to actually express the
Core Loop, these components,
clearly in terms of the action,
the reward, the expansion.
Now, as I have been
saying, make sure each phase
of this feeds right
into the next.
And, sort of, all of the
energy that the player gives
into one part of it flows
around and, kind of,
reinforces the other parts.
Make each iteration meaningful.
And I'll talk about this
a little more as I talk
about progression in the game.
But then also question
your assumptions.
And this is probably the best
advice for any developer is
to go back and really
rethink it and keep iterating
until you know you've
done it well.
And, you know, how do you know?
How do you really know?
I could say playtest, but
that's just a punt, right.
It's like, how do you really
know that you did it well?
Well, you know it by really
thinking it through yourself.
You know, if you find the
clues, will you be able
to solve the puzzle without
some giant leap of faith
or going online to Google how
to figure out this puzzle.
Well, you know, if you unlock
something, if you solve
that puzzle, is it going
to unlock the next stage?
If you unlock that next stage,
will I have something new
or novel to really look
at once I get there?
Okay. So test it.
But, at the same time,
don't feel boxed in.
I am not saying that
every game needs
to follow the same design
methodology or, you know,
kind of deal with its
audience in the same way.
A lot of the really
best expressions
of great games are the ones that
aren't afraid to mix this up.
But, so, now, let me show
you just a quick example,
a game that's really
fantastic in the way
that it does its Core Loop is
the Apple Design Award winner
last year, this is "Ridiculous
Fishing" by Vlambeer.
So it really has, I
think you could break it
down into three distinct
mechanics.
The first one is when you
are dropping your line
into the water.
You're just trying to, you're
using the accelerometer
or the gyroscope and
trying to get the line
down through the water
avoiding the fish,
get it as deep as you can.
Okay. Then once you run out
of line or once you hit a fish
on the way down,
everything reverses.
And now you're going
back up and reeling
in as many fish as you can.
We're back on the gyro again
and just trying now to collect
as many of the fish
and try to run
into them while avoiding
the jellyfish
and other baddies
that are there.
And then the third loop, when
we get up to the surface,
of course, we fling the fish up
into the air and then you tap
on them to shoot them
out of the sky, right,
so and collect points.
And so, and then those
points are what we use
as the expansion in the game.
It lets us get a better lure,
a longer line, and so on.
And so the game is really,
you know, hilarious.
And if you didn't
see it last year
from the design awards,
check it out.
But so that's tuning
your Core Loop.
Now, let me expand
out from there.
And so for the next few parts
of the talk, I want to go
through some aspects of this
next ring around the Core Loop
and I want to start with
the interaction mechanic.
Because obviously, you know,
how the player interacts
with your game is completely
fundamental to the success
of the Core Loop,
to it feeling fun.
And if your players seem
to be having trouble
with the controls,
this is where to start.
And it's to design for touch.
So sometimes when I'm working
with someone who's
bringing a game over to iOS
from another platform like a
PC or a console or whatever,
their first instinct is actually
to just bring their Core Loop
over completely unchanged,
you know, including all
of their old interaction
mechanic, right.
And so, you know, if their game
was based on pressing buttons
than they just overlay
the screen,
superimpose some buttons.
Or if they used to use a
D pad, then, okay, great,
then they'll put a virtual
D pad on the screen.
But the truth is that this is
usually not really optimal.
These overlays get in the way
of the player seeing
the game field.
And, but more profoundly,
they're indirect.
They're controls
that are controlling
that little paddle that's
going to go underneath.
And, you know, it's a
bouncy ball game, right?
And so since they're indirect,
it relies on the player
to really be able
to be in control
of the controls themselves.
But they can't feel when their
finger is in the right spot.
And so they kind of have to look
at their finger a lot in order
to be confident in
their actions.
Okay. Now, if you step back
a moment and really think
about where all this is
coming from, you know,
if the game was designed with a
different interaction mechanic
in mind, then a lot
of the assumptions
of that other mechanic just
get built into the game.
They become kind of implicit and
ultimately kind of forgotten.
And when that happens, the
answer isn't just to, kind of,
remap some controls
onto a virtual joystick
or virtual buttons.
You really need to go back
and rethink those assumptions.
And, you know, go back
and redesign for touch.
And if you're not sure what I
really, really mean by this,
then let's just go
back and look at some
of the Design Award winners
over the past couple of years.
"Monument Valley": tap the
path, and that directs Ida
around to walk around.
She's the main character.
And then you or you do
these little twist gestures
and that'll turn the cranks
and move the walkways.
So it's based on
taps and gestures.
"Blek": You make a
shake with your finger.
And that's the pattern that the
stroke that's generated is going
to follow and you try
and get that to repeat.
And try to hit the dots.
By the way, I'm going
to hang this picture
in John's office
when we get back.
So but it's about
stroking a path.
"Threes". So in "Threes", you
push the tiles against the walls
to make, you know, matching
numbers join together.
It's very, kind of, physical.
You're pushing the tiles.
They're coming, they're
squeezing together
against the walls, and so on.
But it's all based on
short strokes and swipes.
Infinity Blade.
You swipe the screen to control
how your character's going
to swing its sword.
Then there's some buttons you
press to dodge, and raise,
you know, you put
on your shield.
And there's some gestures
you use to cast a spell.
But so it's taps,
swipes, and gestures.
"Cut the Rope": We
just showed you.
You swipe to cut the rope,
and then you tap things
like balloons and you tap on the
bubbles and so on to blow air
around or pop the bubbles.
So it's taps and swipes.
"Where's My Water": You
guys are getting this.
You know, you take your finger,
you drag a path through the dirt
and that's where the
water is going to flow.
So you feel your finger
touching the glass.
You instantly get audio feedback
when you touch the screen.
You feel the friction
as you draw that path,
move your finger around.
And you instantly see
the path you drew.
So it's a game that
gets everything right.
Everything is in sync.
So let's take all this and
sort of distill it down
and summarize what
I mean by this.
So the key to what
all those games,
and others that are all doing,
is to design their controls
around direct interactions
reinforced
by instantaneous feedback.
So direct manipulation
is the key
to that interaction
model on iOS.
You've got to embrace the idea
that the best iOS games are
the ones where you reach
through the glass and touch the
game elements themselves, right.
So it's based on touches and
taps and gestures and swipes
and panning and drawing paths
where those interactions are the
ones that define the gameplay.
And then it's critical that you
provide instantaneous feedback.
So these are the visual cues and
audio cues so that what you see
and what you hear and what you
feel all reinforce what you did.
And they reinforce each other.
But, okay.
So, with all that passion,
that was designed for touch.
But if people seem to be
having a lot of trouble
with your controls, go
back to those principles
and really redesign your
Core Loop around the idea
of direct interactions
that are reinforced
by instantaneous feedback.
Okay, next is to
foster engagement.
So, you know, this about
keeping the player coming back
to your game.
And we use a lot of different
terms to describe this,
you know, it's a
huge, a huge area.
But all this is done because,
just hopefully, you know,
having a really deeply engaged
player is going to generate word
of mouth and viral discovery,
more business for you,
more of a fan base, and so on.
And there are a ton of
things to talk about here.
But, you know, and I'll get
to some specifics in a minute.
But I want to first say
something else that's a little
deeper about this.
So it's really easy for
any of us to, kind of,
get wrapped up in the
details of the Core Loop
and the onboarding and so on.
But it's important for you to be
able to rise above those details
of the game and really see the
game from the player perspective
and understand that the
design process here is
profoundly fractal.
The same patterns emerge
at every level of detail.
And there are resonances
among them.
So even if you get the
game loop completely right,
if you can't rise above
that, it won't resonate
with your meta game
or your progression.
If you get the progression right
but you can't rise above that,
it won't resonate with the
storyline, and so on and so on.
But, okay.
So now taking this down a notch,
back to Earth just a moment.
Do you remember how a couple
of moments ago I said that,
you know, a lot of really
interesting games overlay
multiple Core Loops?
Well, that holds true for
the progression as well.
And so one way that
you can really get,
hold the player's interest is
to provide layers of progression
or overlays of it, of
progression and expansion
with multiple goals, multiple
paths of goals, I mean,
multiple paths of challenges,
and different paths
giving different balance
between risk and reward.
That's something that players
will find very, very compelling.
And you can even gamify
the expansions themselves.
So this is, you know, kind
of the essence of a lot
of crafting games is that you
make the expansions themselves
into choices that the players
have to make that are strategic
to the future of their gameplay.
And then you ensure
that you take them
down different paths
depending on what they've done.
But, okay.
This next one now, so this
is particularly important
for anyone who's making
free to play games.
And that's to provide
value for everyone,
both your paying players
and your non-paying players.
So work through the
entire experience for both
of those audiences
to ensure that those
who are playing your game for
free can progress, can expand,
and, sure, they can
see the benefit.
Show them the benefit of
becoming a paying player.
But if you try to force them,
then you'll lose engagement
with a fair number of them.
And on the other side, ensure
that those who are paying
in your game will feel
that they're getting
properly rewarded in the game
and getting something for the
money that they're spending.
Then next, again, this is
holding the player's interest.
So really do what you can
to incentivize repeat play.
So enable and motivate the
player to try one more time.
Enable and motivate the
player to see what's next.
Enable and motivate to
see how it ends, right.
And if you think about
where these fit in,
"one more try" is
about the Core Loop.
"See what's next" is
about the progression.
"See how it ends" is about
the storyline, right.
Okay. Now, let me talk a
bit about re engagement.
So providing really,
you know, coming out
and providing really
fresh new content
after you've launched
is a great way
to keep your momentum
going and, in many cases,
even to help drive new growth.
So really think about how
you will continue your story
to provide new content or
new levels or new goals
or challenges, and so on.
Or seasonal content
around holidays.
Or regional content
in different locales.
It's all to give your players
another positive reason
to come back into the game.
And it's important that you
plan this out before you launch.
Because the people who have had
catastrophic success are the
ones who a game takes off
and then they realize
people are done.
And they need to scramble
to get more content out.
You're most engaged
players are going
to consume your content very
quickly; so have it ready.
Have it ready to go
so that your really,
deeply engaged players can
have something that's going
to bring them back
into the game.
And you'll attract new
players to come in as well.
Now, it's also important
to really measure
and understand how well
you're retaining your players.
And starting later this fall,
we'll be providing
retention information to you
through iTunes Connect.
So this is going to show you
how many players have downloaded
your game by day, by region,
by platform, by source
and what percentage of them
kept playing in the days
that followed their download.
And so this is just
a taste, okay.
So we'll show you a
lot more about this
in the iTunes Connect
session tomorrow morning.
But so that's number five:
to foster engagement.
So now, let me turn the
focus the other way and get
into a couple of things
on the technical side.
And so this is number six:
to use background transfers.
Huh? Okay.
So you remember back
in the first section
where I was talking
about friction,
I talked about downloading
updates,
and I said that that was
something that we could move
out of the player's way?
That's what this is about and
that's what I'll get into here.
So in "Paddle Mania
3000", we have, you know,
thousands of image
assets because we have
so many levels, right.
We have-and for all of
those different assets,
we have one for Retina,
non Retina, iPhone 5s,
the iPad, iPad Air, right.
And then we have
all of our sounds,
AAC and MP3 for our soundtrack.
We've got Linear PCM for
audio effects with OpenAL.
We've got 13 different
localizations, right.
So English, French, you
know, EFIGS, Japanese,
Traditional Chinese,
Simplified Chinese, Brazilian,
Portuguese, and a few more.
And then we have a binary
compiled three different,
you know, three ways:
armv7, armv7s, arm64.
Okay. So there's a lot of
stuff in "Paddle Mania 3000".
And you know putting all
that together is putting us
over the limit for
downloading over cellular.
So what do you do?
Well, you know, a lot of times,
a discussion will begin, and,
you know, quite often there
will be somebody who will chime
in with advice like this:
"One size fits all!"
Just ship one size.
Stretch it.
Stretch it to fit
on all platforms,
or just ship one localization.
They all speak English, right?
No, they really don't.
So don't sacrifice quality.
And don't shortchange
your global audience.
Realize that what you could
probably get your game
under 100 megabytes if you use
background transfers, you know,
and let the user download
the main bundle of it now
but have more content
that gets transferred
down after they've
run it the first time.
So there's a couple of
things to do this now.
So the first step really is
to take a good solid look
at your game and the
game design and determine
if there is some content
that isn't really
needed right up front.
And games, especially
games with any kind
of a linear progression are
perfect for this, right.
You put the first couple of
hours or whatever, you know,
the first 20, 30 levels in
the bundle at full quality.
And then that's going to
provide enough time for the user
to be playing, and then you
use background transfers
to download the rest while
their playing those first 20.
So how's this done?
Okay. So NSURLSession is an
API that we introduced back
in iOS 7, and the
use is to upload
and download data
from your own server.
And this is intended
for large data sets.
So game levels, big images,
sound files, texture atlases,
all that kind of thing, right.
Now, the transfer, itself,
happens outside of your process.
You just set it off.
You'll get notified
when it's completed.
The player can continue
or the app can even be,
you know, quit or terminated.
And the download is
going to keep on going.
And the app, if it's
running, will be notified,
or it'll be woken up when
the transfer is done.
And it's just enough so that you
can take the content that's been
downloaded and, kind
of, unpack it and put it
into its permanent location.
So it's really useful.
It does obviously, it adds
some complexity, right.
Because you're going to have
to handle some corner cases now
that you didn't have before,
like the player running
out of disk space or, you
know, reaching a level
that you haven't
successfully downloaded yet.
And it's important, also,
that you follow the iOS
Data Storage Guidelines.
So these will tell you exactly
where to put any
downloaded assets.
And also remember, this is about
assets, you know, new textures,
new levels, new sounds, and that
kind of thing, but not code.
If you're making code
changes, that has to go back
up through app review
as an update to the app.
But, okay, so that's number six:
to use background transfers.
And, you know, if you're going
to be targeting iOS 7 and above,
like now is the time, right,
because you can move cleanly
up to all of your supported
devices with NSURLSession.
Okay, number seven: optimize
graphics performance.
So, you know, I've
mentioned I meet
with developers all the time.
I probably met with some
of the people in this room.
And, you know, to give people
feedback on their games,
but one of the things that just
very, very honestly that I love
to do is to run their game
through our performance tools
and, kind of, use that to figure
out what optimizations they need
to make in OpenGL and so on.
It's kind of what I eat
for breakfast, right.
Now, so as I get into this
section, though, the first thing
to realize and to
say about it is
that optimizing graphics is
totally what Metal is all about.
But I'll get to Metal
in a second.
I want to talk first just
about optimizing the games
that are already out there.
So, you know, every game
is different, right,
and most of them are actually
pretty well optimized.
They're okay.
But in the games that are having
performance issues with OpenGL,
it's usually because for some
portion of the frame, at least,
or maybe all of the frame,
they're trying to do a lot
of draw calls with a
low number of triangles
to be processed in
each draw call.
And the worst case scenario
is actually fairly common.
I see it sometimes.
It's particularly in
2D and isometric games
that I'll find this sometimes.
Is that they're just,
they're in a loop
where they're binding a texture,
drawing a quad, and then repeat.
Bind; draw; bind;
draw; bind; draw.
And that's how they draw their
entire scene with one draw call
for every quad, one texture
bind for every draw call.
And, you know, for
OpenGL ES, there's just,
there's a fair amount of CPU
overhead that's involved here
in the validation and the
processing draw calls.
So, you know, the theory behind
this becomes very important
to optimize this.
It's super important that
those developers find a way
to amortize that overhead
over more triangles.
Now, this is something that
I can help any of you with,
and we have tons of people
in the lab this week.
So if you're falling into this
situation, we can help you.
But these 15 recommendations
that are up here cover most
of the cases that I run into.
This is the solutions that we
apply depending on the game,
depending on the structure, and
what they're doing in OpenGL.
But, and I'm not going to
go deep into any of these.
But, so, more broadly,
what you need to realize is
that optimizing graphics
performance is really
and primarily about identifying
the bottlenecks that you have
and then addressing them, taking
some action to address them.
Okay, so that lets me
talk about the tools.
You know, we have
these fantastic tools
that will help you
identify exactly
where your performance
bottlenecks are
and different bottlenecks
that might be happening.
So this is a screenshot from the
GPU performance graphs in Xcode.
And this, along with the
GPU frame debugger in Xcode
and the OpenGL ES
analyzer instrument,
are kind of the tools
of the trade
that you should familiarize
yourself with here.
So now let me zoom in.
So what you see here: Section
at the top you see this sort
of speedometer on the left up
at the top, the purple bars
with utilization in the
middle that's showing me my
GPU utilization.
And then over here on the
right, the frame time,
or how much time the CPU
is working on this frame,
and how much time the GPU
is working on this frame.
Now, in this particular
screenshot,
this is a little different
than what I was just talking
about with bind, draw,
bind, draw, bind, draw.
In this one, what it is, I can
see the renderer utilization is
at 100 percent and that's
pushing the device utilization
up to 100 percent.
And that is typically
a sign actually
of a very expensive
fragment shader.
Okay. And so down in the
bottom here, you can see,
a view here now where I can-it's
showing me the cost of every one
of my shaders that was
used in this frame.
And I can turn down
these disclosures
and see the specific draw
calls that use that shader
and how much each one
of them cost as well.
And, then, I can
also go and drill
down into a particular shader.
I'm not going to walk
you through all the UI.
But once you get to the
view where you're looking
that your shaders, if
I zoom that in again.
Okay. So what this
is showing me now,
look at on the right hand
side, these little bars.
This is taken live
from the device.
It's able to see the
performance data.
And it's going line by
line through the shader
to show you the performance
cost of each line.
And so here I see that,
okay, 59 percent of the cost
of this shader was going
into shadow projection.
And that's probably
something I can optimize.
I can use a lower resolution
shadow map or something.
Because, remember, this was
the most expensive shader
in the app.
And the renderer utilization
was at 100 percent.
So this is the bottleneck,
this shadow projection.
And so it's exactly
what, in this case,
needs to be optimized out.
But, so the point, though,
is that the tools can be used
to exactly pinpoint what's
going on in your app.
Now, you know, if you're
not familiar with the tool
or this isn't something that
you know your way around yet,
just come down to the labs.
We have so many people
down there who would love
to help you to suss this out.
But so, obviously, there's
an opportunity here, right,
for OpenGL ES-based games to
kind of use the tools, optimize
and get better performance.
But I also want to be
super clear, you know,
that seeing so many developers
struggle and face these kinds
of issues are a big part
of the reason why SpriteKit
and SceneKit were
developed, right.
Their purpose is to provide you
with the capabilities
that you need, right?
2D games with SpriteKit,
3D games with SceneKit.
Or now they can be
mixed together, right.
But the real key is that
once you're using them
and taking advantage
of their feature set,
they take on the burden of
rendering optimally in OpenGL.
And you don't have to
worry about it anymore.
And, if you think about it,
one more step, you know,
since Apple provides the
entire technology stack
from these APIs all the
way down to the hardware,
it means that everything can
be made very optimal in a way
that you don't have to work on.
And then, okay, speaking
of optimal, right.
Now there's Metal, right.
So this, this is for those
of you with games or engines
that need to push a
lot more draw calls.
And really allow your code
to have very efficient access
to the GPU to interleave
graphics and compute, and so on.
And really take control yourself
over how the frame
is being rendered.
So that is number seven:
optimize graphics performance.
Okay, number eight: now,
we're lifting out of the tech
in just a couple of
really kind of quick
and light bits of advice here.
This is a super quick one.
It's to make a great
gameplay video.
You know, so earlier
in the talk,
I talked about the importance
of making a really
great first impression.
But what I didn't
really get into then was
that from the user's
perspective,
your player's perspective,
all of that is going
to start on the App Store.
And, you know, as we talked
about yesterday, you know,
when people are really
coming on to the App Store,
they're looking for
something that's cool and new.
You know, they're going to be
looking for some way to kind
of understand what
your game is doing.
And you want to have something
that's going to stand out
and exactly explain it.
And so that they'll
be more confident
and more ready to get your game.
Okay. Now, as we talked
about a little bit yesterday,
so in iOS 8, OS X
Yosemite, you'll be able
to create these short
app previews
or game previews
to demo your game.
You should use this to show
how the game is played.
You know, use it.
Tell a story with
this and really appeal
to what makes the
gameplay so much fun.
You know, here's how it'll look
when it's on the App Store.
We showed this "Monument
Valley" example yesterday.
And how it works is just
the app preview just appears
as the first image there
along with the screenshot.
User taps on that, and they
can see this gameplay video.
But now some details about this.
Okay. So the app preview
needs to be, you know,
a video of your gameplay.
It's not intended to be an ad.
It should convey the real
experience of playing the game.
It can be up to 30 seconds long.
You provide it as an H.264,
you know, MPEG4 encoded file
that you upload into
iTunes Connect.
You can have, or you should
have a different video
for iPhone versus iPad.
And your content itself can
be captured directly off
of your iOS device and onto
your Mac that's running OS
X Yosemite.
The Mac just sees the iOS
device as a video camera.
And you start playing the game,
and you can capture it using
whatever tool you like:
Quicktime Player, and so on.
iMovie is where you
can do your editing.
And then just put it
all together and get it
up on iTunes Connect,
and you're ready to go.
And then this is really
just sort of one piece
of building a great App
Store presence, right.
So having a great icon,
compelling screenshots,
localizations, description,
your keywords, and so on.
Okay. So about app previews,
there's a whole session
on it that's also on
Thursday afternoon.
Check your schedule to see that.
And make a great video
that's going to show players
who are interested in your
game what the gameplay is
really like.
Okay. Number nine
is to localize.
You know the App Store
is a global business.
It's available in 155 countries
in 40 languages, right.
So this, this is an opportunity
that is just phenomenal
and you should think globally.
You know, you need to think
about the distribution
of your game as a
global opportunity.
Now, so the first thing
that you should do,
if you haven't already
done this,
is to localize your App
Store presence, right.
Just so that when a player in
some other region is coming in
and looking at your game,
it just stands to reason
that they'll be more
interested in it
if they can read the description
of these other things
in their native language, right.
So localize the name, the
description, the keywords,
the snapshots, and so on, right.
And then the second
piece of this, of course,
is to localize the
app content itself.
So by that I mean to really go
back and structure your game
for internationalization.
You'll need to do what
you can to separate text
from artwork and texture.
So you don't have to
make copies of big images
for every language
that you support.
And then go through your UI.
And, of course, right.
And translate the text into
all the different languages
that you want to support.
And then, finally, you
know, also, consider things
like whether your game is right
to provide some culturalized
content
where it would be appropriate.
For example, if it
was a driving game,
maybe you would use
local road signs
for different locales and so on.
Local license plates
from different locales.
So, now, here's a list
of some of the languages
that we've recommended before.
It's certainly not exhaustive.
It's a big list.
And it's a good place
to start though.
So first is EFIGS,
right: English, French,
Italian, German, Spanish.
Then many regions in Asia, so
Japanese, Korean, Traditional
and Simplified Chinese, and
then branches out from there.
So Brazilian, Portuguese,
Russian, Turkish,
and Arabic are what
we would recommend
that you really put
some focus into.
And there's a great
resource online:
developer.apple.com/
internationalization.
So this will take you step
by step through the process
of internationalizing and
localizing your app, your game.
And it gives you some links to
third party localization vendors
if you don't have that
expertise in-house.
But, so that is number
nine: to localize.
And so number 10: to
target the state of the art.
So if you think about some of
the best games that are on iOS,
you know, a real common
thread, as we've been saying,
is how they consistently
aim high
and consistently target
the latest and greatest
to differentiate
themselves on our devices.
So to be state-of-the-art
means really taking advantage
of the capabilities
of the latest hardware
like the A7, right.
And target the feature
set of those devices
so that you stand out.
I mean, you guys, you saw
those demos yesterday, right,
during the "Keynote",
the "State of the Union".
They were on this hardware.
You know, you've
seen what it can do.
So take advantage
of that, that power,
that capability that's there.
Then hand in hand with
that, is that state
of the art apps support
the latest versions of iOS.
And I think that this week
should be that turning point
for you where it's time now for
you to realign your projects
to aim for the release of iOS 8
and the APIs and the frameworks
that you'll be learning
about all this week.
And then bring your
minimum OS up to iOS 7.
That is our recommendation.
Support the latest
N and N minus 1.
So when iOS 8 is released,
you'll probably want
to be looking at 7 and 8.
Okay. Now something, you know,
something that we do hear
from developers, actually more
often than you might think,
is that they're telling us
that they'll, they're deciding
to stick with an older version
of Xcode or an older SDK
because they think that if
they move up to what's latest,
they won't be able
to still ship a game
that supports anything
older than that.
But obviously that's
not the case.
So you can adopt the latest SDK
version by setting your base SDK
to what is current and then
setting your deployment target
down to the lowest OS version
that you want to support
and dropping support
for the rest.
And then handle differences
between 7 and 8 in your code.
You know, check for
the existence
of hardware capabilities.
Or check whether
classes are defined.
Or check whether classes respond
to a particular selector
and so on.
Now for those of you who
are coming over to iOS
and are just not as
familiar with that process,
we actually went through
it all in pretty good depth
when we went out for our iOS
7 Tech Talks last November,
December.
And so those videos are online
on our developer website.
So you should check them out.
Then also, state of the
art games are the ones
that integrate with our
built in game technologies
as Geoff talked about.
So we're providing just this
incredible foundation for you.
It's built on a lot of different
APIs, you know, like SpriteKit,
Game Center, OpenGL, and
Game Controllers and so on.
And then the new APIs, like
Metal and SceneKit on iOS.
Right. And these are just
a few of the technologies.
You know this.
But the point I want to make
is about the other things.
You know, the tools and the
APIs that are available to you
as game developers is
comprehensive on iOS.
And you should learn
the entire stack.
Oh, my god, that's a
lot of learning to do.
But really what I mean is
to familiarize yourself
with the technologies
that are on iOS rather
than just taking a project
that you were working on,
maybe on another platform
or on an older OS version,
and just shifting that over and
fitting it into the equivalent.
Your target should be to go
for the latest and greatest.
Target the top, target the
state of the art, target the A7,
target iOS 8 and its
capabilities, right,
rather than just coming
over and just fitting
in with something that's older.
But, so that's number 10:
target the state of the art.
But before I finish, I
do have one more thing
that I want to talk about.
So you know let's say that
you've done all 10 of these.
You've fixed your onboarding,
you tuned up your Core Loop,
you're optimized,
you're localized,
you're state-of-the-art,
etc., all 10.
So where do you go from here?
Yeah, well, go to 11.
Really, give it that extra push.
Go the extra mile.
Because here is my
observation about this,
you know: We keep innovating.
We keep enhancing our
game technologies.
And we have this
thriving ecosystem, right,
where we're investing.
We're adding performance,
and we're adding capability.
You guys, you can't stand still.
Keep inventing.
Keep learning.
Keep current.
Get started on that next update
for iOS 8, and keep up with us
because we love to shine
the spotlight on developers
who can go one louder.
All right.
So thank you, everyone.
That is my list.
[ Applause ]
And just to wrap things up,
I'd like to pass the stage back
to Geoff for just a moment.
So thank you.
>> Thank you, Allan.
So thank you very much, Allan.
And I think, when I step
back and look at this,
we see a tremendous
amount of games.
You look around the room;
there's a lot of you
who are interested
in building games.
And there's a large number
of games in the App Store.
We're talking about how you
can make your game stand out.
It isn't good enough to
just go, "Oh, I'm going to.
I have a great idea.
It's a cool game.
I'm going to toss it up onto the
App Store and see what happens."
It is a very big pond, so
use what Allan has told you.
Use these 10 steps,
and use the 11th step.
And really make your game shine.
These are the things which may
not be apparent when you look
at it, it may not be
apparent when you look
at the Design Awards Winners
that they do these things.
But they really do, they
spend a lot of time.
"Cut the Rope" was
a great example.
Spent a lot of time on
going through with people
who haven't played the
game before and say, "Hey,
when you approach the game
what do you need to know?"
It's not just like that
came to them in an hour.
So take the time with your game.
Take the time to
go that extra mile.
Take the time to adopt
these 10 items and the 11th
and really bring your
content up so it stands out.
And we really hope to
see someone in this room
or many people in this
room on stage next year
at the Apple Design Awards.
Thank you very much
and enjoy the week.