>> Hello. Welcome to
the Advanced Session
on Working with Metal.
My name is Gokhan Avkarogullari.
My colleagues, Aaftab
Munshi and Serhat Tekin,
and I will be presenting
this session.
This is the third session that
we have about Metal today.
In the first session, Jeremy
introduced Metal to us.
He talked about the motivation
behind Metal, the structures
that we build the Metal on,
and concluded it with a demo
from Crytek on collectibles
with thousands of draw calls.
We followed up with the
second session where we talked
about fundamentals of Metal.
We talked about creating your
first application with Metal,
drawing an animated triangle
on the screen, and followed it
up with the details about
the shading language.
In this session, we're going
to do a more deeper dive
into creating a full blown
graphics application with Metal.
We'll follow it up with
data-parallel computing
on the GPU using Metal and
finally, we'll have a demo
of the developer tools
that we build from Metal.
Ok, so let's talk about
why multi-pass applications
are relevant.
The modern graphics applications
are very complicated pieces
of software.
They're built on using
many, many advanced graphics
and computer algorithms and they
do them in a piecewise manner.
Basically they're built on many,
many hundreds of texture passes
and compute passes
and blip passes
to generate a final great
looking image on the screen.
So we're going to go and
talk about a little bit how
to do that using Metal.
We will talk about multiple
frame buffer configurations,
rendering to off-screen and
on-screen textures, using meshes
and different things
with different states
and in different configurations,
and how to set up
multiple encoders.
We'll use a deferred lighting
with a shadow map example
to basically walk through
these code examples.
This is a two-pass
application that we built
for this particular
presentation.
In the first pass, we
have a shadow map pass
where we rendered the
scene from the perspective
of the directional
light to a depth buffer.
And in the second pass we set
up a G-buffer, fat G-buffer,
through multiple render targets.
We generate attributes
in that G-buffer
and we apply the point light
volumes onto that G-buffer
to find out which
pixels are affected.
And finally, using
the framebuffer fetch,
create light accumulation
information and then merge
with the albedo textures
to generate a final image.
Having said that, we're
not really interested
in describing the example in
here; it's just a vehicle for us
to basically talk
about the APIs.
On top of that, the example
is actually published
as a sample code on
the developer website
so you can go ahead and
download it and take a look
at it later if you
would like to.
The way the example
is structured is
that it has two passes.
Both of them are
RenderCommandEncoder passes.
The first one is for shadow
map and the second one is
for the deferred lighting pass.
They're all encoded
into a single buffer
which is...and the
single command buffer goes
into a command queue.
So this is kind of what most
applications will look like;
multiple render texture passes
going into a command encoder
on a frame boundary that's
sent to the command queue.
I'll give a demo
of the application.
[ Pause ]
Ok, I have it here.
So this is the upload
of the first pass
where we are rendering
basically through that buffer
from the perspective of
the directional light.
And this is how our
G-buffer is laid out.
On the top left we normally
have albedo texture,
but we're showing basically the
combined image that is going
to go to the screen
when we're actually done
with our entire rendering.
And there's a normal
buffer, and a depth buffer,
and a light accumulation buffer,
four-color buffers basically
attached to a framebuffer
and depth and stencil
buffers as well.
This is the light accumulation;
there's also the light
accumulation pass.
And these are the visualization
of the lights basically
using light volumes.
They're mapped onto the screen.
And finally this is the final
image that goes to the display.
It looks a lot better on the
device than on the presentation.
Ok, let's go back
to our presentation.
Ok, so how do we set up
an application like this
or more complicated
ones that you have seen
in the demos using Metal?
Just like Jeremy talked about
in the first session and looked
at the things that...at what
frequency things are done
and moved the most heavy ones
to the least frequently
done stages.
An application has a lot of
things that are done once
and there are things that
are done at low-level times
or streaming time, and there
are things done every frame
and in an application
there are also things
that are render to textures.
So we're going to look at
each category and figure
out what is done in these
categories and figure out how
to do those with Metal.
Let's start with the
things that are done once.
Creating a device.
They are the only ones you queue
on the system so you're going
to get a GPU and are
handled through the GPU,
and creating a command queue
on the GPU is only done once
in most of the applications.
And Richard told you something
about this; I'm not going
to talk about that
in this session.
There are things
we do as needed.
For example, we know
up front in all
of our applications
what our render
to texture stages will be.
There are usually a set of
render to texture passes,
that are known up front for
like an indoor environment
or an outdoor environment and
they might change if there's
like wetnesses included
or something like that
but most of them are up front.
You know as an application
developer what your render
to texture passes will be,
in what order they're going
to be done, and what kind of
framebuffers that are going
to be used with those.
So we can actually
define...create the framebuffer
textures for those passes
and define what those
textures are going to look
like up front at once.
And at level load time,
we can download our assets
including our meshes, textures
and then basically our shaders
and associate with those shaders
to create pipeline objects,
and the pipeline objects.
And of course we can
create our uniform buffers
up front as well.
These are the things that we
do either at level load time
at once or depending on if we're
going to stream load or not,
at other times as well
but only as needed.
In our example, we're using
a single command buffer
to submit a set of
render to texture passes
to basically have the results
of our render to texture passes
to show up on the screen
so that's basically a
frame boundary operation.
Every time you want to have
something to go to the screen,
we're going to basically create
a command buffer and use it
to encode our render
to texture passes
so this is something
we do every frame.
Of course there are uniform
buffers that need to be updated
on frame boundaries; that's
where you do it as well.
And finally the things we do
every render to texture pass
such as encoding the command
so that GPU can understand.
Setting up the states
and resources,
and initiating draw calls.
And then finally,
finishing the encoding
so you can go to
the next encoder.
So these are the things we do
every render to texture pass
and we're going to basically
look at each one of them
and understand how Metal is
used to do these operations.
Ok, let's start with the
things that we do as needed
and understand how we can setup
information for our render
to texture passes
up front so that
when we create our
encoders; all the information
that is necessary for
that encoding is ready.
But before we go there, I'd
like to speak a little bit
about descriptors because all
of the code examples have lots
of descriptors and I'd
like to establish that all
of the descriptor...that all
of the descriptors are
defining how an object is going
to be created.
It's like the blueprint and just
like the blueprints
you basically use
to build a house from,
once a house is built,
you don't have actually
a connection back
to the blueprint.
You cannot change the blueprint
and see in fact a change
on an already built house.
You cannot change a
descriptor and expect a change
to the built object
from that descriptor.
Descriptors are there to define
what objects are going to be,
but once they're created,
the connection is lost.
But just like a blueprint as
well, a descriptor can be used
to create more instances
of the same kind of object
or they can modify it a little
bit to create a different kind
of object that shares
some of the personality
of the previous object.
And as Jeremy pointed out
before, everything except
for a few states
that you can set
on the render encoders
are actually built
into the state objects
and the resources
and they are immutable, which
gives us the opportunity acutely
to avoid the state
validation at the draw time.
So a descriptor built an
object and pretty much
that object is immutable
after that point.
That basically makes the
Metal a lower overhead API
by avoiding all the state
tracking, all the state changes,
and reflecting them
at the draw time.
Ok, let's go back
to our framebuffer
configuration,
how we set up that.
Ok, so for
RenderCommandEncoders,
we need to know about the
nature of the framebuffer,
like how many color
detections there are,
what kind of pixel types
there are, the depth
and stencil attachment;
things of that sort.
And those are defined through
a RenderPassDescriptor.
We are allowed up to four color
attachments that are allowed
on Metal and we can
attach a depth
and stencil buffer as well.
And the attachments
themselves are also described
to in other descriptor
that's embedded
into the RenderPassDescriptor,
which is
RenderPassAttachmentDescriptor.
In this descriptor, we basically
define what kind of load
and store actions clear
values and what kind of slice
or mid-level that we're
going to render into;
all of these are
basically defined here.
And it also points to the
texture that we're going
to use to render into.
So this pass descriptor
basically has all
the information
necessary
for a RenderCommandEncoder
to get going.
And we're going to look at
the two passes that we have;
the shadow pass and the deferred
lighting pass in our example
and build render pass
descriptors for those.
So let's start with
the shadowRenderPass.
In this case we only
have a depth buffer;
we don't have any color buffers
attached because all we want is
to create a shadow map
buffer that we can use later
to basically see if a
pixel is all clear or not.
So we're going to start with
creating the texture for that
and what we have in here is
basically a 1k by 1k texture
with no mipmapping, a
depth for 32 texture.
It is created on the device as
we talked extensively before.
There's no concept of context or
shared groups like GL on Metal.
Every resource is created on
the device, they are visible
by the GPU, and also you can
independently modify them,
not the objects themselves,
but like the texture data
or the buffer data, read that in
a requirement of bind to modify.
You can modify them any time you
want as long as you're careful
that they are not modified
while the GPU is accessing them
and as long as you make sure
that memory coincident rules
at the command buffer
boundaries is followed.
After we have our texture,
we can create our
render pass descriptor.
We're going to assign this
texture to the depth detector
of render pass descriptor
because it has only
a single attachment.
And then define the properties
such as the clear value,
load and store actions.
We talked extensively about
load and store actions before.
They're very important
in terms of performance
so you should really
pay attention
to setting them correctly
and most
of the time the default values
are the most sensible values.
Ok, let's go to our second pass.
We need to also create a
descriptor for our second pass;
we're going to actually do the
second render command encoding.
That information will
be available up front.
Those textures are created
up front so we don't have
to pay the penalty of doing
those at the draw time.
In this example, we
have four color buffers,
one of them is actually
interesting;
the one on the top left.
It is a buffer that we're going
to render into and then go
and send it to the display.
So that texture we cannot create
up front; we need to get it
from the Metal layer,
the CAMetal layer.
And we talked extensively about
this in the second session.
Richard basically had a sample
code showing how we can get
that texture from
the Metal layer.
The other three color
textures though and the depth
and stencil texture are
things that we know up front.
They are structures and we
can create them up front
and we don't have
to do them later
so let's go ahead and do that.
Ok, we're going to start again
with a texture descriptor
to define how our texture
is going to look like.
In this example I'm
going to create only two
of the color textures
and then the rest
of them are very similar.
So we basically need to create
something that has a width
and height of the
displayable surface
and there is no mapping
required.
So we create our first
texture using this descriptor,
texture descriptor.
Now as I said before,
the descriptors are kind
of blueprints so we can
actually use the same descriptor
and create the second
texture out of that as well.
This is what we're going
to do as well in here.
Basically we modify
the descriptor
to change the pixel format and
everything like width, height,
the mipmapping properties were
the same so we didn't have
to modify those, and then create
the second texture with that.
So you can see that we basically
have one descriptor creating two
different textures.
So now that...and
we're going to do this
for the third color
attachment, depth and stencil.
Now that we have done all
of those, we can go ahead
and create our
RenderPassDescriptor
so that we can use it later to
create our RenderCommandEncoder.
We first create it.
What is interesting in
here as I explained before:
the first color attachment we
actually don't have a texture
up front ready for it.
We'll have it when we actually
start setting up our frame.
So it's set to "no" initially
and eventually we'll get it
from the drawable when we
create our RenderCommandEncoder.
But despite not having
a texture,
we know actually
the actions up front
so we can define the clear
value, load and store actions
on the attachment
descriptor up front.
And we can go ahead and do it
for the second color attachment.
As you can see in this one, I
used the texture that we created
in the previous slide
as an attachment.
And we can also define
the clear value,
load and store actions
up front over here.
I'd like to point
out the difference
between the store
actions between these two;
for the first buffer
attachment, we'd like it to end
up on the screen so we'd like
it to be stored into the memory.
But the second, third, and
fourth, color attachments,
depth and stencil buffers,
they can be discarded;
they're just intermediate
values that we used
to generate the first
attachment's values.
So we don't really need to store
them into memory; we don't want
to lose memory bandwidth
and GP cycles
for that expensive operation
so we set them as "don't care"
and let the driver figure out
the best kind of operation
for the particular GP
that you're working on.
Ok, so that covers how we
create render pass descriptors
that we want and the textures
associated with the framebuffers
that we are going to use later
for creating render
command encoders
when we do render
to texture passes.
Let's look at now the textures,
buffers, and state objects,
and specifically the pipeline
state objects that we're going
to create at level load
time so that we don't have
to basically deal
with them later.
We've already seen
how to create textures
from texture descriptors;
I am not going
to go into details of that.
I just want to point out
that there are multiple ways
to upload data into
your texture.
This is one of them:
basically a CPU copy.
And you can also use
boot command encoder
to upload data inline through
the GPU to do that as well.
We talked about buffers before.
We don't have a concept
of a vertex buffer
or a uniform buffer.
Buffers are buffers;
they are raw data.
You can create them
for anything you want
and then reach them...you
know, access them through a GPU
in your shaders when you
specify them as inputs.
All we're doing here is creating
one with the information about,
you know, the size
and the options.
And as I said before, you can
modify these really easily while
your GPU is working on,
for example another section
of your buffer, you can
modify this section of buffer.
You need to take care of the
synchronization and you need
to follow the memory coincident
rules, but you don't have
to do anything like locking the
buffer or getting the pointer
to do...both pointers are
always available to you.
You have the freedom to modify
however you want whenever you
want and as long as you
basically pay attention to GPU
and CPU synchronization
issues, it will work correctly.
And finally one other example
of a depth stencil state,
I showed this one; I don't have
much to say about it except
that it is an interesting one
that it has an embedded
descriptor, internal descriptor.
Basically that stencil
descriptor has a stencil
descriptor defined within it.
But you can create all of your
depth stencil states up front
because just like you know
your render to texture state,
you actually know how
your objects are going
to be rendered into
those textures.
You know that, for example
in the shadow map pass,
you don't really need to
write into stencil buffer,
so you can basically say
that information here
or you don't use that.
Or when you have
something that is opaque,
you can basically
update the depth buffer,
but if you're going to do
something that is blended
for example, you might choose
to not update the depth buffer
and then you can actually, if
you know all the sates up front,
you can actually
create them up front
and don't pay the penalty
during the draw time.
Ok so we're going to talk
about next the render
pipeline state objects
but before we go there, I'd
like to revisit the kind
of the OpenGL view of the GPU.
And then go and basically talk
about what's the motivation
of RenderPipelineState objects
and what is included in them.
So this is kind of how it
looks to basically, in general,
OpenGL, but there's actually
a separate vertex shader state
and a fragment shader state
and all the other operations
that are all that looks
like fixed function
hardware-controlled
through basically
state-changing APIs.
Unfortunately the modern
hardware doesn't really work
that way.
If you think about
it, for example,
when your vertex layout
doesn't match your vertex shader
because they're separate,
the meshes are all
altered separately
than your vertex shaders,
there has to be some
code running somewhere;
either a de-imaging code or
a vertex fetch shader code
that needs to bridge that gap
between these 2 layout
differences.
Or in some GPUs we have
tile-based deferred render
so most of the frame
buffer actually is
on the GPU while you're
working on it, so the blending
or write mask is
basically a read, modify,
write operation on the tile.
And we do that by creating
actually a shader code running
on the shader core;
it's not really a state.
So when you actually make a
draw call with one blending mode
for compiled shaders and
then change your blend state
and make another draw call
with the same compiled shaders.
Well we find out
that we actually have
to generate new code for this
new framebuffer configuration
because we have never seen
it before and we're going
to do this fixed-function
looking-like operation
in the shader core and we end
up recompiling your
shader causing a hitch
in your application.
So recognizing the differences
between how the API looks
on OpenGL and how
actually a GPU behaves,
we decided to basically
put everything in the GPU
that closes shader code and has
an impact on the shader code
in one place that's called
"render pipeline state object."
So let's look at
what we have in it.
We basically have the vertex
fetch basically information
about your vertex layout
that we talked about before.
I actually gave a
good example of it.
Aaftab gave a good example of
it in his talk about language.
Obviously, we have the
shaders included in it.
We have
framebuffer configurations like
number of the rendered targets,
the pixel format, sample count,
write mask, blend information,
actually, and depth
and stencil state.
Now we didn't go all the
way to including everything
in the GPU state in the
render pipeline state object
because if we had done that,
you would be creating millions
and millions of them
and actually there would
be only a few unique ones
of these around.
So basically anything that
is...that can easily be updated
or that's really truly fixed
function hardware is not
in the render pipeline state
object such as the inputs.
We need to know the layout
of the buffer for example,
but we don't really need to know
which particular
buffer you're using.
It's really easy to
update the pointer pointing
to the buffer and the hardware.
The same goes true
for buffers as outputs
or the framebuffer textures.
We need to know how they're
configured, but we don't need
to know specifically which
ones are used at any time.
Or the primitive setup
states like the cull mode,
facing orientation, or
information like viewport
and scissor information, depth
bias and clamp and slope.
So those are not included
in your render pipeline
state objects, but everything
that affects your
cost is included
in your pipeline state object
so everything you
create is explicit
and everything you create is
basically you pay the cost
up front.
There are no hidden codes,
there are no deferred
state validation,
no later compilation in Metal.
So what you do, you know
you do it, you're doing it,
why you're doing it, and
the cost is paid up front
when you are actually doing it.
So let's go and create
a few of those.
Basically there's a render
pipeline sate object associated
with every draw call.
And in our example, for example
under rendering the mesh,
the mesh for the temple, we're
going to render it twice;
one we're creating the depth
buffer for the shadowMap
and then one; we are
basically doing light
accumulation...deferred
lighting pass.
So we're going to create two of
them; I'm going to give examples
of how to create them.
We create a new one,
a descriptor.
As we talked before,
you hopefully basically
compiled your shaders on Xcode
on the host-side or in
a library so we can go
and get your vertex
shader from the library.
And now I'm basically setting
the rest of the sates here;
basically we're setting
the vertex function,
we're setting depthWriteEnabled
to "true"
because you actually want
to update that buffer.
Interestingly since there's
no color buffer attached,
you can set your
fragment shader to "no."
There is not really going
to be a fragment
shader operation going
on for this configuration
for this drawing.
And once you have
that information,
you can use that descriptor
to create our render pipeline
state object for our temple mesh
for our shadowMap pass.
Let's do the same thing for
the deferred lighting pass.
Well the deferred lighting
pass is a little bit more rich
in terms of the stream buffer
configuration and terms
of the actions that
are taking place.
So we're going to have both
the vertex and fragment shader
and we're going to
define the pixel formats
for all attachments.
So we have now basically defined
our render pass descriptors.
We created our buffers
for meshes, for uniforms;
we created our textures
and uploaded them;
we created our render pipeline
state objects.Well I think we
can now get into the business
of drawing things on the screen.
So...well Richard
did a great job
in explaining how the command
buffers are formed and used,
so I'm going to, you know, visit
it for just a bit to remind you.
So we have a single command
queue that is our channel
to the GPU and we
get a commandBuffer
from the commandQueue
and that's how we do it:
ask the commandQueue to give
us a new command buffer.
And then once we basically go
ahead and encode all our render
to texture passes, we're
going to be ready to send it
to the GPU so that's how we do
it, by issuing a commit call.
And then finally,
commandBuffers are not reused.
Once they're used, we get rid
of them and then the next step,
next frame, we're going to get
a new one so we set it to "new"
and that takes care of it.
One thing I like to point
out just as Richard did
in the previous session: if
you like to get the results
of your command buffer's
operations to show
up on the screen, you need
to schedule the operation before
committing your command buffer
so that you basically call
the addPresent API to schedule
that so when the command
buffer is executed by the GPU,
the display will
basically know about it
and it will show your
image on the display.
Ok, now is an exciting part:
creating the command encoders
and actually encoding stuff.
Well, it is exciting, but
there's actually not much left
to do at this point because you
have done everything up front.
So all we're going to
do is create an encoder
from the commandBuffer
this time.
There can only be one
command encoder active
at any time on a commandBuffer.
There's one exception to this:
this is a parallel
RenderCommandEncoder.
I'd like you to take a look
at the programming guide
to understand when it's used.
It's mostly when you have a
huge render to texture pass
and you want to basically
paralyze operations
on multiple CPUs; that's
the only time you're going
to use it.
But for most applications, there
will be one render encoder,
RenderCommandEncoder or
a blip command encoder
or a compute command
encoder active at any time.
So we created one in here;
it's a RenderCommandEncoder
for our shadowMap pass
and we create it using the
shadowMap pass descriptor
that we created just
a few minutes ago.
It has all the information
about the depth attachment
and the structure of the depth
attachment and how it's defined
and all the information
necessary
for creating this encoder.
And then what we do
is just set the sates;
they're all baked before so we
don't have to validate them.
And we set the buffers as inputs
for texture samples as inputs
to our draw calls, and then
finally issue our draw calls.
And then repeat this hopefully
thousands and thousands of times
and in each one you will
basically be using a different
kind of state.
But the driver will be able to
just go ahead and fetch them
from a pre-baked place instead
of creating them on the fly
or validating them on the fly,
which makes Metal significantly
faster than the alternative app.
And once you're done,
you finish your encoding
by calling end encoding.
And at this point, the
commands are just created
in the command buffer,
but they're not really
submitted to the GPU.
They cannot be executed on the
GPU yet because that's only done
when you submit your
command buffer,
not when you finish
your encoding.
Let's go create the
encoding for the second pass
because it has an
interesting feature
that we couldn't finish
completing our vendor pass
descriptor early enough because
we didn't have the texture
for our drawable at that point.
So just in the previous session
if you saw that how we can get
that texture, if you
remember doing that,
and then assigning it our
first color attachment
to the texture point of
our first color attachment.
The rest of the descriptor
was well defined before;
we knew what textures to use
and how many textures there were
and so we don't actually
need to modify that part.
We're just going to
basically update this part
of the descriptor and
are going to use that one
to create our
RenderCommandEncoder
for our deferred lighting pass.
We do the usual, just issue
draw calls and finally end
up finishing our draw calls
and closing our encoder
by "End encoding".
And at this point for this
particular application
since you have only two passes,
we just call the command
buffer commit and it will go
to the GPU, and the GPU will
start executing the commands we
encoded just now.
Ok, so that's all I
wanted to talk about;
how to structure your
application to take advantage
of Metal and we're going
to go into a really,
really interesting and new
feature that we have on iOS:
data-parallel computing
on the GPU with Metal
so Aaftab will talk about that.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
>> Thanks Gokhan.
All right, I'm back.
All right, so I have
15 minutes to talk
about data-parallel
computing so I want to focus
on the key points I
wanted to get across.
So we'll first talk about...and
give a very high level overview
of what is data-parallel
computing,
how Metal does data-parallel
computing, and then we'll look
at how to write kernels in
metal and how to execute them.
And we'll actually
take an example,
a post-processing example,
and show how you do that.
All right, so let's start.
So what is data-parallel
computing?
So imagine if you have a piece
of code, let's say a function,
that we can execute all elements
of your data; so maybe elements
in an array or pixels
of an image.
And these computations are
independent to each other.
So that means if I have,
you know, multiple threads
of execution, I can run
them all in parallel
so that's what I mean by
data-parallel computing.
So this is actually
a very simple form
of data-parallel computing and
I'll talk a little bit more
about additional things
you can do in Metal
with data-parallel computing.
So a classic example of this
data-parallel computing is
blurring an image, right?
So for example you
have an image.
For each pixel you're
looking at a nearby region
and you are applying a filter.
Well, I could execute
these in parallel.
So if I had let's
say a 1k by 1k image
and I had a million threads,
I could execute each
pixel in parallel, right?
So how does that work in Metal?
So the code that you're
going to execute in parallel,
we call that a kernel.
And the thing that actually
executes independently,
we call that a work-item.
So on a GPU, a thread may
actually contain multiple
work-items because now a thread
actually may execute multiple
such things in a SIMD fashion
and then you have
multiple threads.
So the work-item is the thing
that identifies each
independent execution instance.
So you're going stop me
right there and say, "Hey,
that looks just like a
fragment shader," right?
Because that's what
fragment shaders do, right?
You execute the shader
in parallel
or multiple fragments; they
don't talk to each other.
Like they are in
their own world.
They take inputs;
produce outputs.
So what is this
data-parallelism?
So that is indeed; we
call it SIMD parallelism
and that is a data-parallelism
model supported in Metal.
And the only benefit here
is that you no longer have
to create a graphics pipeline;
you don't specify a vertex
shader and a fragment shader
and state and things like that.
You just say, "Here
is my function,
here is my problem size,
go execute this function
over there."
But there's more to it than that
because, in data-parallelism,
you can actually tell
a number of algorithms
where you actually
want these work-items
to communicate with each other.
Let's take an example;
let's say I want to --
a very simple example -- I want
to sum elements of an array.
It's referred to as a
classic problem of reduction.
So in that case, you now we
have these work-items generating
partial results and
you keep looking
over until you finally have
you know two partial sums
and then you get the final sum.
But in order to make this
work, these work-items need
to know the results generated by
other work-items, so they need
to be able to talk and you
know talk is always good.
So what you can do in
Metal is you can say, "Hey,
these work-items, they
work together," ok?
And we call that a work-group.
And these work-items
in the work-group can
actually share data
through what we call
local memory.
Remember we talked in the
previous session about global
and constant and
so, for kernels,
you get an additional
high-bandwidth,
low-latency memory we
call "local memory."
Think of it just as
a user-managed cache.
that's all it is.
And then they can
synchronize because now
when these threads want...or
work-items want to communicate,
they need to make sure they
arrive at a place together
so they can exchange data.
So you get all of that with
data-parallelism in Metal.
So let's...
Ok? So I wrote my code
that can do all of this,
but how do I describe
my problem?
So the thing is we called it a
computation domain so depending
on what thing you're going to
execute this function over,
if it's an array, your
problem is one-dimensional.
If it's an image, your
problem is two-dimensional.
So I've specified
the dimensions,
but what else do
I need to specify?
Well, now I need to tell
you how many work items are
in my work-group and then how
many work-groups do I have?
So that describes the
number of work-items
in the work-group times
the number of work-groups
that describes the total problem
that will be executed
in parallel.
So choose the dimensions that
are best for your algorithm.
So if you're doing
an image processing,
a post-processing effect,
you know you're going
to operate on textures.
Use 2D. Yeah, you could do it
in 1D, but who wants to do all
that work to turn that 2D to 1D?
And you shouldn't have to.
And the work-items you
have in your work-group,
how many they are,
it's going to depend
on the algorithm you're using.
It's going to depend on how many
load store operations you're
doing and how much
computations: a ratio of memory
to computations and
so play with that.
Choose the right dimensions.
You have the flexibility
because you can specify these.
All right, so let's
take an example.
We'll look at how to take
pseudo-code C, C++ code,
and make it into shaders.
We'll look at how we do that
for calls and we're going
to take a really,
really simple example.
So this function takes an
input, squares the result
for each element,
and writes it out.
And remember ah,
it has the...the
function is not complete.
So we include the standard
library just like we did
for shaders and we use
the Metal namespace.
So remember, we're going
to execute this function
for each index in
parallel, but first,
I need to tell the compiler that
this is a data-parallel function
so that's what the
kernel is going
to do; that's the qualifier.
All right, I'm passing
pointers so I need
to specify these buffers, what
indices they're going to be in
and that they're in the
global address space.
Remember we talked
in the previous session
about address spaces?
So these are coming in
global and then I need
to tell the compiler that
this ID to I'm going to use
to index is unique for each
instance and so in this case,
I call that a "global ID," ok?
So we have a vertex
ID and compute.
You have global IDs, ok?
So pretty simple,
pretty straightforward.
Well, let's say if
I'm using textures,
how would I write a kernel?
So let's say I'm trying to just
mirror an image horizontally,
so this was my image and I
want to...remember what I said,
"Use the right dimensions?"
So since I'm operating
on an image,
I really want my global ID to
be two-dimensional in nature
and that's what I'm doing here.
And I want to read
from my input texture
after I have mirrored
the coordinate
and then I want to write it out.
So you're going to
find writing kernels,
just like writing
shaders, it's really easy.
Its C++ code; it's
standard with information
so that a compiler knows
what you are trying to do.
Ok, remember we talked
about built-in variables?
You had a special attribute
to say position, front-facing,
and things like that
for graphics?
Well, we have something
similar for kernels too.
Well, global ID; you guys
already know it is now, right?
So in this case, my example, I'm
actually using...I'm operating
on a texture so my global
ID is two-dimensional.
So it can be a ushort2 or uint2
so use the right
dimensions you want.
Now so that's great if I'm
only operating on textures
in my kernel, but what if
I'm passing in buffers too?
So when I access my texture,
I'm going to use my
two-dimensional global ID,
but if I access a buffer, I need
to create a one-dimensional ID.
So we're trying to help you
not have to write all that code
because there may be bugs;
we fixed that for you.
So that's the global linear ID.
So now remember we said,
"Work-items work
in a work-group?"
So within that work-group,
I need to know which
instance I am.
So I have global ID; we
call this the "local id."
And just like you can have
a two-dimensional local ID,
there's also a one-dimensional.
We call that that the
"local linear ID."
So you just specify these
attributes for the arguments
to your kernel function and
the compiler will generate the
right code.
And finally we call this
the "work-group ID."
And so why do I care about this?
Well, remember you specify
the number of work-items
in the work-group and
number of work-groups?
So let's take...for an example,
I'm generating a histogram.
So each work-group...one way you
could do this is each work-group
could generate a partial
histogram, so a histogram
for the things it's working on.
And then you will
run another kernel
that could sum these
partial histograms
and generate a final histogram.
Well, so that means I
need to write the results
of these partial histograms
to some buffer, right?
Well I don't want to create
a buffer for each work-group
so I just want to
allocate one buffer
so guess what index
would I use to write?
That would be my work-group ID
so that's how you
would use it, ok?
All right, so let's see
how to execute kernels.
What commands do I
encode to send work
to the GPU to execute a kernel?
And we're going to take
a post-processing example
so this is going to do
some highlights, shadows,
vignette effects
and things like that
and I'll actually demo
that for you guys.
So let's look at the source.
I'm not going to give the
details of the source;
just give a very high-level
picture of what's happening.
So it takes a number of
images and some information.
It's going to take the
global ID and transform
that using some matrix;
an affine matrix.
It's going to sample
from an image
and then apply a
post-processing effect,
and then write to an image, ok?
And then you're going
to say, "That looks just
like a fragment shader."
Well in this case, yes it does.
But remember, the number
of work-items times number
of work-groups make up the total
problem domain you're going
to operate on.
There is no such requirement
that each work-item must only
operate on only one pixel;
it could actually
operate on many pixels.
And depending on what you
are doing in your code,
again that computation to memory
ratio, you may find its better
to do more work than less work.
So when we do this, we
actually modify this kernel.
So we had a crack
team working on it
and what they did
is they changed it
to four pixels per work-item.
It's like...it was
actually faster.
And so we like faster, don't we?
So that's what it's
doing; it's for...so and so
in fact each work-group is doing
the work of four work-groups.
So we don't need to look at this
code, but it's straightforward.
It's going to loop
over these things
that the compiler
is going to unroll.
But the point here is that
there is no requirement
of one-to-one mapping; you
can have one-to-end mapping.
And so you have a lot
of flexibility, ok?
And that can actually
help...really help you tune your
code; your data-parallel
function that you want
to execute on the GPU.
All right, so let's talk about
the compute command encoder.
So this is what you
need to send commands
to execute kernels on the GPU.
So just like the
RenderCommandEncoder
for compute, we have this
compute command encoder
but first things first.
Remember I compiled my kernel
and so I have created
a Metal library.
And so I'm going to load that
and I'm going to
load that kernel.
The next thing I'm
going to do is I'm going
to create my compute state.
Just like we had the
render pipeline state,
there's the compute
pipeline state.
And all it takes in this
case is just the function.
The compute doesn't
have a lot of states.
So at this point in time,
remember in the Metal library
the information we compiled
from your source to Metal
IR, an LLVM-based IR,
we're going to take that
and when you create a new
compute pipeline state,
we're going to compile it
to the actual GPU binary
that the GPU is going
to execute, ok?
I'm going to create my
compute command encoder.
I'm ready to send commands now.
So the first thing I'm going
to do is set my compute state.
So then I'm going to set my
resources my kernel uses;
remember the buffers
and textures.
And then I'm going to execute
"ready to encode the command"
to execute the kernel.
So in order to do that,
I need to first set the number
work-items in the work-group,
and how many work-groups
there are.
So in this example,
I use a 16 by 16.
Remember they are
two-dimensional problems;
I'm going to give it
two-dimensional work-group size.
And so I know the
output image dimensions,
I know my work-group
size, so I'm going
to know...calculate how many
work-groups there are going
to be.
And now, I encode the
command to execute the kernel.
So two things I specify:
the work-group size
and how many work-groups
there are, ok?
And then I'm done encoding.
So at this point in time,
commands have been encoded
but the GPU hasn't
received them.
So just like we talked
about sending commands,
you have to commit the command
buffer and when you do that,
the GPU will start
executing this kernel, ok?
So let me show you a demo of
these filtering operations.
All right, so that's
applying and we know the fact
that we can do shadows.
[ Applause ]
Ok, so that's the
highlights and shadows filter,
but I can actually
do a tune filter.
And so this is actually...what
it's doing is its taking your
input image and
applying...converting it
into a what we'll
call the LAB space
which approximates human vision,
then does a bilateral filter,
and then actually
does the tune filter,
and then converts
it back to RGB.
Or let's say I want to
sharpen it so I want
to apply a sharpen filter.
So you can see we adjusted the
image, it's getting sharpened.
Hopefully you do see regions of
the image getting sharpened, ok?
So these are some of the filters
and these are really,
really easy to write.
Because in effect what you're
doing now is you're just writing
your code, your algorithm,
just as a set of functions.
And saying, "Execute
this function
or this problem domain."
Really, really simple
to think about.
So focus more on the algorithm
and that's what data-parallel
computing allows you to do, ok?
So that's all I could...that's
all I'm going to say
about data-parallel
computing and next,
we're going to have Serhat come
and show you the
amazing tools we have
and show you how you can debug
profile Metal applications
in Xcode, so Serhat.
[ Applause ]
>> Well, thank you
Aaftab and hello everyone.
Now I'm going to show off the
great developer tools we have
in Xcode for your Metal apps.
We'll be focusing
on some combinations
such as state setup, shader
compilation, and performance,
and how you can use the tools
to address these issues.
So I have the same app that
Gokhan showed you earlier here.
The shadow buffer
pass has been modified
to use percentage closer
filtering for softer shadows,
but my app has a few issues
that I'm going to fix live.
So let's go ahead and run it.
Ok as you can see,
I've got some compilers
and Xcode is pointing right
here at my G-buffer shader code.
So one of the great things
with Metal is its support
for pre-compiled shaders
right here in Xcode.
So in addition to the improved
initialization time for my app
and other benefits, I also
get to see the compilers
and warnings right here
in Xcode at build time
as opposed to run time.
Let's go in and fix
this real quick.
Let's define user
variables and launch the app.
Now you can imagine this offers
a much more productive workflow
for shader development.
Also using it is pretty
easy, all you have
to do is you add your
.mil shader files,
your Xcode project, and
Xcode takes care of the rest.
Ok so my app is running now,
but there's something wrong
with what I'm rendering.
Now I'm going to take a
frame capture and bring
up the frame developer so that
you can see the issue as well
and to do that, I'm going to
click on this camera icon here
in the Debug bar and
trigger a capture.
When I trigger a capture,
the frame debugger harvests
all the Metal commands
that your application
uses in the frame along
with all the other
resources that it uses
as buffers, textures
and shaders.
With these we can reconstruct
the frame and you can replay
to any particular Metal
command that we choose.
So this is what I was seeing
and you can see my scene
is completely in shadow
and I'm missing my
directional light.
So let's use the frame debugger
to figure out the problem.
Well the first thing
I want to do is I want
to check my commands and make
sure everything is in order.
For that, I'm going to use
the debug navigator here
on the left-hand side
of the Xcode window.
This is where the debugger
shows the old Metal commands
that were executing
in the frame.
You can see that it also
reflects the natural hierarchy
of your command encoders
within your command buffers
that's making it a lot easier
for you to navigate your frame.
Well one thing to keep
in mind here though is,
the order you see
here, is the order
that the GPU executes
these commands.
So it's a bit different
than CPU debugging.
You can also see that most
of my objects here have
human-readable names,
not just draw pointer values.
Metal class has a label
property that lets you set this
and I highly recommend
taking advantage of it
as it's a great aid
in debugging.
Within the encoders,
I can further annotate my
command stream using debug
groups shown in the navigator
as these folder icons.
Well, I can do this by using the
push and pop debug group APIs
and the debug groups are great
for bracketing related commands
together here in the navigator.
Now let's investigate the
G-buffer pass and figure
out what's wrong
with the shadows.
I'm going to click on
this structure debug group
to navigate there; there you go.
And as I navigate my frame,
Xcode's main editor
area is going to update
and show me all the attachments
for the current framebuffer.
The assistant editor is
where I see all my textures,
buffers and functions.
Currently, it's in bound GPU
objects so it's only going
to show me the objects
that are bound
to the current command encoder.
All right, so I can see that my
debuffer attachments look more
or less correct except
for the color.
But if I look at the assistant,
I see that my shadow texture
bound to my fragment shader,
here labeled as "shadow",
is all black.
So that explains why my scene
was completely in shadow,
but it also means that my shadow
buffer passes aren't working
properly, so let's just
go there and investigate.
So I'm going to just expand this
and click on the encoder itself.
Now looking at this
I can see right away
that the depth attachment
for this pass isn't
cleared when it starts.
As Gokhan explained earlier,
you control your
framebuffer attachment clears
with the load action
property of the attachment.
Now not only that, but this
don't look like it was rendered
from the point of light either
but if I step through my frame
to see my geometry,
that looks proper.
So let's look at the
framebuffer state and figure
out what the problem is there.
I can investigate this state
of "any Metal object
using the variables view,"
here at the bottom.
I'll expand that a
little bit [inaudible].
On the right-hand side, I have
a list of all my Metal objects.
But I like to use the Auto
View you see on the left.
This is where you see all the
relevant objects and their state
for the current selected
command only.
So I know what I'm looking for.
My framebuffer state
is going to be
under the RenderCommandEncoder
so I'm going to disclose that
and search for framebuffer.
And yeah, as I suspected, my
load action is not set to clear.
And not only that, the attached
texture here is actually depth;
the texture I was looking at
earlier was labeled "shadow."
Now if I disclose my framebuffer
setup that I prepared earlier,
I can see that I already
have a shadow frame buffer
but I'm using debug
framebuffer here.
So that explains why I
was getting a blank shadow
buffer texture.
I can quickly fix this by
using the debug navigator
to take me straight
to the problem.
And I can do that by going
back to the navigator.
Now you setup your framebuffer
when you're creating your
RenderCommandEncoder.
I can disclose the back-trace
where I create the
RenderCommandEncoder and use
that to jump straight
to the source.
So let me go ahead and
fix this real quick.
It should be shadow.
I'd like to stop my
app and re-launch it
and make sure everything
is running properly.
[ Pause ]
All right, so my scene
looks great now but looking
at the frames per
second tray here,
I can see that I'm not really
getting the performance
I expect.
I'm going to click
on this tray to bring
up the graphics performance
report.
Now I'm getting about
35-ish frames per second;
I was getting 60 earlier.
Now looking at the report, I can
tell my GPU is heavily utilized
with most of the work
coming from the render
or the fragment shader stage.
Ok, to get a more
detailed picture,
let's take another frame capture
and see what the Shader
Profiler has to say about it.
And the Shader Profiler
is at Sampling Profiler.
That's going to automatically
and repeatedly run
all my shaders
in my frame for sampling.
This may take a bit longer
for a more complicated scene,
but that small amount of time
is well worth the investment
as it offers an in-depth
performance analysis
that I otherwise
wouldn't be able to get.
Ok, when the Shader
Profiler is done,
I'm going to get this
program performance table here
in the report.
In this table, I get a breakdown
of the performance cost
of all my render
pipelines in the frame along
with all the draw calls
that use these pipelines.
I can disclose this
so you see that.
Another great way to look
at this is to again go back
to the navigator and
switch it to use the
"View Frame by Program" mode.
Now the nice thing about this is
that I can both navigate my
frame and see my shader profiler
and results at the same time.
So let's look at the
most expensive draw call
and the most expensive
pipeline real quick.
I'm going to hide my
draw call highlight
so that I can see my
attachments better.
And in the Assistant,
I'm going to bring
up that costly fragment shader,
so that I can look at this
for us, make some
more room here.
Oops.
Ok, now as I look at my code,
I can see line-by-line profiling
data right alongside my code
here in the editor.
And if I keep scrolling down,
I see that the most expensive
parts of my shader by far is
where I'm doing the
shadow sampling loop.
So this many samples
is an overkill.
Let's reduce it to just a 2
by 2 grid and Save: Command+S.
Now when I do that, my shader
is going to get recompiled
and my changes will
take effect immediately.
And once the shader
profiler is done analyzing,
I'm going to get updated
performance numbers as well.
And I can see that my
attachments look more
or less unaffected; that's good.
And now I'm spending far less
time in the expensive part
of my shader source
and that's great.
And if I scroll all the way to
the end, this is my end result.
Now I can go ahead and resume
my app and I see a nice,
smooth 60 frames per second.
Excellent.
With that, my work here
is done and it's time
to leave the stage
back to Aaftab.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
All right, so let's
summarize, ok?
So Gokhan, you know, took you
deeper into how Metal works.
You know we talked about how
you structure the application.
The descriptors and state
objects; how do you create them
and when to do what, like
for example: things you want
to do once, like creating
your command queue.
Things you need to create
whenever you need to,
like resources, and things
you must create every frame
and every pass, right?
And he showed you how you can do
multi-pass encoding with Metal.
Then I gave you a
small, brief teaser
into data-parallel
computing, ok?
And then finally we showed you
the amazing tools that we have
in Metal that you can use to
write amazing applications.
That was it.
So for more information,
any questions, you know,
Philip Iliescu and Allan
Schaffer are evangelists.
You know their emails are there.
And documentation
is on our website.
You know you can post questions,
emails on the developer forums.
The first two sessions
that happened this morning,
so these are the ones.
Thank you guys.
[ Applause ]