>> Hello.
[ Applause ]
Welcome to Session 610:
"Building a Game with SceneKit."
SceneKit is an amazing
technology that makes it easy
to write casual 3D games.
Because SceneKit is a high
level API that integrates well
with other Cocoa frameworks,
it's really easy to write games.
We built this demo for WWDC,
and I only required
a few lines of code.
We believe that building
a casual 3D game
with SceneKit is really easy,
and anybody can do that.
It's really fantastic.
So, this is a hands-on session,
so hopefully you
are already familiar
with the basics of SceneKit.
You should know what
a scene graph is;
that nodes have attributes such
as geometry, camera and lights;
and if not, we have great
sessions about this,
one just before and
one last year.
I encourage you to check
these presentations
because they have 3D slides
entirely made in SceneKit.
So, in this session, we
will start really quick
by showing you how to start
in Xcode, how to add 3D assets
to your project, and have
your first scene rendered
to the screen.
Then we will show you
our Bananas demos.
It's a great demo because
it shows many features
of the SceneKit framework,
and we will use
that demo throughout
the rest of the session.
We will explain to
you how we made it
so then you can create
your own games.
And finally, Thomas will
join me onstage to talk
about performance and creating
custom tools for SceneKit.
Okay, let's get started.
The first thing you want to have
when building a 3D app is a view
to render your scene, and
that's just easy as you see.
While integrating between
the interface builder,
so all what you have to
do is drag an SCNView
from the object library and
drop it onto your [inaudible].
Then you open the inspector,
where you can set the
visual properties,
and you simply specify
the name of the 3D scene.
You click Build and Run,
and boom: Without having
to write any single
line of code,
you have your first scene
rendered on the screen.
Now, if you are starting a new
project, you might want to start
with a new game template.
It's really convenient because
it creates a universal app
that runs on iPhone and iPad,
and it has a full-screen 3D view
that displays a scene
you can interact with.
The way you add 3D assets
to your game is just
SceneKit asset catalogs.
SceneKit asset catalogs
are new feature in Xcode 6,
and they allow you to organize
and optimize your 3D assets.
The structure of SceneKit
asset catalogs is preserved
when they are copied
into your target.
Also, they automatically track
files that are added to them
or removed from them on disc.
They are really convenient
because they can optimize
your 3D assets for you.
For instance, they help
with up axis conversion.
SceneKit follows the
up axis conversion,
which means that the positive y
axis is the one that looks up.
This is a convention
that is followed
by many other applications
and frameworks,
but some exporters
do things differently
and use a z up axis convention.
With SceneKit asset catalogs,
you don't have to
think about that.
We automatically
and transparently convert all
the animations and geometries
in your scene so that they
follow the up axis convention.
We are also able
to automatically interleave
your geometries at build time.
This means that your
vertices' position, normal,
and texture coordinates are
stored in a single buffer
that makes the GPU really happy
and faster rendering
your geometries.
And finally, on iOS we
support PVRTC textures.
If you have two versions
of the same texture,
one with the PVRTC
file extension -
which is a compressed file
format that is optimized
for iOS - and another version
- for instance, a PNG -
this code will automatically
select the PVRTC texture
when you target iOS
and the regular version
when you target OS X.
So, this is how it
works: Your artist works
in their favorite
authoring tool;
they export all the animation
and models you want to use
in your app in a
COLLADA document.
Then you take over and
you import this document
in SceneKit asset catalogs.
But there is much more
you can do with Xcode.
To help you have a better
understanding of your scene,
we built a scene
[inaudible] into Xcode.
This tool is really great,
not only to allow you
to have a better understanding
of what is inside your scene,
but it's also useful to
tweak and refine the scene.
For instance, with direct
manipulation you can place the
nodes where you want, you can
rotate them and scale them,
and that's much less code
to write in your app.
You can also see how
nodes are arranged.
You can re-bound them.
You can merge them.
You can create and delete nodes
as well as node attributes.
You can immediately see which
node has a camera, light,
or geometry attached to
it, and it also allows you
to have a quick look at all
the entities in your scene.
Remember that in SceneKit
node attributes are shared
by default, and this
is a great way
to know how many unique
objects you have in your scene,
and it helps for performance.
Of course, we have
inspectors in this editor.
You can edit node properties,
and as you make changes,
they are automatically
reflected in the viewports.
This works for node
attributes as well.
You can edit all the camera,
lights and geometry properties
that are exposed
in the raw APIs.
And finally, it works
on materials.
This is really cool.
It allows you to finely tweak
the rendering of your objects.
You can control exactly how
they will render in your scene,
because what you see
here in the editor,
that is exactly how SceneKit
will render the scene
in your app.
It's a huge timesaver.
In addition to the scene editor,
we have a particle
system editor.
It's really useful to edit
particle system properties,
and it becomes very convenient
when you have to do things
that would be very
tiresome in code.
For instance, finding
the right animation curve
to control the size of your
particles can take a very long
time in code.
With the editor and
immediate feedback,
it's really quick and easy.
So, we've already
covered a lot here.
We know how to work
with an artist.
You know how to tweak
scenes in the editor.
You can automatically optimize
them using the asset catalogs,
and you can render them on
the screen without having
to write any line of code.
And now, to show you
how truly simple it is
to write a casual 3D
game, we built a demo.
So, first it's a sample code,
so might you have any questions
about what you are going to see
on the screen, you will be able
to dive into the code
and see how it was done.
And it's a great sample code
because it illustrates many
features of SceneKit: animation,
lighting and shadows,
physics, particles
and advanced rendering.
So, let's have a
look at the demo.
So, this is our game
named "Bananas."
As you can see, we are in the
jungle controlling an explorer.
We use gestures to make the
character walk along the path.
On the track, we can collect
bananas, but there are enemies.
We have some animated monkeys
that throw coconuts at us.
So [inaudible], you
can jump and run.
Look how the scene
looks gorgeous.
We have perfect [inaudible]
real-time lighting
as well as real-time shadows.
Look how the character is lit
when it approaches the torches.
As we advance in the game,
we encounter obstacles.
Here is a lava flow, and falling
into it is not a good idea.
So here we have to start again,
and you will notice how
the explorer produce dust
as she runs.
If you look at the background,
you will notice a volcano.
The volcano is erupting,
and this is where
the lava comes from.
In fact, everything that's
in this scene is animated:
the character and the
enemies, the lava,
the torches, the vines as well.
And as you can see,
everything is 3D in this scene.
When the character moves, the
camera follows in 3D space
and offers new points of view.
We also have a soundtrack
and sound effects.
There is also a basic UI that
show you how much time is left
and your current score.
This one's really supposed to
be on an iPad, but it works
on iPhone too at 60
frames per second.
Okay. Thanks, Thomas.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
So, this was "Bananas."
It's an All Objective-C project,
and it's a small project:
only 2,700 lines of code
for everything you saw
onscreen today for iOS and OS X.
And so, you don't have
to have a big team
to write a 3D casual
game with SceneKit.
Bananas was written by
a team of one designer
and only one engineer.
It's really easy
to make such games.
So first, a quick look
behind the scenes.
Here is our world.
It's a simple track on
which the character walks.
Look how palm trees and rocks do
not always stand on the ground.
This is because your scene
should only be made of elements
that will, at some point,
be visible from the camera.
Here is a side view.
As you can see, vines
aren't attached to anything.
They float in the air, and
the world suddenly ends.
There's no need to have extra
geometry pushed to the GPU
if it's never rendered
onto the screen.
We have low [inaudible]
for the mountains
and the volcano as
the background.
It's absolutely fine to cheat
when you write 3D games.
Here, the scene is sparse,
and you have to find tricks
to make the scene gorgeous
but really cheap to render.
So to give you some idea
of reasonable numbers,
here are statistics
from the game.
We have 10 lights in the world,
but each object is only affected
by three lights at most.
We have 200k polygons
in the world,
but at each frame,
only 80 are rendered.
And to finish, we have at
most 50 draw calls per frame,
and that will make more sense
when Thomas talks
about performance.
So of course we use SceneKit
assets catalogs in "Bananas."
We have about 25 3D documents
that store animation, models,
textures and particle systems.
And how do you use that many
different documents you want
to consider in your game?
Well, let's take this example.
Here we have a document
which stores the jungle,
and then those are documents
which stores our animated
monkey, and we want to view
that monkey in our world.
The first step is really easy.
All you have to do is
to load the two scenes.
We have to - where you
have to be careful is
that you cannot directly
add the root node
of one scene to another scene.
This is because root nodes
are not meant to be rebounded.
What you have to do instead is
to retrieve the node you're
interested in by using its name
and then add it to
the original scene.
And of course, you can add
multiple copies of that node.
So SceneKit is a high level
API that [inaudible] well
with other APIs on
the web platform,
so we support game controllers
to control the character.
But we also leverage
gesture recognizers
and implemented our own
"D-pad" gesture recognizer
to make the character jump
and go left and right.
And then on OS X, we also
support game controllers
and simply listen
to keyboard events.
So how do we move the character?
First, we have to animate it.
Our character is skinned, which
means that it has a skeleton
with bones, and by
animating these bones,
we can define the geometry
and make the character
adopt defined postures.
Our character can
run, jump and be idle.
And you have different
animations
for the bones in these files.
Animating a character
is just as easy
as retrieving a Core
Animation animation
by using the assigned
sceneSource class.
It allows us to retrieve
an animation,
with a unique identifier
of the animation
that you can find in Xcode.
And then, animating the
character is just as easy
as adding this animation
to the character node.
Okay, so now we animating
the character,
but we still have to move it.
There are many ways to do that,
and here is the technique
we used in "Bananas."
In our authoring tool,
we placed empty nodes
at different locations
in the scene.
We then use a [inaudible]
of time
to interpolate these values.
It's a smooth parametric
curve that goes
through each of these locations.
And then moving the
character is just as easy
as evaluating this function
at different times,
between zero and one.
And for the camera, when the
character goes to the right,
we simply [inaudible] the
camera, and at each frame,
we move it by 120 feet its
distance to the character.
This gives us these nice
[inaudible] animations that's
really pleasing when
you play the game.
Note, in iOS 8 and
OS X Yosemite,
SceneKit has an active
support for physics.
And we use collision detection
at many places in the game -
to make the character
stay on the path,
to detect when we
are hit by coconuts
and when we collect
bananas, for instance.
How does it work?
Well, each scene has a physics
world, which has a delegate.
And each time a collision
occurs in the scene,
the delegate is notified
and can react.
We can also explicitly perform
ray tests, and that what we use
to compute is the
altitude of the character.
So we cast a ray and compute the
intersection between that ray
and the ground to calculate
the altitude of the character.
Animating items is different
than animating a character.
For items such as the
bananas, we use actions
that was presented in
the previous session,
that really easy to
manipulate programmatically.
So here's the lighting
in "Bananas."
As you can see, we have objects
that aren't affected
by any light.
They use a constant
lighting model.
For all the other objects in the
scene, we add an ambient light,
so it's very ambient
when it's all black.
Next, we have the
directional key light.
And under there directional
backlight, to add more contrast.
Finally, for torches
and lava flows,
we have only directional lights.
With this dynamic lighting,
we also want shadows,
and we have multiple
techniques in "Bananas."
First, static shadows.
Static shadows are suitable for
objects that aren't animated
in the scene, such
as the palm trees.
Static shadows are
baked into textures,
which means that they
are rendered offline
in an authoring tool.
And that's why they are
generally very complex
and detailed.
Setting a static shadow is
as simple as setting an image
to the multiplied
property of a material.
But we also have
dynamic shadows,
for objects that move,
such as a character.
For dynamic shadows,
we use shadow maps.
These are real-time shadows and
suitable for animated objects.
And making your light
cast shadows is as simple
as setting a property.
Next, of course you
can mix techniques
and use dynamic and
static shadows.
After you make your
light cast shadows,
you can simply exclude nodes
that are using static shadows,
so that they don't
cast dynamic shadows.
This can also be achieved
by using categoryBitMasks.
You use exclusive masks
on the light and nodes
that don't cast shadows.
So this is one example of
dynamic shadows, but we have one
on other, which we
call projected shadows.
Projected shadows are
real-time as well,
but they are simplified,
and they are very suitable
for low-end devices.
Using projected shadows is done
by using the modulated
shadow mode.
You set an image to the
gobo property of a light,
and then every object
that is lit
with this light has this
image projected on it.
So in "Bananas," to make the
floor only receive this image,
we use a categoryBitMask.
Next, particle systems.
We use particle systems
extensively in "Bananas."
We use them for torches and
when the character walks.
Using particle system
is real easy.
All you have to do is
load a particle system
from a file and add
it to a node.
[Inaudible] particle
system of dynamic,
we can make the character emit
a lot of dirt when she runs
and emit nothing
when she stands idle.
We also have some nice visual
improvements in "Bananas."
We use geometry animation
for the vines,
and we use texture animation
for the lava and the volcano.
You might have seen that smoke
is emitted by the volcano,
and that the lava
flow is animated.
This is done using
shader modifiers.
What we do is we have
a shader modifier
that continuously updates
the texture coordinates
of the lava and the volcano.
This is really simple.
Next, we have some
visual postprocessing.
We use SCNTechnique,
which is new this year
and that lets us achieve color
effects and image deformation.
We use that in "Bananas"
when we launch the game
to have this nice
grayscale effect.
We also use SpriteKit overlays.
SpriteKit overlays
are really nice,
because they are cross-platform.
They work on iOS and OS X.
And they let you build
UIs that work everywhere.
In SpriteKit - in "Bananas," we
use that to display a simple UI
that shows you the final
score, and when you're playing,
it shows you the current
time and your score.
And finally, we use an SKAction
to play sound in the game.
So as you saw, we
have a soundtrack
as well as sound effects.
So I hope we showed
you how simple it is
to write casual 3D
games with SceneKit.
We truly believe that
anyone, even a small team,
can write games with SceneKit.
And with that, I hand
it over to Thomas,
to talk about performance.
Thanks.
[ Applause ]
>> Thank you.
Okay. So let's talk
about performance now.
So Xcode has some great
tools to get information
about performance and in
particular with graphics,
performance with graphics report
that you probably already knew.
In this release of Xcode 6,
we are adding a new report,
that we call the
SceneKit report,
that will give you CPU time
information about your game.
So this report is not available
in the first seed
of Xcode 6 yet.
So you will have to wait for the
next seed to have it in hand.
But I would like to
present how it works now,
since we are talking
about performance.
So this report will give
you timing information
about all the different
steps of your game loop.
You'll remember your game
loop looks like this.
It's made of both
callbacks that you implement
to your game logic, and also
of SceneKit internal process,
like rendering itself or
the evaluation of physics
and animations and constraints.
So the SceneKit report will give
you many milliseconds aspect
into those different steps.
And this is for iOS only.
But on OS X, we have something
equivalent, directly available
in the SCNView with the
showsStatistics property.
If you set this statistics
- this property to yes,
it will display a little
overlay on top of your view
that you can expand to get
more detailed statistics.
And basically, it contains
the same information
as the iOS report.
Sorry - here it is.
Okay.
And so this is how
to get information.
Now, let's see how to
analyze this information.
If your game is running slow,
the first thing to understand is
if you are limited by
the CPU or by the GPU.
For this, use a graphic report
and look at the third column.
It will tell you how many
milliseconds are spent
on the CPU side and
the GPU side.
Both should be under 16
milliseconds if you want
to run your game at
60 frames per second.
Now let's say we are alerted
by the GPU, let's say.
You can switch to the
SceneKit report to get details
about the different steps.
And then depending
on the returned -
the numbers that are returned,
there are some obvious
actions we can do.
For example, if it says that
most of the time is spent
in physics, you might
want to reduce the number
of dynamic bodies in your scene
or simplify the shape
of your bodies.
And if it's in particles,
you want to [inaudible]
reduce the number of emitters
or reduce the number
of emitted particles.
So these are the obvious things.
Now, less obvious is
the time you spent
in the rendering itself or when
pushing the OpenGL commands.
Then it's very likely because
your scene requires too many
draw calls to render.
The number of draw calls
is something very important
for your frame rate.
And if you have too
many draw calls,
it will impact your CPU time.
You can check how many draw
calls your scene is doing
with a SceneKit report
by looking
at the third column here.
This is for iOS.
On OS X, you have
the same information
in the statistics overlay
in the lower right corner.
And if this number is big, and
if you are limited by the CPU,
you want to reduce the
number of draw calls.
And to do that, what
you can try to do is
to flatten your static
objects into one single node.
For example, in "Bananas," we
have many plants and palm trees
that are static, and instead of
adding one node for every plant,
we grouped them and flattened
them into a single node,
so that it ends up
into a single draw call
to render many plants
at the same time.
To flatten objects,
you have two options.
You can ask your artist
to flatten directly
in the 3D software.
3D software, great tools
to flatten everything
into a single object.
This is the recommended way,
because everything
is pre-computed,
so that nothing to
do at runtime.
And this is obviously faster.
Now if needed, you can also
flatten things programmatically
with the flattenedClone
method and SCNNode.
It will flatten the entire node
tree and return the new node
with no time load that
render exactly the same.
So flattening is really going to
improve the number of draw call,
but don't flatten too much.
Because let's say you
have a very large level.
If you flatten everything
into a single node,
it will end up into a giant
mesh, with millions of polygon.
And so you will lose the
benefit of the culling
of the objects that
are not visible.
Your big mesh will
be always visible,
and so you will push millions
of polygons at every frame,
which is obviously not
good for the performance.
And also, your huge mesh
will be lit by all the lights
in the world, which is not
good for the performance,
and I will explain why after.
So here is how we
did in "Bananas."
We first split the level
into chunks that are
about the width of the viewport.
That way, when the character
progress, we can directly -
SceneKit automatically culls
the chunks that are not visible,
and so they are not pushed
to the rendering
[inaudible] at all.
And since almost every scene
in one chunk is flattened,
that means that we
are only rendering one
or two chunks at the same time.
And so we are really pushing
a few number of draw calls
to render to chunks
that are visible.
So that's if you
are CPU limited.
Now, if you are GPU
limited, again,
you can use the graphic report
and look at the third column
to check how many milliseconds
you are using on the GPU side.
And if you are GPU limited,
there are two things to look at.
The first one is a
tiler on one side.
The second one is
the renderer/device.
So this is here in
the second column.
So let's consider the
renderer and device for now.
If your renderer and device
usage are at 100 percent,
it is very likely because you
are either fill rate limited,
or you are using too
complex fragment shaders.
So let's consider
first the fill rate.
Fill rate means - if
you're fill rate limited,
it means that you are asking
the GPU to render more pixels -
more fragments per second
than it can actually render.
If that happen, you
can first try to play
with the content scale
factor of your view.
By default, SceneKit is using
a 2x contents scale factor,
which means fully [inaudible].
But you can try, depending on
the device, to switch to 1x
or any intermediate values.
You can also try to reduce the
number of postprocess effects,
since they are usually
full-screen effects.
They are [inaudible].
So typically deferred
shadows, depths of field,
reflective floors and all
your custom postprocessing.
Reduce that if you
are fill rate limited.
Last, you can also try to play
with the anti-aliasing level
by setting the antialiasingMode
property of the view to one
of the available constants
known [inaudible] sampling 4x
for limited sampling.
Note that on iOS, it's
already turned off by default,
and it's 4x by default on OS X.
So that's for the fill rate.
Now, the other reason could be
that you are using too
complex fragment shaders.
And most of the time,
the complexity
of your shaders directly
depends on the complexity
of the lighting in your scene.
So I remind that there
are two type of lightings:
dynamic lighting
and static lighting.
With static lighting, all the
light informations are baked
into textures.
So if they're super-fast,
it can look really great.
But obviously, it only works
with objects that are static.
And so here we focus on dynamic
lightings that we need to use
when objects are moving.
One thing important about lights
is their area of influence.
So you can configure
the attenuation distance
with an attenuationEndDistance,
and beyond that distance,
a light won't influence
the other objects.
And this part is
really important,
because we're getting
into performance.
What matters is not the total
number of lights in your scene.
It's the number of lights
that influence a given object.
So for example, here, I have
three lights in my scene.
But I configured the attenuation
distance so that most
of the objects are only
affected by one light,
or two lights, in
the worst case.
So that means that the light
with the 1, or - sorry.
The object with the 1
will be, the rendering
of them will be relatively
cheap.
The rendering of the objects
with a 2 will be
slightly more expensive.
But at least no objects in
that scene will be affected
by 3 [inaudible]
lights at the same time.
Here's how we did
it in "Bananas."
We placed the torches
and the lava,
so that when the character
progress in the game,
it is never affected
by more than one torch
or one lava at a time.
Related to lighting, shadows,
shadows are also expensive.
Again, there are two type of
shadows: dynamic and static.
Static for this particular
scene is baked
into textures with 3D 2s.
And it's fast, so let's focus
on dynamic shadows
for dynamic objects.
The first thing to
consider is what mode
of shadow you want to use.
If you want to use the
real dynamic shadows
with the 4-1 mode,
which is the default.
And you might want to
consider projected shadows
for low-end devices with the
right shadow image it can write
to, and it is really fast.
If you are using
dynamic shadows,
there are still a
few things you can do
to optimize the performance.
The first thing is to play with
the size of the shadow map.
When you are using dynamic
shadows, SceneKit computes
such shadow maps at
every frame typically
by rendering your scene from
the light point of view.
So if you're fill rate limited,
by setting the shadow map size
to a smaller size, it will
reduce the fill rate impact
of the shadowMapSize
computation.
You can also play with the
shadowSampleCount property
on SCNLight.
This inputs a lot to the
complexity of the shadow
that is generated to
compute the shadows.
Note that on iOS, it is
already 1x by default,
which corresponds
to hard shadows.
And it is 8x by default on
OS X for smooth shadows.
Still about GPU, one more reason
to be limited by the renderer is
when you are doing too many
texture sample in your game.
So first thing to
check is to make sure
that you are not using
unnecessary large textures
in your game.
For example, if your texture is
always rendered small on screen,
there's no need to have
a huge texture for that.
One more thing to do is, it's
better - if you're using tons
of textures, it's better to
pack them into a texture atlas.
For that, 3D softwares
have great tools
to bake your textures
into texture atlases,
and you can also use SpriteKit
to generate texture
atlases for you.
If you are using - if you need
to use very large textures,
you can also try to
play with mipmapping.
Mipmapping improves
the performance a lot
when you are rendering a
large texture at a small size,
because it will pick and
choose smaller resolution
of your texture.
It can also improve
the rendering
by reducing some aliasing
effects and some Moire effects.
It has some drawbacks, though.
It takes more time to
load, and it can use also -
it uses also slightly
more memory.
To turn on the mipmapping, just
set the mipFilter property on,
the mipFilter property on
the [inaudible] property.
Set it to linear to turn it
on and none to turn it off.
OK. So that was for the
renderer and device part.
Now, let's say you are
limited by the tiler this time.
If you are limited by the tiler,
that means that you are pushing
too many vertices to the GPU.
And so by extension,
that you are -
you have too many polygons.
You can check how many
polygons your scene is rendering
at every frame, with
SceneKit report here.
This is for iOS.
On OS X, you have the equivalent
in the statistics overlay here.
And so if you have
too many polygons,
obviously the first thing you
can try is to reduce the number
of polygons in your models.
And the second thing
you can try or so is
to play with level of detail.
SceneKit has some support
for level of details.
For example, here I have
three version of the teapot -
of these teapots with
more or less polygons.
And so with the higher
and lower quality.
And I can group them into a
single level of detail array
and assign that to my geometry.
Then SceneKit will automatically
use the right level of detail,
depending on how big your
model is displayed onscreen.
So you can associate to each
resolution either a distance
from the camera or screen reduce
and to tell SceneKit what level
of detail it should use.
And this can help a lot to
reduce the number of polygons
in your game, because with
this example, here for example,
the teapots in the
background are rendered
with a low resolution,
and so most of the teapots are
using very low - a small number
of polygons instead of having
the huge resolution all
the time.
So to sum up all of this, when
your game is running slow,
you first need to understand
if you are limited
by the CPU or GPU.
And if it's with the GPU,
you have to check the tiler
or the renderer and device.
If you're limited by the CPU,
you can try to reduce the number
of draw calls by
flattening your scenes,
and also if you are using too
- if your time is spent, sorry,
in physics or animations,
you can try to reduce that.
If you are limited by the tiler,
you can try to play with level
of details to reduce
the number of polygons,
and you can also try to split
your scene in smaller chunks
to alleviate the culling.
If you're limited by
the renderer or device,
you can try to simplify
your materials.
It will end up being
simpler shaders.
You can simplify your
lighting, try to reduce the size
of fill textures and try
to turn on mipmapping
if you are using large textures.
And if you are fill rate
limited, you can also try
to reduce the number of
full-screen postprocess.
Now some more, other
performance notes.
First, about sharing.
When you copy a node
in SceneKit,
by default it shares
the attributes.
So this is ideal
for the performance.
But now, let's say you want to
modify NodeA.GeometryA.Material.
It will also modify
the color of Node B.
And so this is a common pitfall.
If it's what you
want, that's perfect.
Now, if you want a
different material for Node B,
what you have to do first is
to copy the geometry as well.
And see, the geometry
is immutable,
it is relatively cheap,
because no geometry data is
actually copied.
It's just shared.
And then you can just simply
copy the material as well,
and now you can modify Material
A and Material B independently
to have a different material
colors for your objects.
Another note, this
time about preloading.
By default, SceneKit
will load the information
on the GPU when needed.
That means that when your
objects are never rendered,
nothing is pushed to the GPU.
And the first time an
object appears onscreen,
we compute everything the GPU
needs to render that object.
And depending on the
complexity of this object,
it can take some time, and in
some cases, it can make you
to miss some frame and so
suffer from frame drops.
To avoid that, you can preload
your objects, if you want,
with the prepareObjects
withCompletionHandler
on SCNView.
You can pass to this
method the following object.
If you pass a material instance,
SceneKit will pre-compute
all the textures
that are referenced
by this material.
If you pass the geometry,
it will pre-compute all
the geometry buffers -
like the vertices, no more than
texture coordinates - and also,
all the materials that are
referenced by this geometry.
If you pass a node, it will
preload the entire node tree,
including all the geometries
that are attached
to these nodes.
And last, if you pass the entire
scene, it can do even more.
It will preload the node
tree, but also all the shaders
that are needed to
render the objects.
It only works when you pass a
scene, because SceneKit needs
to know how many lights
you have in your scene
to pre-compute the
right shaders.
In "Bananas," for
example, at launch,
we preload the entire scene
to have almost all our
shaders directly ready
when the game starts.
Okay. Some notes about custom
tools and workflow now.
So I'm already presented how
to manage your assets
in assets catalogs.
But at some point,
you may want to sort
of customize your workflow.
By, for example,
building your own tools
that we process your assets,
or having your own tools
to debug your game.
And for this, SceneKit
provides some APIs to help you.
The first one is archiving.
Now, this is new
in this release.
All the objects of
the scene graph
of the API conforms
to NSSecureCoding.
So that allows you to
archive whatever object,
an archive with a [inaudible]
NSKeyedArchiver, for example.
SceneKit also allows you to
export your scene as COLLADA.
And here, the advantage is
that you can export to COLLADA
and import it back
to a 3D software.
However, note that only a subset
of SceneKit can be
exported to COLLADA.
If we compare both, so
the first difference is
that archives can be
directly loaded on iOS,
although COLLADA files need
to go through Xcode first
if you want to load them on iOS.
Then you can import back COLLADA
files to any 3D software,
but obviously, you can't
import SceneKit archives.
Both report the scene
graph basics,
like the node hierarchies, the
node names, the geometries,
all the materials
and the animations.
They work for both.
But advanced features like
actions, physics, particles
and even custom shaders,
everything is archived -
works with archive but not
in - supported by COLLADA.
One more note.
As mentioned in the
previous session,
SceneKit is now fully
[inaudible] with JavaScript.
This can be really
helpful for your -
if you want to customize
your workflow
or add debug tools
to debug your games.
It's [inaudible]
with JavaScript call.
And so the "Bananas" sample
code we showed in our -
here is available on
the developer website.
We also have three other
sample codes available:
the little car demo we showed
in the previous session,
the demo that was shown
in the state of the union,
and the 3D slide that was
shown in the previous session
that is for OS X only.
For more information, please
contact our evangelists,
Allan Schaffer and
Filip Iliescu.
We have new gorgeous
documentation available
on the developer
website, as well.
And we have a dedicated
forum for SceneKit
on devforums.apple.com.
Don't hesitate to ask
your questions there.
Some related sessions.
So, obviously, the
previous sessions about
"What's New in SceneKit.
Also have a look to
the SpriteKit sessions,
since both can work well
together to achieve great stuff.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]